<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Freezing Injury of Seed Corn</title>
               <date value="1920-06">1920-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">RESEARCH BULLETIN NO. 16 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FREEZING INJURY OF SEED CORN T. A. Kiesselhaih and J. A. Ratcliff Accepted for publication February, 1918 Distributed Jine, 1920 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD (the regents of the university) HON. JOHN E. MILLER, President. Lincoln Term expires January, 1921 HON. JOHN R. WEBSTER, Vice-President, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey Term expires January, 1921 HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln Term expires January, 192a HON. HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward Term expires January, 1923 HON. FRANK D. JUDSON, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor 3. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc., Director W. W. BURR, B. Sc., Vice Director W. H. BROKAW, Director of Extension Service THE WORKING STAFF O. W. Sjogren, B. Sc. in A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. BtKK, B. Sc., Agronomy T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph. D., Agronomy H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene •J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology and Hygiene F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Chemistry J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture O. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology George L. Peltier, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc., Poultry Husbandry H. C. FiiiET, A. M., Aural Economics W. P. Sntder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte E. M. Brouse, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine J. A. Hoi.den, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell ••L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte J. W. Caivin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry W. J. Loeffel, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry C. K. Shedd, B. Sc. in A. E., Assistant in Agricultural Engineering P. L. Gaduis, A. B., B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy F. D. Keim, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene J. W. Hkndrickson, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry John Luithlt, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry C. C. Wiggans, Ph. D., Assistant in Horticulture H. O. Werner, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture It. W. Gobs, M. S., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physiology J. O. Rankin, A. M., Assistant in Rural Economics •Resigned ••Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agri - culture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS 3 Suinmarv &gt; Introduction a Character of corn embryo and process of germination y Freezing injury not due to arrested development of the embryo 13 Moisture content of corn 10 ( )ld corn if, New corn 17 17 Physical effects of freezing 17 Ice formation in kernels 17 Effect of freezing on color of embryo IS Effect of freezing on embryonic tissues 18 18 Chemical effects of freezing 20 Probable cause of death from freezing 21 Historical review 21 Crushing of plant tissues or rupturing of cell structures 21 Too rapid thawing 22 Desiccation of the protoplasm 28 ■_'•&gt; Physical and chemical disorganization of the proto - plasm and other cell contents 24 Personal interpretation 25 Effects of freezing upon the viability of seed corn cts of freezing upon the viability of seed corn 27 Vitality of corn frozen under control condition-; 28 Apparatus 28 Selection of material 30 Method of handling 31 Moisture tests 31 Subjection to freezing temperatun &gt;i Germination ... 32 )•_ Observation of ice in seed 32 Color of embrvo 3;l ')•&gt; Relation between moisture content and injury at various degrees of freezing various decrees of freezing 33 Freezing at temperature rang* 82 to 28 F 33 Freezing at temperature range 24 to 20 F 30 Freezing at temperature range lfi to 12 F 38 Freezing at temperature range 8 to 4 F 40 Freezing at temperature range 0 to -5 F 42 Summary of germination tests made tinder con- trolled conditions 45 Effect of freezing on dry corn 46 Natural resistance of green corn to cold 47 Vitality of corn exposed to freezing temperatures in the field 52 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Page ( icncral survey .Vj Field selection in 1913 54 Field selection in 1!»14 ■ Field selection in 1!U5 57 Kffeet of early freezing on varieties, 1915. . . . 00 i-uivi in Kaiiy ji n/.ui^ wu iiu» in&gt;, iwi»i. . . . \r\t Kffect of more seven 1 rreexing, L915 &lt;&gt;1 Variation within a single ear (&gt;-j Kffect of first killinj; frost on varieties. 1!)17.. &lt;&gt;4 Degree of maturitv selected at different dates in the fall and winter of 101 T &lt;&gt;."&gt; Condition of corn in cribs on January -J&lt;(. 1918 71 The danger line of freezing injury i p? m — j — • ■* Occurrence of autumn frosts in Nebraska 7'2 Freezing injury inevitable in occasional yeai Selection for earliness i .i fa Alternatives in seed selection 7tl Combination of methods for selecting seed 7!&gt; Ascertaining viability 7!&gt; Relative corn yields for the state of Nebraska in years fol lowing severe seed corn injury S4 Effect of time of selection and preservation of seed corn upon the yield 84 Relative yields of different ear types s." F.ffect of uniform stand on yield H7 Effect of imperfect hills in checked corn ss Probable distribution of plants when seed of low germina - tion is planted !&gt;() Distribution of sound kernels when seed tests 75 per cent !&gt;:_' Distribution of sound kernels when Heed tests 65 per cent 94 Distribution of sound kernels when wed tests 50 jm'i* cent 1)4 Literature cited 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARY 1. Injury to seed corn by freezing in the fall i- of fre - quent occurrence in Nebraska. The underlying causes of such injury are: (1) Late maturity. (-J) abnormally early freezing weather. 2. The embryo, which is the vital part of ;i corn kernel, is in reality a rudimentary corn plant, having -until leivc-. stalk. and root. 3. In the normal process of germination, or growth of the embryo, the primary root develops more rapidly than the plumule. 4. The embryo and endosperm of a kernel of corn develop approximately at the same rate from the time of fertilization until maturity, and the power of germination is attained in about -20 davs after fertilization. ."&gt;. The embryo and endosperm in an air-dry kernel of corn contain practically the same percentage of moisture. How - ever, during the period just before maturity the percentage is greater for the embryo. &lt;». When immature or moist kernels of corn are sufficiently ex nosed to freezing temperatures, ice is formed in t!i ■ inter - cellular spaces and in the larger spaces around the seutellum. plumule, primary root, and root sheath. 7. Severe freezing of immature or moist corn causes the embryo to change from a normally light or craamy color to a dark or yellowish brown color. This change is usually accom - panied by a loss of vitality. The appearance of the embryo, therefore, is a fairly safe guide in judging the germ i native power of seed corn which has been subject to freezing injury. 8. So far as could be detected from microscopic ■ i ximint» - tions of frozen embryonic tissues, there was no rupturing of cell walls or other cytological effect of freezing and ice forma - tion. The change in color of the embryo as a result of freezing would seem to indicate that a chemical change had taken place. 9. The real cause of death from freezing of plant tissues is a difficult matter to determine. Nevertheless, several theories based on certain observations have been advanced to explain it. The most generally accepted theory is that water is withdrawn from the cells during the process of freezing, and that this process continues until death results from desiccation of the protoplasm. The most satisfactory explanation, however, in the light of the evidence at hand, is found in the theory, that freezing produces a physical or chemical change, aside from the withdrawing of water, in the protoplasmic and nuclear material of the cell so that the element of life no longer exists. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Acrici i.tirai, Exp. Station Reheabch Bex. 1&lt;&gt; 10. Death from freezing is directly related to the moisture content of the kernel and also to the duration of the exposure to cold. Seed corn maturing in a natural way b -come- cold resistant progressively as its moisture content diminishes. Seed corn mortality increases progressively as the duration of the killing: temperature is extended. Seed corn samples containing various amounts of moisture were husked from the Held and subjected artificially for twenty-four hours to various freezing temperature ranges. After freezing, parts of each sample together with corresponding unfrozen samples were allowed to thoroly cure, after which germination tests were made. The relative germination of the frozen and the unfrozen samples indicates the degree of freezing injury upon the viability as follows: Tempera- Moisture Content of Grain (Per Cent) ture Ranges 10-15 15-20120-25 25-30 30-3535-40 40-45 45-50 50-55 55-60 60-65 Degrees F. Relative germination (Per cent) 32 to 28 i ... 100 85 75 71 j 69 . 33 31 , 0 24to20 100 96 i 77 67 13 12 12 6 i 0 0 16 to 12 100 88 34 I 12 0 0 0 0 0 0 8 to 4 . 100 98 47 7 0 0 0 0 Oto-5 97 630 0 0 0 00 00 0 Where data are lacking no tests were made 11. The vitality of corn containing from 1j to 20 per cent of moisture will not be injured by ordinary autumn freezing; and corn with 10 to 14 per cent of moisture will stand the most severe winter temperatures without injury to its germin - ative power. 12. The kernels upon an ear of corn may vary in moisture content which may explain partial germination of an ear of corn after exposure to freezing temperatures. 13. Ice formation within the kernel is not necessarily fatal to the vitality of the germ. 14. The variation in time of freezing weather together with the great seasonal variation in time of corn maturity makes freezing injury inevitable in occasional vears. 1"). The best adapted types of corn for Nebraska condi - tions should ripen two or three weeks before the mean date of the first killing frost for the locality in which they are grown. 16. Varieties which ripen too late may be made to ripen earlier (1) by field selection of seed from the earlier maturing </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 7 plants before autumn frosts, and (2) by selection of the lrier and more mature cars later in the season. Such late varieties may often Ik* advantageously replaced by securing seed &gt;f some earlier variety. 17. The conditions are very exceptional in which a satis - factory seed supply cannot l&gt;e obtained by any of the three following methods: (1) Special early field selection before any likelihood of frost. (2) Selecting seed late in September, or early in ()ctol&gt;er while husking corn in the regular way for early feed. (3) Selecting seed while picking corn to crib in the forepart of the husking season. The relative merits of these three methods will vary according to conditions. Crib selection of seed corn may be practiced as a last resort if provision for a seed supply by other methods has been over - looked. In years when corn matures well it is a very good and safe practice to select sufficient seed for two years' planting. 18. The viability of seed corn should be ascertained before planting time. This may l&gt;e done in a general way by a general germination test or by observing the color of the germ. Dark or discolored germs possess little or no vitality. If either of these methods indicate a rather low vitality, a more severe elimination of unsound seed should be made by the individual ear germination test. 19. By a comparison of the yields of corn following years of serious seed corn injury with the average yield of corn for Nebraska during the last 28 years, it seems that predictions of low yields following years of severe seed injury are not justified. 20. Corn harvested early in the fall and given special care in preservation will not outyield seed which has been exposed in the field to the cold winter without special care, provided both are selected for high germinative qualities. As an average for three years, 1915 to 1917. seed corn harvested by special selection from the field in September. November, and March, and given good care after selection, yielded respectively 48.2, 49.6. and 51.2 bushels per acre, while seed saved from the same field during the regular process of husking in November yielded 50.6 bushels per acre. 21. In a comparison of ear types of Nebraska White Prize corn during the four years 1914 to 1917, a long, slender, smooth type of ear yielded 58.8 bushels per acre, which is 0.7 bushels more than the original corn. 7.4 bushels more than the large rough ears, 1.7 bushels more than the short rough ears, and 2.1 bushels more than the short smooth ears. One may conclude that this long, slender, smooth type possesses highly satisfactory </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agkk i lti rai. Exp. Station Kkskain n But. 16 8 yielding qualities, which, coupled with its superior germinative ability, makes it a very suitable ty]H&gt; to grow. 22. Uniform and varied distribution of seed corn in the field were compared for yield of grain. It was found that there may Ik' much irregularity in stand without a material effect upon yield. As an average for the years 1915 and 1916, a uniform stand of three plants per hill yielded 1.8 jkm- cent more than the mean for the varied distributions in which suc - cessive hills contained (a) 1. 2. 3. 4. and 5 plants, (b) 2 and 4 plants, and (c) 1. &amp;, and 5 plants. This is greater irregularity than results from mechanical variation of corn planters, or from planting 75 per cent germinating seed corn at the rate of four plants per hill. 23. Comparative yields were obtained during two years for corn hills containing one. two. or three plants, when sur - rounded by hills with three plants. Two-plant hills and one - plant hills yielded respectively 18 per cent and 30 per cent less than a three-plant hill. Fifty per cent of the yield lost in a hill with one missing plant was recovered in the four nearest adjacent hills at right angles. Seventy-two per cent of what was lost in a hill with two missing plants was recovered in the four nearest adjacent hills. Fifty-six per cent of what was lost in a hill with no plants was recovered in the four nearest adja - cent hills. It is probable that this recovery also extends at least to the four nearest diagonal hills. 24. An application of the law of chance to the random distribution of sound kernels shows: (1) When 75 jier cent germinating seed is planted four per hill. 81.6, 42.3. 21.1. 4.6, and 0.4 per cent of the hills will contain 4. 3. 2. 1. and no sound kernels respectively. These percentages were borne out by actual test. (2) If corn testing 66 per cent germination is planted at the rate of 4 kernels per hill. 17.8. 38.5. 31.1. 11.1, and 1.5 per cent of the hills will contain 4. 3. 2. 1. and no sound kernels respectively. (3) If corn is planted only half of which will grow, at the rate of 5 per hill. 3.1. 15.fi, 31.3. 31.3. 15.6, and 3.1 per cent of the hills will contain 5. 4. 3. 2. 1. and no plants. The actual distribution from a planter will vary some - what from the above figures for the reason that no mechanical planter will uniformly drop a given number of kernels. The use of low germinating seed corn requires a definite knowledge of the germination percentage which can only be accurately determined by a properly conducted germination test. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FREEZING INJURY OF SEED CORN A. K1K88ELBACH AND J. A. KATCLIFF INTRODUCTION Injury to corn for seed purposes by freezing in the fiill is of frequent occurrence in Nebraska and thruout much of tin - corn producing area of the world. The underlying causes of such injury may he (1) late maturity and (2) abnormally early freezing weather. Late maturity may result from (1) late planting. cJ) planting of unadapted varieties, and (3) peculiar weather conditions which do not favor early riptning. I'lidue early freezing may work similar injury to corn that would possess strong vitality under normal weather conditions. When subjected to a severe frost, immature corn suffers a partial or total lo-s of germinatire power. The object of the investigations in this bulletin has been to determine the conditions under which freezing injury may occur to seed corn: to indicate, if possible, the vital changes in the embryo resulting in such injury: and to point out ways by which seed corn of strong vitality and satisfactory yielding capacity may be obtained. CHARACTER OF THE CORN EMBRYO AND PROCESS OF GERMINATION The relation of the embryo to the remainder of tlie kernel of dent corn may W seen in Figures 1 and 2. which are vertical and cross sections respectively. The starchy and horny endosperm may be distinguished surrounding the embryo, which consists of the plumule, primary root, and scutellum. When placed under heat and moisture conditions pn&gt;i&gt;er for "Termination, enzymes are secreted by the scutellum of a viable corn kernel, which convert the food materials stored in the endosperm into forms which may l&gt;e used for nourishing the vouag plant. Tn Figure 3 the pericarp or seed coat of a germinating kernel has been removed to show the development which took place during '■&gt;&gt;■&gt; hours of favorable germination conditions. The root develop* more rapidly than the stem. The effect of -20 hours additional g?rminati«n is shown in Figure 4. Three secondary roots have started growth from the base of the plumule. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Xkhkaska Aquctlttkal Exp. Station Kkskaik ii Bi i.. 16 The differentiation of ti&gt;sues and organs in the embryo of a mature kernel of corn is shown in Figures '5-8. Figure ."&gt; is a cross section thru the plumule surrounded by the scutellum. It may l&gt;e seen how the young leaves are closely folded or curled up within the plumule. Figures 6, 7, and S are vertical sections (8) (3) (4) Fig. 1— Vertical section of kernel of dent corn. Fig. 2 — Cross section of kernel of dent corn. Fig. 3 — Growth after 35 hours favorable germination Fig. 4 — Growth after 55 hours germination showing secondary roots. 1. The material from which these photographs were taken was secured from a yellow variety of ordinary dent corn, Hogue's Yellow Dent. After soak - ing several kernels in water for about 12 hours, the scutellums were removed and dropped at once into Bowan's Picric formol killing and fixing solution. They remained in this solution for 10 hours. Washing with 70 per cent alcohol was then begun and continued until the material appeared whitish and the alcohol was no longer tinted yellow. The material was then dehydrated in 85, 95. and 100 per cent alcohol, after which it was cleared by bringing it up thru the xylol series. This consists of an alcoholic dilution of xylol in the fol - lowing proportions: (1) 1 part xylol. 3 parts alcohol; (2) 2 parts xylol, 2 parts alcohol; (3) 3 parts xylol, 1 part alcohol; (4) pure xylol. Infiltration with paraffin was then begun by placing the material, together with a small block of paraffin, in a bottle of pure xylol. It remained in this bottle overnight and was then removed to the paraffin bath, where it remained for about 10 hours, and was then imbedded in paraffin. Sections were made of this material in the usual way and fastened on slides. The paraffin was removed from the sections with xylol, and the xylol removed with 95 per cent alcohol. This prepared them for the stain, methylene blue being used. They were stained for about 2 minutes and then dehydrated in 95 and 100 per cent alcohol, cleared with xylol, and mounted in balsam. The material was then in permanent form and oould be studied under the microscope at any time. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Freezing Injury of Seed CYrx Fig. 5 (ivper) — Micro-photograph of cross section thru plumule of corn embryo Fig. 6 (lower) — Vertical section thru plumule of corn embryo, showing leaf formation </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Achici i.ti rai. Exr. Station Remearch Bt'L. 16 Fig. 7 (upper) — Micro-photograph of vertical section thru the medial area between the plumule and root of a corn embryo. Origin of plu - mule, primary root and secondary root are visible Fig. 8 (lower) — Vertical section thru the primary root of a corn embryo </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Frekzixc; In.u hv of Sekd ( v kn 13 respectively thru il) the plumule. {2) the medial area between the plumule anil root, and (3) is seen to Ik' a miniature plant. distinct. the primary root. The embryo with its vegetative orpins fairly FREEZING INJURY NOT DUE OF THE TO ARRESTED DEVELOPMENT EMBRYO The loss of vitality or lack bv autumn freezing is not due of germinative power occasioned merely to arrested development ~,* - - - r» - - — -^ ,- - — - - - i of the seed. There is much experimental evidence as well as general observation that corn acquires the power of •Termina - tion very early in the development of the kernels. Corn Table 1 — Yiul/Uiti/ of rani hfii't'cxted &lt;it I'tiriotti %tiuje* of maturity (191~&gt;-1!)17) Date of selection Weight of 100 kernels Germination ■Corn was in th»- milk Rtage at the first selection each year. 'Pollination occurred on August 1. July 31, and August 10. in 1915, 1916 and 1917 respectively. 1915 1916 1917 9 1915 1916 1917 1915 1916 j 1917 9 9 | Aug. 22 Aug. 22 Aug. 2&lt; Aug. 29 Aug. 29 Sept. 4 Sept. 5 Sept. 5 Sept. 11 Sept. 12 Sept. 12 Sept. 18 Sept. 19 Sept. 19 Sept. 25 Sept. 26 Sept. 26 Oct. 2 Oct. 3 Oct. 3 Oct. 9 Gram* 11.2 16.0 18.9 23.0 27.0 29.9 31.0 Grams 15.4 19.7 22.3 25.9 28.2 31.4 32.3 Grcmx Per cent Per cent Per rent 10.0 66 83 92 15.4 88 94 94 20.0 89 94 99 23.8 95 96 99 28.6 96 96 99 30.9 94 96 99 31.0 96 97 100 Three year average Date of Condition of grain lelection Ratio wt. Days Weight of of embryo Germina- sinee fertil- 100 kernels to wt. of tion ization 3 kernel- lug. 24 Milk stage lug. 31 Late milk stage Sept. 7 Roasting ear Sept. 14 Late roasting ear . Jept. 21 Denting &gt;ept. 28 Glazing )ct. 5 Mature (Gnms) (Percent) 20 12.2 .078 80 27 17.0 .105 92 34 2C.4 .110 94 41 24.2 .103 97 48 27.9 .106 97 55 30.7 .112 96 62 31.4 . ... 98 2 Data for 1917 only. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Aurici i.ti ral E.\i\ Station Kkskar( ii Hi i.. 16 harvested in the "milk" stage has been found to give a fair per - centage of germination, and a perfect germination may be secured from seed harvested in the early "dough'' stage. In the seasons of 1015. 1016, and 1917. seed of Hogue's Yel - low Dent corn was selected at successive stages of maturity. Immediately after being selected the seed was hung in a dry, airy place and thus cured free from mould or other injury. It was tested for germination late in the winter after becoming air-drv. The results are shown in Table 1. The average date of pollination during the three years was August 3. This would indicate that the date of fertilization of the ovules was August 4. The average date during the three years of the first selection of corn was August 24. which is approximately twenty days later than the date of fertilization. This first selected seed which had but three weeks development after fertilization weighed only 3!) per cent as much, moi-ture - free, as the best matured seed. Nevertheless, in spite of this premature selection, the earliest gathered seed germinated 80 per cent on an average. The moisture-free weights of 100 kernels for the successive selections were respectively 12.2, 17.0, 20.4, 24.2, 27.9, 30.7 and 31.4 grams. The respective germinations of these seven lots of seed were 80, 92. 94. 97. 06 and 08 per cent. The germinative ability of very immature corn does not appear to be, as is commonly believed, due to more rapid growth and earlier maturity of the embryo than takes place in the endosperm. The embryo does not mature early with a later filling in of the endosperm. But rather both develop in approximately tb*&gt; same ratio as will appear in Table 2. Table 2 — Relative development of embryo and kernel of Hogite'x Yellow Dent corn har rested at rarious stages of maturity (1917) Days Mo ; sture-fr^ weights of Sample Condition Date s'nce 1 1 1 number of grain of fertiliza- I 100 ! 00 kernels Ratio of harvest! tion of 100 em- without i embryo kernel kernel? : bryos embryo to kernel Gram* Grants] Grams i •" m&gt; 1 Milk stage Aug. 28 18 8.28 0.&lt;"5 7.63 .0785 5 Denting Sept. 25 46 25.10 2.67 22.43 .1064 6 Glazing Oct. 2 53 28.04 3.12 24.82 .1117 Late milk stage Sept. 4 Roasting ear Sept. 11 Late roasting ear Sept. 18 25 32 39 13.45 17.54 21.17 : : 1.41 1.94 2.18 12.04 15.60 18.99 .1048 .1106 .1030 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Freezing Injury 15 Seed Corn For this test, grain harve stages of maturity in 1!&gt;1 7 and The grain was soaked for a si facilitate an accurate separatioi ;ted at the first six different Inscribed in Table 2 was used, ort time in water in order to ){ the embrvo from the rest ;t lire- free weights of 100 reprt sentative kernels and their eml determined fo vo free weights of 100 seeds for stage of maturity. The moist each stage were respectively 8.28. 13.45, 17.54. 21.17. 25.1 while the moisture-free weights of the embryos 28.04 gr Fig. 9 — Representative kernels of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn harvested at various stages of maturity in 1917. Top row shows the condition 20 days after fertilization of ovule; second row from top, 27 days; third row from top, 34 days; fourth row from top, 41 days; fifth row from lop, 48 days; bottom row, 55 days. See Table 2 &gt;f the kernel. The relativ were respectively 0.(55. 1.41. 1.94. 2.1K. -2Au, and 8.12 grams. The resj&gt;ective ratios of weight of embryos to total weight of t«9f 9 Oft COPff II' </seg>
            <seg id="p016">XkHKASKA AoRH I I.Tl RAI. Exi\ STATION UkSK.WM II Hi I.. 1 16 kernel were .078, .10."). .110. .108, .106, and .112. With the exception of the least mature grain, the embryo bore practically a constant relation to the whole kernel regardless of the stage of maturity. For the earliest selection the proportion of embryo was the lowest. This may be accounted for in part by the fact that the initial development of the kernel, prior to fertilization, is a greater factor in the relative weights of the embryo and kernel than at any succeeding time. When corn was harvested '21 days after fertilization, the scutellum measured 7 millimeters long and the germ from tip of plumule to tip of root was 5 millimeters long. For corn har - vested .")."&gt; days after fertilization, the length of the scutellum was !&gt; millimeters, while the germ from tip of plumule to tip of root was 7 millimeters. MOISTURE CONTENT OF CORN Since the moisture content of corn is a factor in freezing injury, data were secured to determine the relative moisture content of the embryo and the endosperm. It was thought that this might help to throw some light on the effect of freezing and might perhaps indicate where freezing does its greatest damage. Tests were made with l&gt;oth old and new corn, the results of which are given in Table 3. OhI Corn. The tests with the old corn were of a pre - liminary nature. In order to insure differences in moisture content, the corn was divided into three lots and treated as follows : (1) Lot 1 consisted of air-drv corn (•2) Lot '2 had been placed in a l&gt;ed of cool, damp soil and allowed to remain for 24 hours. (3) Lot 3 had l&gt;een buried in cool, damp soil for 48 hours, The embryos were then separated from the endosperug of all samples, and moisture determinations made. The results indicate that in the air-dry condition, the mois - ture content of the embryo is likely to be as low or lower than in the endosperm. The ratio of the moisture content of the embryo to that of the endosperm was 1.03. In the lot of seed buried in cool, damp soil for "24 hours, the embryos had taken up more moisture than had the endosperms. Here the ratio of the moisture content was 1.36. This difference increased in a still greater degree in the lot buried for 48 hours, the ratio here being 1.77. This represents somewhat the condition of the kernels in the fall before having thoroly cured. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Freezing Ixjiry of Seed Corn 17 r.viu.E -\ — Relative mouttnre content of embryo and endosperm Xfir Corn. Twenty-five seed ears were selected in the fall before becoming well dried out. Twenty kernels were removed from each ear and the relative moisture content of the embryo and endosperm determined, {riving a ratio of l.'2'.K When this corn had become practically air-dry, the ratio of the moisture content of the embryo to that of the endosperm was reduced to 0.81. PHYSICAL EFFECTS OF FREEZING ICE FORMATION IN KERNELS It is known that ice is formed in kernels of immature corn when exposed sufficiently to freezing temperatures, and that death frequently follows such exposure. The temperature at which ice is formed within the corn kernel depends very largely upon the moisture content of the kernel. For the most imma - ture se &gt;d tested in these experiments, containing 60 to 80 per cent moisture, the freezing point was only slightly below the freezing point of water. On the other hand, no ice formation could he detected in air-dry kernels or in kernels containing less than IK per cent of moistur &gt;. when subjected to the lowest temperature observed: namely 10° F. below zero. During the freezing process, in case the moisture content was excessive, the water seemed to be drawn from the cells into the larger spaces around the embryo, and about the plumule. the primary root, and the root sheath, and doubtless into the smaller spaces between the cells. In these larger spaces, which may Ik 1 seen in Figures 1. 2, 5, (&gt;. 7. and 8. the ice would form in a solid sheet around the tissues. In fact, when very moist kernels were exposed to the lower temperatures, the whole kernel M Moisture content Description of grain Embryo Ratio embryo Endosperm to endosperm OLD CORN Air-dry Embedded 24 hours in moist soil Embedded 48 hours in moist soil NEW CORV Selected from field before dry Same corn when practically air-dry Per cent 7.91 21.37 36.81 31.1 10.5 Per cent 7.6 1.03 15.62 1.36 20.83 1.77 24.1 1.29 12.9 0.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Acrk i i.ti ral Exp. Station Research Hi i.. 16 18 appeared to be a solid frozen mass. The ojx»n spaces in and around the embryo also appeared to 1m» enlarged by the ice formation. Usually where ice was formed in the kernels, and remained in a frozen condition for practically -24 hours, the vitality was destroyed or weakened. In a few cases, however, ice was noted and still the vitality of the kernel remained unimpaired. Ice formation within the kernel, therefore, even when a coat is formed a round or partly around the embryo, does not neces - sarily mean death. The retention of life dejx»nds quite largely upon the duration of the frozen condition. Data regarding the relation between ice formation and injury are given in Tables ") to 12. In cases where the freezing was severe, frozen kernels weiv left in ;i soft, watery condition after thawing. The cells seemed to !&gt;:■ unable to absorb the water which had b&gt;en drawn from them during the freezing process. EFFECT OF FREEZING ON COLOR OF EMBRYO The embryo in a kernel of immature or moist corn usually changes from a light or creamy color before freezing to a dark or yellowish brown after freezing. The larger the percentage of moisture, the more sensitive the embryo to cold, and the more readily discoloration takes place. Corn containing 37 per cenl moisture and frozen three days at 0° F. showed a slight embryo discoloration in three days and very pronounced darkening in six day- after thawing. By looking over the notations regard - ing embryo color in Tables ."&gt; to 12. it will be s:&gt;en that the dark color is very closely correlated with loss of vitality. Generally where no loss of vitality resulted from the exposure to the cold, the embryo retained its normal color. The presence of both dark and light embryos on the same ear is associated usually with only a partial loss of vitality, and is frequently dn« to variation in moistwr 0 content of the kernels. The practice of judging the germinative power of seed corn by the appearance of the embrvo therefore se»ns justified. When los* of vitality has resulted from freezing, this s-&gt;eins to b? a fairly safe guide. However, it seems possible that, in very exceptional cases, a loss of vitality might result from some other source without causing a discoloration of the embryo. The method, therefore, can hardly be said to take the place of a germination test. EFFECT OF FREEZING ON EMBRYONIC TISSUES Since ice is formed in kernels of immature corn when exposed sufficiently to freezing temperatures, often resulting in </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 19 Figs. 10 and 11 — Micro-photographs of cross-sections of the primary root of frozen and unfrozen corn embryos respectively </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nkiihaska A&lt; ifioi/n hai, Exf. Station Rkskaiuii Bitl. 16 20 death, the effect of such ice formation upon the cell structure of the kernel embryo was studied. It was thought that such micro - scopic studies of frozen embryos might give some clue concern - ing the cause of deaih by freezing. Figures 10 and 11 are micropbotographs of cross sections of the primary root of frozen and unfrozen corn embryos res]&gt;ec - tivelv. The gnu represented by Figure 10 had been frozen for 48 hour- at a temperature of 5° F. below zero, and had a moisture content of 35 per cent. Figure 11 represents grain from the same ear which had not been frozen. A large number of frozen and unfrozen grains were sectioned and examined microscopically. Xo rupture of cell walls or other cytologictJ effect of fre&gt;/.ing and ice-formation within the kernels was apparent. CHEMICAL EFFECTS OF FREEZING Opportunity did not offer for an exhaustive study of chemi - cal changes involved in freezing injury. However, an ordinary fodder analvsis was made in triplicate of both frozen and un - frozen immature grain. A composite sample of sh-lled ■ •orn containing 37 per cent moisture was divided into two parts. One portion was dried immediately. The other was frozen for three day&lt; at a temperature of 0° F. At the end of three more days the embryos of the frozen grain had turned dark. This grain was dried and both samples analized. The results are given in Table 4. The differences recorded are probably within the limits of experimental error. Doubtless some chemical change has taken place, otherwise the tissues would not have darkened in color. A germination test of the frozen and un - frozen seed showed 0 and 100 per cent viability. Tabi.k -1 — Composition of frozen and unfrozen seed corn Composition of moisture-free grain Character of grain Crude Nitrogen- Crude protein free extract Fat fibre Ash Crude Per cent Per cent \ Per cent Per cent Per cent 13.13 78.65 4.54 2.30 1.38 12.94 78.61 4.63 2.37 1.45 Unfrozen Frozen Ratio of unfrozen to frozen .985 .999 1.02 1.03 1.05 These analyses were made under the direction of F. W. Upson, Station Chemist. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Freezing Ix.ii ky ok Seed (Ykx 21 PROBABLE CAUSE OF DEATH FROM FREEZING HISTORICAL REVIEW Then* is no doulrt luit that plant tissues, under certain con - ditions, die as a result of freezing, hut just what freezing does to the vital part of such tissues to bring about death is not fully understood. The theories which have been advanced to explain death by freezing seem to lack sufficient evidence to prove their correctness. Wide differences of opinion -iri' held by various investigators regarding the direct cause &gt;f l;&gt;ath. At the present time, therefore, any explanation of the phenomenon of death by freezing must be considered as an expression of the probable cause and not as a definite statement of whit Hctuallv happens. The theories which have be'.Mi advanced to explain the cause of death from freezing may b? grouped as follows: (1) crushing of plant tissues, or rupturing of cell structure-. (2) too rapid thawing. (:■!) desiccation of the protoplasm. (4) physic:il and chemical disorganization of the protoplasm and other cell contents. CRUSHING OF PLANT TISSUES OR RUPTURING OF CELL STRUCTURES As stated by Salmon ( l'.UT). the early observers of ice for - mation within plant tissues, knowing nothing of the cellular structure of plants, attributed death from fre?zing to rending or crushing of the tissues. In 1~:?7 I)u Hamel and Hutfon proposed that death resulted from a rupturing of the cell walls due to the ■»xo.m&lt;ioii which accompanies ice formation. The same opinion was held by Geo|&gt;ert (1830) who discovered ice within the cells and also outside the cells in the intercellular spacs. Sachs ( lsc&gt;&lt;») found that ice was sometimes formed within the cells, and Miiller- Thurgau (188(5) concludes that ice is formed within the cells only in case of verv large size, or very rapid freezing. Supercooling followed by ice formation, and very rapid cooling are more injurious to plant tissues than slow cooling, according to Mez (11)05). Neither supercooling nor rapid cool - ing give the water in the cells time to escape and ice is. there - fore, formed within the cells. In each of the above case- wheiv ice was formed within the cells, whether it was the result of slow or rapid cooling, or whether the tissues had l»een suj&gt;er - cooled. the investigators seemed to think that the increase in volume probably worked some injury to the cell walls. Plant tissues containing a large percentage of water, such as turgid leaves, and young, growing twigs are especially sub- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska A&lt;;mci i.tirai. Exp. Station Research Bui* 1&lt;&gt; ject to injury from ice formation. Wiegand (1900) found the upper and lower prrts of leaves entirely separated by layers of ice, and also the outer layers of twigs separated from the inner by a sheet of ic;&gt;. The injury resulting from the freezing of preen plants U due to the change in volume when the water in the plant fivezes, according to (Jassner and (iriinme (1913), and not to any special effect upon the plant cells. The result of this increase in volume is a tearing of the tissues, or si break - ing up of the &lt;\'ll structure. This form of injury is recognized by Chandler ( 1918) as Innng entirely possible, for he speaks of the tearing of tissues due to the tension developed at low temperature-. While studying the influence of the temperature of liquid hydrogen on the germinative power of seeds. Thiselton-Dyer (1899) suggest that the sudden vacuum caused within the seeds by immersing them in liquid hydrogen might possibly produce physical rupture which would weaken or destroy their vitality. Adams (190f&gt;) also mentions the possibility of injury from this source, but thinks the vacuum too small to be of any serious consequence. He concludes, further, that the intercellular spaces in seeds are very small, and that in moist seeds, after freezing has gone mi for some time, these spaces become filled witH a solid mass of ice. Then if the temperature is still further low - ered, more ice is formed, and it is likely that complete rupture takes place, causing a separation of the cells from each other. TOO RAPID THAWING Many have thought that the phenomenon of death from freezing i- not due directly to fr."ezing but to the rate or rapidity of thawing. Sachs (18(10) an early investigator, was an ardent supporter of this l&gt;elief. and for many years his work was considered conclusive. Later. Miiller-Thurgau (188(&gt;) pointed out inaccuracies in his work and showed by experiments with a large ni'mber of plants that there was no difference in the amount of killing whether tissues were thawed rapidly or slowly, except in the c:ise of rij&gt;e apples and pears. It was found also by Molisch (1897) and Chandler (1913) that in general the rate of thawing is not related to the amount of kill - ing at a fire* temperature, the exceptions to this rule being the leaves of lettuce, leaves of Agave americana, and ripe apples and pears. In arguing against the theory that plant tissues are killed by the rate of thawing rather than ny freezing, Detmer (1893) mentions several mosses which can remain in a hard frozen condition for a long time without showing any </seg>
            <seg id="p023">FkEEZING IxJIHY )K SeKI) CoKX 23 material damage after thawing whether the latter process takes place slowly or suddenly. Coining hack again to the belief held by Sachs, it is stated by Adams (1905) that during: the freezing process water is drawn from the cells and solidified in the intercellular spaces, and that if freezing has not gone too far. and if thawing be gradual, the ice melts and is absorbed again by the cells and no injury results. In discussing the effect of freezing on '•ulti - vated plants. Galloway (1895) makes a similar statement. Brown and Eseombe (181)7-181)8) while trying to determine the influence of very low temperatures on the genninatire power of seeds, express the opinion that the vitality of the seeds was injured more by rapid thawing than by gradual thawing. DESICCATION OF THE PROTOPLASM Probably the most generally accepted theory of the cause of death from freezing has been, that death results from desic - cation of the protoplasm when water is drawn from the cells into the intercellular spaces in the process of ice formation. It was early discovered that when plant tissues freeze, water is drawn from the cells and ice crystals are formed in the inter - cellular spaces. Geoppert (1830) and Sachs (I860) both observed these phenomena but reached rather different con - clusions as to the real cause of death. Geoppert thought that death resulted as a direct effect of freezing and that death occurred while the tissues were still in a frozen condition: while Sachs thought that death occurred during the thawing process. That water is withdrawn from the cells during the process of freezing and that ice crystals are usually formed in the inter - cellular spaces, and only rarely within the cells, was again declared by Muller-Thurgau (188(5) and also by Molisch ( 1W»7) : the latter observing the movement of water and the formation of ice crystals in plant tissues under the microscope. Both of these men were of the opinion that death from freezing is due to the withdrawal of water from the cells, and that it is essen - tially the same thing as death from desiccation. Miiller- Thurgau went so far with his work as to determine the amount of water drawn from cells by freezing. For apple he found that at a temperature — 13 degrees C. 03.7 per cent had been lost, and at — 15.2 degrees ('.. 7'.).'2 per cent of the water had passed from the cells. In regard to the effect which the removal of water may have upon the cell contents. Wiegand (lOOfi) thinks it is proba - ble that death from freezing is caused by drying out of the proto- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Acrh i i.ti kai. Exp. Station Research Hi i.. 1&lt;&gt; plasm beyond the critical water content. Maxiinow (1908) jgrees with Miiller-Thurgau and Molisch in that the withdrawal of water daring the freezing process is the killing factor. He concludes, however, that the withdrawal of water is limited to the plasma membrane, and that this membrane is the part of the cell which is injiuvd and that as long as a film of water can be kept in contact with this membrane no injury takes place. Matruchot and Molliard (1901) also believed that water was drawn from the protoplasm and nuclear material of the cell in the process of freezing and that this continued until they con - tained less than the minimum required to maintain vitality. Protoplasm, in order to retain its vitality, according to Ewarts (1897). requires from 2 to 3 per cent of water. Adams (1905) contends that if these theories be true the same argument should hold for dry seeds which contain al)out 12 ]&gt;er cent of water. But dry seeds are not killed by freezing. Hence some other explanation must be found. PHYSICAL AND CHEMICAL DISORGANIZATION OF THE PROTOPLASM AND OTHER CELL CONTENTS Many who have sought to determine the cause of death by freezing have concluded that freezing produces certain physical and chemical changes in the protoplast and other cell contents, and that these changes result in death of the living matter. In harmonv with this view. Detmer (1893) states. "In consequence of the disorganization of the protoplasm the cellular fluids leave the plasma: at the same time the nature of the hyloplasmic layers undergoes a complete change and they are now pervious to many substances which in a normal condition they did not permit to pass. This is the cause of the discoloration of frozen plants and of the phenomenon that pieces of frozen red beet, if put into water, readily part with coloring matter and sugar, while the living cells tenaciously retain these sulistances." Becquerel (1905). in studying the action of liquid air on the life of seeds, found that if sufficient moisture was present in the tissues the cold disorganized the protoplasm and nucleus, mak - ing germination impossible. Galloway (1895) also contributed to this same idea, for he concluded that a freezing temperature may l)e sufficiently low to cause a chemical disorganization of the living substance and that the part of the plant where this takes place dies. Gorke (1906) and Sehaffnit (1912) both found that freezing precipitated certain proteids from the cell sap and that the ease with which these proteids are precipitated bears some relation to the hardiness of the plant. Precipitation of the proteids. therefore, according to their interpretations, is </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Freezing Injikv &gt;k See:i Corn 25 the cause of death. Chandler (1913), however, (loos not agree with this. He found no precipitation of proteids in the sap of young t\vi&lt;rs of apple, plum, or pear and only slight traces of i' in other plants. He calls attention to the fact, however, that frozen plant ti»ues. soon after thawing, take on a In-own color and a soft watery condition, and that evaporation goes on much more rapidly from the surface of such tissues than it does from the surface of similar tissues which have not l&gt;een frozen. PERSONAL INTERPRETATION One of the objects of the experiments reported in this bulletin was to determine the effect of freezing upon the cellular structure of the corn kernel and especially of the embryonic tissues, for the purpose of indicating the true cause of death resulting from freezing. It was thought that if death was due to some mechanical injury to the tissues or to disorganization of the cellular material, it would be indicated by a separation of the cells from each other, or by broken down cell walls, or by a difference in tin- appearance of the cell contents. With this idea in mind, careful studies wen- made both of frozen and unfrozen sections of embryonic material, permanently mounted and stained sections beinjr used. Mechanical injuries of the cell structure or rupturing of the tissues were soujrht for with con - siderable care, as it was thought that these probably were the primary causes of the hoss of vitality. Xo such injuries were found, however, in the embryonic tissues of the kernel. It was thought, then, that if such in - juries result at all from freezing, they should occur in the tender tips and stems of young corn seedlings. Sections of frozen tips and stems of such material were, therefore, studied. Even in this tender, rapidly growing material no rupturing or break - ing down of the cellular structure could be detected. However, from the observations of Wiejrand (1906). Chandler (1013). and others, then' c:&gt;n b&gt; no doubt but that a rupturing of plant tissues sometimes results from freezing; but from the evidence at hand, it must be concluded tint death from freezing is not due to mechanical injuries but to some other cause. The protoplasmic and nuclear material of the cells of frozen and unfrozen tissues were studied microscopically: the same nii'terial lieinjr used for this as was used while searching for mechanical injuries. So far as was observed, no disorgani - sation or change of appearance was detected. It should be stated here, however, that observations of the cellular material were not very extensive, and the material used for studv had </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Xv.hu ti.ti rai. Exp. Station Reskakch Bri.. 16 26 been placed in the killing and fixing solution while still in a frozen condition. It is probable, therefore, that killing took place l&gt;efore there could be any material readjustment of the living matter. It was thought, however, that the change in color of embrvonic tissues and other plant tissues and the soft watery condition characteristic of all tissues which have bean frozen to death indicates that some physical or chemical change has been brought al&gt;out. Even tho the change in color of the embryo of a corn kernel after freezing may be due to the action of some enzyme or of bacteria, the fact remains that a change has been effected which makes possible such action. The instance cited by Detmer (1893) of pieces of frozen red beet giving up their coloring matter and sugar when placed in water, while these substances are tenaciously retained by the unfrozen material, adds some evidence of a physical or chemical change. The soft, watery condition of plant tissues after freez - ing also appears to be the result, at least in part, of disorganiza - tion of the cellular material, and not entirely to a withdrawal of the water from the cells. That this is true is drawn from the observations of Miiller-Thurgau (1886) and Mez (1906) re - garding the formation of ice within the cells when the tissues are supercooled or frozen rapidly. If the extraction of wat«r from the cells was the only cause of the watery condition in question, tissues which are frozen rapidly or supercooled, so that crvstalization takes place largely in the cells, should not exhibit this condition. But this water-soaked condition is characteristic of frozen tissues whether the freezing has been done rapidly or slowly. Altho chemical changes have not been established by chemical analysis, it seems certain that changes take place within the protoplasmic and nuclear contents as a result of freezing and that these changes make it impossible for the processes of life to continue. The withdrawal of water from the cells by freezing has been considered by many as the cause of death. It was noted that in moist corn kernels, water was withdrawn from the tissues and ice formed in masses and sheets in space surrounding or separating different tissues, and that death usually accom - panied such ice formation. It was also noted that air-dry corn, which contains from 10 to 12 per cent of moisture, was not frozen, at least its vitality was not injured, and according to the observations of Brown and Escombe (1897.-8). Adams ( 1906), Thiselton-Dver (1899), and others it was not injured even when exposed for several hours to the temperature of liquid air or </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Freezing Ix.ury ok Seed Corn ■_'7 liquid hydrogen. According to Miiller-Thurgau (lSS(i). apples lost &lt;&gt;3.8 per cent of their moisture when frozen at — 1.5 degrees C. : 30.2 per cent of the total water, therefore, remained in the cells. Kernels of corn which contain a large percentage of water will freeze at this temperature and die. If the moisture content of the cells of a kernel of corn were reduced to 30 or even 20 j)er cent at this temperature, the vitality should remain uninjured, so far as moisture is concerned. Dry seeds contain only 10 to 12 per cent of moisture, yet they retain their vitality, and a still further reduction in the moisture content can be made without injury. Ewarts (1897) shows that the fatal minimum moisture content of protoplasm is 2 or 3 per cent. The theory is, then, that as the cooling goes on, more and more water is withdrawn until less than this amount remains in the cell, and death results. This should also hold true for dry seed which contain 10 or 12 per cent of water, but these are not injured by such freezing. An example may also be taken from Table 9. where corn containing 20.5 per cent of moisture was entirelv ki!'"d. while corn containing lfi.3 per cent of moisture showed no injury. The freezing evidently did not reduce the moisture content in the former case more than 2 or 3 per cent, yet the vitality was destroyed. It does not seem probable that the removal of so small an amount of water would cause death. It seems more probable, however, that the small difference in moisture content was sufficient to permit disorganization of the protoplasm in the one case, while in the other it remained unaffected. The rate of thawing and its relation to killing was not studied. The results which have been obtained and reported by Muller-Thurgau (18SC). Molisch (1897). and Chandler (1913) seem to indicate quite clearly that it has very little to do with the amount of killing. It can hardly b;&gt; considered, therefore, as an important factor in bringing about the death of frozen tissues. EFFECTS OF FREEZING UPON THE VIABILITY OF SEED CORN Ordinary freezing temperatures do not injure mature, dry corn, but it is always the immature or damp corn that is injured by freezing. It was proposed, therefore, to determine at what temperature freezing and loss of vitality take place in corn at different stages of maturity as indicated by differences in moisture content. The effect of freezing upon the germinative qualities of seed corn has been tested experimentally under two sorts of </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Statkix Research Bra. 16 conditions: (1) Artificial freezing under control conditions; and {'2) natural freezing of corn standing in the field under prevailing natural conditions. VITALITY OF CORN FROZEN UNDER CONTROL CONDITIONS APPARATUS The low temperatures used in these experiments were n?e'ired tinder control conditions bv the use of a freezing mixture of salt find ice. By mixing the salt and ic? in the proportion of one part of i-alt to two parts of ice a temperature of — 5° F. was secured. In order to secure the various ranges of tempera- Mire and to maintain those temperatures for several hours, two different devices were used. For teni|)eratnr &gt;s above zero, an insulated freezing box was made. The essential parts of this box are: (1) A compartment for containing the freezing mixture. This was large enough to hold al&gt;out two hundred pounds of crushed ice. (2) A com - partment for containing a sM - ong salt solution and a freezing cell. This compartment or chamber was large enough to hold twenty gallons of brine. (8) A freezing cell into which the material whs put for freezing. This cell was cylindrical in shape 5 inches in diameter and 18 inches deep, with capacitv for section* from 30 e'r-i of corn. (4) A series of connected cells in the fr&gt;ezing mixture compartment. This series of cells was connected with the brine chamber in such a way as to allow the cells to fill with brine. (5) A pump for circulating the brine thru the cells ard buck into the brine chamber, (ft) A thermometer to indicate the temperature in the freezing cell. The working principle of this device was somewhat as follows: The freezing mixture of salt and ice was packed around the series of brine cells. This reduced the temperature to 0° F. or lielow in this chainl)er, and cooled the brine in the cells. The brine was made strong enough so that it would not freeze at this temperature. The corn was then placed in the freezing cell, the lid closed, and the thermometer inserted. When all wtl ready, the pump, operated by an electric motor, was starred s»nd the chilled brine from the series of cells was forced into the large brine chamber and other brine drawn into the cells to cool. Bv this method the twenty gallons of brine was pt-mIu-'Hv cooled to the desired temperature. As soon as the desired temperature was secured, the pump was stopped. The large volume of brine which surrounded the freezing cell maintained a comparatively even temperature in the latter for several hours. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Freezing Ixjirv of Seed Corn 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Aurici ltirai. Exp. Station Reseaim h Bcl. 1(5 30 Properties of Solution of Salt — From J. E. Siebel, Compend of Mechanical Refrigeration and Engineering Pounds of salt Weight Freezing Percentage of salt by weight per gallon of per gallon point solution 39 °F. Fahrenheit 0. . 1. . 2 2.5 3. . 3.5 4 5 6 7 X 9. . 10 12 15 20 24 25 26 For securing the temperatures below zero a different sort of device was used. This consisted simply of a barrel with a small keg placed inside of it. The space around the keg was filled with sawdust. The freezing cell from the other apparatus was placed in the keg and the freezing mixture packed around it until the keg was full. It was then covered well with burlap and a tight lid put on the barrel. By this method a tempera - ture of — 5° could be maintained almost constant in the freezing cell thruout the twentv-four hours. After the corn was frozen it had to be dried quickly in order to keep it from becoming mouldy. A screen wire box was. therefore, provided in which the corn could lie cured. This box was placed in a warm, dry room and near a south window where the breeze could strike it. This arrangement was found to be satisfactory, as the corn dried within a few days. SELECTION OF MATERIAL In order to facilitate the selection of material for the freez - ing tests, four plots of corn were planted. The first one was planted early and the other three at successive intervals of ten bounds) 0 0.084 0.169 0.212 0.256 0.300 0.344 0.433 0.523 0.617 0.708 0.802 0.897 1.092 1.389 1.928 2.376 2.488 9. fim (I Pounds) 8.35 8.40 8.46 8.50 8.53 8.56 8.59 8.65 8.72 8.78 8.85 8.91 8.97 9.10 9.26 9.64 9.90 9.97 10 04 Degree, 32 30.5 29.3 28.6 27.8 27.1 26.6 25.2 23.9 22.5 21.2 19.9 18.7 16.0 12.2 6.1 1.2 0.5 — 1.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Freezing Injury &gt;k Seed Corn 31 days each. The same variety of corn (Hogue's Yellow Dent) was used for each planting. Thus ears of the same variety but of different degrees of maturity could easily l&gt;e selected at any one time in the fall. As soon as the early planted corn was well matured, selections were made from each plot. These selections included ears representing four stages of maturity. The first sta&lt;re was green corn, much greener than would ever U' selected for seed. In fact, this represented the "roasting ear" stage of development. The ears of the fourth stage were the most mature ones that could he found in the field at the time. The starchy part of the kernels was l&gt;eginning to appear dry and mealy when cut with a knife. The horny part of the kernels also had begun to appear hard and brittle. As the season advanced, the corn secured for the fourth stage became drier and more mature, while the selections for the Hrst stage remained very much the same thruoiit the season. The second and third stages represented intermediate degrees of maturity between the fiist and the fourth. MKTHon OF HANDLING The ears selected were taken at once from the field and treated in the following manner: (1) A part of the tip was removed and discarded. i'2) Each ear was divided into three sections. The section next to the tip was used for a moist ire test, and the adjacent section for an immediate freezing est. The remaining prrt of the ear was stored in a dry. airy place where it would have a chance to cure thorolv. This part to - gether with the frozen section was kept in borage for four or five months. At the end of that time germination tests were made. MOISTURE TESTS Moisture tests were made of the grain on each ear. The samples were dried at 1(K)° to 110° C.. and the percentage of water was calculated, using the green weight as a basis. In all cases the sample for the moisture determination was taken next to. or from the part of the ear which was to be subjected to the freezing temperature. The percentage of moisture thus secured represented very closely the actual moisture content of the corn placed in the freezing 1 test. SUBJECTION TO FREEZING TEMPERATURES Ears representing the four stages of maturity were sub - jected to different ranges of freezing tenij&gt;erature for a j&gt;eriod </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Xkbraska A&lt;;rh i i.tirai. Exp. Station Rekeabch Bi'L. 1&lt;&gt; «f twenty-four hours. That is. one lot of ears consisting of four or five from each stage of maturity was subjected to a tempera - ture ranging from 2S° to 3-2° F. A similar lot was subjected to a range from '20° to "24° F. : another from 12° to 1C»° F. ; another from 4° to S° F.: and still another from — .V to 0° F. The ears were placed in the freezing chamber within an hour or two after Wing brought from the field. The temperature was then lowered to the desired degree as quickly as possible. For the higher temperature and for the range below zero, from one to two hour-; were required, while for the intermediate tempera - tures three to four hours were required. The difference in length of time was due to the difference in the degree of cold and in the apparatus used. After exposure to the cold, no attempt w:s made to bring the corn gradually to a higher tem - perature, but it was removed from the freezing chamber and exposed at once to the air temperature. It was then placed in a screen win box which was set in a warm, dry, airy place. Here the ears dried quickly, so that but little loss from damp or mouldy seed was experienced. All freezing tests except those in a speciil experiment in 1!)1(&gt; were made with ear corn from which the husks had l&gt;een removed. GERMINATION After the samples had been subjected to freezing tempera - tures and had remained in storage until thoroly cured, ger - mination tests were made from each section. The corresponding section from the same ear which had not been exposed to the freezing temperature was placed in germination test at the same time. The ()ercentage germination of the latter serves as a standard with which the germinative ability of the exposed part may be compared, or by which the enect on vitality of exposure to the low temperatures may be measured. The germination tes's were made between blotting papers on moist sawdust. Wet burlap was used as a covering over the blotting paper. The germination boxes were placed in a warm incubator having a teni]&gt;erature of 30° C and allowed to remain for six days, when the counts were made. The germination |-erceiiti&lt;ges anl&lt;*H otherwise stated mean perfect germination with prospects for normej development. OBSERVATION OF ICE IN SEED Hecause of the supposed relation between the formation of ice within plant tissues and death by freezing, observations were made regarding the temperature at which freezing actually </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Freezing Ix.iiry &lt;&gt;k Seed Corn 33 occurs in corn containing different amounts of moisture. By freezing is meant here, the formation of ice crystals within the kernel. The observation was made by cutting thru the small end of the kernel, and by scraping the cut surface, or by digging in and around the embryo with a knife. The observa - tion was made immediately after removing the sample from the freezing chamber. The occurrence of ice crystals was not noted in all of the tests. In those tests where notes weiv taken all of the ears were examined. In the tables, the presence or absence of ice in all cases where examinations were made is indicated. It was very difficult to detect the ice in the samples of low moisture content localise of the small amount present and Itecause of rapid thawing. There is a possibility, therefore, that ice crystals may have been present in some of the samples and yet escaped detec - tion. The presence of ice is discussed in connectoin with the following i n vest i "rations. COLOR OF EMBRYO &gt;'otes were also taken regarding the color of the embryo vt the time when the germination te&lt;ts weiv made. The color was designated as either dark or light. The light color repre - sents the natural color of a normal embryo. On the other hand, a dark or brownish color is quite characteristic of a frozen embryo. In a number of cases a part of the kernels on iui ear would have a dark embryo and part of them a light embryo. Usually this condition was found to bs associated with only a partial loss of vitality. For convenience of comparison, all ears which were sub - jected to a given range of temperature are grouped in the tables according to moisture content, a range of 5 per cent l&gt;eing allowed for each group. In all cases where there were more than one sample in a given moisture range an average for the group is given. RELATION BETWEEN MOISTURE CONTENT AND INJURY AT VARIOUS DEGREES OF FREEZING FREEZING AT TEMPERATURE RANGE OF 32° TO 28° F. The data for all the samples frozen at the temperature range of 32° to 2H 0 F. are given in Table 5. It would seem from the data in this table that the vitality of corn with a high moisture content may l&gt;e seriously injured or almost totally destroyed by such a light freezing ».s is represented by the above temperature range when prolonged for a period of "J4 hour-;. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Aurici lti rai. Exp. Station Research Bet. 1(5 Table 5 — Effect of freezing temperatures on germination of corn differing in moisture content (1913 and 1914) Temperature range 92° to 28° F. Germination obsSred Embryos dark in grain or h * ht Moisture Moisture range in grain Normal Frozen , Ratio . „,-;., of normal Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 80 to 85. { §};} 0 0 0 0 Dark Dark Average 82.5 0 0 f 72.1 100 0 0 0 Dark Dark Dark 70 to 75 1 71.8 100 71.0 100 Average 71.9 100 0 f 69.2 20 0 69.2 100 0 Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark I 68.4 100 0 ,.,.„,„ I 68.3 87 65 to 70 . at o inn 0 67.2 100 20 66.5 100 0 66.2 100 0 65.2 100 0 Average 67.5 88.4 2.5 * * Dark Dark ( 59.7 100 50 100:50 * * * 55 to 60 577 10 ° ° 55 to 60 . K j 100 30 100:0 Dark 100:30 • Light 55.2 87 :i7 100:43 Ice Dark and light Average . 57.6 96.8 29 100:31 f 54.7 90 75 100:80 Ice Dark and light 100:0 • Dark 100:0 Ice Dark 54.0 100 0 50 to 55 •: 53.9 100 0 Ice Dark 52.3 100 87 100:87 Ice Dark and light 100:0 Ice Dark 51.2 100 0 Ice Dark Average 53.2 98 32.4 ' 100:33 •No observations made. gram gram - = fiOtnfifi / 628 10 ° ° 100=0 60 to 65 . &lt; 611 1(H) Q 100 . 0 Average 62.0 100 0 100:0 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn Table i&gt; (Continued) — Effect of freezing temperatniv on (/&lt; r - mination of corn differing in moisture content (1913 and 1914) Temperature range 82° to 28"F. Germination Moisture Moisture Ice . Embrvoa riarW range in grain Normal VloaeR \ Ratio observed tm ° r r^ ark w ■» tEs ™ ""° ht Per cent Per cent ! Per cen/ Per cent 45.8 100 100 100:100 * 44.1 100 100 100:100 ♦ 100:40 40 to 45 M 44.1 100 40 Dark Dark Light 44.0 100 40 100:40 • 42.4 75 50 100:67 None Average 44.1 95 66.0 100:69 39.5 100 55 100:55 100:20 100:100 100:50 Light Dark Light 38.9 100 20 38.7 60 60 38.6 100 50 * * 37.1 100 58 100:58 • Light Light Light Light Light 35 to 40 &lt; 36.3 100 80 100:80 * 36.1 100 85 100:85 None 100:87 None 100:100 • 35.9 100 87 35.8 100 100 35.6 100 100 100:100 • 100:100 • ♦ 35.1 100 100 Light Average i 37.1 96.4 65 100:71 33.7 100 100 100:100 • 100:39 None 100:100 • 100:60 • * o 0 to o fi | 33.1 90 35 30 to 35.., j 306 100 10() Light Light 30.3 100 60 Dark and light Average 31.9 97.5 73.8 100:75 28.3 100 100 100:100 • 100:80 • * 28.2 100 80 * Light 28.1 60 60 100:100 100:100 * 100:87 None 100:100 * 100:20 • Dark 25 to 30 'I 278 10 ° 10 ° 25 to 30. 1 27.3 100 87 Light Light 27.3 80 80 Light 26.4 100 20 * Dark and light 25.7 100 100 100:100 * Light Average 27.4 92.5 78.4 100:85 •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Aorhti.tx rai. Exp. Station Rebkabch Brx. 10 Table •"• (Cm, fumed ) — Evert of freezing tempentture* «/&lt; ger - mination of earn differing in woixttire content (1913 &lt;tn&lt;\ 101If) Tempera ure range 32° to 98° F. Germination Moisture Moisture j 1 T~ [ q^^^ Embryos dark range in grain Nornla i Frozen of^™ a , in grain or light grain grain to frozen Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent The ear~ with the lowe-t moisture content were uninjured, while many of those of intermediate moisture content showed more or less loss of vitality. It will also be noted that ice crystals were found in the kernels containing 50 j)er cent or more of moisture, while no ice was noted in kernels containing less than this amount. All kernels with high moisture content showed dark embryos. The chance in embryo color and in ice formation to no ice, together with the germination tests, seems to indicate that the transition from a critical moisture content to one where little or no injury resulted took place between 50 and 40 percent. TEMPERATURE 24° TO 20° F. Table &lt;&gt; contains the data for all the freezing tests in which the temperature ranged from 24° to 20° F. The same observa - tions were made as for the previous range of temperature. By comparing the germination of the normal and of the frozen grain in this table with those in Table 5, it may lie seen that the exposure to this range of temperature is fatal to corn of lower moisture content than was the temperature of 32° to 28° F. Even corn containing as low es 2C&gt; per cent of moisture showed some ice. Discoloration of embryo is more pronounced, and the transition from a fatal moisture content to one not fatal seems to have occurred lx«tween 35 and 28 per cent. 10 to 25 f 21.4 21.2 20.3 ' 20. 1 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100:100 • • 100:100 • Ligh 100:100 * 100:100 * Ligh Average 20.8 100 100 i 100:100 verage 20.8 • V . . vn t h i IS'" III: ■ le </seg>
            <seg id="p037">FrKKZING Ix.IlRY OF SkKI) CmRX 37 Table ('&lt; — Effect of freezing temperature* on germination of torn differing in moisture content ( lttl-l awl l'H.\) Temperature range 2\° to 2(&gt;°F. • Germination Moisture Moisture „ , , Ice . Embryos dark range in grain Nor™. Frozen J*^ &lt;?|™1 J^ "to frozen i i _ Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent ' 79.0 100 0 100:0 * Dark 7&lt;itn«n 76 - 5 10 ° ° 100:0 * Dark 75 10 80 ... y ?59 62 0 100 . 0 Ice Dark 75.7 75 0 100:0 Ice Dark Average . 76.8 84.2 0 100:0 f 73.5 100 0 100:0 * Dark 70 to 75 J 70.6 87 0 100:0 Ice Dark 1 70.2 100 0 100:0 * Dark Average 71.4 95.7 0 100:0 65 to 70.. 68.8 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark fin tn fi&lt;&gt; / 61 - 5 10 ° ° 100:0 Ice • botobi&gt; | 604 100 Q 100 . 0 Ice Dark i i Average 61.0 100 0 100:0 f 58.9 100 0 100:0 * Dark 55 to 60 J 58.6 100 0 100:0 * Dark [ 57.4 100 0 j 100:0 Ice Dark Average i 53.3 100 0 100:0 V) to tt / S 3 - 9 10 ° ° 100:0 Ice Dark 501066 | 51.3- 100 12 100:12 Ice Dark Average 52.6 100 6.0 100:6 41 to 50 i / 496 1°° 25 1°° :2 5 Ice 45 tow .j 461 1(M) Q 100 . 0 Iw Dark i : i . Average] 47.4 100 12.5 ! 100:12 f 43.1 100 25 100:25 Ice • 44.9 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark 40 to 45 424 1°° 37 10« ; 3 7 Ice Dark and light 40 to 45. j 420 100 0 100 . 0 , Dark 41.7 100 0 100:0 * Dark 41.0 100 12 100:12 Ice Dark 1 l i Average 42.5 100 12.3 100:12 i i ' ' i i •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Acjrhvlti rai. Exp. Statkjm Rkseakth Btru 1(5 Table C&gt; (Continued) — Effect of freezing temperatures on &lt;jer- m ination of corn differing in moixture content (1913 and 191$) Temperature range 2',° to %,"¥. TEMPERATURE RANGE 16° TO 12° F. The data for the corn subjected to a temperature ranging from U&gt;° to 12° F. are given in Table 7. It will be noted from this table that the fatality range is very much the same as for the temperature of 24° to 20° F., but runs somewhat lower. Samples containing 33 per cent or more of moisture were killed by the 24-hour exposure to this range of temperature; the embryo generally showed a dark color, and ice formation was Germination Moisture Moisture :r_ o h«J?Ld Embryos dark range in grain Normal *_,_ RaUo observed Qr grain grain t0 frozen Per cent Per cent Per cent j Per cent ( 40.0 100 0 100:0 Ice • 35 to 40 . i 39.4 100 0 100:0 * Dark i 35.5 100 40 100:40 * Light , Average 38.3 100 13 100:13 f 33.8 100 0 100:0 * Dark 30 to 35 \ 30.9 100 100 100:100 None * I 30.7 100 100 100:100 None * Average 31.8 100 66.6 100:67 28.8 100 20 100:20 • Dark 28.8 100 75 100:75 Ice Dark 28.3 100 50 100:50 Ice Dark and light 25 to 30 &lt; 27.5 100 100 100:100 None 27.4 100 100 100:100 • Light 27.1 100 100 100:100 * Light 26.2 87 87 100:100 Ice Light _________ ! | ' Average 27.7 98.1 76.0 100:77 I 22.6 100 100 100:100 * Light 20 to 25 &lt; 22.1 100 87 100:87 None Light I 20.4 100 100 100:100 None. * _________ ' I I ■ Average 21.7 100 95.7 100:96 15 to 20 17.0 100 100 100:100 * Light i ' i i i i •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Freezing Ix.fi kv of Seed Corn 39 Table 7 — Effect of freezing temperature* on germination of coin differing in mointure content (1913 and 101^) Temperature range 16° to 12°F. Germination Moisture Moisture Ice Embryos dark range in grain Ratio observed or light Normal Frozen of normal in grain grain grain to frozen Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 55 to 70 67.2 100 0 100:0 Ice 50 to 65 61.8 100 0 100:0 * Dark 55 to 60 60.0 100 0 100:0 Ice 50 to 55 54.6 100 0 100:0 • Dark f 48.9 100 0 100:0 • Dark I 47.7 100 0 100:0 Ice »5to50 ' 48.5 100 0 100:0 • Dark i 47.6 100 0 100:0 • Dark { 46.2 100 0 100:0 * Dark Average 48.0 100 0 100:0 10 to 45 . 44.5 80 0 100:0 • Dark f 39.6 100 0 100:0 * Dark J5to40 ' 38.5 100 0 100:0 • Dark 36.8 100 0 100:0 * Dark i 35.9 75 0 100:0 Ice Average 37.7 93.8 0 100:0 f 34.6 100 0 100:0 * Light I 34.1 100 0 100:0 Ice JO to 35 ■ 33.2 100 0 100:0 * Dark | 31.5 100 60 100:60 • Dark and light [ 31.2 100 0 100:0 Ice * ' | __ Average 32.9 100 12.0 100:12 29.7 100 20 100:20 * Dark and light 28.9 100 0 100:0 • Light 26.5 100 100 100:100 • Light 25 to 30. 26.4 100 60 100:60 * Dark and light 26.4 100 60 100:60 • Light 26.1 100 0 100:0 None * 26.0 100 0 100:0 * Dark \verage 27.1 100 34.3 100:34 •Nu observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricvlti rai, Exp. Station Reskarch Bii.. K&gt; 40 Tabij: 7 (Continued) — Effect of freezing temperatures on ger- mination of corn differing in moisture content (1913 and 191 b) Temperature range 16° to 12° F. Germination Moisture Moisture range in grain Ice Embryos dark Ratio observed ' or light Normal Frozen of normal in grain grain grain to frozen Per cent j Per cent Per cent Per cent Light Light Light Light Light Light Light Light 24.4 100 40 23.9 100 100 22.7 100 100 * 100:100 • 100:100 ; * 100:100 '• * 100:100 * 100:100 » 100:100 * 100:100 * 100:50 None I 22.1 100 100 20 to 25 &lt; 21.5 100 100 21.4 21.0 20.8 20.8 Average 22.1 f 19.8 Light Light Light Light Light Light Light 18.1 17.8 15 to 20. 17.2 17.0 15.5 15.3 Average..! 17.2 •No observations made. noted thruout the range. The transition here from a fatal moisture content to one free from injury seems to have occurred between 30 and 25 per cent. Below this range, no definite in - jury appears to have resulted from the exposure as indicated by the percentage germination or by the color of the embryo. TEMPERATURE RANGE 8' TO 4° F. The data for the freezing tests in which a range of tem - perature from 8° to 4° F. was used are given in Table 8. In these tests, freezing and loss of germinative ability took place at a lower moisture content than in any of the previous tests. The transition here from injury to no injury seems to have occurred between 25 and 19 per cent moisture content, and but little loss of vitality appears to have resulted where the corn contained less than 20 per cent of moisture. 100:40 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 » 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 * 100 50 100:50 Noi 100 87.8 100:88 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 • 100 100 100:100 • 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 * 100 100 100:100 • 100 100 100:100 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Freezing Ix.n ry of Seed Cobn 41 Table 8 — Effect of freezing temperature* on f/ermin/ition of corn differing in moisture content (1013 and 1914) Temperature range 8° to J,°F. Germination Moisture Moisture ; Ice Embryos dark range m grain Ratio observed or light Normal Frozen of normal in grain grain grain to frozen Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent r ft tn „ 52.6 30 0 100:0 Ice outo55 51 5 100 Q 100 . 0 Ice , Average 52.1 65 0 100:0 40 to 45 41.7 55 0 \ 100:0 Ice * 35 to 40 37.7 100 0 100:0 Ice * 30 to 35 . 31.2 100 0 100:0 Ice * ' 29.5 75 0 100:0 Ice * 25 to 30 27.4 100 20 100:20 * Dark 26.9 100 0 100:0 Ice Average 27.9 91.7 6.6 100:7 I 24.8 100 100 100:100 * Light 20 to 25 22.9 100 0 100:0 Ice * 21.0 100 40 100:40 * Dark and light Average 22.9 100 46.6 100:47 f 19.4 100 100 100:100 * Medium dark : 19.3 100 80 100:80 * Dark and light 18.5 100 100 100:100 * Medium dark 15 to 20 -I 17.7 100 100 100:100 * Light 17.6 100 100 100:100 * Light 16.4 100 100 100:100 * Light 16.0 100 100 100:100 * Light [ 15.7 100 100 100:100 * Medium dark i ■ I i Average 17.6 100 97.5 100:98 f 14.8 100 100 100:100 * Light 14.7 100 100 100:100 • Light 14.1 100 100 100:100 * Light 13.8 100 100 100:100 * Light 10 to 15.. i 13.7 100 100 100:100 * Light 13.2 100 100 100:100 • Light 13.0 100 100 100:100 * Light 11.7 100 100 100:100 * Light 10.8 100 100 100:100 • Light Average.. 13.5 100 100 100:100 ■ i i i •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska A&lt;;rki ltiral Exp. Station Research Hi l. 1(5 TKMPKRATURE RANGE 0° TO —5° F The notes on the corn subjected to a temperature of 0° to — 5" V. are compiled in Table i). It will l)e observed here that the injury resulting from exposure to this temperature occurred in those ears having a moisture content greater than 16 per cent. Below that, little or no injury resulted. The transition seems to have occurred between 20 and 18 j&gt;er cent. Loss of viability or power of germination occurred here with a slightly smaller percentage of moisture than at the tempera - ture of 8° to 4° F. Ice crystals were found in the kernels from a few ears in which the moisture content was as low as 20 per cent. However, little or no loss of viability occurred in oars containing 1&lt;&gt; j&gt;er cent or less of moisture. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Freezing Ixjiry of Seed (\irx 43 Tabus J) — Effect of freezing temperature* on germination of corn differing in moisture coritent (1013 and 191$) Temperature range 0° to — ~"F. Germination Moisture range Moisture in grain Normal grain to frozen Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 65 to 70 67.8 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark 60 to 65. 60.4 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark 59.6 59.2 100 0 0 100:0 100:0 Ice Ice Dark Dark 55 to 60 100 Average 59.4 100 0 100:0 51.1 50.3 100 0 0 100:0 100:0 Ice Ice Dark Dark 50 to 55 100 Average 50.7 100 0 100:0 4H.7 100 0 100:0 Ice « Ice « Ice Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark 48.8 100 100:0 « 0 48.5 100 0 100:0 48.2 100 0 100:0 « 46.8 100 0 100:0 45 to 50 45.9 100 0 100:0 * 45.6 100 0 100:0 Ice Ice 45.4 100 0 100:0 45.3 100 0 100:0 * 45.2 100 0 100:0 Ice Average 46.9 100 0 100:0 43.6 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark 43.3 100 0 100:0 * 42.3 100 0 100:0 Ice Ice 40 to 45 41.0 100 0 100:0 40.9 100 0 100:0 40.7 100 0 100:0 Ice Ice 40.2 100 0 100:0 Average. 41.7 100 0 100:0 •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agrktlttbal Exp. Station- Reheabch Hi l. 10 Table 9 (Continued) — Effect of freezing temperature* on ger- mination of com differing in moitture content (1913 and 191b) Temperature range C° to — 5 °F. Germination Moisture Moisture . — — Ice Embryos dark range in grain Normal Ratio observed or light ■"*» V™ foSn '" gram Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent f 40.0 40.0 39.9 39.8 39.5 39.5 39.1 15 to 40 38.8 38.8 38.4 37.9 37.7 37.7 36.8 35.1 I 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 100:0" 100:0 100 K) 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100 K) 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 ♦ * Ice * Ice Ice * * Ice lee Ice • Ice Ice Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark 1 Average 38.6 100 0 100:0 33.8 33.1 I0to35.. \ 31.1 30.4 30.1 100 100 100 80 100 0 0 0 0 0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 Ice * Ice Ice Dark Dark Dark Medium dark Dark Average.. 31.7 96 0 100:0 30.0 28.7 27.6 15 to 30 j JJJ 25.9 25.2 25.2 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 100:0 Ice * * Ice * Ice * Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Medium dark Light Dark .verage . irage | 27.0 100 27.0 0 i 100:0 I •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Freezing Ixjiry of Seed Corn ■t:. Table 9 (Continued)^ — Effect of freezing temperatures on ger - mination of com differing in moisture content (1913 and 1914) Ttmperature range 0° to —5°F. SUMMARY OF GERMINATION TESTS UNDER CONTROLLED CONDITIONS A summary of the average germinations of corn exposed to the different ranges of temperature, and containing various amounts of moisture, is {riven in Table 10. The data in this table are taken from the detail tables for the different tempera - ture ranges. It will be noted from this table that (1) as the moisture content of the corn diminishes, the injury (with some Germination Moisture Moisture range in grain Normal Frozen Ratio obse^rpd Embr yos dark in grain or h K ht Per fen/ Per e nt Per cent Per cent { 24.8 100 0 100:0 I 24.5 100 0 100:0 I 24.4 100 0 100:0 20 to 25 &gt; 22.3 100 0 100:0 21.5 100 0 100:0 21.2 100 0 100:0 20.5 100 0 100:0 Ice Dark None Dark • Dark None Light Dark * Medium dark Ice Dark \verage . 22.7 100 0 100:0 20.0 100 20 100:?0 19.9 1C0 0 100:0 18.9 100 60 100:60 ,e t _o 0 I 18.4 100 20 100:20 l&amp;toJ0 1 16.3 100 100 100:100 i 15.6 100 100 100:100 ! 15.5 100 100 100:100 { 15.3 100 100 100:100 None Dark and light Ice Dark and light • Light * Medium dark None Light None Light Light None Light Average.. I 17.5 100 62.5 100:63 f 14.8 100 100 100:100 14.4 100 80 100:80 I0to1&lt;5 I 143 10 ° 10 ° 100:100 10 to 15. } 136 100 1(M) i 00:100 I 13.0 100 100 100:100 { 11.9 100 100 100:100 * Light Light Light None Light None Light None Light Average . 13.7 100 96.6 100:97 ; i i ■ i •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Acrkt i.ti rai. Exp. Statkix Research Hi i.. 1&lt;&gt; 46 Tabij; 10 — S a in ma r;/ tthoirhif/ effect of I'arioua freezing temper - atures on (termination of corn differing in moisture content (1013-1014/ Temperature ranges (deirrees F.) mrirtw'in 32 t0 28 24 t0 20 16 to 12 8 to 4 0 to -5 Kraln Germination Germination Germination Germination Germination per cent per cent per cent per cent per cent 'This table is compiled from the averages found in Tables 5 to 9. The given temperatures were continued for a period of twenty-four hours. irregularity) to the vitality of the kernel from exposure to any given temperature becomes less; (2) in the case of immature corn, freezing injury at a given moisture content increases as the temperature lowers: and (8) the vitality of corn with a moisture content ranging from 10 to 14 per cent is not injured by exposure to temperature of 0° to — 5° F. for a period of 24 hours. For corn containing 20 to 25 per cent moisture, the germination percentages, when exposed to the temperature ranges of 32° to 28° F.. 24° to 20° F., 16° to 12° F., 8° to 4° F., and 0° to —5° F., were respectively 100. 96, 88, 47, and 0 per cent. EFFECT OF FREEZING ON DRY CORN In litll. freezing tests were made with corn which had been cured one month in a dry room, and also with corn cured three months. The grain at the time of freezing contained from 12 to 14 per cent moisture. The results of these tests are shown in Table 11. Practically no loss of vitality resulted in either case, even at the lowest temperature. 80 to 85 75 to 80 70 to 75 ... 65 to 70 .... 60 to 65 55 to 60 50 to 55 45 to 50 40 to 45 35 to 40 30 to 35 25 to 30 20 to 25 .... : 15 to 20. . 10 to 15 0 0 0 3 0 31 33 69 71 75 85 100 0 0 0 0 0 0 6 12 12 13 67 77 96 100 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 12 34 88 100 0 0 0 0 7 47 W 100 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 fi:i 97 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn ■17 Table 11 — E fleet of freezing temperatures on the germination of corn which had been cured in a dry room before freezing (H)ll ). Moixturc range in grain 12 to J .!f per rent. Per cent germination T . . . . Temperature ' Number Length of drying period range Normal Frozen of samples degrees F.) grain grain tested NATURAL RESISTANCE OF GREEN CORN TO COLD It was thought desirable in connection with this work to determine as nearly as possible not only the degree of cold necessary to weaken or destroy the vitality of the corn kernel but also the length of time necessary for cold to operate before injury results. The latter tests were made as nearly under natural field conditions as possible, so far as the corn itself was concerned. — the ears being undisturbed in the husks, and placed in the freezing apparatus as soon as brought from the field. Five or six ears were frozen at a time. The plan was. to select ears of the four degrees of maturity used in previous tests, and subject them to a given range of temperature for varying periods of time. Again similar sets of ears were subjected for a given time to varying ranges of temperature. As soon ;is the ears were removed from the freezing chamber, moisture samples were taken and the ear husked and laid away to dry. Later, germination tests were made and notes taken regarding the color of the embryo. The data are compiled in Table 12. The ger - mination tests tend to indicate that light freezing temperatures of short duration are not particularly injurious even to corn of high moisture content, while long exposure. 20-24 hours, to the same temperature may prove fatal. As the temperature is reduced, the duration of exposure necessary to injury becomes shorter. This is indicated in summary Table 13, The data for the 24 hour period in this table are calculated from Tables 5 to 0. While tests at this temperature are not strictly com - parable with those of 1015 in that the husks were removed from month 28 to 32 20 to 24 12 to 16 4 to 8 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 97 ,- t i i -I months 28 to 32 20 to 24 12 to 16 100 100 100 100 100 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agrh i ltirai. Exp. Station Research Hi l. Hi Table 12 — Effect of exposure to ranges of freezing temperature for different periods of time on the germination of corn differing in moisture content. All ears were protected naturally by the husks (1915) Moisture Du ™ tion Minimum Mom- Germ . Ice observed Embry08 dark ™*e expire S^n ination in ** n or M « ht Hours Degrees F. ?" Per cent Percent cent 4 fi 24 77.4 32 76.4 92 * Light and dark 75 to 80 100 Light 70 to 75 I 32 71.6 100 • Light and dark 65 to 70 12 28 67.6 «:J Dark 2 32 62.5 30 61.5 28 60.7 28 64.4 100 Light 4 100 Light and dark 60 to 65 4 100 * Light 12 93 Light and dark 4 30 59.7 28 55.9 14 57.8 23 55.5 18 58.8 100 » Light and dark -1 100 • Light 4 75 let- Light 8 100 Ice in some kernels Light 50 Ice Light and 55 to 60 8 Ice Light and dark X 3 56.7 14 58.4 25 56.1 8 I if Dark 10 19 Ice Dark 15 92 Ice in some kernels Light and dark 2 32 54.5 24 50.5 16 51.2 23 52.5 23 51.4 14 53.2 100 • Light 4 100 • Light and dark * 6 25 Ice Light and dark 50 to 55 8 100 * Dark * 10 91 Ice in some kernels Light 10 67 Ice Light 10 3 52.7 0 ; Ice Dark 2 23 49.5 10 45.9 14 45.6 23 48.7 23 47.8 25 48.5 25 47.9 100 * Light « 2 85 • Light and dark 75 Ice Light and dark 100 I • Light 4 45 to 50 6 * 8 100 Ice in some kernels Light and dark 100 Ice in some kernels Light 75 Ice in some kernels Light and dark 15 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Freezing Ixjikv of Seed Corn 49 Tabi.K 1'2 (Continued ) — Effect of e.r /insure to rant/ex of freez - ing temperature for different periods of time on the ffer - inimitioti of corn differing in moist lire ,-ontent. All earn irere protected naturally by the husks (1915) . . Duration Minimum Mois- /-.___ t_ _v. j P u j ■ Moisture of tempera- ture in 9*™- lce . ob^r ved Embryos dark range exposure ture grain lnatlor ' m « raln or h * ht Per Per cent Per cent Hours Degrees F. cent 2 2 6 27 43.5 100 Light and dark 20 44.4 100 Light 23 42.1 100 Light and dark 42.2 42 Ice Light and dark 23 45.0 18 43.0 3 44.2 100 Ice in some kernels Light 100 Ice in some kernels Light and dark 8 8 40 to 45 Ice 8 0 Dark 10 14 43.8 67 Ire Light and dark 12 21 42.1 100 Ice in some kernels Light 63 lee in some kernels Light and dark 96 Ice in some kernels Light 12 14 44.6 15 25 44.3 9 23 37.9 100 Light 4 5 35.4 45 Ice Light and dark fi 23 36.2 16 38.1 100 Light 35 to 40 6 50 Ice in some kernels Light and dark 50 Ice Light and dark 6 39.9 Ice Light and dark 10 23 36.2 100 None Light and dark L2 21 39.2 None Light and dark 83 12 1 37.3 10 33.0 23 34.1 3 34.7 0 Ice Light and dark 2 4 92 • Light 100 Light 8 47 Ice Light and dark 30 to 35 10 23 34.5 100 None Light 10 3 34.6 1 32.4 8 Ice Light and dark VI 25 Ice Light and dark ■i2 25 33.6 100 None Light 2 9. 20 29.4 100 * Light 10 26.6 100 Light and dark 25 to 30 4 5 28.0 21 26.4 92 Ice Light 12 None 100 Light 12 1 27.8 42 Ice Light and dark 2 4 20 24.4 100 * Light 20 to 25 14 24.3 16 22.2 18 16.4 3 19.4 100 None Light 100 None Light 10 100 None Light 15 to 20 92 None Light and dark 10 to 15 4 5 13.6 100 None Light •No observations made. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agrh tlti ral Exp. Station Research Bul. 10 50 Table 13 — Summary shotting effect of length of exposure and degree of cold on the vitality of corn varying in moisture content (1915) M . . M nimum Minimum Minimum Minimum Minimum Moisture D urat ; on tempera- tempera- tempera- tempera- tempera - ln gram tnrp!&gt;fi°F tiir*&gt;18°F. rnr*&gt;10°F. tiirp 2°F rnrp — K°F ture26°F. ture 18°F. ture 10°F. ture 2°F. ture — 5°F. 'This table is compiled from Table 12. The germination tests for the 24 - hour period are calculated from Tables 5 to 9. Where data is lacking no tests were made. D . u Germination Germination Germination Germination Germination Percent Hours p er Mni Percent Percent ! Percent Percent 2 4 ... 92 6 100 70 to 80 8 10 12 83 15 24 0 0 2 100 4 100 6 60 to 70 I J 12 88 15 ... ... j ... 24 2 0 0 ... 0 2 100 4 100 100 75 6 ... 25 pa i O ... OO ... O Mto60 1 10 ... 91 43 0 12 15 ... 92 24 32 2 0 0 0 - 2 100 100 85 4 ... 75 6 ... 100 ... 42 *° to5 ° io ::: 94 67 ° 12 ... 100 63 15 ... 98 24 69 12 0 0 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Freezing In.hky of Seed Corn 51 Table 13 (Continued) — Summary xhowing effect of length of exposure and degree of cold on the vitality of corn varying in imiixtiirr content (191"j) M . t Minimum Min'mum Minimum Minimum Minimum . " Duration tempera- tempera- tempera- tempera- tempera - ln grain tnrp2fi°F tnrp18°F tnrp10°F tnro 5&gt;°F tnrp — 5°F ture26°F. ture 18 °F. ture 10°F. ture 2°F. ture — 5°F. D . I, Germination Germination Germination Germination Germination rercent Hours p er eent Percent Percent Percent Percent this corn before being exposed to the freezing teaipenttures, and the minimum temperatures were not exactly the same, yet it was thought that owing to the length of the freezing period both the husked and the unhusked corn would be affected in prac - tically the same way. This is the reason for including the data for the -24-hour period in this table. 30 to 40 ■ 4 6 8 I 10 12 15 24 . . . 72 1VU 100 100 100 83 40 50 7 45 50 47 8 0 13 0 20 to 30 &lt;j I 5 I * 1 10 12 15 24 . . . 90 100 . . . 100 83 100 100 100 64 92 *28 42 0 I 10 to 20 f 2 6 8 10 12 15 24 ioo 100 100 100 92 99 77 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nkhkaska Acrici i.ti hai, Exp. Station Research Bul. 1&lt;&gt; 52 VITALITY OF CORN EXPOSED TO FREEZING TEMPERATURES IN THE FIELD GENERAL SURVEY As a sort of check on the work done under controlled con - ditions in the laboratory, a study was made of the vitality &gt;f corn exposed to fall and winter freezing in the field during the years 1913-1917. Moisture tests were made at 'the lime the corn was gathered. When the corn was thoroly dry, ger - mination tests were made and the color of the embryo was noted. A record is given of all freezing weather to which the corn was exposed prior to gathering. Because of the differences in exjnwure and the repeated freezing and thawing, these data are not strictly comparable with the data obtained from the laboratory tests. However, these data substantiate the principles established under the con - trolled conditions. Prior to these note detailed investigations, a general study of the condition of corn had l&gt;een made in the fall of 1!)11 and 1912. In the fall of 1911 a severe frost occurred :&gt;n Novem - ber 11 and 12. At this time the temperature dropped so low, and corn contained so much moisture, that a very large per cent of the crop in Nebraska was frozen and its power of ger - mination destroyed. The average corn crop contained at that date from '20 to 25 per cent of moisture, and much of it con - tained more than this amount. The temperature fell as low as 2° F. and remained at that low mark for four hours. (Ta - bles 14 and 15.) Corn which ripened earlier and was drier, however, was not injured. This together with the other field studies and lal&gt;oratory tests seems to indicate that corn which contains as low as 16 or 17 per cent of moisture is in no dan - ger of losing its vitality from exposure to the ordinary autumn freezes. The freezing which occurred in 1911 prior to November 13 is indicated in Table 14. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Freezing Ixjikv ok Seed Corn 53 Fable 1-1 — Freezing temperature (hiring autumn 1911 Defiree* h Hour Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Oct. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov Nov Nov Of day 21 23 27 28 29 31 1 2 3 4 7 10 11 12 13 A.M. 12-1 16 27 31 4 17 1-2 32 15 27 31 32 4 19 2-3 32 32 32 31 15 27 31 29 2 20 3-4 32 32 32 32 30 32 14 26 30 27 2 21 4-5 31 32 32 31 32 29 27 14 26 31 23 32 2 21 5-6 31 32 31 30 31 28 26 13 26 32 22 30 "&gt; 6-7 30 30 29 28 23 12 26 32 21 26 3 *&gt;4 7-8 31 31 28 27 20 13 26 31 21 21 4 25 8-9 32 32 31 21 27 27 22 1" 7 29 ,9-10 21 22 28 25 14 9 10-11 21 25 29 28 13 12 II- 12 , 21 27 30 32 12 15 P.M. 12-1 23 28 31 12 17 I- 2 25 30 31 11 19 2-3 24 29 32 11 20 f* 24 29 32 11 20 &lt;-5 24 28 10 20 M 22 28 10 18 «"7 21 27 9 18 I* 20 27 8 17 8-9 19 27 7 16 ,»-10 18 26 7 15 I! 10-11 17 26 31 7 16 H-12 16 27 31 .. .. 6 16 I ' I ! Table 15 — Duration fit/i mean and minimum temperature of freezing perioth during autumn 191V !-&gt;„,. Hnnro Mean Minimum Date in Ziod temperature temperature ln P 6 "** 1 degrees F. degrees F. Oct- 21 5 3i.o jo Oct. 23 2 32.0 32 Oct. 27 7 31.4 30 Oct. 28 7 30.6 28 Oct. 29 j 5 318 31 Oct. 30 7 29.1 27 Nov. 1-3 60 24.2 12 Nov. 3-4 8 31.0 30 Nov. 7 2 31.5 31 Nov. 10 11 25.6 21 Nov. 11-13 ; 53 142 2 ■Compiled from Table 14. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska A(iKi( i lti ral Exp. Station Reheabch Bex. 1&lt;&gt; The dates on which the first freezing temperatures recorded by the weather bureau, three miles distant, have occurred during the last seven years are as follows: 1911, October 21: 1912, October 22: IMS, Octol&gt;er 20: 1914. October 27; 1915, October 8: 191&lt;&gt;. September 29: 1!»17. October 8. This shows Octol&gt;er 15 to be the average date for the first freezing temperature recorded by the weather bureau, during this period, wherea-s the average date for the first killing frost was October 12. The freezing temperatures which occurred on the above dates were not low enough, however, to affect the vitality of the corn in any way. unless the corn should have been exceedingly iminautre. Even this class of corn is rarely injured by the first freezing temperatures because of their short duration. (See Table 13.) The approximate moisture content of the average corn crop in eastern Nebraska on October 15, 1911, was 22 per cent; in 1912, it was 20 per cent: in 1913, it was 17 per cent; in 1914, it was 15 per cent: in 1915, it was 35 per cent; in 1910, it was 18 per cent: and in 1917. it was 37 per cent. These figures are based on the moisture content of corn harvested from the general field plats of the Experiment Station. They represent, no doubt, very nearly the average maturity of corn in eastern Nebraska at the time when freezing temperatures are likely to occur. It will be seen that usually corn is too mature to l&gt;e injured in vitality by the first freezing weather. Even in 1015 when the moisture content was large the first freezing did little or no damage to the life of the seed. (See Table 22.) Farther north and west in the State, however, the season is shorter and freezing comes earlier. The corn in these sections, therefore, should be correspondingly earlier in order to insure normal vitality in the seed. Heavier freezing during the late fall and winter is more likely to do serious damage to the germination of corn not fully matured. FIELD SELECTION IN 1913 In the fall of 1913. corn samples of various degrees of dryness were selected from the field on Octol&gt;er 30, after 9 days of considerable freezing weather, during which time 98 hours of freezing temperature prevailed, with a minimum of 15° F. Th° notes on viability and color of germ are given in Table US. The freezing temperatures which occurred during the fall and to which the corn had been exposed are indicated in Table 17. Table 18 summarizes these tempera - tures, giving the duration and the inwn and minimum tem - perature of each freezing period. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Freezing Injury ok Seed Corn 55 Table 10 — Germinative ability of corn -which varied in degree of maturity and which xras exposed in the field to the freezing temperatures of nut mini. The degree of maturity is indicated In/ the moisture content of the grain, ('urn har - vested October JO, 191J. 1 Moisture in grain Embryos dark or light Moisture range Germination Per cent Per cent Per cent 39.7 39.7 0 Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark Dark 0 39.4 0 35 to 40 37.0 36.9 0 20 35.7 0 Average 38.1 3 34.3 4(1 Light Dark Dark Light Dark 34.1 0 30 to 35 33.5 20 :i2.9 60 32.3 0 Average 33.4 24 30.0 20 Medium dark Dark Light 29.8 0 27.7 40 25 to 30 27.6 100 Light Dark and light 27.1 60 26.7 M) Light 26.4 0 Dark Average 27.9 48 24.4 100 Light Light Light Light Light Light 23.9 Ml 23.2 BO 20 to 25 22.7 100 22.3 100 21.2 100 Average 23.0 m 20.0 100 Light Light Light Light 19.4 100 15 to 20. . 15.3 100 15.3 100 Average 10 to 15 17.5 100 14.2 100 Light Light 14.1 100 Average 14.2 100 'See Tables 17 and 18 for freezing temperatures prior to October JO. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Nebraska Agrici ltiral Exp. Station Research Bil. 16 Table 17 — Freezing temperature* during autumn, 1913. Table 18 — Duration with mean and minimum temperatures of freezing period* during autumn of 1913 1 'Compiled from Table 17. Degree* F. Hours of day A.M. 2-1 .... 1-2 .... 2-3 .... 3-4 .... 4-6 .... 6-6 .... 6-7 7-8 .... 8-9 .... 9-10 .0-11.... 1-12... Oct. Oct. Oct. 19 20 21 26 28 25 26 24 25 23 24 23 23 25 23 27 22 29 24 . . 32 26 28 ... 31 Oct. 23 | 32 32 ■ • I Oct 26 32 32 Jet 26 P.M. 2-1 .... 1-2 . ... 2-3 8-4 .... 4-5 .... 6-6 .... 6-7 . ... 7-8 .... 8-9 .... 9-10. 0-11 .... 1-12 . ... 30 28 27 29 28 29 ■ * 32 29 Jet. 27 Oct. 28 Oct. 29 Oct. 30 Oct. 31 Nov. 1 : I""" 28 26 25 24 23 22 24 21 30 31 30 28 27 26 26 21 21 21 21 19 18 15 15 17 20 23 26 23 22 21 20 19 19 18 18 21 24 28 25 24 23 23 22 22 22 23 25 32 32 32 32 32 32 32 26 27 28 28 26 25 24 23 23 23 23 22 28 31 32 30 28 27 26 26 25 23 31 29 27 25 I I I •ct. 19-20 let. 20-21 •ct. 28 •ct. 26 •ct. 26-27 •ct. 28-29 •ct. 29-30 •ct. 30-31 fov. 1 Date Hours in period 14 12 2 2 11 32 19 14 Mean Minimum temperature temperatur degrees F. ! degrees F. 26.9 23 25.8 22 32.0 32 32.0 32 25.8 21 23.8 15 23.4 18 25.2 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Freezing In.h rv or Seed Corn ■ u The corn w i- grouped according to its moisture content, with a rang- (if 5 jx»r cent for each group. Corn ranging in mois'.ure content from 10 to 15 per cent, and 15 to 20 per cent gave KM) per cent germination; 20 to 25 |&gt;er cent moisture germinated 93 per cent: 25 to 30 per cent moisture "Terminated 43 per cent: 30 to 35 per cent moisture germinated 24 per cent; and 85 to 40 per cent moisture germinated 3 per cent. These results conform very closely to those from the lab - oratory tests at a temperature range of 1&lt;&gt;° to 12° K.. as may l&gt;' seen by comparing with Table 7. In the laboratory, when subjected to a temperature of H&gt;° to 1:2° F., corn containing 15 to -JO. 20 to 25. 25 to 30. 30 to 35. and 35 to 40 per cent of wfeter germinated respectively 100. HS. 34. 12, and 0 per cent, while the same grades of corn exposed in the field to a mini - mum temperature of 15° F. germinated respectively 100. 93. 43. 24. and 3 per cent. FIELD SELECTION IN 1914 The results for corn selected from the field on November 22. 1914. after intermittent subjection to 111 hours freezing tem - perature with ;; minimum of 4° V. are given in Table 19. The freezing temperatiuvs ««re given in detail in Table 20 and arc HiimniPrized in Table 21. which gives the duration and the mean, and minimum temperatures' for each freezing period. The respective mean germinations were 100. 67.6, 60. 55. and 30 i&gt;er cent according to whether the moisture content of the grain ranged from 10 to 15. 15 to 20. 20 to 25. 25 to 30. or 30 to 35 per cent. FIELD SELECTION IN 1915 A study was made in the fall of 1915 of the effect of early freezing temperatures on the vitality of corn when left in the field and exposed to the natural freezing weather of October and Novemlwr. This year the corn was very immature at the time of the first killing frost and continued to retain a large per cent of water thruout the fall. Since there was also considerable variation in the maturity of individual ears, the opportunity was exceptionally good for studies of this kind. The freezing temperatures which occurred during the fall are recorded in Table 24. and put in summary form in Table 25. It will be noted from these that the first freezing occurred on Octol&gt;er S. and again on October 9. The first was very light and of short duration, while the second was more severe and slightly longer. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Nebraska A&lt;;ri&lt; vi.ti rai, Exp. Station Research IUi.. 16 Tablk 19 — Germinatire ability of corn which varied in degree of maturity and which was exposed in the field to the freeMtmff temperatures of autumn. The degree of Maturity is indicated by the moisture content of the (/rain. Corn imr - rt'xted November 22, 191 p iSffif Germination Embryos dark or light Moisture range Dark Light Dark Dark and light Dark Light Dark Dark and light Light Light Dark Dark Light Dark and light Dark and light Light Light Dark and light Light Dark and light Light Light Light Light 'See Tables 20 and 21 for freezing temperatures prior to November 22. Per cent Per cent Per cen 3ot ° 35 ;{ 3?i 0 60 &gt;__ i Average 32.8 30 f 29.4 ( 26.3 60 80 20 60 . 1 1 Average | 2'.7 55 i 24.? 24.0 23. S 22.5 20 to 25 21.4 21/? 21.1 2\5 2P.2 20 20 60 100 80 60 100 60 40 Average I 22.1 60 19.9 19.9 19.6 i5to2 ° I ia 17.8 17.6 16.8 40 60 20 100 40 100 100 80 Average. . 18.7 67.5 10 to 15 . . 13.4 100 I </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Freezing Ix.iiry of Seed Corn 59 ■Compiled from Table 20. Table lio — Freezing temperatures during autumn, HH.4. Degree* F. 1 Hours Oct. Oct. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. Nov. of day 26 27 8 13 15 16 17 18 19 20 22 A.M. 12-1 28 . .... 22 25 12 19 1-2 ...... 27 31 ... 23 25 10 19 2-3 27 30 . 22 25 . . 8 20 3-4 26 29 .. .. 21 26 .. 7 21 4-5 25 28 . . . 19 27 32 6 22 32 5-6 ...... 24 27 .. .. 18 28 31 5 22 30 6-7 25 26 . 18 29 . 5 22 30 7-8 26 26 32 31 19 28 . . 4 23 29 8-9 ...... 31 30 29 21 30 .6 26 28 9-10 .. . 30 24 .. .. 8 10-11 .. .. 31 25 .. .. 11 11-12 .. 27 . . .. 14 P.M. 12-1 29 . . . 18 1-2 . . . . 31 . . . . ! 19 | . . 2-3 .. 32 21 3-4 .. 32 .. 22 4-5 .. .. 31 .. 21 5-6 31 28 .. 20 6-7 30 27 . 20 .. 7-8 . . 27 25 32 20 8-9 ....• 32 25 25 . 27 19 9-10. 30 23 24 23 19 i .... 10-11 30 22 25 19 18 11-12... 28 .. 21 24 15, 18 i i Table 21 — Duration with mean and minimum temperatures of freezing periods during autumn of 1914 1 i Mean Minimum Date Hours temperature temperature in period degrees F. degrees F. Oct. 26-27 13 27.6 24 Nov. 8 1 8 28.4 26 Nov. 13 1 32.0 32 Nov. 15 ; 4 30.2 29 Nov. 15, 16, 17 ! 40 25.3 18 Nov. 18 ; 2 31.5 31 Nov. 18, 19, 20 : 38 16.9 4 Nov. 22 ! 5 29.8 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska Ac.hh tltvhal Exp. Station Rebeabth Hi l. 1&lt;&gt; EFFECT OF EARLY FREEZING ON VARIETIES. 1915 On October 10. corn was gathered from twenty-seven differ - ent varieties and hybrids for moisture and germination tests. These varieties and hybrids represented many different stages of maturity at the time the frost came. Some were late varieties and weiv still very immature, while others were early and were comparatively dry. Intermediate stages were also represented. The moist im* content of the grain and also of the cob at the time of harvest, together with the germination for each variety, is shown in Table 2ii. It will be noted from this table that the moisture content of the grain was still rather large for most varieties. The germination tests, however, are so nearly perfect for all. thai it seems hardly possible to trace any injury back to the effect of the frost. Table 2*2 — The (termination of corn varying in degree of maturity and gathered on October 10. after the first killing — — — -j — ,/ — - — — — — - - — / — - — f— - — • j frost in 1915. The degree of maturity is indicated by the per cent of moisture in the cob and in the grain 1 Tasseling Per cent moisture p er cent Variety name I date l_^ -— | germinatio. Cob Grain Hogue's Yellow Dent I 8-16 67.0 38.0 99 Boone Co. White j 8-21 60.3 44.7 97 Boone Co. White x Hogue's 8-20 64.9 47.9 99 Nebraska White Prize 8-20 61.2 45.2 100 Nebraska White Prize x Hogue's 8-18 63.3 43.2 99 Bloody Butcher 8-19 55.0 39.9 99 Bloody Butcher x Hogue's 8-18 57.7 43.2 94 Calico 8-17 59.2 40.4 100 Calico x Hogue's 8-17 55.3 40.4 100 Reid's Yellow Dent 8-16 60.8 37.8 97 Reid's Yellow Dent x Hogue's ... 8-16 59.1 35.2 99 Iowa Silver Mine 8-15 51.1 33.7 99 Iowa Silver Mine x Hogue's . 8-14 57.9 40.6 99 St. Charles White | 8-13 53.8 31.6 100 St. Charles White x Hogue's ....] 8-15 58.0 32.1 100 Pride of the North 8-13 41.1 23.8 100 Pride of the North x Hogue's 8-15 51.5 32.9 99 University No. 3 1 8-13 57.3 35.4 97 University No. 3 x Hogue's .... 8-14 56.6 36.5 99 White Cap 8-12 50.3 29.0 100 White Cap x Hogue's 8-14 52.5 33.6 97 Iowa Gold Mine 8-10 51.6 31.6 99 Iowa Gold Mine x Hogue's 8-12 55.5 35.4 97 Learning 8-9 57.1 33.8 99 Learning x Hogue's 8-13 55.1 39.0 100 Minnesota No. 13 8-4 40.9 18.3 100 Minnesota No. 13 x Hogue's ... 8-8 47.4 26.6 I 100 ■See Ta bits 24 and 25 for freezing temperatures prior to October 10. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Fkeezixc; Injury of Seeii (\iitx 61 EFFECTS OF MORE SEVERE FREEZING. 191 On the morning of November !&gt;. while the frost was still on, a innnl&gt;er of ears were examined in the field for ice formation in the kernels. Moisture samples were taken from these ears and germination tests were made later. After rather severe freezing on November 14. and ajrain on the 15th, observations were made, the same being taken as in the previous cast". The data are compiled in Table -23. One interesting tiling shown in this table is that ice formation in the kernel is not necessarily fatal to the vitfllitv of the era in. also that the freezing of p — — i . _ — _ November !* with a minimum of was not of sufficient duration to 30° F. and lasting five hours affect germination. From the data of November 15 it is iiiteivs ears on which the kernels were a solid frozen mass gave a fair cases, however, the viabilitv plainly was reduced. Table "2H — Germinatire ability of corn which wax exposed in the p'ehl to the freezing temperature* of autumn, iftlo* *ST Extent of freezing in kernels CORN GATHERED NOVEMBER 9 Per cent Per cent SECOND LIGHT FREE E Not frozen, no ice found in kernels 36.0 100 Not frozen, no ice found in kernels 32.2 100 Not frozen, no ice found in kernels 31.3 100 Ice 'ound in the base of some of the kernels ■ 39.1 100 Ice found in the base of some of the kernels 30.7 100 Ice found in the base of some of the kernels 41.9 100 Ice found in the base of some of the kernels 41.8 100 Ice found in the base of some of the kernels 47.8 100 CORN GATHERED NOVEMBER 15 Whole kernel frozen solid 53.3 K7 67 Germ frozen solid, rest of kernel not frozen 43.4 Ice in base of kernel, germ and endosperm not frozen 26.3 75 Not frozen, no ice found in kernel 16.9 100 'See Tables 24 and 25 for freezing temperatures prior to November 15. tin&lt;r to note that even those per c"iit of germination. In the; FIRST =EVERE FREE'E </seg>
            <seg id="p062">(52 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station Research Bui* 1(&gt; Table 24 — Freezing temperatures during autumn of 1915. Degrees F. Hours of day j Oct. 8 Oct. 9 Nov. 9 Nov. 13 Nov. A.M. Hours of day Oct. 8 Oct. 9 Nov. 9 Nov. 13 Nov. 14 Nov. 15 Nov. 16 A.M. 12-1 32 . . . . 26 26 24 1-2 30 32 .. 25 25 24 2-3 30 31 . . 24 24 L4 3-4 31 . . 23 23 28 4-6 30 . . 22 22 23 6-6 30 . . 22 22 ■2-i II 6-7 32 . . . . 22 24 29 7-8 21 21 27 27 8-9 . . 26 26 30 2» 9-10. 30 10-11 11-12 P.M. 12-1 1-2 2-3 3-4 4-5 31 5-6 30 6-7 30 31 7-8 29 30 8-9 28 28 9-10 28 27 10-11 28 26 11-12 28 25 Table 25 — Duration with mean and minimum temperatures of freezing periods during autumn, 1915 1 Mean Minimum Date Hours j temperature temperature in period ! degrees F. | degrees F. Oct. 8 1 32.0 32 Oct. 9 3 30.7 30 Nov. 9 5 30.8 30 V Nov. 13-14 18 26.3 21 Nov. 14-16 15 25.9 23 Nov. 16 4 28.8 27 "Compiled from Table 24. VARIATION WITHIN A SINGLE EAR It was observed that there was a great variation in the maturity and moisture content of kernels on the same ear. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 63 In order to determine definitely the actual difference which may be found, moisture tests were made. For this purpose' two ears were selected showing great variation in maturity of different kernels. The kernels from each ear were divided into groups according to maturity. The kernels from one ear were grouped as dry. and as damp. Only the extreme types were taken. The dry group represented the driest kernels on the ear. while the damp group represented the most immature kernels. Sprouted kernels were found on the other ear. and these were placed in a group by themselves. Moisture tests were then made for each group from each ear. The results are shown in Table 20. The table shows an average difference of 15.8 per cent between the damp and dry kernels. The sprouted kernels averaged (iO.T piT cent moisture. The difference here indicated is sufficient to cause a great difference in susceptibility to cold, as indicated in previous tables, and no doubt explains in many cases why some kernels of an ear are killed by freezing while others are uninjured. Tabu: 2fi — Variation in moisture content of kernels from the Climatic conditions combined in such manner in 1917 that no season in this generation has been quite so unfavorable to the maturing and drying of the corn crop. The early growth was retarded by a cold, wet spring. Later it was again retarded by deficient moisture in July. Following that came an un - usuallv cool August and September, which prolonged growth and delayed ripening. The first killing frost in the early morning of October 8. with a duration of nine hours and a minimum temperature of 24° F.. (Table 30) was an unusually severe first frost. This was followed by three weeks of cold and freezing weather which not only retarded the drying of corn but continued to reduce its vitaiitv. same ear of corn at the time of harvest. X November 10. 1915 ■ I Car Description of Kernels Moisture content . Least mature Most mature Per cent 65.4 49.2 f Least mature 2 | Most mature Sprouted . ... 63.5 48.2 60.7 FIELD SELECTIONS IN 18 !i 17 '.i </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Xkhranka A(iiii( ti.ti itAi. Exp. Station Research Bi'L. l't 64 EFFECT OF FIltST KILLING FROST ON VARIETIES. 1917 The test with corn varieties and hybrids reported in Table ±2 for 191ft, was repeated in 1!)17. Types varying widely as to earliness and related moisture content were represented. An unusually large amount of moisture was present at the time of the first killing frost on October 8. Ten eais of each variety and hybrid were gathered the following day and tested for moisture and germination. The results are given in Table 27. The varieties and their hybrids represented many different stages of maturity at the time they were gathered for testing. The fjrain varied from 1(5 to 47 j)er cent moisture content. according to variety. -The germination tests show very little injury from this first frost, even for the late maturing varieties. Table 27 — Germination of corn varying in degree of maturity and gathered after the firxt killing froxt on October #, 191~&gt;. ij ----- — , / ..-,.^ —^ — j r _. „, — .. The decree of maturity is indicated hi/ the per cent of in oixt ure in the (/rain. ■For freezing temperatures see Table SO. Variety name Tasseling date Per cent moisture Per cf nt germinatio: Hogue's Yellow Dent Boone Co. White Bnone Co. White x Hogue's Nebraska White Prize Nebraska White Prize x Hogue's. Bloody Butcher Bloody Butcher x Hogue's Calico Calico x Hogue's Reid's Yellow Dent Reid's Yellow Dent x Hogue's . Iowa Silver Mine Iowa Silver Mine x Hogue's St. Charles White St. Charlrs White x Hogue's Pride of the North Pride of the North x Hogue's University No. 3 University No. 3 x Hogue's White Cap White Cap x Hogue's Iowa Gold Mine Iowa Gold Mine x Hogue's Learning Learning x Hogues Minnesota No. 13 Minnesota No. 13 x Hogue's 8-7 8-12 8-11 8-10 8- 8 8-11 8-10 8-10 8-10 8- 6 8- 7 8- 7 . 8- 7 8- 5 8- 6 8- 2 8- 5 8- 8 8- 8 8- 5 8- 6 8- 9 8- 8 8- 8 8- 7 8- 2 8- 4 39 46 50 44 42 46 47 34 41 38 44 26 44 37 :8 29 37 37 40 38 34 32 41 37 44 17 27 94 97 88 96 91 93 94 94 95 100 99 100 92 94 96 95 97 95 95 96 96 95 88 94 94 99 92 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Freezing Ixjiry of Seed Cor DEGREES OF MATURITY SELECTED FROM FIELD AT DIFFEREN DATES IN FALL AND WINTER OF 1! Five 10-ear samples of corn differing in maturity and moisture content were selected from a field of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn on October 8, li&gt;17, following the first, but severe, freezing spell of the season. As nearly corresponding samples as possible were selected at four succeeding dates, namely on November 10. December 11, December L'it. and January 15, for the purpose of observing the effects of additional degrees of freezing under natural field conditions. The field was neither the ripest nor the greenest at the Station, but was of medium maturity, and represented about an average condition for eastern Nebraska that season. The five selected samples of this seed ranged from mature seed down to the late dough stage of maturity. Two additional samples were selected from other fields at each of the al&gt;ove dates and tested together with the above five samples. One was mature seed selected from a field of Hogu/s Yellow Dent corn which had Ihmmi cut and shocked late in September. The other was very immature seed selected in the milk stage from a field of late planting. A description of the seven samples together with their moisture content and germination are given in Tables -2H and 2V. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">M N Nebraska Acjrici ltiral Exp. Station Research Bul. 10 5 Z Illlll eS-s-s! 81 § §§§§§§ § iss°°2 o »i 3 ir 11 ■w ■- oo oo t- 1- w e&gt;) «o oo — — — t- -&gt;r ~i O fc .! OS Oi Ol OS OS Ol 1O O&gt; OS t- ■*■ -H * ( (i | "Ilk « — .*-.-. ° 1 1 1 i dn (5 § E I *4 _C i I 5 a c c I 3 «? c C w ! co eo O3 ■*■ ■* us &lt;c "•^ o o &gt; js 1^ I— if t 5» M o " 8 o teoOH^nn 5| _? «_ ? 1_ |§ h°.s « £ * .5 ji ..::::: *£ -1 I :•&lt;••• $ = -g © 2 2«S : : : 2 | I 1 1 1'S I : : : ; ii i § mm .11 li I Uli.i: a o "3 . c H I w t) ■** ~~~ " "S «e nausoopM I o t-lONfflO 2 CO rtNNTO ■ I 1 i\i \\ \ g =3 : : : "5 jo m-"^ &lt;S cd t- a; ■ 0) 0) as c ■ ■ c . .1 B ; ; ; C8 4) CO J2 -"t; 2 E*£3&gt;&gt;S» ■ life "v . c 1 - s - ■ 2 J i - I ■ ! I I- ° - a </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Freezing Injury ok Seed Corn 67 B *§ »= - t-5 .* i &gt;£ 1 § i g E H 11 MM 1 § — 1 (I I "I 1 IT jj_ Ja.s M | •goo II 9 I I ; I I 1 •s o \c 1— •o I S E 1 I 1— | 1 © 00t-&lt;O TT OO O 3030 00 « 1O IO 3; -i O a&gt; OS aoiM -^ i-i | | CO t-0)Ot-00 OS X [ - -i — — 1 us toooc3&lt;oaoeo CO C~ US 00 ■■«*• t^ t» •-i »-" N CO ■* rjt -fl" O 1-iONlOO 1 Hi i ; ; eg uC« ■ ■ • * * g E : : : &lt;n S &lt;t 8 n 01 k «r ®^ gcjcoTiIid&lt;et&gt; &lt; oo o I 3 E | | 5 | ! §ao c-i » s = o 00 X^iO^OO os o; t- rj — « S5 SS2 1 * 00 «C U5» OS — 00OS _ ___.,«,., 00 [-BrtM^fUJ i-i __ re -o^i^i 0 t-iflMUlO « — MNCC • '. '. • ■** ! '. ! . "3 . . . 1 =3-1 E : : : E E«"-S • a s t I a&gt; i a c ■ .» B . . . "° "° &gt;;5 • ' ■ 5s5l&amp;«| : Jh § 04 » us co t- </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Nebraska A&lt;;rhi i.ti rai. Exp. Station Resk Hi L. 10 ARl 11 i got. *=^ ■^ -*~ -•^ • o — &gt; Sts 63 1 ». Be I- 3 •I It I* 5.3 a* 8 B * C **S 3 &gt; O5 J 5^ gM*CO-«lO«l&gt; i- -3 g E ill's ! * S §£2 OO ° *» E 2 *&gt; ** w a s 1 I ti " -g II ? "S 1 -I I I - - ° TT: I ft. C I g c 1 I •tS eg «5 .a — — i- -. rii- x f a a^ I c — .2-3 2 g "S s 1 1{J ; ; 1 I isl: ■ a *^&gt; as si -^ £ a "Soo I is 33 O So I 1 a ■ p </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Freezing Injury of Seed Corn 69 t- I i s 35 ~*^ c s -- .£•? ££ L. -&lt; i &gt; ft 1 * J. •~^ I i :• -^ ■^ c j. z t- -a ■^ g 1^ S e "SiS "S . "9 teooiotooo u S 15 4 lo •S&lt;. N !* a K I » s i » B &gt; &gt; c &amp; I .»-§ •v. 3 « « * C o *» "3 I P "? OJ «t-Q« «* *3 N3 t3 w COCO -^"^"lOCO &amp;&gt; ° •Soo B : B : g : : : : : : ! h fa ri &gt; § 4 &lt;e oo 1-1 osoo - 00 00 (O IM &lt;M t- 31 TfioOO ! 00 t- 35 O t- O © 1 1 *&amp; 00 C^ C*J *~&lt; '- H I *"* X Tr-^o &lt;-i t- 00 00 •*" NNN^ ■»* -^» r*- as cji t- QO r-4 •-» NNN •II "rf : "8 :&gt;;:•§: $ 1? ■8dSlW15?^loJia i §J -g c ....•= </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Nebraska Acrkt i.ti ral Exp. Station Rbneabch Bul. 1(5 The freezing temperatures prevailing up to the time of the last selection — January 17, 1918 — are indicated in Tal&gt;le ;50. Table 30 — Duration, mean temperature, and minimum tempera - ture of freezing periods durint/ autumn and earlu winter (1917-1918) Mean Minimum Hours in period Date temperature temperature (degrees F.) (degrees F.) Oct. 8 9 27.7 24 Oct. 10 1 32.0 82 Oct. 11-12 11 26.8 23 Oct. 12-13 K 27.9 25 Oct. 18-19 l:S 23.8 is Oct. 20-21 5 31.2 31 Oct. 22-2:i 13 28.8 23 Oct. 24 •' 32.0 32 Oct. 26 5 31.0 30 Oct. 27 H 31.0 30 Oct. 28-30 45 25.2 25.2 17 Oct. 30-31 12 26.7 24 Oct. 31 -Nov. 1 12 27.8 26 Nov. 1-2 10 30.2 29 Nov 4 5 30.2 29 Nov, 18-19 14 26.1 21 Nov 28 10 28.1 24 Nov. 23-24 15 25.4 19 Nov 24-25 17 30.2 2^ Nov 26 2 32.0 82 Nov, 26-27 5 30.6 30 Nov 27-28 14 23.4 18 Nov. 29 3 32.0 32 Nov 30 9 28.7 26 Nov, 30-Dec. 1 10 28.1 28 Dec. 1-2 10 28.6 27 Dec 3 12 25.9 22 Dec. :i-4 14 20.1 22 Dec 4-16 290 5.6 -16 Dec. 17 3 31.7 31 Dec- 18 • • ....'.'.'. 5 30!6 30 Dec. 20-21 14 26.4 25 14 26.4 25 Dec. 21-22 14 27.0 20 Dec 24-26 61 17.6 12 Dec 26-Jan. 1 136 11.3 —18 Jan. 2-3 33 20.7 15 Jan. 3-4 16 29.1 25 Jan. 5-17 ...'.'.'.'.'. 290 7!o —23 At !&gt; o'clock A. M.. on October 8, following the heavy frost earlier in the morning, a thermometer inserted into the center of the cob of corn ears hanging naturally in the field recorded a </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Freezing Ixjiisy of Seed Cobn 71 temperature of 31.5° F. Thus the freezing temperature of this first freeze penetrated thru the husks to the center of the ear. The grain on the more immature ears was considerably frozen. The selection of the various samples, as described in Table 28, was based entirely upon the external appearance and feel of the ear. At each successive selection the corn was noticeably drier. However, each sample in the later selections was chosen as nearly as possible to duplicate the corn in the corresponding sample in the first selection. No attention was given to the appearance of the germ in selecting each sample. However, the germs were later examined for color, and the probable ger - mination was estimated, based upon the color of the germ. The data in Table 28 show that a fairly reliable estimate of viability may 1h&gt; made by an examination of the germ. The data in Table 20 indicates that most of the freezing injury to seed corn in the field in 1917 occurred between Oetol&gt;er 8 and November 1!&gt;. and that little injury occurred following this date. Altho much more severe freezing followed, the corn had dried out sufficiently to withstand it. In general, corn in the field which was sound on November 10. 1017. was also sound on Januarv 15, 1018. The vitality of grain containing more than 17 per cent of moisture on November 10 was so reduced by the temperatures which prevailed up to that date as to make it unreliable for seed purposes. On the other hand, the driest grade standing in the field, and that from the shocked corn, was not injured seriously, giving germination tests of 86, and 88 per cent per - fect germination respectively, tho exposed to all the low tem - peratures prior to January 17. On this date, the field from which the various selections reported in Tables 28 and 20 were made tested 31 per cent germination, field-run. CONDITION OF CORN IN CRIBS ON JANUARY 26. 191$ The condition of corn in three Lancaster County eorncribs was investigated on January 26, 1018. These cribs contained Reid*s Yellow Dent. Chase's White Dent and St. Charles* White Dent corn. The crib-run tests of these cribs were 4."&gt;. 39, and 26 per cent germination respectively. The corresponding tests of seed selected because of the sound outward appearance of the ears were 80. 80. and 00 per cent germination. It was estimated that to select 1 bushel of these grades of corn from each of these cribs required 80. 100. and 1+0 minutes resj)ectivelv for one man. All these tests could doubtless have l&gt;een improved by further testing and elimination of the inferior ears. Seven, </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Nebraska Agricixti ral Exp. Station Research Bil. 16 six, and three per cent of the corn in the respective cribs were selected for the above grades. THE DANGER LINE OF FREEZING INJURY An approximate safety zone free from freezing injury may be established for seed corn differing in moisture content. The combinations of low temperature and freezing duration which seed corn will withstand as indicated in Fig. 13, are constructed from the various tests reported in this bulletin and should be regarded as approximate rather than absolute. They set forth the probable duration of a given low temperature which corn of given moisture content will withstand without injury. A slight lowering of the temperature or a longer duration of the exposure may initiate a reduction in the per cent germination but will not prove entirely fatal. Greater fatalitv will result as the adverse factors are extended. It will be noted that in general an extension of the time of exposure is comparatively as dangerous as is the lowering of the temperature, until the moisture content in the grain is reduced to nearly 20 per cent where it manifests a decidedly greater resistance to the duration of exposure. A still more marked proportional resistance to the duration of exposure is shown by corn containing as low as 17 per cent moisture. When air-dry, containing 14 per cent or less of moisture, corn will endure any natural low winter temperature for any length of time. OCCURRENCE OF AUTUMN FROSTS IN NEBRASKA The dates for the first autumn frosts occur with great irregularity in Nebraska. As extremes for Lincoln, Nebr.. dur - ing the last 21 years, the first killing frost occurred in 1902 on September 12, and in 1914 on October 27. As seen in Table 31 the dates of the first killing frost and the first dates with a record - ed freezing temperature or 32° F.or lower do not always coincide. This is due to the fact that the Weather Bureau temperatures are obtained at a considerable distance above the ground, where the temperature does not always drop quite so low as it does nearer the surface. The average date of the first killing frost at Lincoln during the past 21 years has been October 12. Table 31 gives the duration of the first freezing temperature together with the mean and minimum temperatures of the period, during the last 21 years at Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Freezing In.iiry of Seed Corn 73 su </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Nebraska Aurici i.tiral Exp. Station* Reskakch Ri*l. 1(&gt; Table 31 — Date* of the frst killing frost and of the fiixt freez- Iimj temperatures at Lincoln. Nebr., during 21 years, 1897 to 1917 i i Date of First date with Duration Mean Minimum Year first killing temperature of of freezing temperature temperature frost 32 °F. or below temperature during period during period (Hours) (Degrees F.) (Degrees F.) 1897 Oct. 29 Nov. 2 10 30.0 29 1898 Oct. 6 Oct. 6 3 31.7 31 1899 Sept. 29 Sept. 29 7 29.3 27 1900 Oct. 17 Nov. 8 14 26.3 21 1901 Sept. 18 Sept. 18 3 31.7 31 1902 Sept. 12 Oct. 28 6 30.5 29 1903 Oct. 27 Oct. 27 3 31.7 31 1904 Oct. 25 Oct. 25 3 31.7 31 1905 Oct. 20 Oct. 20 7 31.0 30 1906 Oct. 10 Oct. 10 10 29.5 26 1907 Oct. 12 Oct. 12 4 31.0 30 1908 Oct. 11 Nov. 2 5 31.0 30 1909 Oct. 12 Oct. 12 16 28.0 21 1910 Oct. 22 Oct. 27 12 29.0 26 1911 Oct. 20 i Nov. 1,2 and 3 58 23.6 12 1912 Sept. 30 Oct. 22 6 31.3 30 1913 Oct. 20 Oct. 20 14 27.0 23 1914 Oct. 27 Oct. 27 13 28.0 24 1915 Oct. 9 Oct.- 9 3 31.3 30 1916 Sept. 29 Sept. 29 5 31.0 30 1917 Oct. 8 Oct. 8 9 27.7 24 Av'ge Av'ge Oct. 12 Oct. 18 10 29.6 27 Oct. 12 Oct. 18 10 8BPT.S6 r* »AMA &lt;J_« |0 * w f • R ■ • I siqwx lHt«OA« o m 7 * C1D*« /I DC. M • V f • OX ■ WTTl '!«■« ...Si Foe* i tlilT OOIII 7 •LttNt &gt;u' \z y\ K • COTT-» •U«T&lt; -rlocT.e C.dMN •OONC •A&lt;Mf* H«PHCR»ON .-H «U« Xf )DOC ITU .••«, ■ ■■•All. C HCV- [NN( DIUtU ft I I T N Lr z *ou lUTl in 7 Oil " • AW (O M lUFf , N * U •o kcwA«o 8EPT.: (Mil ..... flOITlfl 0 / *OAU» ki&lt; 5^ •ALINt 9TOI -— i ..... S^ I no 7^ "7 H/" C«Gl MMII OCT. 1 OCT. » Fig. 14- -Average date of the first killing frost in autumn. By G. A. Lovi </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Freezing Injury or Seed Cons 75 This variation in time of freezing westher together with a great seasonal variation in time of corn maturity has a marked bearing in different years upon the condition of corn for seed when left standing in the field. The average dates of the first killing frost in the field in the fall for various parts of Nebraska are given in Figure 14. FREEZING INJURY INEVITABLE IN OCCASIONAL YEARS Experience has taught that the Im'M adapted, highest pro - ducing corn for any locality in Nebraska, or in the greater part of the Corn Belt, does not mature and dry sufficiently in all seasons to escape freezing injury when left exposed to low tem - peratures either in the field or in the crib. It would not be practicable in most of the Corn Belt to grow corn sufficiently early to escape damage from freezing every year, because such corn would be too small and early to give best results. The best adapted and most productive types apj&gt;ear to be those which utili ■ • practically the entire growing season of the aver - age year. In the majority of years, such tvjies should ripen fully before the fir&gt;t killing frost, altho in occasional years both the yield and the quality may be reduced by autumn frosts. Seasonal variation in the time of maturity of a given corn in a given locality may l&gt;e illustrated by the relative maturity of Hogne's Yellow Dent corn at the Experiment Station in 1914 and 1917. This is a standard well-adapted type for con - ditions prevailing at the Experiment Station. In 1914 the grain, of this corn contained only 14 per cent moisture on October 1, while it contained 38 per cent on October 1, 191". It was well matured on September 0&gt;. 1914. whereas it was not so mature a month later in 1917. In this vicinity the normal date of ripen - ing for this variety is September 20, while the mean date of the first killing frost is October 11. According to this, corn which is unsurpassed in average production at the Experiment Station ripens, as pn average, about 3 weeks before the mean date of the first killing frost. This seasonal variation makes possible in many vears the growing of late maturing tvp;'s of corn in localities where thev normally are not adapted. But the character of the season and the date of the first killing frost cannot be foretold at plant - ing time. Therefore, nnidapted, late motoring types which do not reach their full development before the average date of the first killing frost should not be grown. They require for their full development the exceptional seasons in which the first killing frost comes very late. In too great a proportion of thb </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station Rheakch Bcl. 16 seasons they fail to mature, and too frequently produce an inferior quality of corn together with a low yield of grain per acre. SELECTION FOR EARLINESS Wherever varieties of too late maturity aiv b?ing grown, this may he overcome in several ways: (1) Securing seed of some earlier type. This may originate in the same_locality or be of some previously tried variety obtained from a distance. Before a new corn is extensively substituted for an old one, definite knowledge should l)e had regarding its local adaptation. (2) Field selection of seed from the earlier maturing plants before autumn frosts, while such difference is readily discernible. (3) Selection of the drier and more mature ears later in the season. To a considerable extent, such ears are more mature because of inherent relative earliness. Corn mav lie made to average a week or ten days earlier in maturity in a very few years by such selection. It is probable that most of the corn grown in Nebraska could l&gt;e made a week earlier without reduc - ing the average yield, and the quality would be improved. A rather arbitrary ideal of deep rough grain is held by many corn growers. This qualitv is usually associated with late maturity and also high shelling percentage. A mistaken conception prevails that high shelling percentage means high acre yield. To the contrary, corn with a rather medium depth kernel yields fully as much grain per acre, ripens somewhat earlier, is often of much better quality and frequently possesses stronger viability. ALTERNATIVES IN SEED SELECTION (1) Special, early field selection, before any likelihood of frost, may be practiced regularly each year. When such corn is stored and cured in a dry. well-ventilated place, good ger - mination without further trouble is reasonably certain. This procedure, systematically insures sound seed corn. An essential requirement in this practice is to avoid immediate contact be - tween the different ears so long as they are not well dried out. Thus mould and decay will be prevented. By going thru the field with a sack hung over the shoulder, or other simple device, the best developed and most matured ears may be readily gathered. Seed selected in the stiff dough stage is sufficintly mature to produce strong, vigorous plants. However, more mature seed is more ecsily preserved. (2) Selecting seed late in Septemlier or early in October, while husking corn in the regular way for early hog feed, is a safe </seg>
            <seg id="p077">FkEEZINU Ix.JIRY OF SkK!) CoItX 77 and convenient manner of obtaining sound seed corn. Precau - tion should be taken to insure rapid drying and avoidance of mould. This procedure usually requires some busking Itefore the hulk of the corn is sufficiently dry for genera) husking. The necessary seed for the average farm may usually be selected from several loads of this earlv husked corn. If this plan is systematically followed, a supply of sound corn may l&gt;e fairly certain year after year. (3) Selecting seed at the time of general kusking is the most common of all methods. Either h box is attached to the side of the wagon into which the seed ears are thrown while husking, or else the seed ears are selected from the wagon while unloading. This method, and particularly the practice of pick - ing the se«d ears in the field while husking, has many com - mendable features in years of early maturity when a large percentage of the ears will possess strong germination even when left exposed in the field to severe freezing weather. In other years, such as 15)11. 1915, and 101". there may be such a small portion of viable ears after subjection to freezing weather, that much annoyance and difficulty is experienced in selecting them. If necessary to select seed ears from a field where freezing injury has been severe, the rather slender, hard, solid, smooth ears with relatively shallow grains (Fig. 15) will l&gt;e found most certain to give satisfactory germination. For those who do not favor this type of ear. it may l&gt;e said that it is likely to yield fully as much grain to the acre as the larger, rougher types, even in years when both give equally good germination. Severe freezing destroys the viability of immature seed. This is a factor in the natural adaptation of the crop. It tends to eliminate the later strains, while the earlier ones survive. Uy selecting the ears, therefore, which have withstood severe freezing in the field, more consistent earliness is developed. (4) Corncrib selection may l)e practiced in an emergency as a last resort. Tf provision for a seed supply by other methods has been overlooked, well matured and sound seed ears may in most years be selected from the crib during the winter or spring. Such home grown seed is to be recommended in preference to imported seed whose adaptability is not definitely known. (5) Old Reed. In order to insure against emergencies, it is a desirable practice to select sufficient se°d in years when corn matures well for two years' planting. It seldom happens that two successive bad years occur, and by this practice much un - easiness and annoyance mav be avoided in bad years. One-year- </seg>
            <seg id="p078">8 Nebraska Aokkvltiral Exp. Station Rbbeaich Hi k. 1(&gt; 78 Fig. 15 — Standard and smooth ear types of Hogue's Yellow Dent corn. This smooth ear with kernels of only medium depth may be relied upon as the soundest seed in such crops as grown in 1911, 1915, and 1917. It also yields fully as well. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Freezing Ixjiry of Seed Corn 79 old seed corn is entirely satisfactory if it has been well pre - served. COMBINATION OF METHODS FOR SELECTING SEED For many farm operations, the procedure may be variable from year to year according to the seasonal conditions, or the individual farmer's fancy or convenience. This holds true in regard to the time and manner of selecting the seed corn supply. The conditions are very exceptional in which a satisfactory set'd supply with apparently equal productivity cannot be selected by any one of the first three methods just descriU'd. The relative convenience and practicability of the methods may vary from year to year. In years when corn is backward, it is good prac - tice to select seed from corn husked early, before heavy and continued freezes are to l)e expected. In years of early maturity, when corn is well dried out. it may be quite as well to pick the seed ears at the time of regular husking. Whether special early selection is practised in such years may be left entirely to the convenience of the farmer. However, in years when corn is late in maturing, early selection and preservation of seed corn may avoid the great annoyance of sorting over a large quantity of corn for the small percentage of sound ears that will give satisfactory germination. Early selection is probably of greater importance in the northwestern half, than in the southeastern half of the State. ASCERTAINING VIABILITY After the seed ears are thoroly cured, a general germination test may l&gt;e made of a composite sample of kernels taken scat - teringly from each of several hundred ears at the rate of about six kernels per ear. If less than about 00 per cent perfect ger - mination is obtained, t more severe elimination of unsound ears should l&gt;e made. Discarding all ears with discolored germs and the making of an individual ear germination test are rather effective methods. The making of such tests is generally under - stood by farmers. If germination tests are made, care must be taken to provide proper germinative conditions, in order that misleading results may not be secured. The most reliable general test may be made by planting the seed in a box of soil. The number of seeds actually producing plants may thus l&gt;e ascertained. If the tests are made between moist blotters, cloths, or by any other similar device, the kernels, after sprouting, may easily be exposed and the germination counted. With well-matured seed, only strong, vigorous sprouts </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station Research Hi l. 1G Fig 16 — A final germination test should be made to definitely determine what percentage of the seed will grow. The corn planter may then be adjusted for an average drop of the desired number of kernels Pig. 17 — The individual ear germination test shows definitely which are the unsound ears </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Freezing Ix.ii ry ok Seed Corn 81 are obtained. Where less mature corn has been subjected to severe freezing, as high as 10 or 15 per cent may germinate imperfectly. Such seed may have either the plumule or the primary root killed, while the other end of the sprout may develop normally. If the plumule has been killed a viable root can never grow a new plumule. But if the primary root only is dead, the secondary roots may, under favorable ger - mination conditions, develop at the base of the plumule and a normal plant result. Such imperfect sprouts may Ik&gt; seen in Figure 20. Germination tests are often reported as so many strong, weak, or dead kernels. It would probably be quite as well to report perfect and imperfect germination and dead kernels. Since proper development of imperfect germs is doubtful, a classification into perfect and dead seed should suffice. Perfect kernels reported as weak are often relatively backward merely because of inherent slower germination or because of unum - form. unfavorable germinating conditions which act as sources of experimental error in testing. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">Nebraska Acjrici i.tirai. Exp. Station Rbnlakch Bex. 1&lt;&gt; 82 Fig. 18 — Germination box filled with sawdust and covered with burlap to retain moisture Fig. 19 — The germination box shown in Figure 18, uncovered. Note the much more vigorous growth at the ends of the box where the burlap was folded back and greater pressure exerted by the box standing on top. The germinative ability of the corn at the center actually equalled that at the ends. This illustrates possible experi - mental error in testing for germination </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 Freezing Ix.ii kv or Seed C&lt;wx Fig. 20 — Kernels showing various degrees of relative germinative ability (1) Perfect germination; (2) imperfect germination; (3) dead kernels </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Xkmeask a A(iRi&lt; i i.ti kai. Exp. Station Ukseakch Bru 16 84 RELATIVE CORN YIELDS FOR THE STATE OF NEBRASKA IN YEARS FOLLOWING SEVERE SEED CORN INJURY The average yield of corn for the State of Nebraska during the last 18 years. 18110 to 1D17. as estimated by the Bureau of Crop Statistics and the State Board of Agriculture, has been 24.9 bushels per acre. During this period, there have been three years of serious seed corn injury, namely 1806. 1011. and 1915. The acre corn yields for the State in the years following this seed corn injury (years in which the affected seed was planted) were respectively 30.0. 27.1, and 3±&lt;&gt; bushels. Since the yield has l&gt;een al&gt;ove normal each year in which it was necessary to plant seed selected from corn undergoing severe winter injury, it is evident that the formers meet the situation in a fairly satisfactory manner. The average superiority of these three years aliove the % &gt;H year average has l&gt;een 5.0 bushels per acre. Therefore predictions of low yields following years of severe seed corn injury do not seem justified. The actual increase in yields is probably due to accidentally more favorable climatic and moisture conditions. EFFECT OF TIME OF SELECTION AND PRESERVATION OF SEED CORN UPON YIELD An experiment whs begun in the fall of 1914 to determine the effect of the time of harvesting Heed corn upon its yielding power provided rare is taken in selection to obtain equally high germination. A comparative yield test was made in 1915 of September, November, and March selections from a field of Nebraska White Prize coin. This is a standard variety grown at the Experiment Station and adapted to southeastern Nebraska. A similar test was made in 1916 and 1917 of seed selected in Septemlier. October, November. Decenilier, February, and March. The md was carefully preserved in a dry. well-ventilated place after l)eing harvested. After danger from freezing injury, only seed ears which showed a bright clear germ were taken. Ears with discolored germs were discarded because they promised low germination. A large number of ears were composited for each selection. Four systematically replicated 3-row plats were planted from all selections each year. The rows were 7'2 hills long with hills 44 inches apart. Six kernels were space planted by hand in each hill. The stand was reduced by thinning to 3 plants per hill after growing alnwt 2 weeks. This insured practically a full and uniform stand. The first fifty hills having 3 plants, and surrounded bv a full stand were harvested from the center </seg>
            <seg id="p085">FUEEZING Ix.HKY OK SkKI) CtllN 85 row of each plut for the yield test. Tliis arrangement permitted a direct comparison of the inherent yielding capacity of the different lots. The results follow in Table 3:2. Table 8 - 2 — Relatire yield* of need corn selected at variant dates during the fall mid winter (1915-1917) Yield per acre Date of seed D " pl j ca - selection 1 t{ ? m Averagp Three each year 1915 1916 1917 1916 and year 1917 average 'The seed was harvested about the 1'ith of each month. check seed Wai harvested from the same field while husking in November. As an average for the three years 1915-1917, seed corn har - vested bv special selection from the Held in September. Xovem - l)er, and March, and given good care after selection, yielded respectively 4s.-_&gt;. 49.H. and 51.2 bushels per acre, while seed saved from the same Held during the rejjuhtr process of husking; in November yielded 50.fi bushels per acre. We may conclude from these data that corn harvested early and given, special care in preservation will not outyield seed which has bw»n ex - posed to the cold of winter without s(&gt;ecial care, provided l&gt;oth are selected for hijrh jrenni native qualities. Seed which has received no s|&gt;ecial earlv selection and preservation may be expected to yield as well as specially cared for seed, provided equally satisfactory stands are obtained. Xo claim is made, however, that seed nelectsd late in winter will necessarily •Terminate as dependably as will that gathered earlier. RELATIVE YIELDS OF DIFFERENT EAR TYPES During the four years 1SM + to li&gt;17. four ear types of Nebraska AVhite Prize corn have been compared in yield with the original undetected corn from which the types were selected September October November December. February .... March 4 4 4 4 4 4 Bushelx 66.6 65.9 64.7 Bushel* 36.1 36.9 37.3 39.3 44.3 42.1 Bushelx 38.3 38.3 41.6 42.4 41.7 42.6 Bushel* 37.2 37.6 39.4 40.8 43.0 42.3 '.-■ Bushels 47.0 48.3 49.8 Check' i 4 66.3 40.3 41.1 40.7 49.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Xkkka.ska A&lt;;ki&lt; ri/ri uai. Exp. Station Hkskaih ii IU x. 10 each year. This variety has been {frown lit the Experimental Station many years. The method of testing was the same as that descril)ed on paj;e 84. Basinjr the yields upon equal num - bers of plants vrown under uniform conditions enabled a fairly reliable test of the relative inherent yielding qualities. The results are given in Table 33. Table 33 — Yield per acre from different ear types of Nebraska White Prize corn (19H-1917) Fig. 21 — Rough ear and long, slender, smooth ear of Nebraska White Prize corn. At the Experiment Station on an average for four years, the rough type has yielded 51.4 bushels, compared with 58.8 bushels for the smooth type Type of ear &gt;riginal 1914 Bushels 48.7 1915 Bushels 64.8 1916 Bushels 65.5 1917 Bushels 53.5 Average Bushels 58.1 large rough Ihort rough ihort smooth ,ong slender smooth 30.0 44.4 45.0 48.7 65.3 68.9 72.6 66.4 64.4 65.1 60.1 65.2 45.9 49.9 49.2 54.9 51.4 57.1 56.7 58.8 i umber of duplications 6 8 14 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Freezing Ix.ii ky of Seed Corn 87 As an averagp for the four years, the long, slender, smooth type yielded iiS.H bushels per acre, which is 0.7 bushel more than the original corn. 7.4 bushels more than the lar&lt;re rou&lt;rh ears. 1.7 bushels nmr 1 than the short rough ears, and 2.1 bushels more tliiin the short, smooth ears. One may conclude that this long, -lender, smooth sype possesses highly satisfactory yielding qualities which, coupled with its superior germinative ability. make* il n verv suitable type to grow. This type of ear is gaining greater popularity among corn men of the State, altho the old prejudice for dee]) rough ears with a hi&lt;rh shelling per - centage has been rather persistent. EFFECT OF UNUNIFORM STAND ON YIELD Aii investigation was made in 1J)15 and 1916 to determine the effect of varied distribution of plants upon the yield of corn. The number of plants per acre was the same in all cih'&gt;. but the number of plants in adjacent hills differed. The pur - pose was twofold: (\) To learn the effect of variation in stand caused by mechanical variation in dropping by corn planters, when corn with perfect germination is planted. (2) To learn what result mi&lt;rht be expected from planting corn, only part of which will grow, but for which the rate of planting has been calculated to &lt;eed the desired number of sound kernels per acre. The tests were made in duplicate 5-row blocks and equal num - bers of each type of hill wer? harvested within each plat. The methods of distribution compared wen (1) All hills with uniformly -\ plants. rj) Alternating hills with •_' and 4 plants. {'A) Alternating hills with 1. -\. and 5 plant (4) Alternating hills with 1. -2. 3. 4. and 5 plants. The re~ult&gt; are given in Table - y A. The average yield for the thret ompared with uniform distribution (1915 and 1916) Table •&gt;! — Effect of varied distribution &lt;&gt;f plants in plitntinij Plants per hill Y fie] ;ld per acre 1915 1916 Average Unif onr ly 3 plan's Alternating 2 and 4 plants Alternating 1, 3 and 5 plants Alternating 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 plants Bushels 93.4 89.8 88.0 95.1 Bushels 55.2 58.4 52.4 54.4 Bushels 74.3 74.2 70.2 74.7 Ave*»ge for varied distribution . . . 91.0 55.1 73.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">Nebraska A&lt;;rhtltvral Exp. Station Kkskaucii Bex. 1&lt;&gt; 88 varied distributions whs 73.0 bushels compared with 74.8 bushels for the uniform planting rate of 3 plants per hill. A uniform stand of 3 plants per hill yielded 1.8 jier cent more than the mean for the various distributions. Variations in stand due to the planter, or to the presence of dead seed in corn testing as low us 75 per c?nt. is less marked than the variations in the al&gt;ove special plantings. The data in Table 34 aiv substantiated by a very similar experuntftt conducted by Montgomery in 1007 and 1008. the results of which are given in Table 35. The average yield of the varied distributions in this test was ±1 per cent lower than a uniform distribution of three kernels. Table 35 — Effect of varied distribution of need in planting compared with uniform distribution (1907 and 1908)* •Data In Table 35 taken from Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 112. by E. G. Montgomery. EFFECT OF IMPERFECT HILLS IN CHECKED CORN The data in Tables 3&lt;&gt; and 37 show how the crop adjusts itself for missing plants in an otherwise uniform stand. Dur - ing the two years, 1014 and 1017. a rather large number of corn hills containing either 1. 2, 3 or no corn plants were scattered systematically thruout a field of checked corn other - wise containing 3 plants per hill. By harvesting the hills separately, the effect of hills containing 1. 2, or no plants upon hills with the normal number of 3 plants could be determined. Also the relative yields of hills containing 1. 2. or 3 plants when surrounded uniformly by 3-plant hills could be determined. Grains planted per hill riraiie nlantf^H nvr Vi i 1 Yield per acre uraos piantea per nu 1907 1908 Average Fnif ormly 3 grains .lternating 2 and 4 grains .lternating 1, 3 and 5 grains .... .lternating 1 and 5 grains Uniformly 3 grains lternating 2 and 4 grains . . . . .lternating 1, 3 and 5 grains . .lternating 1 and 5 grains .... Bushels Bushels ' Bushels 71.2 58.9 65.5 70.4 56.9 63.6 70.7 60.1 65.4 64.5 60.6 62.6 .verage for varied distribution . 68.5 59.2 63.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">FlEEZIXG Ix.Il KY OK SeED C KX 89 Table 3&lt;i — It el tit id- yields of one, two, ov three- phi nt corn hills when uniformly surrounded In/ three-plant hitts. Xehrnska White Prize corn (1914 find' 1917) Number of plants in Total Number Average grain yield per hill hills surrounded by number hills of ears per uniform 3-plant hills averaged 100 plants Actual Relative Table 37 — Relative yields of three-plant corn hills when adja - cent to hillx with rnridiix numbers of plants. Aceraye for WU and 1917 Three-plant hills Total Number Number Average grain yield surrounded by 3-plant number of of ears per hill per hill hills except as hills plants per 100 indicated below averaged per hill plants Actual Relative As an average for the two years, the two-plant hills yielded 18 per cent less than a three-plant hill, but each of four adja - cent three-plant hills yielded •! per cent more, due to the one missing plant. By adjacent hills, in this discussion, is meant the 4 surrounding hills in rows at right angles to each other and designated in the diagram l&gt;elow as 1. 2. 3, and 4. ills with 3 plants 'ills with 2 plants ills with 1 plant 598 120 80 S9 99 141 J ounds 1.073 0.883 0.656 100 82 61 iurrounded by hills with 3 plants idjacent to 1 hill with 2 plants idjacent to 1 hill with one plant Ldjacent to 1 blank hill 598 360 302 366 3 3 3 3 89 91 94 94 Pounds 1.075 1.098 1.151 1.224 100 102 107 114 i z </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 Xkhraska AciRici i.ti it.vi. Exp. Station Rkskaih h Bt'L. K'&gt; A one-plant hill yielded 39 jkt &lt;;&gt;nt less than a three-plant hill, but on account of the two missing plants the yield of each of the four adjacent three-plant hills was increased 7 |&gt;er cent thus recovering nearly three-fourths of the loss. A no-plant hill yielded nothing, but each adjacent three - plant hill yielded 14 per cent more due to the three missing plants. To sum up. — 50 per cent of the yield lost in a hill with one missing plant was recovered in the four nearest adjacent hills; 72 per cent of what was lost in a hill with two missing plants was recovered in the four nearest hills: 56 per cent of what was lost in a hill with no plants was recovered in the four neareset adjacent hills. While our experimental data show the effect of incomplete hills upon only the 4 nearest adjacent hills located at right angles, it is quite likely that the recovery extends at least to and possibly beyond the 4 nearest diagonal hills also indicated in the diagram at 5. (!. 7. and 8. The fact that the yield is not greatly reduced by an un - uniform distribution of the plants (within reasonable limits) may be explained by the large feeding area of the roots of a corn plant. A corn hill is not limited to its own '.) feet 8 inches of land, but mav laterally draw considerably beyond its adjacent neighboring hills for water and plant food material. Since these materials are usually limiting factors, a relatively greater abundance made available by one or more missing plants goes to increase the yields of other plants. If a hill with one or two missing plants was partly sur - rounded by hills containing only a partial stand, it would not be reduced in yield to the same degree as when fully surrounded by 3-plnut hills, because the competition would not l)e so large. PROBABLE DISTRIBUTION OF PLANTS WHEN SEED OF LOW GERMINATION IS PLANTED Every farmer has in mind some rather definite spacing of plants in the field which he regards as an optimum planting rate for his locality in the average year. Various experiments have indicated that there may lie some variation in the planting rate without a material effect upon the yield. Rather than to procure imported, unadapted seed with perfect germination in years of seed corn injury, locally grown adapted seed testing as low as 75 per cent, or 65 per cent should be used if sounder seed cannot be selected. When the test is </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Pkeezixu Injtry &lt;»f Seed ('&lt; its 91 Table 38 — Shtt-iring chance distribution of plant* irhi-n seed (jeitni)ltlti)i&lt;l ?■&gt;, (/•'). inn/ 50 per rent is p/dntid in liills 44 inchen upnvt Where corn germinates 75 per cent and 4 kernels are dropped per hill Where corn germinates 65 per cent and 4 kernels are dropped per hill Per cent such hills Total number such Seed dropped per hill hills per acre 4 sound 17.845 38.455 31.059 11.144 5T.s 3 sound, 1 dead 2 sound, 2 dead 1 sound, 3 dead 4 dead 1,246 1,007 361 1.499 4!' Total 100.(100 3,241 Where corn germinates 50 per cent and 5 kernels are dropped per hill Total number such Seed dropped per hill Per cent such hills hills per acre 5 sound 3.122 101 4 sound, 1 dead 3 sound, 2 dead 2 sound, 3 dead 1 sound, 4 dead 5 dead 15.622 506 31.256 1,013 1,013 31.256 15.622 506 3.122 101 Total 100.000 3,240 Seed dropped per hill Per cent such hills Total number suci hills per acre 4 sound 3 sound, 1 dead 2 sound, 2 dead 1 sound, 3 dead 4 dead 31.588 42.258 21.105 4.664 0.385 1 .H24 1,370 684 151 100.000 3,241 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Nebraska A«W ■ 1 ■ 1 ■ 1 1 Kxp. Station Reseam h Bi'L. 16 below 85 an allowanc* should be made for the dead seed in the rate of planting. By using partially unsound seed, a uniform stand cannot be obtained. But it has been shown that absolute uniformity is not necessary for maximum yields. An application of the law of chance (Table 38) shows how the sound kernels will be dis - tributed when seed testing 75 per cent. 6S per cent, and 50 percent is used with an approximate adjustment in the planting rate to compensate for the reduced germination. The chance combinations of sound and dead seed ]&gt;er hill in Table 38. are calculated from the following formula: The probability of dropping p sound kernels and q dead kernels from a composite sample containing m sound kernels and n dead kernels is: Acknowledgment is made to Prof. Carl EngberS, for supplying this formula. For purpose of illustration, it will 1k&gt; assumed that approxi - mately the rate of three sound kernels per hill is desired. The hills are spaced 44 inches apart. An acre contains 3.241 such hills. DISTRIBUTION OF SOUND KERNELS WHEN SEED TESTS 75 PER CENT If the corn tests 75 per cent and a stand of 3 plants per hill is desired, then 4 kernels should 1h&gt; planted per hill. The average hill will cont-tin three sound and one dead kernel, but they will not l)e uniformly distributed. On the other hand, 31.fi, 42.3. 21.1. 4.6. and 0.4 per cent of the hills will contain 4, 3. 2, 1, and no plants respectively. In an acre with 3.241 hills there will lie 1.024 hills with 4 plants. 1,370 hills with 3 plants, 684 hills with 2 plants. 151 hills with 1 plant, and 12 hills with - out plants. Results almost identical with the al&gt;ove calculation were obtained in an actual test with 1.500 hills, each of which con - tained 4 kernels taken at random. In this test 31.3. 41.fi, 22.7. 4.1 and 0.13 per cent of the hills contained respectively 4. 3. 2. 1, and no plants as compared with 31.6. 42.3. 21.1. 4.6. and 0.4 per cent for chance calculations. For purposes of this study, the dead kernels were white and the sound kernels were yellow, which per- m ' (in + n — p — q) ' /&lt; ' (/&gt; + ({) ' where (m—p)&gt; (»&lt; + »)' fn—q) 1 p' q' tn ' = Di (in — 1 ) (m — J) (m — 3) 3, J. 1 = product of ill intergers from 1 to m. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Freezing Injury of Seed C'cux </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 Nebraska Agrici i.ti-rai. Exp. Station Research Btx. 10 mitted correct separation. Figure 21 shows how these hills ar - ranged themselves by chance in 2."&gt; rows of *&gt;0 hills each. It is understood that this and the two following examples are illustrative and would be varied somewhat in farm practice for the reason that a planter cannot lie set to always drop a uniform number of kernels per hill. DISTRIBUTION OF SOUND KERNELS WHEN SEED TESTS 65 PER CENT If corn testing 05 per cent germination is planted at the rate of 4 kernels per hill, then 17.8. 38.5. 81.1, 11.1, and 1 5 per cent of the hills respectively will have 4. 8, 2, 1, and no plants. An acre containing 3.241 hills will have 578 hills with 4 plants, 1,240 hills with 3 plants. 1.007 hills with 2 plants. 301 hills with 1 plant, and 40 hills with no plants. The no-plant and one - plant hills are likely to be distributed ambng the others in such manner that little reduced yield per acre need be expected. By planting seed with a viability of 05 per cent at the rate of 4 per hill. 87 per cent as many plants per acre should be expected as when 75 per cent viable seed is planted at the same rate. DISTRIBUTION OF SOUND KERNELS WHEN SEED TESTS 50 PER CENT If corn is planted 5 kernels per hill, only half of which will grow, an acre will contain 101 hills with 5 plants, 504) hills with 4 plants. 1.013 hills with 3 plants. 1,013 hills with -2 plants. 500 hills with 1 plant, and 101 hills with no plants. The average rate per hill for such planting is 2*4 sound kernels. The yield to be expected from such a distribution of plants should l)e fairly satisfactory. However, there seems little need for planting corn with so low a test. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Freezing Injury or Seed Corn 95 LITERATURE CITED Adams, J. 1905. The effect of very low temperatures on moist seeds. (Sci. Proc. Roy. Dublin Soc, n.s., 11. No. 1, p. !&gt;.... 22, 2 iEt CJl'EREL, P. 1905. Action de l'air liquide sur la vie de la grainr. (Compt. Rend. Acad. Sci. Paris, 140, No. 2.'&gt;, i&gt;i&gt;. 1652-1654) 24 190"&gt;. Action de l'air liquide sur la vie de la graine. (Compt. Rend. Acad. Sci. Paris, 140, No. 25, pp. 16. r )2-1654) 24 Bbown, H. T. and Escomhe, F. 5i:o\v\, H. T. and Escombe, F. 1897-8. The influence of very low temperatures on the germina - tive power of seeds. ( Proc. Royal Soc., No. 62 p. 160) . . . .2-',, 26 1897-8. The influence of very low temperatures on the germina- tive power of seeds. ( Proc. Royal Soc, No. 62 p. 160) . . . .2.',, 2t Chan in eb, W. H. 2HANDI KK, W. H. 1913. The killing of plant tissues by low temperatures. (I'ni. Mo. Research Bui. 8 ) 22, 2."), 27 191:5. The killing of plant tissues by low temperatures. ( Tni Mo. Research Bui. 8) 22, •'&gt;. 'IT, Detmer. W. Dkt.mkii. W. 189:5. The influence of moisture, temperature, and light on tht - process of germination. ( l T . S. Dept. Agri. Weather Bureau Bui. 11, p. 2. Rept. Internat. Meteorolog. Congress pt. 2, p. 414) 22, 24, 26 189:5. The influence of moisture, temperature, and light on the process of germination. ( U. S. Dept. Agri. Weather Bureau Bui. 11, p. 2. Rept. Internat. Meteorolog. Congress pt. 2, DrHAMKi. and Burros 1737. Observations des differents effects que produisent sur les vegeteux les grandes gelees d'hiver et petites gelees du printemps. (Mem. d. l'Acad. Roy. Sci. Paris, 1737 p. 237) 21 DiHamki. and Bikkox 17:57. Observations des differents effects que produisent sur les vegeteux les grandes gelees d'hiver et petites gelees du printemps. (Mem. d. l'Acad. Roy. Sci. Paris, 1737 p. 2:57) 21 Ewaht, A. J. 1897. On the power of withstanding desiccation in plants. (Prac. Liverpool Biol. Soc. XI, pp. 151-159) 24,27 Ewaht, A. J. 1897. On the power of withstanding desiccation in plants. (Prac. Liverpool Biol. Soc. XI, pp. 151-159) 24, •' . Galloway, B. T. 1895. Frosts and freezes as affecting cultivated plants. ( I'. S. Dept. Agri. Yearbook 1 895, p. 143 ) 23, 24 Galloway, B. T 1895. Frosts and freezes as affecting cultivated plants. ( r. S. Dept. Agri. Yearbook 1 895, p. 143 ) 23, 24 Gassnkk, G., and Ghimme, C. 1913. Beitrage zur Frage der FrosthJirte der Getreidepflanzen. ( Ber. Deut. Bot. Gesell., 31 No. 8, pp. 507-516) 22 Gassnkk, G., and Giiimmk, C. 1913. Beitrage zur Frage der FrosthJirte der Getreidepflanzen ( Ber. Deut. Bot. Gesell., 31 No. 8, pp. 507-516) ■&gt;. Gkoi'K.kt, J. H. R. 1830. I'ber die Warme-entweekelung in den Pflanien; deren Gefrieren und die Schutzmittel gegen dasselbe. ( Breslau, J. Max und conip., 272 p.) 21, 2-', Gkoi'K.kt, J. H. R. 1830. l T ber die Warme-entweekelung in den Pflanzen; deren Gefrieren und die Schutzmittel gegen dasselbe. ( Breslau, J. Max und comp., 272 p.) 21 &gt; Gokkk, H. 1906. I'ber Chemische vorgange beim Erfrieren der Pflanzen. ( Landw. Versuchs. Vol. 65, p. 149 &gt; 24 Gokkk, H. 1906. I'ber Chemische vorgange beim Erfrieren der Pflanzen. ( Landw. Versuchs. Vol. 6."., p. 149 &gt; 24 I.dVKl .AMI, G. A. 1913. The climate of Nebraska. (University of Nebraska, Col - lege of Agriculture Extension Bui. 14, 16. p.). I.dVKl AMI, G. A. 1913. The climate of Nebraska. (University of Nebraska, Col lege of Agriculture Extension Bui. 14, 16. p.). Matmhthot, I-., and Moi.i.iakd, M. 1901. Sur l'identiteg des modifications de structure produites dans les cellules v^getales par le gel, la plasmolyse et la fanaison. (Comptes Rendus Acad. Sci. Paris, 132, No. 8, pp. 495-498) 24 M.\THorcnoT, L., and Moi.i.iard, M. 1901. Sur l'identiteg des modifications de structure produites dans les cellules vegetales par le gel, la plasmolyse et la fanaison. (Comptes Rendus Acad. Sci. Paris, 132, No. 8, pp. Maximow, N. A. 1908. Chemische Schutzmittel der Pflanzen gegen Erfrieren. (Ber. der Deutsch. Gesell. Vol. 30 pp. 52-65; 293-305; 504-516; also Travaux d. 1. Soc. Natur. de St. Petersbourg Vol. 37, p. 32) 24 1908. Chemische Schutzmittel der Pflanzen gegen Erfrieren. (Ber. der Deutsch. Gesell. Vol. 30 pp. 52-65; 293-305; 504-516; also Travaux d. 1. Soc. Natur. de St. Petersbourg Vol. 37, Mez, C. 1905. Neue Untersuchungen fiber das Erfrieren eisbestandiger Pflanzen. (Flora, Vol. 94, p. 89) 21, 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 Nebraska Auhici i.ti rai. Exp. Station Rkskaiu h Bio. 1(5 1 In lli - l.iil rl I'lUi' Molisch, Haxs. 1897. Untersuchung uber das Erfrieren der Fflanzen. (Jena, G. Fisher, 73 p.) 22, 23, 24, 27 Mvi.i.er-Thi-ruau, H. 1886. Uber das Gefrteren und Erfrieren der Pflanzen. (Landw. Jahrb. Vol. 9, p. 133, 1880, and Vol. 15, p. 453, 1886) 21, 22, 23, 24, 26, 27 Sachs, J. 1860. Krystallbildungen bei dein Gefrieffen und Veranderung der Zellhaute bei dem Aufthauen saf tiger Pflanzen-theile. (Ber. u. d. Ver. d. Kon. Sachs. Gessel. d. Wiss. Zu Leipzig, 1860, Vol. 12, p. 1. Also Landw. Versuche, 186", p. 167, Heft 5 ) 21, 22, 23 Salmon, S. C. 1917. Why cereals winterkill. (Journal of the American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 9, No. 8) 21 SCHAKKXIT, E. 1912. Uber den Einfluss nieder Temperaturen auf die Ptianz. Zell. (Zeits. Of. All?. Phys. Vol. 12, p. 323. Also Mitt. Kaiser Wilhelm Inst. Landw. Bromberg, Vol. 3, No. 2, p. 93, 1910) 24 SlEBEL, J. E. 1911. (Compend of Mechanical Refrigeration and Engineering, p. 421. Nickerson and Collins Co., Chicago I Thisei.ton-Dyer, W. 1899. On the influence of temperature of liquid hydrogen on the germinative power of seeds. ( Proc. Roy. Soc. 65, p. 361 ) 22, 2(i Wiegaxd, K. M. 1906. The occurence of ice in plant tissues. ( Plant World, Vol. 9, No. 2, p. 25). Also passage of water from the plant cell during freezing. (Plant World, Vol. 9, No. 5, p. 107) .. .22, 23, 25 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>