<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00063.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00063.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Secretary of State of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1928-06-30">1928-06-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR TWENTY-FOUR MONTHS EXDIXG JUXE 30, 1928 Frank Marsh, Secretary of State TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Office of Secretary of State Lincoln, Nebraska Juno 30, 11)28 To the Honorable, The Governor, Adam McMuIIeu, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. My dear Governor: Conforming to the statutes of the Commonwealth, I have the honor to present herewith, my report as Secretary of State for the State of Nebraska, for the twenty-four months ending June 30, 1928. This report contains an exhibit of the affairs of the office and the method of conducting the same during the term now closing. It also sets forth the amount of moneys expended by this de - partment, a classified statement of all moneys received by the office as fees. It further sets forth a statement of the number of corporations incorporating, qualifying, withdrawing or dissolving, the registration of trade marks, the registration and renewal of brands, the granting of charters to chattel loan organizations under the provisions of Sec - tion 284G, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and a report of the Board of Pardons. In the interests of economy, we have abridged the report as much as possible, eliminating several features that heretofore have been embodied, which would increase the cost of publication, and are in themselves not of vital public interest. Respectfully submitted FRANK MARSH, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OP STATE 3 SECRETARIES OF STATE TERRITORIAL 1. Thomas B. Cuming, August 23, 1854, to March 12, 1858. J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861. to Feb. 21. 1867. •2 a STATE 4. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871. Win. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 12, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879, to Jan. 4, 1883. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1883, to Jan. 6, 1887. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889. Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by the death of James Laird. 5. li. 8. it. 10. 1 1. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891. Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by resigna - tion of Gilbert L. Laws. 12 John C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891, to Jan. 3, 1895. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895, to Jan. 7, 1897. William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 3, 1901. George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907, to Jan. 5, 1911. Addison Wait, from Jan. 5, 1911, to Jan. 7, 1915. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 7, 1915, to Jan. 9, 1919. Darius M. Amsberry, from Jan. 9, 1919, to Jan. 4, 1923. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 4, 1923, to Jan. 6, 1927. 13 14 15. it; IT IS lit 21 ■&gt;' Frank Marsh, from Jan. 6, 1927, to </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE STATE OFFICERS DURING BIENNIUM Adam McMullen, Governor Beatrice Geo. A. Williams, Lieutenant Governor Fairmont Frank Marsh, Secretary of State Norfolk L. B. Johnson. Auditor Omaha Dan Swanson, Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. ..Fremont W. M. Stebbins, Treasurer Gothenburg O. S. Spillman, Attorney General Pierce John H. Miller, Railway Commissioner Lincoln Charles A. Randall, Railway Commissioner Newman Grove John E. Curtiss, Railway Commissioner Geneva Charles W. Taylor, State Superintendent Lincoln UNITED STATES SENATORS George W. Norris McCook 1925-1931 R. B. Howell Omaha 1 923-1 92!t CONGRESSMEN John H. Morehead Falls City First District Willis G. Sears Omaha Second District Edgar Howard Columbus Third District J. N. Norton Polk Fourth District Ashton C. Shallenberger Alma Fifth District Robert G. Simmons Scottsbluff Sixth District ADMINISTRATIVE BOARDS Of Which the Secretary of State is a Member Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Board of Canvassers. Board of Pardons and Paroles. Board of Depository Bonds. OFFICE FORCE OF THE DEPARTMENT OF STATE Frank Marsh, Secretary Norfolk G. B. Thomas, Deputy Omaha Verna Hall, Bookkeeper Lexington Pauline Hill, Corporation Clerk Lincoln Roberta Johnson, Recording Clerk Omaha Lydia Hill, Correspondence Clerk Lincoln CORPORATION DEPARTMENT The table below sets forth the number of articles of incorpora- tion, amendments to articles of incorporation, appointment of agents, dissolutions, etc., handled during the past twenty-four months: </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OP STATE 5 DOMESTIC CORPORATION'S Total number of domestic corporations registered 4057 Number domestic corporations incorporated during biennium- 767 Number domestic corporations filing amendments 254 Number domestic corporations voluntarily dissolving 240 NumbeT of domestic corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 93 FORKIGX CORPORATIONS Total number foreign corporations registered 685 Number foreign corporations qualified during biennium 215 Number amendments to appointments filed 86 Number foreign corporations voluntarily withdrawing 76 Number foreign corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 9 XOX-PROFIT CORPORATIONS Total number non-profit corporations registered 724 Number non-profit corporations incorporated during biennium- 216 Number of non-profit corporations filing amendments 35 Number non-profit corporations voluntarily dissolving 3 Number non-profit corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 14 Grand total all corporations, domestic, foreign and non-profit, engaged in business at this date in Nebraska 5466 TRADE MARKS Total number of Trade Marks 48 Number of Trade Marks filed during biennium 19 STOCK BRANDS This department is charged with the assignment and registration of brands used for the purpose of marking live stock, as by the statutes so provided. The year 1927 was the year in which all stock brands were required to be renewed. This renewal comes but once in five years, and the year 1927 being the five year period since 1922, all stock brand owners were renewing accordingly. A sum- mary of the business for the past twenty-four months is as follows: Total number of brands registered 6921 Number of brands issued during past six months 853 FINANCIAL STATEMENT This office collects fees for filing articles of incorporation, cor- poration permits, notary public commissions, registration of brands. certificates of transcripts, trade marks, loan licenses^ under provis- ions of House Roll No. 44, Session Laws of 1915, etc. "The following is a true and correct exhibit of moneys received during the past twenty-four months from all sources: </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE KK( EIPTS July 1, 1926 July 1, 1027 June 30, 1027 June 30, 1028 Corporation Filings, Domestic $ 25,291.70 $ 19,330.65 Corporation Filings, Foreign 5,459.25 5,765.25 Corporation Permits, Non-Proflt 608.00 579.00 Corporation Permits, Domestic 111,249.50 112,037.75 Corporation Permits, Foreign 31,587.25 26,501.75 Notary Commission Fees Brand Registration 2,310.00 2,346.00 2,475.45 5,236.29 Loan Company Licenses 660.00 960.00 Miscellaneous Fees 2,327.00 2,199.57 Total $1 SI, 96 8.15 $174,956.26 Total receipts for biennium $356,924.41 EXPKXDITURKS Salary, Secretary of State $ 5,000.00 $ 5,000.00 Salary, Deputy Secretary of State 2,640.00 2,640.00 Salaries, Clerks 5,265.97 5,070.00 Maintenance 2,537.08 2,247.08 Administration of initiative and referendum laws Registering Brands and publishing book.... 2,851.35 1,075.36 Total $ 18,294.40 $ 16,032.44 LOAX AGKXCIKS Sec. 2846. Compiled Statutes for 1922, provides for the licens- ing of loan agents or loan agencies, and is designed to regulate the loaning of money in small quantities upon chattel securities, salaries, etc. The bond to be given by the company is in the sum of $2,000.00 to be renewed and filed annually on March 1st. The companies now operating are as follows: Peoples Loan Company Omaha Provident Loan Society Omaha Popular Finance Company Omaha Industrial Finance Company Omaha Rex Company Omaha Omaha Loan Company Omaha Community Finance Corporation Omaha United Loan Company Omaha Motors Finance Lincoln Lincoln Finance Corporation Lincoln Industrial Loan &amp; Investment Company Lincoln Farmers Loan and Investment Lincoln City Loan Company Lincoln General Finance Company Lincoln These companies have been examined annually, as provided by law, and reports of examination are on file in this office. Respectfully submitted, FRANK MARSH, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 7 BOARD OF PARDONS Below is shown a list of the number of applicants heard by the Board of Pardons from the Penitentiary, Reformatory for Men and the Reformatory for Women from June 30, 1926, to June 30, 1928 Total Number of cases heard 437 Total Number of cases denied 60 l'KXITEXTIARY Discharged by expiration of term 365 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted 41 Paroles granted 157 Number of violators 24 Violators returned 17 Violators in custody (awaiting return) 2 REFORATORY FOR MEN: Discharged by expiration of term 212 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted 9 Paroles granted 183 Number of violators 22 Violators returned 10 Violators in custody (awaiting return) 6 REFORMATORY FOR WOMEN: Discharged by expiration of term 48 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted 0 Paroles granted 6 Number of violators 0 This board is composed of the Governor, Attorney General and Secretary of State. The board meets the second Tuesday of each month during the year, except in the month of August. The percentage of violations of paroles in Nebraska during the past biennium is very low — 13.2% — or in other words less than 14 out of every hundred persons granted clemency have violated the confidence reposed in them by the Board. This is a creditable show- ing as compared with that of many other state; Respectfully submitted. FRANK MARSH, Secretary, Board of Pardons. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>