<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SEED LABORATORY</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OJ NEBRASKA. REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SEED LABORATORY AND NKI.l.i: STEVENSON, A. H.. I.ahokvtoky Aid, i.nnilnry. United Stales IVpartinent of Agrii-ulum- l«». LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A Ihk University of Nebraska. Volumi XXI. Aktk i.k IV HY WII.COX. I'm. I).. Piohmoi of KatacvurvtULl Botany Collaborator in Chane, </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION AGR OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD T». ..O..T. Or T~« u,,....«T) hut. Lincoln l!&lt; S. ALLEN, I'r,, W II. 1. 1AM (i. WHITMORI Valley hick h. Aimori Auror; KIR (;. I.Yl'ORI). Kail City K CHARLES IV ANDERSON. Crete &gt;NORABLE GEORGE (( HIM. AND. Klirin THE STATION OFFICERS A. BURNETT, IS. &gt;c .. Ihnrti.r THE STATION OFFICERS I) s DALES. M. I'm.. Financial Secretary M I'm .// Si in In !i \1 \V MARSH \l.l.. Exeemtim Ckrk THE WORKING STAFF Uii.inx. I'h 1).. Agricultural Hntnnu .1. ALWAT, I'h. D.. Agricultural ('hcnnxtri/ II \l.l. Kj Cli THE WORKING STAFF {ariruHural Hnlnni/ [grieuttural Chemistry . H. Smith. H. S&lt; .. Animal Hmmhamdru T. 1'kikio. 1). V. \1.. Animal Pttkaitigy I.. Huikkii. B. S( . A. Ihiinj Hmammdr* \nimal Huslnmlry V. \1.. Aimnul PatkoieQj) . S( . A.. Dairy Htubamtry WVHKNC K Kill NKK. li. S&lt; . . A'«/"IH"/i«/7 li Montgomery. A. M.. Experimental Agronmntg .1. Paiujn, M. 1'.. Formtru Entomology V. M.. Experimental Agronomy i M. F., Fart 'Mr &gt;i rwis II IVviihih ». I'h. 1).. Gtlafu K. i'iiuhihn. \ M.. Highway Engineering \ Ehekmon. B. S&lt; .. llnrhiullnri V. I*. Srm i'. ('. E.. Irrigation Engineering \. l.uvKi.AM). IV S( .. 1. 1.. B., Mttmialmau \\ . PVGMJCY, B. &gt;■ iinmiiist Ph. I)., Geology M.. Highway Hi II,, V... Irrigation Enq ring 1. 1.. B., l/W. 1 \i.\i\ Ketheb. \ M . Sotb \ M Vorl/i '. 1'. Snviikh. M S '"i' Experimental Subatatitm, Si II. (Iain. li. D. »'.. Aiwriirti in Animmi Pathology -i,,\k. \l \'/ri&lt;ultiirul BataUM •4«ri in rimtitliil Suhxttttitm ml Pathology 1 1 iillunil Baton]) knis \\ . Pool, A \1 \&lt;iriniltuml Bammm 14. HvukKii. A. B., A**&lt;*t'int in AarammnM i s A Kiksskuhi h. B. s&lt; . \. B., A—ittaml in Aaramamm, U. Sti hdk\ vsr A. M.. M. l&gt;.. .4Mutanl "i Animal Patnamag i/rirultiirnl Hotim;/ . A. \1.. I K. B. I A I'/ I. H. S\\K\k. A. M.. .1 Mirtiiwi ill Sntaatatm/g I. V. Howa«d, B. 8c. in Auk.. Amntmmi in Horticulture V. W. Briiu. B. 8c., AmtiMant in Saib &lt;m&lt;l Crap*, \'»rth I'lnttr \\. I'k.kin. farm Superintendent !?i/ in Sodi i/»'/ Crop*. Yartt /■*/&lt;!/(( X. W N, N'ki.i.k Sikvknshn. A. B., Lamwatorjf Aid, Smmi hmmwatm% Surma Waddle. A. B., Laboratory Aid, Seed Laboratory ■I June 1. ISO v the Cnite l)ep:irtinent of AgrieultUI* </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SEED LABORATORY ;■&gt; 1).. 1'kdkkssok of Agbicultcbal Bht\n^ ( 'ha tur \XI INTHODICTION he United States Department ol liners in the purity and viability si among ratoriea had long been in opera- established here and as a natural unmarketable under the German t era t ion of the better grades of home-grow ■ s ■;■(! n to realize the import SB -I rest in (rood seeds in the West led Department of Agriculture to establish in .lan- &gt;n with the Nebraska Experiment Station. t Lincoln. This Laboratory is seeds for fanners and seedsmen nt state*. The following persona have nnected with this Laboratory during the periods indicate 1). Heald, Professor of Agricultural Botany and Collaborator c mber 1. lltos. i K. Mead Wilcox, Professor of Agricultural Botany and Col- Froin September I, HM)s Mrs. Herbert H. Mowrv (nes Miss M. L. Crosl, H. Mow I '.His. i:\r. sTTATION nl NEBR. VOL. XXI, ART. IV \ I. STEVENSON. A. IV. I.akokatoky Am. ry United Stetei Dqwtiimit of Agriculture ■xperimeni stations ba to the United States. At the pn rge amount of very poor and eheap md extent &lt;&gt;f the impurities found in the ■ percentage of these seeds that will gw- '_ r ii"(l Julv </seg>
          
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SEED LABORATORY i\ Pl-&gt; &gt;K AORICULTUBAL BoTAN 1 Chant* \M A. B., Lamomatomi Aid. Department of Agriculture h:\knson • I State INTKODl'CTION United States Department of itc experiment stations ha n»; farmers in the purity ami viability laboratories hail long been in opera - were established here and as a natural was unmarketable under the German the United States. At the ]&gt;: amount of very poor ami cheap n of the better grades of home-crown a. clover, ami ■( s. Dur tanners have just begun t&lt;i realise the important ■ing the character and extent of the impurities found in the they plant ami the percentage of these seeds that will te. This widespread interest in good seeds in the West led "niti Depart merit of Agriculture to establish in Jan- 190s, in cooperation with the Nebraska Experiment Station, Velna-ka Seed Laboratory at Lincoln. This Laboratory is ned t &lt; • make examinations of seeds for farmers and seedsmen eliraska and adjacent states. The following persons have connected with this Laboratory during the periods indicate. r". 1). Heahl. Professor of Agricultural Botany and Collaborator I large. (Resigned September 1. IV E. Mead Wilcox. Professor of Agricultural Botany and Col- I ator in Charge. (From September 1. I90S Mrs. Herbert H. Mowry (nea Miss M. L Crosby), Scien- Assistant. (Resigned July, 1908.) IK I., lin. AUK. KM'. STATION t»I NEBR. VOL. XXI, Alt I IV </seg>
            <seg id="p007">So. of KIS |«.K Illinois ».'» Iowa Kalis; Miniii M i — &lt; mri . Montana. York .'(I 1 .") 38 III ii South (aroliM; Souili I):iknl:i K 8 il ii ' -ii;:i in; IUHU 1 1 11 Table II how tin nuinhei received the n tlld ature and appean that net nlv half the samp) numbers being of red c will u i \ t \\'M) »ver and awnlesw !n&lt; A careful examination of thi&gt; t;tl&gt;l Hin Nolle Stevenson, Laboratory Aid. (From lei 1906, to June 26, 1908 Miss N'diina Waddle, Laboratory Aid. (From &lt;&gt;&lt; The purpose of the present report is to present in a si Sr way ■ome "f the most interesting results securei tory from the time of its establishment to July ic following table (Table I) shows the number of .(•(I from each of the thirteen states represented and and number of tests made. It will be seen that over ")(l |h E samples and tests were of seed received from Nelirask: seedsmen. A grand total of 463 samples wax receive! different tests were made during the first year, and Iil7 ami 950 different tests during the second year up to May Table I. -General xumnuiru &lt;&lt;; tin two yearn work, xh •l&lt; </seg>
          
            <seg id="p008">r .lS)U.)A\ i- -^ 9 • c - '-. 5E ■ - — £ i- i- r. — ri — __.,,__ . — r — n x — — ,ifli:j.i.\\ — r — ri / — — '""'I / =?! = = O» - • I -/•-.— - — / -•II £ ?l \ i- - - -.-. - --v - — *) / / !-"(-! II - _r^- i3i:ha\ ltt "'I - - / i- = ccr / i - i - c - y "1 S !I1 M -^-.--j- - — r — ?^rJs^ s I,: ,-r - t- - .- /. noil —::/-•.: - in,! "" "' ■in x. ■ uol|\:.)ijuu.i|'| "" paAiaooj s.)(dun- ■ — "' "?J" r ?I l — S — ||&gt; J.H|U1!11I | I. i a a. a. a. a, i i --i n </seg>
            <seg id="p009">greal importance it has wt—li ba«&lt; to 0 the samples of alfalfa, red clover, and 1 in the Laboratory and particularly to union weed seeds found in these samples, irination herein contained will prove of tout to purchase neck for use. Tin :■ seeds or seeds of low vitality is of three ' introducing noxious weeds which may trouble and loss for many years. lin a targe percentage of impurities or b or stand may result. s it may be necessary to buy other seed and olvea a serious loss of time and labor n &lt;&gt;f the soil and planting. les include the results of the examination ) .Iulv!l."l ( .tus. VLFALFA if alfalfa seed were examined '.'111 samples in Table 111 * a **—* o Q f w &amp; o Green foxtail was found in over •').") per cent of these samples 13 weeds that were found in 10 per cent or more of fhe needs of the following sorts of dodder were found Ufalfa weda I U../i../,., «*•■). The natural mm of the seeds is c rieht. From bannew' Hul. V . &gt;■ !&gt;&lt;'i&gt;t. Agr. IH If. I. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 1,1,.. ( 'uxcuta I'vm.i: III. K [ENTIH Sitlsuln kali inlh u.' I'tiintnifii In ( 'hi nopottiut Polygon Seiaria ylaua Panicum ni}&gt; trimechioa t lilohis tp.. \\ Poiygtmum Solanum «p.. Atripiex »p Ciixoitn jianiflora Dnuiiis nimtti . . Ml \\i Ctueuta n Ambnma ttrtemimi folia.. Him Amaranthu* btUmHen.. Sun Ihiiitttria mnjuinali* Phmtago artrtata. t iri m/t lint aquarromt Lappula r,,l,,irsl Hairy »tick»ei •''"''■" rotutulifoliti (■(Hiiincin mall ((iinii Htimt.r irisjins Silni s/i. Polygonum nmvohmlu*.. \\i|,| Verbena ofllrinalis. Eun&gt;| Cuamta rpitkgmum. (love I'ciilniinu x/&gt; Cust iiln iniii i nnt l.ntus cnnii, iilntu* 1'icris i ih innl is. ( l\ Trifolium sunn Ciiscntu planiflora alfalfa \Ua ar reruns field do CumetUa epUkgmum eloi Cuxcula indecora larm Sit, inn r, /u'fii/ntstis sp. . ; 'in hum Bratunca up </seg>
            <seg id="p011">I IN. \\ Mil [ IMMIIS ' \\ ilil Rtinflowe Wliitr s\vtt't clove ■&lt;l plantaii Small trail trr: i.sli sr Kidney vete Kcil |iini|«Tiu'! ApFtakiua peppergrii \\ liiif campion Heal-all Luily'M-thumh rrrl Ni'ltlr-lr.iM Poverty weed Howry ew SniaU-flfmreml inclili Hur clover. S|M&gt;t t«-«l luir olcivcr Evening pnmroae. Sinuate-leaved evening itriniroi Hawkweed pier Hitter dock. Hint' ficlil mailder « Imp elover. I irlil ik'Iiiiv ere— , </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 /. . \ RK1) CLOVER A total of (il s:iiii| eS 111 1 period. Table IV shows th weed seeds were found. It is is the most frequent weed seed hen in over ?•'{ per cent of the sample: aeeds i- sliown ai th" \&gt; Tli" va dicated below //ii einlhif 'III sp Clover dodder \\ u clover samples Table I\. Kind ■CIKMIHK \\Mt ~ r Panicum captlhin . I'lantiii/o limitohihi (/In ma. . ('hiHiipmiium iilhiiin Amiinwthu* sp.. fcuphorlna prtslii... DigUaria kumifuaa Smanum tp. l'oltltjonum inrsiiiimi Lady Hunux crityu* ('uric (uric I'lunlwiii rui/i/ii. . Biaek-seeded Ambroniit (lrtrmisiijnlin .Ragweed... Erhinochloa rrux-ynlti Barnyard er Sill IK S/i. Miiliituio lupuliim. , Velio* I'dIi/ijokkiii .*/&gt;.. Hutnex acetocella . . . . Stie* i |&gt; sorrel. . </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 II IN « Hl&lt; H (lover dinkier Wild carrot. i ! European vervain Kidney vetch. •* Heal-all &gt; Evening pnmroM Hawkweed picris Hitter dock Cut-leaved craiie's-liill Dove— fiMit crane's-hill (linn plant.. . . Velvet Poverty weed Apetaloiis peppergnuui. Kound-leaved toad Hax Small-flowered nielilot .Slender paspahmi Common plantain Knot weed Pale smart weed Russian thistle Blue field madder Tumble mustard mustard. KoiiijIi rush graM zltias COMMON N 1MB Wild i Red pim|&gt;ernt'l. Fremont! guu— fort Spreading punicum ( &gt;x-toneiM BirdVfoot trefoil Braetod plantain. Field ruin&lt;&gt;niiU Mayweed Spiny sjila. Tlire&lt;&gt;-stf&lt;ie(l mercury </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 WVM.I WS HIJOMi; (IRAS A total of ■_&gt;&lt;; samples of awnless hrome graae w a&gt; &lt; In Table V is shown the number of samples of awnles In Table V is shown the Dumber of samples of awnless br in which the various sorts of weed seeds were found. 1 in which the various sorts of weed seeds were found. II 4 wheat gram {Agropyron) are most frequently species of wheat gttm {Agropyron) are most frenuen lirome jtrass samples. 1 \ hi. i. \ . hi in; 1 \ ii 1. 1 \ . A / /,&lt;/., IK.VTIFK s IKvm " n nmmn mami .XijriijDiriiu m rpyron *p. Hnillttis sirnlin . ( |,, liriini ii '-"/'/'»/" trhimaU Kuropean Mi, i. Lappula eckinata Bromw&gt; n, S, T1 ,,,,il, , Bromua rat ' nenopotlium Ijunh«-&lt;inartprs ( 'Kenopotliu n \\ Wil.l buckwl • ♦*""•• led dock. mlrat ( 'nni jHtsitnt xp. urBMI N I.I /till, Kill 'I/I, lull. l.i -piiliuiH apttohtm linsn tp. linsn tp ■ Vrik. ttnil • "' Bund ■ lh,,i \\ a jiilun \\ j) ( | " ■•■)&gt;. &gt;. I'lMtttnti jn-mtnt Kremont ■ m lanreolatum. \\w\\ thUtle &gt;■ &lt; fiitlti/rniiin (lover iliMlilcr •jHniilllll jl, n Utnreolatum a i /n Ih i/ni a in Euphorhia I'rxtiira rp f.tyiimiiiiixii, tf !.&lt; pnli urn tp PuuUago lanceoiala Poiygonum pen Polygonum perrin LadyVthumli Suymbrium a*U*in.un Tumble inu&gt;t :1 r Thins/ii urn us, Table \ I shows a Complete occurrence of various weed seeds in the samples examined numlx»rs indicate the number it sampl :it «he top in which each sort </seg>
            <seg id="p015">&lt; IV ■f. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 amixiH J -» A() i.) joau].) .»lii|.\\ Huniju umijoju i J8AOIJ I^H tnujvjd wnijojui J3AO1,') .151IS|\- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">■• * I U 1 :i * i II -* ■A-rr-r r?s -r 7 Z J "J a # &gt; I i^ C 3 rr P 5 ??! aal 1*3 ' ~ "2 "^ </seg>
            <seg id="p018">• &gt;J1UM|\- J . I A 1 1 1 ) ism&gt;1) aiii|.\\ xujdjj u/nt/o/uj J.»A&lt;)[.) |M H »kw.»;iu(/ wnifo/ui J«}\H|, ) J&gt;(IS|\ mnpuqKi( i«nt;o/uj '■'11! IV uimiu.*;&gt; l)JI]V)l 1IIJ1J).I\,- wmtQ Mifg spnirej mi,! AI|)&lt;M1II [ tm»JOjd uin,)/if,i Ctwmj |&gt;,m H iijnuut) nuo/mu WJIV IKIl/lty tl/ill.tl/it J\' ■si:j;i ,»a"}J |i:;iiu.u.i ( | uad inn i jn- 1 ■) ...\» ll.:i|D] ■ ujliijimi wnifo'f </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I I * -'- &lt; -I . • J. 4m I j. r. 7. Z / 5 P -S S-. ■•^ i.. * ~c me 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 ajnjxijy 88*19 ajnjxijv J.)\oi.) jj.\o|,) .nii|\\ 1 mtiifiijux J.»AI&gt;|.) !&gt;,&gt;&gt;] - A -1 — MU.iivjd luni/ojui Jd.voj, ) .»(I^1V uinfUMftiij tutitfol ui t^IHIV &gt;'" ; ""'&gt;:) ii.iijii)i Ug .(Il|t| A5(01UU.&gt;\| I DOJ ■&lt;srj;) .(11(51 KpiJin:, ) DM utl uw.t 90J Al l'"'"!.l "/'"/&lt;/ 1: JI I: JI\ / tilil: I'/" l\ \}\ |i:iuu.u.i,i JUII.IJIll Illllljli-I i:ji) oa&gt;j ui:||i:il HI )Ut}jl 1 1)11111 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">/ </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 ( )u Account ot their noxious characte in agricultural seeds the following weed seeds are de illustrated. By the use of a small hand lens a fan t&lt;&gt; identify these seeds from the descriptions riv&lt; BRA(TEI) PLAN UN" (/ These seeds are romtm 11 I nited States. Thev are H ami have a shallow t which thev may he readilv iden is broad, with white horder are seen in a reddish-brown This is an am m characteristic feature Kig. :i. StiMs of braeted pi of the s&lt;&gt;c&lt;ls i&gt; shdwn at the rifrlit in l/'i nun I m ( KHOKN. RIB-GRASS ( il ENGLISH PLANTAIN i/', Seeds of this plant are frequent which they could mostly be removed bv tin somewhat longer than clover seeds but of iu They are rounded on one side and with a deep longitudin on the opposite side with a black spot, often with a light rintf about it, in the center of this channel. 1 plant, is the preaenci 1 ) T*( IVV M W \ I I 1 1 ' ill! ■«»&lt;&gt;!■ i ■»- \ 1 1] 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">2o V A •ennial with numerous long flowers. ll-knuwn | m ,11 «* }**. hiticmldlnt. The natural size of the of the figure. From Fanners' Bui. horn (Pioatop :hi liarul enrm W RKEN FOXTAII Seiaria riruli tboM &lt;&gt;f red clover so much n.it surprised to find then so plant rt'Sfli I.I ml weight that oik v«&gt;rr"~ commonly found in nt. They u ilso &lt;ilit greenish-brown altho mmbb The flort't is oval and unequally rinj: glume having tli" j:rc mular bui the edgM at the palaa moiilv a H wlutisli-vt'llow the Hi&gt;\v( face is er and shining. n annual, naturi tiled from Europe and commonly North Ameri America. V v" 4jr , xt -iil II"' nitural sin- of the ,:f tin' tiiiurc. From Fanners' Mill. U. S. Dept. Vp lainl)'s-i|iiartfis. or pigweed as it is also call d. are n those wf red clover bui are almost always prci nt t i 1 the other cnmmeicial clovers and VMBH-tjlWRTERS (Ckenupmtium album </seg>
            <seg id="p024">The seed is nearly circular ii marginal protuberance from one rid center of that face. The surface is color. In form and color the seed •( Enths. for which it mig ■ast parts of it, is usual granular ami dull. The plant is an aoi America. mjtm &lt;$ •:•: WII VHH&lt;H These seeds a Eat all similar. 1 J-be&amp;ring portion the other portion lorn found intact Eli a barb which i~ o f rows of spines are l-beariag portion i. - lighter, almost yellow. The plant is a biennial a • me parts of the United S 1 r 1%. i . Seeds of wild carrot .' ra in t!ie center of th« I mI the &gt;im'iI&gt; i&gt; shown i Mul. r. s D,.|,i ■ m**? </seg>
            <seg id="p025">It i\\ TREFOIL .1/ '!/&lt; a adulterant » »t" red el litticult td detect. They resemble it" of practically the same nit and general tr. ovate rather than kidney-ehaped, aiul ■ ecmdition Ikmiijt due to t he fact that pod. The scar also is nearer the small } J. tth pulina i. The natural foil (.1/ urure. From Karmere' Hul. I'. S. lK'pt X(i AM VUANTII i ich smaller than those of red clover ami nb's-quarters very closely. The scar-notch i slightly depressed near the scar. The dish-brown to a jet black and the Mr - polished. It is low and much branched broken off at the surface of the bout by the wind. than in those of alfalfa. tal and is common in waste place •A :imarant li I ''* ti the center of the fil ■ I dinners </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Report i&gt;j th&lt; Xthni.tki ni.n S, YELLOW KOXTAI1 The aeeda of this plant are larger than t and of a yellow color. The floret is plano-convex. 1 roughened bv transverse fes •( indistinct. This m^t\ occurs very comn red clover. The plant i I ip. 10. Sec, Is ol yell, . - Bhown :ii the lower IliW Hul. V. S. Dept. OLD-WITCH ( ;R v- These seeds ai Eon both sides, and 1 yellow in color. Th one side and two on &gt;n ■hia is another eommo away and act like tun IX)|)!)i:i! Field Dodder {Cuamia arvenrig) Clover Dodder (Cttacttta tpithym Larf;e-seeded Alfalfa Dodder &lt; Sinall-seede.l Alfalfa Dodder •,( &lt;td Four species of dodder hav&lt; alfalfa and clover by this Laboratory. No seed si in which any one of these dodders is (.resent even The palea is also crossed by ritlj:&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 I No. S4 (\V Kit over on&lt; ibout thirt \ dodder i-an l&gt;e removed _&gt;() mesh steel wire cloth a piece of this wire cloth 12 inches square. Put sieve and shake well for irdinaiily \&gt;e enough to required in some cases. t tlic laree-seetU a wooden frame about half pound of seed into this seconds. One sifting will • the use &lt;&gt;f a sieve made of 2 :iinl \Y.) cause wire. Tack ■ St'COIUlS. (MIC Billing Will </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 /. Ki A. M i d irihi - li. ('in &lt;n 1 It'll { iIihI.Ii The Lateral study nf any seed r-aniplo senl states l&gt;v Beedsmen and farmer? Tlif examination of samples dodder requim hut little time am all other work. All umplea sent fo at uiice au&lt;l reports sent by mail ■ II — •■« jiiliuin pratenm He. I cloi nver i WORK OF THi: KKHKASK PRESENCE OF ADULTERANTS OB </seg>
            <seg id="p029">11 ■( i ! S III 1 ,i 1. I Nebraska 8t &lt; &lt;l Laboratory MECHANICAL PURITY ration of the samples into three | ind being examined). seeds not of the kind being exmmii rt. and chaff. he percentage by weight of each of the ie weed seeds present nsiderable time and can Ik&gt; made only icilities of the Seed Laboratory will |&gt;ermit not such tests to l&gt;e made for any one firm or in- calendar month. These tests will \w Bad mptly as possible ami in the order in which ■eeived CERMINATION ade to determine the percentage of seed which ler favorable conditions. The seed of cereal.-, vegetables can be easily tested without tin us. Some seeds, however, including a numlxr more difficult to test, requiring exact eondii d moisture. ie tested for termination in the order in which &gt;ut not more than ten i KM tests for germination nv one firm or individual in anv one calendar VT SHOULD ACCOMPANY SEEDS SENT TO THE LABORATORY TO BE TESTED tuples with a statement as to the exact pur- e sent, as follows D for presence of adulter ■chanical purity. nits or dodder. rmination iii ml all correspondence concerning seed tesi - i Nebraska Seed , Laboratory Agricultural Kxperiment Station </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>