<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host</title>
               <date value="1925-10">1925-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 34 A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host 111. FURTHER STUDIES OF THE VIABILITY OF THE UREDINIOSPORES OF PUCCINI A GRAMINIS TRITICI GEORGE L. PELTIER ( Department of Plant Pathology LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OCTOBER, 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rust m the Absence . of an Alternate Host 111. FURTHER STUDIES OF THE VIABILITY OF THE UREDINIOSPORES OF PUCCINIA GRAMINIS TRITICI GEORGE L. PELTIER INTRODUCTION In a previous report 1 the author showed that the influence of relative humidity on the viability of the urediniospores of Puccinia graminis tritici (Pers.) Eriksa. and Henn. Phys - iologic Form 111 was very pronounced and closely associated with temperature. At the end of 16 weeks the spores were still viable at the medium humidities and lower temperatures . employed, as determined by the percentage of spore germ - ination and the ability of the urediniospores to produce in - fection on wheat seedlings. With all humidities at higher temperatures the spores were viable only a short time. There appeared to be a direct relation between the viability of the urediniospores and the temperature and relative humidity. This study has been continued with two_ other Physiologic Forms of Puccinia graminis tritici. During the season of 1922-23 the urediniospores of Physiologic Form IX were used, while the following year an attempt was made to determine how long the urediniospores of Physiologic Form XXI remained viable at the medium relative humidities and the lower temperatures. METHODS The same apparatus as previously described was used. Likewise, the same methods were used x namely: 7-day old seedlings of Little Club (C. I. No. 4066) were hand inoculated with the urediniospores of the Physiologic Form to be studied and incubated for 48 hours at the optimum tempera - ture for infection. After incubation they were trimmed and i Peltier G. L. A Study of the Environmental Conditions Influencing the Development of Stem Rußt In the Ab.ence of an Alternate Host. L The Viability of the Urediniospores of Puccinia graminln trltlcl Form HI. Neb. Aer. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 22, 16 PP. 3 figs., 1922. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 34 placed on a bench in a greenhouse held at a temperature of approximately 25" C. Fourteen days after inoculation, the leaves with pustules were cut off and placed on the stands in the dishes previously described. 1 At stated intervals the leaves were withdrawn from the dishes and spore germina - tion tests made. The method used for the germination of the urediniospores was modified somewhat in order to obtain more uniform results. In the preliminary experiments the spores were placed in a drop of water on a cover glass and inverted over a glass ring, mounted on a slide. It was found that much better and more uniform results were obtained by dusting the spores onto a drop of water in a Syracuse watch glass, so that the spores floated on top of the drop. All the germination tests were run in triplicate. The same counting methods were used to obtain the per - centage of spore germination. In the greenhouse 6 or 12 seedling wheat plants (Little Club C. I. No. 4066) were inoculated with the spore material remaining after the spore germination tests were made. Fourteen days after inoculation the number of leaves infected together with the number of pustules on each leaf were recorded. EXPERIMENTAL DATA VIABILITY OF THE UREDINIOSPORES OF PHYSIOLOGIC FORM IX Germination tests. — The same set of 6 temperatures (5°, 10°, 15°, 20°, 25° and 30° C.) and 11 relative humidities (from 0 to 100 per cent at approximately 10 per cent inter - vals) were employed, as in the previous report. 1 Owing to the fact that none of the spores of Physiologic Form IX were viable at the end of the first week in the first trial at any relative humidity when held at 30° C. and only a low per - centage of germination over a short period of time was obtained at some of the medium relative humidities when maintained at 25°, daily germination tests of spores held at these two temperatures were made. The results are listed in Table 1. The results show very clearly that at 30° C, with relative humidities between 60.7 and 100 per cent, all the spores were dead at the end of 9 days. Likewise, the spores were not viable after 10 days at the lowest 2 relative humidities. However, at the medium relative humidities the spores were viable for about 1 week longer or a total of about 2V_ weeks. , &gt;l c. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host BABp gf I3?JV oo o ooooooo oooooooo oo o • S3 — ! — **• ***P98*»WV ooooooooooo oooo | o | oooo q ■ vpSZWtv ooooooooooo ooooooloooo .fe. — : •J_ BA«PTZ Ja^IV ooooooooooo oooo I I I oooo Os -S ' " a BXBp^zJajJV ooooooooooo ooooo | | oooo &gt;. _ ' • . c *i «*BPIZ-'*&gt;IV ooooooooooo ooooo||||oo _:3 *■ '■— ■ IS ■_* bX«p oz Ja.IV ..... 3 S -. r uc. .»» OOOOOOOOOOO OOOO I OO £ 6 ;s - — : '__ ■_■'•' ._ . £*. •5 MBP6IJ91JV ooooooo I |oo oooo I I I I I oo 58 .00 o_ - •I ««P1I*&gt;WV oooooooo |oo oooooo| I |oo si 1 S a-8p9iJ3.iv oo6ooo||loo . oooo I I I I I &lt;_&gt;«_ S| •| «*«P9l»WV ooooo||||oo oooo| I I I |oo 7+ "S ~ ++ § S*»P « mn oooooo I I I oo ooooo I I I 1 oo (Jj' : — tS — : o v^. "**? 81 "1JV g ooooo I I I I oo g oooo I I i I I oo _ •o _„ B pnja)jv ooooolMJoo ooo | | I I I I oo _; §. * ft »-'9*" OT ooooolllHI oooo|m||o •1 : • ;§ »^P 6 »VV O I O I I I I J .« j O I I I I I _ _ _ _ I I S «X«p 8 J^JV o| |o| I I I I I I I I I I I I M I I I ii ■ JjS 4. **__ ?•«? • o 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ii i Mm i || » mt«p 9 »UV. o I I I I M M I I Till +++* **\ _|-g .§. — : ||1 j| _it.pt. jsijv HIUHHu I ..-+*++.-. Igjs J§ ?**Pt WV . I I M++++ +Il | l++ ++ +++ll ||| I sKspZ j*iiv n++++ ++1 + 1 +-H-+ttt++« * I._ r-l + +++ &lt;»M H Xip, _»,;y ++++ ++ ++f + l '. H _ H +£h J _ Hf rj X)tpIOinq £ quiia^t-oqioiawq g © ci io *# c&gt; o, o in io o © OAUV13J w oc_oooc.o6c.thoo 3 doioddowoiHod ei__i!»c_d_v b ©'».*«-»■»«««.« fc o»St-S»»«« rt </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 34 Table 2. — Viability of the urediniospores of Puccinia graminis tritici Physiologic Form IX *. * r, _ r, _ r. _ _ I .. i _ 3; j _&gt; _ _ _ oo _ .* _- J _2 f -2 -Z -_ I J __ -- _-__ J_ _2 I __ _2 M M -2 _ 88 *-S*8|S s s« H «*11 *1 _&gt;,*!* * : * j * * * * * * * * * * * * * * 'k - •- ~ n ~ ' t «. I to I t- I 00 ci 3 — .1 ..-.«_;__-- - o|£ ;■ ; i _;___iij_'_iii J S _ _ _• __ P_- cent 2,1" C. 100.0 |*l — '- — 0 II 0 I 0 I 0 I 0 I 0 1 0 0 I 0 I 0 i 0 0 0 89.9 * — , — ■- 11 0 I 0 ; 0 I 0 0 0 010,0,0 0 0 80.5 *■ - ; — ----- o 0 I 0 &lt; 0 | 0 0 ' 0 1 0 ( 0 0 0 70.4 + — — — — — » — 0 j 0 i 0 I 0 Olo 0 i 0 0 0 60.7; + i + : + l * - — I — - 0 00— 0 — — I — — * 49.0 + + +|*i- -- - j — — — — | — - . — — « 38.0 + + i + + + •- ! + + I + | + *+—)_. — -b * I — * * 29.5 | + + i -. ( * - - *;— I + I — — 00 00 010 0 0 21.6 + + 1 + . * - * * _,=__= + + - _,\ o olo 0 0 10.5 + * ■ — 'oooooooo 0 0 o.o i + -- i __ - o I o ! n i o o 1 o ' o o o o Percent 1 .5° (.'. loo.o * ; * ii oo o ii oooo o o o o l o i o 89.9 * I — I) 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 I 0 0 80.5 f + * II (I (I - 0 10,00 0!0 0,0|0|0 70.4 *i+ * — i — OO'OOiO 0 I 0 i 0 ! 0 0 0 60.7 , + ' * * * ■■= » _,,_=!— _|_ — o' — '— — I* 49.0 + + + * * — « . « » | « g »'- — - j — i • 38.0 + + 1 + -• - J- - + | + ' * + | — * ! — I — i * __,! + 29.5 - i - - - -"- • * i + — i -» — ■ * i — I — - j — i 0 0 i 0 21.5 -r - 1 - • - • *■ j * * * * | — — * + 0 0 (I 0 ! 0 io... + * « — i - - -lolojoloioloio 0 ' 0 1 0 0.0 * * I ■ ' - - 0 (I 0 (I ! 0 | U 0 . 0 ' 0 Per cent 10° C. 100.0 * - - — ■ - ■ — - '■ — 0 | 0 II 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 89.9 - =■= *= - + * — 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0,010 80.5 —'**-- — | — ■ — -- 01-10 0 000 0 , 0 I 0 70.4 + + '+!+ + — + I — + 1 — — 0 OlOOOIOOlO 60 7 I + + + 1 + i + — j + *|+*|**;*(*0|— __ I _- I _. 49.0 ++++ -i- » + + + *!«!_. + + ■__—'_. _, _, _ 38.0 ! + I + + + + * + * + + + I — ' + +*!— 1*1* - - 29.5 +++•■+; + ++ * * + «■ — ■ — I * j 0 ' (I j 0 0 0 21.5 |++ + + . + +I + : + I + * + + -b -b I + I — 0 — 0 0 0 10.5 + +!++* — —! + - * — — OOlOoloO 0 0 0.0 1 + i + I * I + I - ■ + - - — I — I 0 I — J 0 I 0 0,0 010 Per cent 5° C. 100.0 + * | — — | — — — -_ — __ 000000 89.9 +++ » * * * + + — - 0 — — 00000 80.6 * + * + * * * — — - 0 -00-000 70.4 +++ + + * + * + * * * + * — — + =•=« 60.7 ++ + +++* + ++ -= + + + * =_=__= + + + 49.0 ++ + +++ + + + + + * * * **=_ + + + 38.0 +++++++ *++- + + + + * _.._=__,_.-. 29.5 +++ + ++++ + - + + + * — — — — — — 21.6 * + ++++ + * - * * * =_— 00— — — 10.5 _ + + _, + + — — — — 0— — OOOOO o.o + + * * * I + ; - — — o — — ooooo * Material exhausted. * =&gt; 5 to 10 per cent germ inn tion. 0 -- No germination. + = 10 to 40 per cent germination. — = 1 to 5 per cent germination. + + = above 50 per cent germination. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Stem Rust in the Absence op an Alternate Host As stated above, no urediniospores were viable at the end of the first week at any relative humidity at 30° C. when weekly tests were made. However, when daily germination tests were run, the spores retained their viability at the medium relative humidities for as long as 19 days. In fact only those spores held at 100 per cent relative humidity were not viable at the end of 7 days. Apparently the removal of the lid from the dishes long enough to obtain the material necessary for the daily test had some influence on the viabil - ity of the spores. Similar results were noted at 25° C, especially at the medium relative humidities. The relation between the viability of the spores and the relative humidity at 25° C. was the same as at 30° except that the spores were viable for a longer period of time and over a greater range of relative humidities. At the end of 5 weeks a few spores were still viable at two of these relative humidities. . The results of the weekly germination tests obtained at the temperatures of 5°, 10°, 15°, and 20° C. are listed in Table 2. Comparing the results obtained with Physiologic Form IX with those previously reported for Physiologic Form III it would appear that the spores of Physiologic Form IX were viable over a longer period of time at all temperatures and relative humidities than Physiologic Form III. The method used for germinating the urediniospores of Physiologic Form IX may account in part for this differ - ence. However, the same general relation between the viabil - ity of the urediniospores and the relative humidity and tem - perature was maintained. Infection Tests. — In order to check the results of the germination tests, 6 plants were inoculated each week from material held at each temperature and at each relative humid - ity. The results are listed in Table 3 and for the most part are a complete check on the germination tests. While the number of pustules per leaf are not listed in the table, as a rule the higher the percentage of infection obtained the greater the number of pustules per leaf were recorded. As a rule infection was obtained when 10 per cent or more of the spores were viable. In some instances infection was not obtained when a higher per cent of spores were viable. These may be accounted for in part to the lack of proper conditions during incubation, cloudy weather, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 34 Table 3. — Number of plants out of 6 infected with urediniospores of Puccinia graminis tritici Physiologic Form IX after being exposed to various temperatures and relative humidities for different periods of time Z ~* T~. T~T~s~T~s £33 3 I s |71 s 1 s - S£S_i_.&amp;u_)o_i_Sv_)_r_)_&gt;C}£ !&gt;,*****&gt;*&gt;**&gt;***»**_; "Sot? — __..■._ to t- oocto — _i co -. to to t- co u. — — - -. _ _ -. V. -. ___ .. t. ..... l _ _ _, _i _ C_ ----__ _ _ _ _______ _ cr , c _ -. -j _ _ -j _ «._._, —i -i _&gt; *. .. _&gt; _. &lt;£_:&lt; «.&lt;«:«.&lt;«. &lt;&lt;, &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;.&lt;&lt; &lt; Per cent 10° C. 100.0 |....|....|....|....|....!....l 89.9 ! 80.5 70.4 1 60.7 1 1 1 1 * 49.0 1 1 1 1 3 1 » 38.0 1 2 1 .... 4 2 1 29.5 2 21.5 1 10.5 0.0 I .... i I .... I .... I ■ Per cent W C. ,0 8 0 9-.9 . .H -"!■ '-I |"l I :: 80.6 .,..; I 70.4 60.7 3 1 2 1 1 » 49.0 2 . ... 1 2 1 2 1 2 2 1 * 38.0 1 , . . . Ill 1 2 1 3 4 2 1 4 29.5 1 1 1 2 21.6 I 10.5 | 0.0 1 j. ...1.-..I....1 1 Per cent 10° C . _ 100.0 ..I.... I 89.9 1 80.5 1 '.. 70.4 1 I 60.7 I 1 1 1 3 1 2 1 3 5 3 1 49.0 3 1 1 .... 1 .... i .... 1 4 .... 4 4 .... 1 38.0 3 . . . . 1 2 1 .... 4 29.5 2 .... 1 21.6 1 ' 10.6 1 ........ 1 0.0 ....I I Per cent 6° C 100.0 89.9 ... 1 1 1 80.5 1 4 : 70.4 3 .... 2 1 2 ... 5 4 .... 3 1 2 * 60.7 1 1 1 3 1 .... 1 5 .... 4 3 5 2 49.0 2 .... 2 3 6 .... 3 3 4 3 38.0 4 4 1 2 1 29.5 3 1 .... 1 21.5 2 .... 1 3 10.5 1 0.0 1 * Material exhausted. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Stem Rust in the Absence op an Alternate Host VIABILITY OF THE UREDINIOSPORES OF PHYSIOLOGIC FORM XXI Germination Tests. — In this experiment enough material was put into the dishes to last one year, when bimonthly ' tests were made. Only the temperatures of 5°, 10°, 15°, and 20° C. were employed together with the relative humidities between 29.5 and 70.4 per cent. This series of relative humidities has been previously referred to as the medium relative humidities. The results of this experiment are listed in Table 4. A glance at the table shows that the same general relations exist as have been previously pointed out; namely, with increasing temperature the viability of the spores decreases ' irrespectively of the relative humidities at which the spores are maintained. At any stated temperature the viability of the spores is greatest at the medium relative humidities, while the optimum for spore viability is at 49.0 per cent relative humidity. The decline in the viability of the spores at the lower relative humidities is not as rapid as at the higher humidities, but nevertheless is faster than that at the medium relative humidities. It is interesting to note that urediniospores have been carried thru, under the con - ditions of the experiment, for 52 weeks at a temperature of 5° C. and at a relative humidity of 49.0 per cent. At the end of this period germination tests showed that 30 per cent or more of the spores were still viable. Infection Tests. — Greater care was observed in maintain - ing the proper conditions for incubation in this experiment. Artificial light was used during cloudy days. The number of plants inoculated was also increased from 6 to 12, and with more inoculum at hand all conditions for successful infection of the plants were as ideal as possible. As a consequence a very high percentage of infection was obtained thruout the • experiment. The results of this infection test are given in Table 5. In many instances it will be noted that the infection tests proved that the spores were viable for a longer period of time than was determined by means of the germination studies. As a rule, however, the same general results were obtained, which need not be discussed here except to point out that spores held at 5° C. and at 49.0 per cent relative humidity for 52 weeks produced a rather heavy infection on 2 out of 12 plants inoculated. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 34 .1 i i I I I a st^^_._ £C aa.JV ooos_ ©o = se coooo, © c. + © i £ N, __ I l_ 3 . «^;w*_ no i-njv © ©© ©o © © © © © ooccoi ©o+i |] 5 h , j — |-i I SJJ-WM «t J.OJV © = © ©© © c © ©© ©©©Jo, ©o fl |. I 5 -5 S^.W.W &lt;|| J.MJV occoo osc:s ©cs | © ©o+i I £ -i wi*.* 71 pijv ©oe.se 0 o o = ■= 0 = ='=' ="=+', I o &gt;. —J.- 3 -^ a I § -5- nj*a« ntwiJV © = = c = ©©o = © c©©©. 00+5 I J ■ i — -- _______ 1 — 1 _1 £ * ~^ , 1 •■ 2 =&gt;. bii*i« hi: j.hjv = = c = = == == ooi |oj ° I + I og-g fcC- 1 I U--C &gt; — — i -; •.« ~" in\ mm 91 J.'ijv = = = = = = = = ce&gt;|&lt; »H| i e£Z '&gt; _ . 1 — _ _ _t • - - _w .--. bv|.m.« |;:J'11V = = === = = = = &lt;+'! E- = _ - ; — '- 1. B c , Sis, «_|._t.« f«|V = = = = = == s'l*-l *+ *' t_"_. '_ _; ||g Bii^»Moi:J.ijjv = = = = = == «*+4 t- 4 - * | e . _ x -r &gt; _ . _ z = C ,M._M_(_.|.I1I. = = = = = == . • « -+_ . » + + " : . a-. 82 1 _ . - f + + C I + ' •- S^'^'--&gt;l\ = = = = = == . . 4 -__.+ ~ + + •C . — - — - . __ fe 4-4+4., +++ .a _ .,!*,.« 1,-i-uv .= = = = = ■ -• .. +* a _ &gt;- - _o-.-+ ; j- t ++_- . " - • 5 "-.. + ._+ • ? _,*,*!_J-11V = = = = = = t - =-- + - "- + -' I _ .__?. +_ + _____ s g »n*.,» na j-ijv ==== = 1 c -m *^+*„, . &gt; »t(.i.i.« wi j.ujv == = •-* .* - a -£ _: - 44-4. 4. - 1 - -*- * c ~ 'i_ . x- I +-» £.__ .5 m-Ma_g.ja.IY = = = I =- .. . 4-4 -I- , , ±± «_ &lt;; 4-+ j ++ __~ _ " — _ ' + 4--,4 |"g . - ~ snaa« || Jajiy - , ..44 . *** • ! E'S 5.2 S 1 +4.4-4 '- -+ Eg __ I - _._ _ _ V +4-4-4+ + -+:-?£ £c --: si)i«a_ j 1 jaljv ==«! 4- + T + 4 t+, 8. e_ ~ ,__ . _______ i______ ____ s » il • V *4 4-+-i ++++ |«_ _ M ~ _ !,n,aaa_ UI ja. JV = + +« » ++ + --4 .__ + + * J|JS§ i&gt;, ; _ — . . _ _ I — j . — . . — ■- — ■ a j- o t» u ."S -t- + + +-*- + -» +J-+4 + + +++ E^uo -3 H—» -WV :. +++ l t +j , ■ « A+++ +++++ t *_%.l __ 1 — 7-j ! — a2s° - ■i ! SH*»9 JJ1JV 1 1 1+ + '+ + 4-4 f + 4«+, - + «+« " = 0°° l_. j: + ' + I l-Z-to Il 1 + 4-4.4-4! 4.--.4- , + 4+4 fl £ 1 n ir , ""'" wv " + "+ + tt-+' +ttt + i +++++ 11° h S j — _ ; ; JH H ll 8 -.^9-1 l^^o,«j« ]Uw* !-.«.cc« ? "* aiouintOJddv _? t-o-fs-w b t-S-rw« t r-«s«*p;N! 5 t-«"^«N ii o, '_, a, a, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Stem Rust in the Absence of an Alternate Host Table 5.; — Number of plants out of 12 infected with the uredinio - spores of Puccinia graminis tritici Physiologic Form XXI after being exposed to various temperatures and relative humidities for different periods of time 1 J? jj 1 _.. J. jj 5 jj jj jj 3 jj jj 1 J~ q $$S_,_)uv_)_)woS_Sq_. Ex*** ****.* »*»**»* *a».ti« ** • °° O N •* W flO O N *&lt;f W 00 N S -J-n H ' ft . — --. CJ W N W C_iO l. ■— — *- la (. i. i- t. __. u t- t. u (_ (_■ 1_ __• o^.e a a a a a a a a a . a a a a aa &lt;£_=&lt;&lt;&lt; &lt; ' &lt; &lt; &lt; &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; &lt;&lt; Per cent 10° C 70.4 1514 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 60.7 8 6 13 18 13 1 49.0 9 I 5 73212 1 3 I. 2 1 : 38.0 97 5610 8313 62 29.5 19 12 8 1 7 I 7 I 9 I 1 I _ I I Per cenl tS° C. 70.4 10 4 1 8 | 4 1 5 3 60.7 8 2 6 11 11 11 1 3 12 3 2 1 49.0 10 3 3 9 11 12 12 I 9 5 6 4 2 2 1 38.0 85 4 99 1243 74 5 13 29.5 8 7 4 3 12 12 I 11 I 7 9 6 11 17 Per cent 10° C. 70.4 12 7 2 7-1 11 II 4 4 5 1 2 1 2 60.7 6 3 3 U 12 12 12 12 8 11 10 8 9 I 49.0 7 5 4 10 12 12 11 11 12 11 12 11 9 3 38.0 4 4 12 10 11 11 11 12 7 10 11 9 6 29.5 .2 2 5 11 12 12 10 I 9 11 I 10 12 6 I II 1 Per cent 6° C 70.4 6 1 3 2 10 10 11 10 I 10 1 6 5 4 3 ..... 60.7 2 2 4 8 12 12 12 12 12 8 11 10 9 4- 49.0' 1 2 8 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 7 11 12 9 2 38.0 0 2 1 1 11 12 10 11 12 3 6 10 10 1 29.6 2 6 6 8 10 8 11 7 1 11 3 8 3 'Temperatures in greenhouse too high lor good incubation and subsequent infection. Experi - ment discontinued until (all. DISCUSSION The writer is unable to offer any explanation of the under - lying principle involved in this study nor is he able to cor - relate the results obtained with what actually happens under field conditions other than what was stated in a preliminary report.' The results of this study indicate a convenient method for holding rust material over a long period with a considerable saving in time and insuring the purity of the Physiologic Forms, especially when a large number are being carried on stock plants in the greenhouse. Further it solves the problem of carrying rust thru the summer, when the green - house temperatures are exceedingly high. ' &gt;L. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 34 For example during the season of 1924, approximately 140 collections of Puccinia graminis tritici were made in Nebraska. As this material was collected it was sent directly to Lincoln, where the collections were immediately placed in the chambers previously described, maintained at approx - imately 49.0 per cent relative humidity. These dishes were placed in a cold storage room held at near 5° C. This material was held in this room until the outside tem - peratures were low enough so that fairly constant green - house temperatures could be maintained. Stock from these rust collections was then built up when time permitted, and was extended well on into January. Of the 140 collections, only about 10 per cent were lost thru storage. When a Physiologic Form was obtained from any of the collected material, it was immediately put away in the chambers in cold storage, so that the purity of these forms could be maintained. The amount of routine labor saved in not having to carry these forms continually in the green - house can only be appreciated by those who have had to do this work. SUMMARY 1. The influence of relative humidity and temperature on the viability of the urediniospores of two Physiologic Forms of Puccinia graminis tritici has been determined. 2. The same general relation between the viability, of the urediniospores and the relative humidity and temperature was found, namely, that the lower the temperature the longer the spores retained their viability at all relative humidities, while at any stated temperature the spores were viable the longest at the medium humidities. 3. Urediniospores of Physiologic Form XXI held at 49.0 per cent relative humidity and maintained at a temperature of 5° C. when tested for germination at the end of 1 year yielded 30 per cent germination and produced a heavy infec - tion on 2 out of 12 plants. 4. The application of this method for the storing of rust material for long periods is discussed. 14 M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>