<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twelfth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR For the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">£ A. 1 I J * OF THE Nebraska State Hospital AT INGLESIDE, NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR For the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE BOARD OF CONTROL Hon. E. B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings Chairman Hon. Addison Wait Secretary of State, Secretary Hon. Walter A. George State Treasurer Hon. Grant G. Martin Attorney General RESIDENT OFFICERS IB. Kern, M. D i. W. James . Superintendent Steward Geo. B. Alexander Accountant MEDICAL STAFF W. B. Kern, M. D Superintendent F. H. Kuegle, M. D Assistant Superintendent C. A. Oa'-ces.M. D Second Assistant Physician G. M. White, M. D Third Assistant Physician A. J. Chapman, M. D Fourth Assistant Physician H. G. Maul, M. D Pathologist </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1 0 iltS FjXC&amp;Ll€YlCy j \yrlG&amp;t€T /I • A.KtTlPn f \jf)WTTlOT OJ IS €OTQ&amp;KQ, Dear Sir: In compliance with legal requirements I submit herewith the twelfth biennial report of this institution, the Nebraska State Hospital at Ingleside, for the biennial period ending November 30, 1912. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION On December 1, 1910, there were being cared for in this institution ten hundred sixty-one (1,061) patients, six hundred ninety-three (693) males and three hundred sixty-eight (368) females. During the biennium four hundred thirty-one (431) patients were admitted, of whom two hundred eighty (280) were males and one hundred fifty-one (151) females. In addi - tion to this, two hundred eighty-nine (289) patients, (one hun - dred eighty-eight (188) males and one hundred one (101) females, have been returned from parole. During the biennium one hundred sixty-five (165) have been discharged as recoverd, thirty-seven (37) improved, and three (3) unimproved, eighty - six (86) are on parole at this time, eleven (11) on the escaped list, and one hundred fifteen (115) males and sixty (60) females have died, leaving six hundred ninety (690) males and three hundred eighty-one (381) females, or a total of ten hundred seventy-one (1,071) patients in the institution today. § During this biennium a daily average of ten hundred fifty - (1,059) patients has been maintained, at a daily average capita cost as follows: Maintenance (only) 34 cents Officers' salaries and employees' wages ... 17 cents Total 51 cents GENERAL HEALTH AND SANITARY CONDITIONS I During this biennial period the general health of the in - s has been excellent, and the sanitary conditions of the in - tion in all its various departments is exceptionally good. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">252 IMPROVEMENTS A large number of very important improvements have been made in and about the institution during the biennial period just closed, a few of the more important ones being as follows: [A new food tunnel seven (7) feet wide by seven (7) feet all under ground, and approximately sixteen hundred •0) feet long, connecting the general kitchen with the various ital and ward buildings, and providing a means of conveying s from the general kitchen to th6 various departments, in the most satisfactory way. Electric food elevators ite between the floor of this tunnel and the various hospital ward buildings, also a large electric food elevator operates een the floor of the tunnel and the general kitchen, which ere it complete in every detail. I The refrigerating system in the cold storage department been overhauled and remodeled, and is at present in first condition and giving very excellent service. iA large and important pathological laboratory has been )lished, in which much modern and up-to-date work of a ological and laboratory kind is being done. RA new and well equipped X-ray department has been in - lled, provided with a new and up-to-date Western Static Ehine, a large modern Scheidel-Western X-ray coil, and all r equipments necessary to make such a department com - 2 in every detail, and at this time the best possible work in line is being done. I Five years ago we equipped the floors and wainscoting of bath rooms and lavatories throughout the first and second rs of the institution with the best vitreous tiling, which adds only very greatly to the general appearance of these depart - its, but to their sanitary condition as well. This improve - it was taken up again early in the present biennium, and the aining bath rooms and lavatories, including all the basement top floor wards, have been remodeled and tiled in the most lern and sanitary way. In addition to the large amount of h room and lavatory tiling, there has also been installed con - rable vitreous tiling in many of the vestibules and ap - iches to the various wards, including a few of the smaller </seg>
            <seg id="p005">253 Many of the wards in the institution have been remodeled redecorated and greatly improved. The large substantial ward occupied by filthy and untidy male patients has been very largely overhauled, and the transfer halls immediately adjacent to the bath rooms and lavatories tiled in harmony therewith, the tiling and finishing of these transfer halls adding very greatly to the general appearance of this department, and has also made it possible to keep the ward very neat and clean, and the sanitary condition therein is greatly improved. tTwo new hydrotherpy departments have been installed, in connection with the female sick ward, the other in con - ion with the large sick ward in the male department of the ital. These departments have also been tiled, and finished very sanitary way, and are proving very satisfactory. 1A new laundry building has been erected and equipped, and been in operation since October 14, of this year. This is of the best, most satisfactory and up-to-date laundries in middle west, and is complete in every detail, equipped with and modern machinery throughout, and will answer the Is of the institution for many years to come. KThe exterior of all the institution buildings has been re - ted with two coats of paint, and presents a very much im - ed appearance. A new carpenter and paint shop, thirty-six by seventy-eight (36x78) feet, and two story, has been completed, the first floor being occupied as a carpenter and repair shop, while the second floor is occupied by the painter and decorator, an addition which has been much needed for many years. tA small canning factory was installed at the beginning of season and did a very liberal amount of good work, putting ight (8) gallons of peaches," ninety-five (95) gallons of plums, hundred sixty-seven (167) gallons of apple jelly and four sand three hundred and thirty-two (4,332) gallons of apples. iA new circulating library with five hundred fifty (550) mes has been installed, and is patronized and very much eciated by a large number of patients in the hospital. i Approximately fifteen thousand (15,000) additional square of manufactured stone walk, and five thousand (5,000) r feet of heavy manufactured stone curbing has been in- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">254 t^ small brick addition to the general kitchen building has erected, and the kitchen proper remodeled and repaired, the floor and wainscoting finished with a vitreous tile, ig very greatly to its general appearance and sanitary con- IAn additional sick ward in the male department of the pital has been installed and equipped, giving increased room the care of recent, acute and invalid patients. K Approximately twelve (12) acres have been added to the about the institution, and during the biennium five thousand ►0) trees have been set out, nearly all at this time in good healthy condition. The old green house, for many years occupied by the vege - table gardener for the purpose of starting plants required in that department for the early season, has been torn down and rebuilt in another and more desirable location, and very much enlarged. KA large additional silo adjacent to the dairy barn has been .lied this year, giving the institution two silos, each with parity of about one hundred eighty (180) tons. A new Kirker-Bender fire escape has been installed at the new Northeast Annex, making in all five (5) Kirker-Bender escapes, providing the institution in all its various departments with ample protection. A new and much needed hot water heating plant has just recently been installed at the Farm Cottage, and is giving very excellent service. I The old building formerly occupied as a laundry has been xieled and converted into living rooms for nurses and em - ees who formerly occupied rooms on the various wards of institution. This plan is not only a very desirable improve - t and convenience so far as the comfort of the nurses and loyees are concerned, but at the same time increases the icity of the institution somewhat by permitting the rooms the various wards, formerly occupied by nurses and em - cees, to be used for the care and comfort of additional insane A storage building, twenty-four by forty-eight (24x48) feet, and two story, has been built just northwest of the general store building, for the purpose of storing in large quantities salt, lime </seg>
            <seg id="p007">255 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE and cement on the first floor, and mattresses and other supplies on the second floor. Within the past few months we have effected an arrange - ment with the C., B. &amp; Q. Railway Company, by which the Ingleside station is placed on their freight list, hence freight shipped over the Burlington line to the institution is delivered on the institution switch at Ingleside at the Hastings freight rate. This arrangement dispenses with the former expensive and laborious plan of draying between the city and the in - stitution, and the extra handling of supplies. A new machinery building, thirty-six by eighty (36x80) feet, for the housing of the entire stock of farm machinery, wagons, etc., has been erected, and is one of the very substantial but inexpensive improvements. This building is provided with a second story, which is used for the purpose of storing alfalfa. 1A poultry department has been added during the biennium, has progressed very nicely, furnishing, in a very liberal way, kens and eggs for the institution. AMUSEMENTS I A new and up-to-date moving picture machine has been in - ed in our amusement hall, and a better class of shows is g given for the benefit of patients than ever before. The eside Athletic Park has been rearranged and enlarged, pro - •d with a new and substantial enclosure, and the grand d, very much improved and enlarged, has at present a seat - capacity of about fifteen (1,500) hundred. During the past on an excellent base ball team was maintained, which formed ;ry prominent part in the regular entertainments and amuse - its. The usual amount of orchestra and band work, in addition to other amusements and entertainments, has been carried on during the biennium, and at this time, the close of this biennial period, the institution has perhaps the best orchestra and the most efficient and capable musical director and organizer it has had in a number of years. NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION The institution is at this time very much in need of an additional detached building, modernly constructed and equipped for the care of female patients. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">256 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT A modern tubercular hospital cottage for the care of tuber - cular insane is very much needed. Such a building, modernly constructed and equipped, located a reasonable distance from the institution proper, with a capacity of one hundred (100) beds, would add not only very greatly to the general comfort of the tubercular insane, of which there is always a large number in every institution, but would also be very beneficial in way of preventing tubercular infection in other and recently admitted and acute mental cases cared for in the hospital. tThe institution is very much in need of an additional half on of land. This could be operated in a very satisfactory profitable way, and without the employment of additional CONCLUSION I In conclusion I desire to express my earnest appreciation the efficiency and loyalty of our steward and accountant, physicians constituting our medical staff, the various heads the departments, and all other employees who have so wil - fly and efficiently performed their respective duties, and who re contributed such valuable assistance in the successful nagement of the institution. tTo his Excellency, the Governor, and to the individual ibers of the board of control, I wish to acknowledge my ation and to assure each of my earnest appreciation of the tesies and assistance extended me in the management of institution. Respectfully, W. B. Kern, M. D., Superintendent. LAND AND BUILDINGS L«nd On section land, less C, B. &amp; Q. right-of-way. . $80,000.00 Buildings Administration building 115,000.00 First wing, north 45,000.00 First wing, south 45,000.00 The Humphrey building (second wing north) 85,000.00 The Crounse building 85,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">257 South annex North annex N. E. annex 80,000.00 85,000.00 55,000.00 45,000.00 35,000.00 40,000.00 50,000.00 22,000.00 Cottage building, rear center Bakery building Nurses cottage (old laundry building) Amusement hall building New laundry building Driving horse barn . 6,000.00 2,000.00 Carpenter and paint shop building Night watch cottage 22,500.00 8,500.00 2,800.00 6,000.00 2,500.00 1,000.00 Farm cottage Horse barn at farm cottage Dairy barn and annexes. . Hog house Slaughter house and equipment One (1) silo 400.00 One (1) silo (new) Two (2) greenhouses 450.00 4,000.00 . 2,000.00 30,000.00 One (1) gardener's greenhouse (rebuilt and new). Engine, boiler and cold storage buildings Additional Buildings Barns, poultry and incubator houses, granaries, vegetable cellars and storage buildings, reser - voir, air-lift wells, stand pipe and fire equip - ment, food tunnel, manufactured stone walks, curbings, crossings, etc., and other permanent improvements 66,102.75 Total $1,021,252.75 Value of Stock, Machinery, Furniture, Supplies, Etc., on Hand December 1, 1912 Farm, dairy, live stock, driving horse barn, etc Lock, driving horse barn, etc $29,840.15 Machinery and supplies in laundry 11,007.10 Machinery, tools and supplies in engine room 66,917.30 Supplies and furniture in administration offices 2,544.10 Supplies and fixtures in store room, cold storage, etc 17,245.95 Supplies and fixtures in bakery and kitchen 5,426.58 5,426.58 Furniture and supplies on female wards 24,612.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">258 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Furniture and supplies on male wards 41,817.92 Furniture and supplies on administration building. . 8,133.91 Furniture and supplies on cottage 1,242.05 Furniture and supplies on employees' dining room . . 1,019.30 Supplies and fixtures in greenhouses, station and barber shop 4,738.94 Fixtures and supplies in sewing room 1,445.34 Furniture and fixtures in amusement hall 2,033.85 Furniture and fixtures in night watch cottage 3,187.62 Drug room, laboratory and X-ray room 6,275.12 Supplies and fixtures in paint shop and carpenter shop 2,494.29 Garden tools, vegetables and canned fruit 5,182.50 Total $235,164.35 STEWARD'S CASH REPORT Balance with state treasurer, December 1, 1910 $3,161.00 Cash on hand December 1, 1910 76.16 Cash received from labor on tunnel 1,830.40 Cash received from other sources 11,713.60 $16,781.16 Expended $14,717.64 Balance with state treasurer 1,546.20 Cash on hand 517.32 $16,781.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 259 n-noooooto© ■ I •* . I I ~ -»• -w ■»- •_- v _^ a I _-T,_r ■ * CO «C - IO — •» ■ •» 2 U % fe : : ::::::: S5 f 3 30 * C4 3". o Is £•:::::::::» B H » : I IOMO O O O Om O O 4 o w '32 ■ 5 z ?L^L~ * ■o St-OOOOOOOO I rt •OOOOOOOOO I (O c — ad aiujiflioooioooo a d c 6! SS S ©ooooooooo o S?y3 oooooooooo o d OOOOOOOOOO O OOOOtjiOOOXO M s 1 -. 15? O. H&lt;ia«NN))MHd "3 » I . ■Si, I S5§§§§§ lo te O M l o&lt; * a ! ■x. • 3o a rt to.-." t- &lt;j pa||s- ; : : s x 1 I ....;.. &gt;. fi v: ii c S on • m ?, c I « : : ; g.- ■ : :.« | a &lt; f ft o £ C I "O I xt*6od6dxdd E-i ei o &lt;c so co d m co ~* o ' to b : b"s ■&lt; -.-"caeca. | I iiliiif|i itliJiliJi j IlifiJiMii </seg>
            <seg id="p012">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 260 SEWING ROOM REPORT Articles Made in Sewing Room During Biennium Ending November 30, 1912 IS » 543 Night gowns 636 Eies' drawers. . l's drawers . . . . 1*1 night shirts i's undershirts l's shirts 732 684 176 320 885 Kies' underskirts ;ts 669 5,098 2,261 » Pillow cases Door curtains 27 Transom curtains Shelf curtains 102 66 Screen curtains 36 Window curtains, pairs Stand covers 1,211 904 Ker towels le towels 626 2,817 K rating towels le cloths 204 438 Napkins 676 Burial suits (complete) Burial squares 54 12 Camesoles 13 Ladies' neckties Bibs (feeding) . Dresser scarfs . Commode scarfs Pillow shams 138 200 107 121 284 Rubber sheets 46 Sofa pillows and covers for pillows Rubber pillow ticks 1,847 t IB </seg>
            <seg id="p013">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 261 Pillow ticks (ticking) Curtain straps 36 896 Tea towels Bonnets 2,125 90 Comforters «7 Ei mattress i mended dry bags robes 375 439 56 2 Candy bags 2,247 Sacks mending 562 Miscellaneous articles repaired Piano cover 4,535 1 Eird table cover board scarfs . . bination scarfs ating gowns . ps' underwaists 1 -1 30 36 329 FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCTS Alfalfa 440 tons Cane hay Millet . . 188 tons 245 tons Oats hay tons i Corn ensilage Ear corn .... 620 tons 125 bushels 1,609 bushels Rice corn Onions . 20 bushels 172 bushels Potatoes 5,248 bushels Kitoes, sweet bage 115 bushels 66,583 pounds Greens 440 bushels Green peppers Sweet corn . . . 36 bushels 6,522 dozen Lettuce 30 bushels 227 bushels 32 dozen 1,050 bushels Eiflower dps </seg>
            <seg id="p014">262 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Carrots 194 bushels Pumpkins 2,690 bushels 2,990 bushels Watermelons 3,163 bushels Pumpkins 2,690 Squash 2,990 Watermelons 3,163 Muskmelons 1,191 Tomatoes 353 bushels Chard 551 bushels Beans 373 bushels Radishes with tops 262 bushels Radishes, winter, without tops 68 bushels Parsnips 750 bushels Egg plant 170 bushels Rhubarb 130 bushels Cucumbers 2,081 dozen Green onions 271 bushels Veal, 83 head Pork, 255 head 8,539 pounds 72,147 pounds Milk 131,130 gallons Chickens 3,400 Eggs 3,744 dozen MONTHLY ADMISSION OF PATIENTS Admitted During the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 Months Male Female Totals December 1910 12 4 16 January, 1911 13 3 16 February 11 7 18 March 15 5 20 April 11 7 18 - Mav 16 7 23 July 6 11 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">263 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE « 3 s 8 9 13 .) September October 8 11 11 19 E ember jmber &gt;s 14 IS 27 January, 1912 February 12 19 &lt; 13 6 4 8 19 S h 9 o 12 20 s 11 10 21 15 20 :&gt; 16 23 ( August 16 24 8 a 6 6 IS September October 15 15 10 November 10 1H 280 Total 151 RESIDENCE OF PATIENTS BY COUNTIES Admitted During the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 Male Female Totals Adams 14 9 2 4 Box Butte 9 4 Boone '1 t Bovd 1 29 Buffalo 17 12 Butler 6 4 Chase 3 Cheyenne 4 Clay 4 11 i 19 9 Dawson o : Douglas •&gt; ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p016">264 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT r niniore / 1 y Franklin 2 5 7 Frontier 4 4 8 Furnas 5 3 8 Garfield 2 2 4 _ Gosper 1 3 4 Grant 1 1 2 Greeley 3 . 3 Hall 25 14 39 Hamilton 7 2 9 Harlan 5 6 11 Hayes 2 2 4 Hitchcock 2 . . 2 Howard 6 1 7 Jefferson 7 6 13 Kimball 2 2 4 Kearney 4 2 6 Keith 3 1 4 Lancaster 1 1 Lincoln 6 3 9 Madison 1 . . 1 Merrick 3 1 4 Morrill 2 .. 2 Nance 8 1 9 Nuckolls 17 7 24 Pawnee 1 . 1 Phelps 7 4 11 Perkins 4 4 Polk 5 6 11 Red Willow 8 2 10 Scotts Bluff 6 1 7 Sioux 2 2 Sherman 4 3 7 n Thayer , 4 6 10 Valley 4 3 7 Webster 9 3 12 Wheeler 2 2 York 9 9 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 265 AGE OF PATIENTS WHEN ADJUDGED INSANE Admitted During the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 Years Male Female Totals 1 . 1 Between 10 to 15 Between 15 to 25 Between 25 to 35 Between 35 to 45 Between 45 to 55 Between 55 to 65 Between 65 to 75 Between 75 to 85 Between 85 to 90 44 12 56 72 27 99 56 33 89 47 31 78 27 17 44 21 17 38 10 13 23 2 1 3 Total 280 151 431 FORMS OF DISEASE OF PATIENTS Admitted During Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 Disease Male Female Totals I. Infective Exhaustive Psychosis 4 2 6 1. (a) Allied to infective exhaustive psychosis 4 4 ■ Intoxication Psychosis 1. Alcoholic (a) Pathological alcoholism 8 8 (b) Acute hallucinosis 1 . 1 (c) Chronic alcoholism 1. Mania 4 1 5 2. Hypochondriacal and de- pressed states 2 . 2 3. Dementia 1 . . 1 4. Pseudo paresis 2 2 (d) Paranoiac states 6 6 2. (a) Morphine psychosis 2 . . 2 (b) Cocaine psychosis 1 . . 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">266 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Disease Male Female Totals t3. Post puerperal psychosis Organic Psychosis 1 1 1. (a) Cerebral syphilitic psychosis (b) Arterio sclerotic psychosis . (c) Post paralytic psychosis. 5 3 1 i 10 4 (d) Traumatic psychosis 2. Senile dementia et deleria 3 Paresis 2 1 27 30 13 2 I Dementia Praecox Group 1. Hebephrenic 2. Katatonic 3. Paranoid 29 24 I . 3 3 21 14 I Manic Depressive Group 1. Manic states 2. Depressed states 3. Mixed states m 18 6 ■ I 8 2 (a) Allied to manic depressive psychosis 11 11 I Anxiety Psychosis L Involution melancholia. 2. Agitated melancholia. . 3 1 4 I f. Other Depressed States 1. Simple depression 2. Symptomatic depression . 3. Depressive hallucinosis 16 1 1 6 ■ 7 II. Paranoiac States 1. Simple paranoia 2. Hallucinatory paranoia 3. Erotic 7 3 2 5 12 § Epileptic States 1. Mania 2. Melancholia. . . 3. Dementia 8 1 7 3 ■ 1 X. PSYCHOGENIC NEUROSES 1. Hysterical psychosis. . . 2. Psychasthenic psychosis 4 3 1 '! XI. Development Defects 1 Idiocv 1 1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">267 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE Disease Male Female Totals 2. Imbecility a) High grade . . . 4 3 (b) Middle and low grade 14 9 23 3. Constitutional inferiority 1 1 XII. Unclassified 2 2 1. Convict-moral degenerate 2 . . 2 2. Juvenile delinquent — Bad habits. 1 . 1 3. (a) Locomotor ataxia — Irritable 9 ■&gt; temper (b) Locomotor ataxia Modified morals 1 1 c) Locomotor ataxia — Cum paranoia 1 1 Total 280 151 431 CAUSES OF DEATH OF PATIENTS Occurring During the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 Male Female Totals Acute appendicitis 2 . . 8 Acute diletation of the heart 3 1 4 Acute cholecystitis 1 1 Acute cystitis 1 1 Acute nephritis 1 . 1 Eic regurgitation 1 . . 1 rio sclerosis 5 . . 5 inoma of the esophagus 1 . . 1 Carcinoma of the stomach 1 1 Carcinoma of the liver 1 1 Cerebral hemmorrhage 3 9 12 .Cirrhosis of the liver 1 1 Choked on meat 1 . . 1 Chronic nephritis 2 3 5 Chronic myocarditis 2 . . 2 1~v i ■* 4 O </seg>
            <seg id="p020">268 Male Female Totals Epileptic exhaustion 6 . . 6 Exhaustion from psychosis 9 9 Gastro intestinal intoxication 2 . 2 General tuberculosis 1 . 1 Glandular tuberculosis 1 . . 1 Hasmophilia 1 . . 1 Hemiplegia '. 3 2 5 Inanition 4 . . 4 Influenza 1 1 Intestinal obstruction 2 . . 2 Ischio rectal abscess 1 . . 1 Killed by train 1 . . 1 Manic depressive psychosis 7 . . 7 Miliary tuberculosis 1 . 1 Mitral heart disease 3 1 4 Myocarditis 1 1 Paresis 7 3 10 n Pericarditis 1 1 2 Peritonitis • 1 . . 1 Pneumonia 2 3 5 Pulmonary abscess 1 . . 1 Pulmonary congestion 1 . . 1 Pulmonary tuberculosis 15 11 26 Pyaemia 1 1 Senile terminal infection 23 10 33 Septicaemia 2 . . 2 Strangulated hernia 1 . . 1 Tubercular enteritis 1 . . 1 Typhoid fever 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">269 NATIVITY OF PATIENTS Admitted During the Biennial Period Ending November 30, 1912 United States Males Females Totals Alabama 1 ! Arkansas 1 Colorado 9 District of Columbia 1 1 Illinois 34 21 18 1 Indiana 8 10 Iowa 35 9 Kansas 6 3 Kentucky 4 3 &lt; Maine 1 ! Massachusetts 1 Michigan 8 4 12 2 Minnesota 1 1 Missouri 8 3 11 Nebraska 58 22 Nevada 1 1 New Hampshire 1 New York 9 5 14 Ohio :.. 9 9 18 Oklahoma 1 1 Pennsylvania 10 17 i Rhode Island 1 ! South Dakota 1 Tennessee 1 Virginia 4 4 8 Vermont 1 West Virginia 1 1 Wisconsin 7 3 l J i Wyoming 1 Total 208 114 Unknown </seg>
            <seg id="p022">270 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT NATIVITY OF PATIENTS Foreign Countries Male Female Totals Austria 3 . . 3 Bohemia 8 2 10 Canada 5 . . 5 Denmark 6 4 10 England 3 1 4 Germany 17 14 31 Finland • 2 . . 2 Greece 1 .. 1 Ireland 6 .. 6 Luxemburg 1 . . 1 Moravia 1 . . 1 Norway 2 • Poland 3 1 4 Russia 1 1 2 Scotland 1 .. . 1 Sweden 9 5 14 Syria 1 l T» ulCo ■ ,. X X Total 70 30 100 Total of United States .208 114 322 Total foreign born 70 30 100 Total unknown 2 7 9 Total 280 151 431 Occupation of Patients Male Female Totals Auto liveryman 1 • . . 1 Baker : 1 . . 1 Bartender 1 . . 1 Boiler maker 1 . . 1 Carpenter 8 . . 8 Car repairer 1 . . 1 Convict 7 . . 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE 271 Male Female Totals Domestic 16 16 Druggist 1 .. 1 Editor and printer 1 . . 1 Engineer 1 . . 1 Farming 151 . . 151 Gambler 1 . . 1 Gunsmith 1 . . 1 Hair dresser 1 1 Hotel porter 2 . . 2 Housekeeper 109 109 Inmate Soldiers' Home 4 .. 4 Laborer 48 . . 48 Laundress 2 2 Lawyer 1 . . 1 Machinist 2 . . • 2 Market gardener 1 . . 1 Merchant 1 . . 1 Miller 1 .. 1 Musician 2 . . 2 None 13 . . 13 Nurse 1 1 Physician 3 . . 3 Railroad conductor 1 . . 1 Railroad brakeman 3 . . 3 Real estate agent 3 . . 3 Salesman 2 . . 2 School teacher 2 6 8 School boy 1 . . 1 Section hand 1 . . 1 Shoe cobbler 1 . . 1 Stenographer • 2 2 Stockman 2 J Tailor 1 . . 1 Telegraph operator 1 1 Tree trimmer 1 . . 1 Unknown 13 13 Woodworker 1 . . 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">272 Hereditary Causes Predisposing to an Unstable Nervous System of 'Neuropathic Constitution" Male Female Totals Percent Psychopathic forebear 48 11 59 13.7 Alcoholic forebear 32 • 23 55 12.8 Syphilitic forebear 5 5 10 2.3 Epileptic forebear 7 :. 7 1.6 Neurotic forebear 10 7 17 3.9 imbecile forebear 2 4 6 1.4 Forebear suffering from malnatri tion or a debilitated condition at the time of conception from tuberculosis, old age, excessive venery, etc 5 7 12 2.8 Youthful forebear (prior to maturity) 1 . . 1 .3 Consanguinity in forebears 2 2 4 .9 No Known Heredity Predis posing Cause 168 92 260 60.3 Total 280 151 431 100.0 Direct or Exciting Cause of Psychosis of Patients Male Female Totals Percent Shock or crisis in the life of an individual inheriting a "neu- ropathic constitution" 112 59 171 39.8 Alcoholism 44 6 50 11.6 Syphilis 29 5 34 8 Arterior Sclerosis 33 25 58 13.4 Acute infections 2 8 10 2.3 Chronic infections 5 2 7 1.6 Drug habitue 4 . . 4 .9 Traumitism 10 3 13 3 Unknown 41 43 84 19.4 Total 280 151 431 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">273 HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, INGLESIDE Civil Conditions of Patients Male Female Totals 149 34 Widower Widowed Unknown 87 83 17 31 31 27 s 13 o Total 280 151 Religion of Patients Male Female Toa|ts 155 104 259 Protestant Catholic . Adventist 104 259 46 15 61 •1 9. 1 9 Christian Science Spiritualist 2 1 74 1 None 28 Unknown 3 3 Total 2*0 151 Educat on of Patients Male Female Totals Collegiate 5 2 i 10 34 44 K 131 73 204 118 25 143 Illiterate Unknown 16 8 9 24 9 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p026">274 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT The Wasserman React on in 100 Cases of Psychosis Disease Positive Negative Totals Alcoholic paresis 1 1 Arterio sclerotic psychosis 1 1 Cerebral syphilis with psychosis 2 '2 Chronic alcoholism 1 1 Chronic chorea 1 1 Congenital imbecility 4 . . 4 Dementia praecox 28 28 Epilepsy 16 16 Locomotorataxia 2 1 3 Manic depressive psychosis 3 3 Organic dementia 5 6 11 Paranoia 1 1 Paresis 15 . . 15 Secondary dementia with epithelioma. .1 . . 1 Senile dementia 5 5 Toxic depression with multiple neuritis ... 1 1 Toxic depression with plandular tuber- culosis 1 1 Unclassified 14 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">HOSPITAL FOR INSANE, [NGLGSIDE 275 o S I ■ -n I- «z c II 00 t~ ?! El ■ -x ■•■•••»•• 1"N 3i -w 2&amp; 01 ~ &gt; 2 2 o II © • ■ tow « ■ ■ MN ■2 &lt;eonu3MO9)MX&gt;a t--^&gt; 10 tt x w* re n •-&gt; t cc —i rnj: CT&gt; 00 z ; &gt;» . x S . C so : : : £ : g : :.2 : g : : : : :5 :.2 : :S : " S^ ; H? 1 Ml &amp; tlliiiisl lii IIIIIlIllll i </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>