<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA HFOR THE TWO ENDING NOVEMBER- 30, 1908 1908 THE WOODRUFF-COLLINS PRESS Lincoln, Neb., I </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ADVISORY HOARD Mrs. J. C. F. McKbwoit, President Mrs. Callen Thomnoh, Secretary Mrs. Clara S. Caksi addkn Lincoln Mrs. Dr. Towmi Mrs. Dr. Wilcox HKH i I y ■) H V. I \ TITUTION Lkna E. Ward Superintendent W. K. LOUQHUDGE BUDE B. \V\KD Physician Matn-n KM l'l.i H K&gt; M. Kvki.yn MSI kii Nettik K. Ad \ Myrta Hili.iv&gt; Chris Glbisbbb&lt; irv and Teacher Sewing Teacher Kndneer Milt Loyitt Omaha Hul&gt;t&gt;e]l </seg>
            <seg id="p003">able Board of Public Lands and Building--. Lincoln, .\ebr. : rlt it with pleasure that I herewith submit for your considera - the tenth biennial report of the Nebraska Industrial Home, located at Milford. Nebr., for the two years ending November 30, 1908. And I desire to express my warmest gratitude to you. individ - ually and collectively, for the many kindnesses and courtesies, which you have shown me. Whatever degree of success may have been made, I feel, is ly due to the prompt and hearty support which you have given me. and to the faithful, and earnest work of those who have labored here, in the Home, with me. Trusting that our work may meet with your approval, 1 am Very respectfully yours, </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">The Nebraska Industrial Home was located at liilford, Nebr., twenty years ago. During this time over seven hundred horn. penitent girls have sought the shelter and care of the Home. Perhaps no institution in the state has been rely criti - cised or spoken of so unkindly as has this Home. But we believe that this is due to the fact, thai so many do not understand the in - tent or purpose of the Home, or the class of girls we have in the Home. This is not a home for bad women, as many suppose, bat is a home for homeless, penitent girls, who have not or who cannot receive the proper home training, and who are liable to be led into sin and vice, if not cared for. Then many of our girls come from good homes, where they have l&gt;een carefully trained. l&gt;ut who have hail to leave their h&lt; while yet too young, either that they might have better school ad - vantages, or as is the case many times, to earn a living for them - ami sometimes to help support a nunil&gt;er of younger brothers and sisters at home. The majority of these girls are ignorant of the ways of this world and have no idea of the wickedness there is in the world, or of the hundreds of snares laid by cunning, vile men to rob the their virtue and womanhood, knowing full well, that it will 1&gt; and not they, who will have to bear all the suffering and shame. These girls are not had girls hut are simply poor, unfortunate creatures, who should l&gt;e pitied and not blamed. They come to this Home, feeling that everything in this world was lost, they have no friends, no home, and no money. The death angel would l&gt;e gladly received by many of them, and yet they fear death, for they feel that they have committed an unpardonable sin, and that in heaven there would l&gt;e no welcome for them. It is for such girls as these that the grand old state of Nebraska supports this Home. Here these poor creatures may come and re - ceive a welcome, and the encouragement, which they must have or they will go on down and down, until they have reached the very bottom of degradation and sin. For the world at large shows but very little sympathy for an unfortunate girl. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">402 Upon entering the Home each girl must %gnt to remain one year. During this time every possible effort is made to gi\ . .1. mental, moral, and spiritual training, so that, by the time her year is up. she is in every way letter prepared to right the battles of life. Then there are the poor helpless babes of these unfortunate girls. They are just as bright and innocent as any bftbM and, if placed in good homes, where they will have good Christian training, and where they will be educated, we see no reason why they should not make good men and women. We have, during the past twenty months, placed twenty-four of these bal&gt;es into good homes, where they are loved and cared for iiefullv as any bftbe could be, and we feel, that if one half of these, (and i i why they might not all make good citizi ■ a up to l&gt;e good Christian men and women, that the state has l&gt;een paid for all it has cost. For who can estimate the value of one human soul? GOVERNMENT \\ '&lt;■ have found this to be an easy matter with but few excep - tions. In the first place, we aim to have every hour of the time so full, that there will lx» no chance for wrong doing, for we have long since learned, that "Idleness is the mother of evil.'' so we try to keep every girl employed at some kind of work. And we make them feel that this is their home and that the happiness and the standing of the Home depends upon each one of them individually, and what their li Mere in the Home, is what their lives will be out of the Home. As a rule I believe every girl tries to do the -he knows. Of course some of them have never been taught ■ rid to do this promptly and willingly is a hard matter at I &gt;ut after they are in the Home a short time, and see the others who do obey and who are trying to do right in every way, they soon fall in line, and by the end of the year some of those who were the most disobedient are the most obedient. Of course we have some who do not have the proper amount of pride and self resect, and who will indulge in gossip and do many things that are injurious, not only to themselves but to the Home neral. With these we deal as we think best at the time ac - cording to the offense and the individual. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">403 I X D 1ST K 1 A I. VHP A K I M h N T The work of the Home is divided into details of six week- U follows: kitchen, dining-room, laundry, sewing-room, nui hospital and general housework. It is our aim to give eacl good practical training in each of these departments, so that by the time she is ready to leave the Hume, she is well fitted to with the work in any good home. It is very gratifying to see the interest the girls take in their work. We do not have a regular laundry teacher or cooking teacher as bo many institutions do. Hut this is all under the snpervi-i : the matron so that it is impossible for her to be with the girls all of the time. Hut after she has planned the work and the girls know what is to l&gt;e done ami how. they go ahead and do it. when si turns she not only finds the work done, hut well done. Th greatly appreciate in the girls and every one. who has visited the Home, has remarked about their willingness to work and the in • they take in their work. Many of our girls have gone out into homes and are earning from three to six dollars per week, as di tics. SKWINC HOOM In this department, we have a competent teacher who is with the girls all of the time, and who not only teaches them to do plain sewing and mending hut to cut and fit their dresses and also to do some fancy needle work. So that any girl who is diligent and who has any ability is well ahle to care for her own wardrobe. Then if any girl wants to earn her living with her needle, allowed to remain over time and is given every possible chan that she will he thoroughly capable when she leaves the Ho: EDUC VTION \l. All detail work closes at 2:30 and every girl is expected to at - tend school until 5:00. The branches taught are reading, penmanship, langu. ing, geography, history, physiology and arithmetic. While it is impossible in the short time which we can give to school work to accomplish as much as we would like to, yet wi that this is an important part of our work. As some of the girls can scarcely read and write when they enter the Home, and what schooling they get here will l&gt;e all that many of them will ever have. Then others are high school girls and some even out of the gi </seg>
            <seg id="p008">404 ect to enter .school iigain as soon as they leave here, and this them an opportunity to keep up their studies or review them. Then as any and all education is worthless without moral and religious training we have Sunday School every Sunday afternoon _ V) and eha[&gt;el exercises every evening at 7:15. The chapel exercises are conducted by the different teachers E'pt &lt;&gt;n Wednesday night, when we have our Christian Endeavor ting&gt;. These meetings are always conducted by one of the girls, remarkable, the interest the girls take in the Christian Endeavor tings ami the splendid programs they prepare. KAKM Our farm consists of about thirty-seven acres, the railroad ng taken off about three aci. I Of this amount eleven acres are in pasture, four acres in alfalfa M in timothy, four and one half acres in garden, four i itatoes. two acres in orchard, and nine acres in lawn ami yards. HE PAIRS Upon taking up the work here, one year ago last April, in the question of repairs was a serious one, for it seemed that thing on the farm would have to l&gt;e repaired or replaced. Just l»egin. what to do first, and just how much could 1k&gt; done and how much therewith the amount allowed us. was the ion. But by careful and close figuring, we have !&gt;een able to a numl&gt;er of these much needed repairs. I The first thing we did was to give the plumbing a general over- There was not a respectable or sanitary toilet-room in ■r building. The pipes all leaked, the bath tubs and lavatories all enclosed in a frame work, which made it impossible to clean nd them as they should be. All this we had torn out. the leaky I taken up and new ones laid and in place of the old tubs, lava - 8 and closets, which were no longer fit for use, we have nice And each one of these rooms received a fresh coat of that we now have toilet-rooms that we are no longer med of. and our plumbing is now in a good sanitary condition. tThe next thing we did was to tear down the little old port ■li were no longer safe, and have nice, large, new porches built, :h have not only been a comfort to us, but which add so much to appearance of the buildings. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">405 We then set to work to clean up the inside of the buildings. The walls and woodwork all over were in a very had condition. A great deal of plastering had to be done before we were able to put on any new paper. After getting the walls in as good a sh:r we were able to, forty-one rooms and six halls were newly pa] and painted and fourteen steel ceilings were put on. A nunil the carpets and a great deal of the old furniture was entirely worn out. so we had to get new furniture and new carpets for a numb the rooms. The whole interior ol the cottage was papered and painted. The laundry too was in need of repairing and (leaning up. ; new pipes had to be laid, walls painted, glass put in windows, and a number of things done. Then there was no way of drying the clothes on stormy days, except hanging them around the hoi. - radiators or in the basement, where the winter vegetables are kept. So we had an addition, twelve by twenty feet, built to the laundry and put in a sectional metallic dry-room. It is now possible for us to get our clothes dry in stormy weather. All the worn out board walks around the buildings hav&lt; taken up and eeraent walks laid. A new smoke stack for the boiler-house has been put up. ■ the boilei The dynamo-room was badly in need of repair. Tin leaked, the sand and lime were constantly falling down en the machinery, so that we had to put on a new roof, ceiling and \ cot ing. Thirty-eight new window screens were put on. and six screen doors were hung. Then we were fortunate enough to find, stored away in the basement, two barrels of mineral paints, so with no cost, c - twenty dollars for oil and white lead, we have been able to our barn and other out-buildings look like new. The fences were all down, so that it was impossible to keep the stock in the pasture or lots. These we have either repaired or re - placed by new ones, until we now have good pasture for both hogs and cattle. The trees have all been trimmed and the yards and lawns have been cleaned up. While there is a great deal of repairing yet to be done, still we feel that we have been able to accomplish a great deal in t hi years, and with the amount allowed us for repar </seg>
            <seg id="p010">406 RKPA1KS NEEDED The old boiler-room, which u only a hole in the ground, and only five feet from the kitchen door, is in very bad condition. We only made what repairs we felt were absolutely necessary here. for we were in hopes that the next legislature would move this away from the buildings, for it is not only a dirty thing to have m the main buildings, but is unsafe. The walls are caving in. one boiler must !&gt;&lt; new engine and pump are badly needed. We just have an old wooden tank for water supply, in pi] this there should be a new standpipe. for in case of tire we would be -t helpless The question of the sewerage of the institution must be settled. for the cess-pools are constantly overflowing and cause a great of trouble Both buildings should l&gt;e pointed up, and storm windows made ich. Also a number of new raditaors will l&gt;e needed. The tire in each building is beginning to leak and will soon have to I*- replaced In making out this statement of repairs needed, we have tried over the ground carefully, and not ask for anything that is not needed to preserve the property of the state and to keep up the tution in a creditable manner. I iBULAi ED STATEMENT Nuinl&gt;er adults in Home Deeeml&gt;er 1. 1006 40 NuiuImm admitted from December 1. HMMi to December 1. H)(i v Numl&gt;er American parentage 24 Number foreign parentage 42 Number parents living Number parents dead 6 Number father, only, living 15 Number mother, only, living M Number returned to friends 4tf Number married. . 5 Average age 19 Returned to other institutions 1 Number placed in homes to work . J.'&gt; Number of adults cared for each year 53 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">407 Number died. 1 Number adults in Home December 1. 1908 Number of children in Home December 1. 1906 Number children in Home December 1. lito* Number horn f nun December 1. 1906 to December 1. 1908 Number transferred to Home of the Friendless Number died Nu:nl)er still-born III 4 Number taken by mother Number placed in Homes Numl&gt;er babes cared for each year. Number children and adults in Home December 1. 1908 Total number children and adults cared for each year Average daily attendance of children and adults .",1 WIIKK BOSK l\ KWINli Id « &gt;M Dresses, adult- I4"_' Sleeve aprons, adults 1"&gt;7 White waists, adults Colored waists, adults. Black serge skirts, adults Black sateen skirt.&lt;. adults ('■owns, adults 1 1"&gt; Corset covers . HMi Sanitary belts Sanitary napkins Kitchen aprons 121 Drawers 10 Hose supporters Infants' dresses Infants' skirts H»7 Infants' shirts 205 Infants' gowns H"&gt; Infants' bands 129 Infants' pinning blankets. Infants' receiving blankets Diapen v -&lt; Infants' coata 44 Infants' hoods 4ii </seg>
            <seg id="p012">408 Infants' quilts. : *1 Crib 104 pillow r;i-c- l"&gt;4 ,tal 12 Bands, hospital _'4 Skirts, hospital 10 BO Sunbonnett 29 Ironing sheets 85 : holders . M ■is hemmed 4!i Table cloths hemmed 13 ■ cloths hemstitched ins hemstitched towels idry hups 1« pads quilted 4 Comforts tied 1" Curtains Scrim, hemstitched _'(i pairs Muslin, ruffled JO pairs insertion and la _'4 pairs nhroidered and hemstitched 12 Pillow cases monogram I s Mittens, pair 31 Number garments mended 8,084 WOKK. DONE IN KITCHKN I \ heat bread 15,236 graham bread 435 Graham gem- 4,988 ?,778 Bum Cinnanion mil!- 2.4^« . i- I'J.dlO 744 £ l\3 Douglmuts 5,168 .*•* l . Sheets ginger bread 130 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">409 Loaves coffee cake M*4 Pancakes 1 .ikis Fritters _'.74:i Puddings 2.430 Cream puffs 107 Canned Fruits ( loose berries . . 4(i quarts Pie plant 28 quarts _'v CherriM 14 quarts Crab apples •')&lt;( quarts Tomatoes 14.~&gt; 2 quarts Apples 42 quarts Total canned 334 2 ved — Peaches 42 quarts quarts Watermelon 14 Total preserved ."&gt;ti quarts Pickled Beans Jersey Chilli". :it&gt; quarts ■&gt;•&gt; quarts 28 quarts Chow Chow Piccalilli . . . (»() quarts (14 quarts Tomatoes Peaches. 60 quarts 24 quarts Total pickled 294 quarts Butter Apple 14."&gt; 138 quarta quarts quarts Tomato Peaches 24 Total butter .SOT quarts Jelly— Apple Grape 61 2 quarts 1 quart Total if*llv </seg>
            <seg id="p014">410 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Jam I*MTY Granil total 1'HHIH (I ( &gt;h OUTDOOR I.AHOH bushels. -MC) • potatoe Onions M) bushel bushel bushel bushel pound: 50 4:-! Turnips Cab Lettuce Carrots us. KM) i:-!.l(t() dozen bunches bushels :»() 2.5 .-)() bushel bushel: bushel: bushel dozen . Tomatoes Corn SI I S.) 7ii Squash ■&gt; ■&gt; Pumpkins. Cucumbers 2(K) bushel bushel t 10 Pie plant Cherries Appk 1.0 bunches bushels bushels quarts. 9 125 M . 7."&gt; Strawberries -eberries Radishes. . . 20 125 quarts. bushels dozen 37.50 /.) Milk 300- 2 7.7 l .ts gallon pounds 1.10H.7U Butter Hogs s;, 4."&gt;. 00 Hav _'. ls't.oo tons tons Alfalfa Fodder 20 3 1K3.00 51.50 137.00 40. (HI Hog pasture </seg>
            <seg id="p015">II Ml. TAB LI Winter Rising hell Breakfast bell For girls. . For officer ii:4.". 7:30 \t work in all departments Summer .Von A M 6:00 Rising hell Breakfast At work in all department* 6 'in Dinner bell — For girls For officer; 11 :M) 1 J :()(» M. 1:00 1'. M. _'::5(l At work in all departments School Recreation ."&gt; .( )( i Supper bell — For girls For officer .V.:*n 9:00 Retiring Chapel SUMMARY OF INVKNTORY DECEMBER 1. MM)S Land $4,810 00 s Two main buildings. 30,000 00 Cottage 3* Barn . 800 00 Laundry 1,600 00 Engine house and machinery . Horses, cows, hogs and poultry Vehicles, harness and robes .-&gt;.()( Ml 00 Ml 14;&gt; 00 Farm and repair tools Furniture, both buildings 5,000 oo Clothing and dry-goods. 1.400 00 Provisions 7* Fuel ■•_ Total </seg>
            <seg id="p016">412 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT STATISTICAL REPORT Population From Dec. 1. 1906 to Dec. 1. 1907 Male Female Total Number inmates present at l&gt;eginning of fiscal year 13 45 tit; Number received during year 24 51 75 Numl&gt;er discharged or died during year. . 25 57 74 Number at end of vear 12 39 51 Average number of officers and employes .35 8 Kxj&gt;enditures Current expei Salari.- $4,278.81 Maintenance 8,544.16 Repairs 6,063.20 Total $18,856 23 Population From Dec. 1. 1907 to Dec 1, 1908 Male Female Total Number inmates at beginning of fiscal year. . 12 39 51 Number received during year 23 43 56 Number discharged or died during year.. .20 46 66 Number at end of year 15 36 51 Average number of officers and employes . . 3 I 8 F^xpenditures Current expenses — Salaries $4,250.00 Maintenance 7.235.77 Repairs 843 49 Total. $12,329.26 Total 18,85623 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">413 AVERAGE PKH CAPITA COST OF MAINTENANl I. ■cini-annuul period Dec. 1. L906 to May 31, L907 1120 37 For semi-annual period Juno 1. 1907 to Nov. 30, 1907 12^ 59 For semi-annual period Dec. 1. 1907 to May :\\ . 1906 For semi-annual period June 1. 1908 to Nov. 30, 1908 92 SA Total per capita cost for biennium $437 65 AVERAGE PKli CAPITA i &lt; i-&gt; 1 OK UKI'AIH- For semi-annual period Dec. 1. 1906 to May 31. l'.tOT *'.' 47 Far semi-annual period June 1, 1907 to Nov. 30, 1907 11"&gt; 47 For semi-annual period Dec. 1. 1907 to May 31, 1906 1 1 :V_&gt; For semi-annual period June 1. 1908 to Nov. 30, 1906 Total per capita for liiennium $13 Grand total $577 21 AVERAGE PEK CAPITA &lt;■ MAINTENANCE WEEKL1 -i-mi-annual period Dec. 1, 1908 to May 31, 1907 . 1 46 Average daily attendance For semi-annual period June 1. 1907 to Nov. :{(). 1907. 1 7^ Average daily attendance 4n For semi-annual period Dec. 1. 1907 to May 31, 1906.. 1. 08 Average daily attendance For semi-annual period June 1. 190S to Nov. 30. 1906 Average daily attendance Total average per capita cost per week for biennium 1 30 Average daily attendance for biennium. (ASH FIND Cash on hand Dec. 1, 1906 $210 58 Cash receipts from Dec. 1, 1906 to Dec. 1. 1968.. 1.490 35 Cash expended from Dec. 1. 1906 to Dec. 1. 1906. 803 77 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1906 807 16 APPROPRIATION OK 1905 Overdrawn Drugs, paints and oils $60 22 Feed for stock. 52 55 Official expense - 39 52 Maintenance.. 1,429 86 Fuel and ligh- 7( </seg>
            <seg id="p018">414 Employe! 1272 40 Fuel and lights Repairs and improvements 12 . l&gt; Stationery, postage and telephone 4.17 Drugs, paints and oils Hi 70 38 03 APPROPRIATION OF 1007 Appropriated Expended Balance Officers' salaries $4,000. 00 $3,333.30 Employes- wage?. 4,720.00 3,702.52 1.017 4s Maintenance 19.000.00 12,499 50 ti..-&gt;00.50 Repair "«&gt; 00 'is 1,31 MATED APPROPRIATION Full COMING BIENNIUM Salary of superintendents for 2 years $2,000 oo Salary of matron for 2 years 1.200.00 Salary of physician for 2 years l.tiOO.OO Employe* for 2 yean .').oso.OO Maintenance for 2 years l'.UMIO.OO General repairs for 2 years 11,000.00 ted appropriation n ').00 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>