<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers Effect of Light and Heavy Feeding on Wide and Narrow Rations</title>
               <date value="1922-08">1922-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 1*1 August, 192 1 Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers EFFECT OF LIGHT AND HEAVY FEEDING OF WIDE AND NARROW RATIONS DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY 4GB1CULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THK UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">i GROWTH STUDIES OF DAIRY HEIFERS EFFECT OF LIGHT AND HEAVY FEEDING OF WIDE AND NARROW RATIONS "EPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY I In- determination of the growth requirement* of normal dairy eifers and the establishment of normal growth curves are very necessary for the proper study of the nutrition of dairy cattle. Mitch valuable research, especially with respect to light and ivy feeding of one particular ration, has been done along these tes, but no extensive investigation has dealt with the effects of lit and heavy feeding of wide and narrow rations. The results nafter recorded are a contribution to the subject. Growth is ■ more ov less continuous process from birth to ma- rity. it- regularity probably being governed largely by external nditioa», such a&gt; environment and feed. As yet the control - ler factors of growth are not all known. Heredity and the quan- ty and quality of feed are important factors affecting growth. These studies are concerned entirely with the influence of feed. i- to kind, quantity, and quality. The environment was the same case*, and as far as possible related animals were compared n the breed. METHODS OF INVESTIGATION Kight purebred Jersey heifers and an equal number of pure- Holstein heifer* were selected for the trials and were started the experiment shortly after birth. Each animal was weighed _ w — ! , o regularly at weekly intervals, the weighing l&gt;eing done in each case after feeding and before watering in the morning. The weight recorded is the monthly average. Each month the height at the withers was determined by three successive measurements for eacli animal and the average recorded. These data indicate the progress of body development. For the purpose of determining the effect of different rations, the animals were divided into general classes and further sub - divided into groups. Four Jerseys, herd Nos. 532. 534. 536, and .138. and four Holsteins. herd Nos. 237. -230. 240, and 241, were assigned to Class I. These animals received corn as the sole con- 'Thi- &lt;l»t» recorded were collected by W. B. Nevens. E. G. Woodwmrd. »nd J. W. Hendrickson. under the supervision of J. H. Framlsen. The data were aatemblcd and prepared for publication by H. P. Davit and Benjamin Huuroviky. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">NkhKASKA Kxi-KKIMKNT STATION Hi 1.1.KT1N 1M1 4 cent rate ami a I f ;i I t'a hay a&gt; llie only roughage. Class I was mi1&gt; - divided into four groups, (iroup l-.J consisted of Jerseys. Nik M and :&gt;:W. and litmmp l-H of Holsteins. No&gt;. j:57 and 23!&gt;. All animals in these groups were fed a ration consisting of two pounds of corn chop (ground corn) daily for the firs! '200 pounds of live weight and on* 1 pound additional for each l'N) pound* gam in weight until a maximum of six pounds daily was reached. The maximum was continued until the close of the experiment, which continued 24 mouths for Jerseys ami - _'7 months for Holsteins. (iroup 2-. I of Class I consisted of Jersey-. Nik 534 and .Vis. and (iroup 2-H of Holsteins. Xos. -_'4&lt;i and 241. These group- were fed daily one pound of corn chop for the first li' K t pounds of live weight and one half pound additional for mth 1&lt;K) |&gt;ouuds of gain until a maximum of three pound- was reached. The maxi - mum was continued until the end of the experiment, winch wa - of the same length as for Groups l-.I and 1-11. Class II consisted of an equal nunilier of animals of each l&gt;ree&lt; and was also stilxlivided into groups, (iroup 3-J consisted o Jerseys. Nos. 537 and "&gt;H!&gt;. and (iroup :J-H of Holsteins. Xos. 22! and -234. The quantity of concentrates fed wa&gt; the same a- it (iroups 1-J and l-H. A grain mixture of five Mttt corn chop two parts wheat bran, and two parts lin-eed oil meal (old pro cess). by weight, was substituted for the corn ration. (iroii| 4-J consisted of Jerseys. Xos. ."&gt;4li and ."&gt;41. and Group 4-H o Holsteins. Nos. 230 and 233. These groups received the --anii quantities of the mixed grain ration described above as Group 2-J and -i-II received of the corn ration. The feeding period were the same as in Class I and averaged 24 months for tb •lersey.s and 27 months for the Holsteins. The plan of the feed ing is graphically outlined in the diagram on page .*&gt;. At the start the calvo were fed whole milk until they were two weeks old. Then during a period of a week a gradual change to skim milk was made. The quantity of whole milk fed de - pended upon the size, strength, and hreed of the calves. Skim milk was fed in proj&gt;ortion to the weight of the animal, ten pound - for the first 100 pounds of live weight, five |x&gt;unds additional for the second 100 pounds of live weight, and an additional two and one-half pounds for each succeeding KM) pounds until a maximum of twenty pounds of skim milk daily was fed. Milk was fed in two equal daily feeds. When &gt;ix months old the calves were weaned. Hay and grain were added to the ration as soon as the calves were old enough to eat them, usually when about two week - old. Adjustments in the quantity of grain fed were made at th • </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers 5 l&gt;eginniiig of the month on the basis of the previous month's weights, drain and hay were fed daily in two equal feedings. The quantities of whole milk, skim milk, grain, and hay con - sumed during the first six months are given in Table 1. EFFECT ON HEIGHT AT WITHERS Inasmuch as it was impossible to select heifers exactly the same in height at withers at birth, adjustments were made from the actual measurements in order to obtain comparable results. The height of the shortest heifer at the withers was taken as a stand - ard. For example, in Table 2 the heights of the two animals in each group were averaged and the average figure recorded. Group 1-H of Class I has an average height at withers at birth of 70.8 centimeters. When the heights in this table are plotted on chart 1. Group 3-H of Class II has had 4 cm., the initial difference in t Ian of Feeding Experiment tng 'xperiment Wide ration, Liberal feeding Group 1-H No. 237 } 2 Holsteins No. 239 Receiving daily as a grain ration corn not to exceed 6 . ' pounds and alfalfa hay as a Group 1-J No. 532 roughage ad libitum. 2 Jerseys No. 636 Light feeding ( Group 2-H No. 240 I 2 Holsteins No. 241 Receiving daily as a grain ration corn not to exceed 3 . i pounds and alfalfa hay as a | Group 2-J No. 634 roughage ad libitum. { 2 Jerseys No. 638 Narrow ration. Class II Liberal feeding &lt; [ Group 3-H No. 229 Receiving a mixed grain ration j 2 Holsteins No. 234 of corn chop 5 pounds, wheat bran 2 pounds, oil meal (o. p.) 2 pounds, not to exceed 6 pounds Group 3-J No. 637 daily of grain and alfalfa hay 2 Jerseys No. 639 as a roughage ad libitum. Light feeding Group 4-H No. 230 } 2 Holsteins No. 233 Receiving the mixed grain ration not to exceed 3 pounds | daily and alfalfa hay as a Group 4-J No. 640 roughage ad libitum. 2 Jerseys No. 641 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Exi'kkimknt Station Hi i.i.ktin 1M height, subtracted every month. The true height of thi- lattt class can be ascertained from Table 2. The Holstein heifers a illustrated in Table 2 and the corresponding chart 1 show th apparent effect of the various rations upon height. Group 3-H fed the narrow ration of mixed feed, showed a gain in height ir 24 months of ."&gt;".:&gt; cm. over their average height at two months. Table 1. — Feed vtumuiiiptSun. p'r*t si,- month CLASS I Group 1-H Group 1-J Group 2-H C (LASS I Group 1-H Group 1-J Group 2-H Group j^j nt j , Kind of feed Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow of feed Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow C 237 239 532 536 240 241 237 239 532 536 240 241 534 Lbs. LI*. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. I Lbs. LI*. Lbt. L Lbs. Lbs Whole hole milk 148 151 131 Skim milk 148 151 Ul 92 157 171 1 cim milk 2,355 2,196.5 2,465 Corn milk. 2,355 2,196.5 2,465 I .Ml 2,156.5 2,242.5 2,4 4L 1 »rn meal 301 236.6 265 Alfalfa me«l 301 236.6 265 223 151&gt; 172 . Ifalfa hay 419 304 2K0 260 50:J.5 4M \ 4: CLASS II CLASS I Group 3-H Group :{-J Group 4-H ( Group 3-H Grouj Kind T^jnH . _____^^ of feed Cow Cow Cow Cow »f feed Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow C 229 234 537 539 230 233 Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lba. Lbx. I l. Whole milk 188 216 92 114 Skim milk 2,681 2,239 1,978 1,74 Mixed grain 369 264 238.H 23 t Alfalfa hay. 460 357 327 42 The next in point of greatest gain was (iroup 1-H. heavy feeding of the wide ration. This group gained 54 "-—*»• -~ c — l r- Group 2-11 ranked third with 4 ( .&gt;.'.&gt; cm. and (iroup 4-11 i 1 Data are not available for evi-ry anima with the Jerseys and 27 months in th U </seg>
            <seg id="p007">(iKOWTII Sri DOBS i&gt;t Dairy Heifers 7 |!(jffS5a8SS88882S22858SS;SJaS858SS : I I S1 1 y. s s oioiaoioooioctooioo be x * x « o to i- x v « x ■J &lt;M TO CC ■"» 1 £ b — — 'Xt-t-i— tt-O«3WXi-t o&gt;fr:x-i«-»-.^™tJ--NNNd™6-do'Nci6p6«!| ■•»: &amp; i 1 «N«!eegoot-«t-Nmoo!DN» ; 8 X ""-""•HNNNNMNn t- M ll * ?&gt; j! t *^ ■ ;« »!l El = Jtt'JlOlCSXaOnNS'JCSI- «• INMNMMMNb "!«jiaooio»oii3U3L': &amp;o •£ </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bclletin 181 5 - is 3 X. §1 a— r J5 .S g NU!U!O»- ; «)&lt;i^t--.«« ;'o~ lie op a s T — i- v^ |^ " : ■*■ = 5 e • &lt; °") | °'° l &lt;&gt;99&gt;&gt;^ l ';x3')oqniii«ia9&gt;3oo«e3&gt;i«o r S 3 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Growth Stvdies of Dairy Heifers 9 6t-XtDOO'0^'^t*&lt;003i36»NO«^ I - l !0|0^'t- ■*• ?:?:««^ i »-^NC i i'-^'nN^'N«NMn w ca t^ «NNNmnn«nTrTf&lt;iflioio»!oet-(-t-t- (st.t.N-«tBonqtc»«t-;iooq!BNNn«a a (M^lCM AO&lt;OOOOtOOOO&gt;flOiQOIOOifllOiO&gt;C -4 J5 rs ■&gt;»•«• t ■*■* M •*««■*«« -^ « co n us im ■»• cc « l- ■J. -f. oiflioiatoooooioioooiQiAOidCu: t '*^*'W3 k ""5"5^O c C^CI^ c^ 0C00c^ n«rtioxnt-ont-io»t-^(Oio«iM»»on,« 2 . t-OCO'^'0»t^Ot^t&gt;OI&gt;C^OOU3^COaO&lt;DOil&gt;;&lt;I5&lt;CSC ioS«x»*r.oooboo---HH;H--- ■I. A I '■ 1 - ■L r. c B f*rf ........... "^ t-^r — «-»io — h&lt;c*o»h »«'-t-05-H-«r«sio us^I«^'««cvi'-'-"C&gt;«'-^o — o — c-h _ x </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Kxperimkxt Station Hi i.i.ktin l*»l 10 * ■r. | js. .ioinqc | fltooiou:iow!0'cou:iocifl00ioi0'nc 5~. / ~ - • C5 .£ * o^-oou3oqu50s^t^c^i'^;^suscccc3CU3'— "Cvix"5 ' m ■ '- / -- JZ ,W(Ct-iOOX?:N00'Ot-^O'OX«3iVi0?:-tD3'.X ,5f; E»t»d^6«6?:'ioxc!~iO!cx66nvWBicNixioi: "*^ 'jiteeM-xxissiaooo J c . ooo&gt;A&gt;aioooou;icioqou3ioioioioiau30C "3^ fi^werid^uai-ji-^-oiexiox'ss-t - : 3 j§ e-i'VNO x«x cc Tf r: c-i n m ■^ i 3 «•». Jc .oqosuc&lt;3iii«:iiio&lt;)css&lt;iqioc«c«ii3&lt;i JS .Sf — « t- si a; k « t- — ia -«r « c — — x a; 4* jiotf y.ntC'-iflx^xx — ic J; ?. n . 1 = /. c O c • ov eg -^ ■* « us us t- *. / C £ .O9«O-"tt)t-N^1| .SP Su5'*6«M^-Tftcaw'»«t-xc:jirir-«;«'[-xxx 1 n r »et-^«x3i»3i«ecooe--------- K^ 5T« w 1 I i N ; M : N i : : : ; : : M ■ L I *^ ~ x: .iflincqifl'OOioioiotoq'CcicinctoooiC'OtnC'* </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BOWTH SllDlES OF D.URY IIkIKERS 11 i 4:&gt;.!i cm. In nearly all cases the Holstein heifers showed r grMtwd growth in height :it the withers l&gt;etween the ages if four ami eight months. The Jersey heifers, as shown in Table 3 sponding chart _'. did not show exactly comparable re - group receiving liU-ral quantities of corn, (iroup 1-J, g with an increase of 56.6 cm. from the second to the i -fourth month, (iroup 2,1 showed the next highest gain Iliis was closely followed by Group 4 J, lightly n mixed grain, with a gain of 48.2 cm. The heavily fed </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Biixetin 181 I mixed grain lot. Group 3-J, showed the lowest gain, 47.8 cm. The cause for the poor showing of the group fed liberally on mixed grain is not apparent. In all cases the Jersey heifers made their most rapid gains in height at withers l&gt;etween the ages of two and six months, as is shown in Table 3. It might l)e thought that the failure of the heavily fed inixe( grain group to make proportional increase in height at wither could Tx&gt; attributed to digestive disturbances or some such con H r~ 1 H — ?M- -L p : A KT LPTT fe»fr- L --h- -r -r -i r i- 4- 4- A I k£ '• V '1 ;! i - r • ,' " 1? i /ft*/ Cor^ /»»»y /*«"*#«• ■ ■ — / " 4 • 3 JO AP •^ /m *a ro ze r* r* ?a 4w /^ AfosrfAs */£/?$£ Y /7f/S-f/ej </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Growth Sti mes of Dairy Heifers 13 "*A — L / S * R *«*- /j -i — r- 7 /' ■ U- / -i — — r 14 / 'A / / p » //, i 3 _ V v &lt;■' ■ / n / nV- / JUV 4- c/**/?r rto j A L«j/7f Cors? — — — 4 Hccvy Corn - ■f ? a ~&amp; —^ 75 ?5 ?5 T* /}?c //7 Afon//&gt;-3 — Afoi-sre/n rtc/resrs </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Hi i.i.etix 181 14 ZT &gt; '^ t 7V •1 1 / / *' \ '; \. / y\ 5L»f "I -J // f\ / /'' K'H 8 c/mt?r /y, n 'Si / mi A r Ca*-~ — /, /fwvy Cow? — "I ™ 1 n 2 • » *o s* /* &gt;m /s to e* *■* /7yg /r? A/o/y//n — «^r/PJ&lt;f&gt;^ /^■//■vr&gt;g'j </seg>
            <seg id="p015">(ilMWIH Sit D1K.S OK D.MRV HlIRI 15 I i M i I V i i ! ! 1 mi. n veai A careful study of the data, however, does not bear this \\ lint the inheritance of the different animals was and what axiiuum height at maturity was cannot be determined, &gt;st of the animal&gt; arc dead. Distinct variations occur in \ |&gt;e. there lieing small, refined animals commonly referred tnd type, and larger, heavier, and somewhat coarser ani- iled American type. The kind used in these experiments ermediate in type, altho more inclined toward the Ameri- VI EFFECT ON BODY WEIGHT iremeuts of height at withers do not always provide a lex for comparing growth of animals under different &gt;f feeding. Since skeletal growth tends to reach the in- i/.e even under limited feeding, it is, therefore, generally iiMe during growth than the IkkIv weight. On the other much greater variability of body weight is noticeable r different conditions of feeding. It follows, then, that when &gt;\ving animal i&gt; liberally fed. the rate of gain in body weight ■uallv proportionally greater than the gain in skeletal de - iment. these studies the monthly gain in weight is the difference en the average weight in a particular month and the cor- ng weight of the previous month. The animals were weekly each month and the average taken. Most cases nail gains or losses occurred were due to the animal being •k or "off feed." Periods following such instances y showed gains slightly greater than the average, which nd with the work of other investigators. The recovery t may be accomplished either by a more rapid rate of &gt;r by a prolonged growing period. The daily gain was on the basis of 1000 pounds of live weight as being com para I &gt;le for all animals thruout the ex|)eriment. The t- in Tables 4 and 5 were computed according to the fol- fnrmula (iain for month 1000 Daily gain per 1000 pounds Live weight of live weight ;n be total average gain for each group was calculated by start - at birth and continuing the gain thru the twenty-fourth tit. Group S-H led with an average gain during the two period of 1086 pounds per animal and was closely followed </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 181 by Group 1-H with an average gain of 1028.5 pounds. Chart 3 shows how close these two groups were together, the difference being considered insignificant. Group 4-H showed an average gain of 873.5 pounds compared with Group 2-H which average 843.5 pounds. There appears, in the Holstein groups, to have been a considerable influence due to heavy feeding. Corn liberally fed seemed to be practically as good as mixed feed, when fed in the same proportions, in producing gain in weight in growing Holsteins. Light feeding of mixed feed was much poorer than the liberal feeding of either mixed feed or corn, and li&lt;rht feed - ing of corn was inferior to li&lt;rlit feeding of mixed feed. l"p to al&gt;oiit five months old there was comparatively little difference Group 1-H Group 2-H Month Cow Cow Cow Cow 237 239 240 241 Tow Cow Cow 19 234 230 Lbs. Lbs. Lb*. LI, Lb*. Lbs. Lb*. L 1 4.4 12.7 10.1 11.1 I 10.9 9.8 9.3 7.3 K&gt; 5 8.6 7 7.6 3 8.2 8.3 5.3 4.6 «.a ■4 7.0 5.8 4.4 8.1 4 .: I 6.6 5.3 8.8 4.6 5.6 5.9 5( 6 6.0 5.6 2.5 3.7 4.9 7.3 2.9 7. 3.9 2.2 2.7 2.9 4.9 4.0 .8 4.2 8.. 4.3 4.4 3.1 1.7 1.6 4.0 2.0 3.4 9 3.2 4.1 1.2 3.1 •i.O I 10 2.9 2.7 3.2 1.8 3.0 3.9 11 | 2.0 3.9 ! 3.8 2.1 •) 12 2.2 2.5 1.8 1.8 1.8 4.4 13.. 1.5 1.0 2.7 2.6 1.3 2.8 1.3 1.4 14 12 1.9 2.5 1.3 .9 2.3 3.2 .9 .8 2.6 15 3.0 1.3 2.7 2.8 16 ; .4 ! 1.4 2.0 .8 1.3 .5 2.9 1.4 17.. 3.0 .9 1.8 .5 2.3 I 2.3 .9 2.5 18.. 2.1 1.4 1.7 .8 1.5 2.2 1.0 .4 1.3 .8 1.7 1.9 19 1.8 1.6 1.6 2.1 6 20 —.4 2.1 I 1.4 1.1 1.4 2.2 1.4 2.3 .8 .6 1.5 .8 .8 .6 1.1 .1 21 2.3 , .0 .6 .2 22 L.4 23 1.2 .9 1.1 .9 1.5 1.6 .6 .9 1.1 24 25 1.2 1.2 1.4 3.8 1.6 1.2 1.7 1.5 1.4 ! 1.1 1.7 1.5 1.4 26. 1 4 27. 1.0 Tam.k 4. — I huh/ i/,iiu in weight per 1000 poundt of Uvt »■ Hiilstihix. Group 3-H Group 4-H 1.5 .4 1.4 1.8 .6 1.3 1.7 1.6 1.5 1.6 1.2 1.8 1.1 ! .4 1.3 .9 1.5 ; 1.4 1.7 .8 .1 I .3 1.5 .4 l/_&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers 17 between any of the groups. From that time on. the heavily fed groups gained much more rapidly than the lightly fed ones and the lightly fed corn group (Group 2-H) dropped appreciably below the lightly fed mixed group (Group 4-H). Chart 3 shows, also, the normal growth curve as given by Eckles. From birth to five months his normal curve agrees with the curves of the various groups in this experiment. After that age the curve of the heavily fed group was above normal and became increasingly divergent, the greatest difference being at twenty-four months. The curve of Group 4-H on light mixed feed showed a gain very slightly lower than the normal curve for the period from the fifth to the thirteenth month. At the latter point it crossed the normal and showed a progressive deviation, reaching the great- -t difference at twenty-four months. Group 2-H, on light corn r.xiu.K 5. — Daily (fain in weight per 1000 pounds of live weight — Group 1-J Group 2-J Group 3-J Group 4-J Month Average Cow Cow Cow Cow 532 536 538 534 Cow Cow Cow | Cow 537 539 540 541 Lb*. Lbs. j Lb*. Lbs. 4 I 10 11 11' 13 14 15 Iti 17 1* 19 20 21 22 23 24 .7 i 1.2 .5 i .8 Jersey*. Lb*. I Us. I Lbt. Lbt. Lb». 5.8 0.9 8.4 8.6 7.9 5.3 5.5 5.4 1.5 3.8 3.4 1.9 3.1 1.7 3.6 1.0 1.5 1.4 1.1 , 2.4 1.4 1.5 1.4 8.3 6.6 11.8 7.8 7.1 7.3 3.5 2.5 3.1 2.9 .7 3.1 1.8 ! 2.2 2.1 .6 1.7 | 2.5 , 1.0 2 i 2.1 1.6 12.4 8.5 7.8 6.8 5.2 5.5 1.7 1.4 3.1 2.4 2.3 3.2 2.2 1.8 2.6 1.4 3.0 .9 1.6 .9 1.5 2.0 1.3 11.8 8.8 6.6 4.8 a 1.5 1.6 1.3 2.4 .6 3.1 3.2 2.0 2.6 1.2 .6 1.9 1.5 2.0 1.1 1.2 1.5 N.6 4.0 6.1 TJ 6.9 5.6 :i.4 M 3.3 .9 1.7 3.3 l.S 2.9 1.1 2.4 1.9 1.6 1.9 1.5 .2 .6 .2 1.0 4.1 8.8 13.6 4.6 6.6 5.0 4.4 5.0 2.0 3.0 2.9 2.7 2.6 2.2 2.3 1.6 1.1 .9 2.6 .8 1.6 1.4 .7 2.9 3.9 12.3 7.2 9.1 6.4 5.4 3.4 2.1 2.3 2.0 2.9 1.5 2.8 .2 2.7 1.9 1.5 1.1 2.8 1.6 1.2 .9 1.2 1.3 1.9 12.4 8.5 6.9 7.2 12 3.3 2.6 1.9 2.8 3.3 1.0 2.2 2.3 1.3 2.5 1.2 1.4 1.7 1.2 .8 1.8 1.6 1.3 7.1 10.2 8.7 6.9 6.3 4.9 3.3 3.0 2.3 2.5 2.9 2.4 2.4 2.1 2.2 1.5 1.5 1.4 1.7 1.5 1.2 1.4 1.3 1.2 I I i </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 181 from the fifth to the fourteenth month, shows ■ eurre thai w«« distinctly below. At the fourteenth month, hanrwer, it crossed and became increasingly divergent, reaching the greatest dif - ference at the twenty-fourth month. In the case of the Jersey*, all groups showed curves with comparatively little variation from normal up to the seventh month. From the seventh month to the fifteenth month. Group 2-J (light corn) and Group t-.I (light mixed feed) showed curves below Eckles' normal. After that time, both these groups showed greater gains than the nor- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers 19 mal. The heavily fed groups, 1-J (heavy corn) and 3-J (heavy Bind feed), followed the normal up to about one year old, after which they showed greater gains than Eckles" normal. Summarizing the interpretation of the tables and charts, chart i&gt; show-; a hypothetical medium of gain for Holsteins based on all the animals of that breed in this experiment, and a like hypo - iliftical medium for Jerseys. While none of the animals in this experiment were fe«l on what is considered a medium ration fed in medium quantities bat were fed two extremes, it is interesting in calculate and plot the results for a possible medium. The hypot hdticul curve for Holstein growth shows almost a straight thruont the experiment A like curve for Jerseys, while owing a smaller proportional gain, is also almost straight. The r.vni.K •;. — Comparison of height at withers ami lief tceif/ht of mihiKilx on iliffereiit ration*.* \ge in month \ U From Miiauuri Research Bulk Hoi lsteins Jerseys leight Weight j Height Weigh Cm. Lbs. Cm. Lbs. 71.8 76.8 B.0 MJ U2.0 96.5 100.9 104.0 107.1 109.1 111.2 112.6 114.0 115.7 117.4 118.8 120.3 121.3 121.8 122.7 123.8 124.3 124.9 125.7 126.5 90 121 157 200 249 302 349 389 425 466 501 529 558 574 596 612 643 660 686 715 746 774 796 824 841 66.1 55 70.3 76 74.7 105 79.3 140 83.9 174 89.3 222 93.7 260 96.8 302 99.8 340 102.8 376 105.0 407 106.5 432 108.3 456 110.1 480 111.4 503 112.7 520 113.4 533 114.6 553 115.6 572 116.8 598 117.5 621 118.1 649 118.9 668 119.8 689 120.4 716 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 181 / U'" / M w L I _xi /. 7, u A i? 7 !/ fX + a Mk \ V \s\ r-t 7 *&gt;o\ 5 j H I csiA&amp;r fro 6 ty/*thffical TThdium Qimfli Comptrtd mM the Normal Gmifli qf Hoiite/n tnd jersty He/fen. -^o /£ /■* At /0 fo- re i* it a&lt; '* s/7 /yonfSra </seg>
            <seg id="p021">( iw&gt;\\ I II Sll D1KS v Dairy Heikerk 21 Parlj ithirx urn/ lire weight of (Adapted from EeHm.j 1 ri tin i HOLSTEINS Heavy fed Light fed 2 Average for breed 1 \K&gt; months Height Weight i Height | Weight Height Weight Cm Lhs. Cm Lbt. Cm. Lbs. 1.9 89 224 86.3 189 104.4 422 98.0 317 103.6 350 110.2 444 117.6 664 10 1 1 432 115.8 548 120.4 620 125.9 912 116.0 598 123.9 710 _'l 130.0 1,110 122.9 731 127.0 900 132.5 1,231 125.9 849 132.5 1,231 125.9 849 JERSEYS JERSEYS 69.6 70.1 69.6 70.1 79.2 157 78.9 150 92.4 298 89.4 252 80.5 265 104.6 378 104.6 378 108.9 495 102.8 371 110.2 468 108.9 495 102.8 371 110.2 468 15 114.8 556 114.8 556 II 118.1 722 109.9 495 119.3 598 118.1 -M 121.4 827 115.5 607 122.9 750 30 123.9 942 118.8 799 799 ■The height meuurements are transformed into cm 'Mo. Agr. Exp. Su. Bulletin 135. 'Erktoa and Warren, Dairy Farming, p. 122. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 181 rate of gain in weight for Holsteins as presented by Eckles show. - a practically straight line up to nine or ten months and ours coincides with it up to that point. From that point on, the gain t given in Eckles' normal showed a progressive decrease with in casing age. Our curve, on the other hand, does not exhibit the progressive decrease. The hypothetical curve for Jerseys ap - proximately coincides with Ecfcles' normal up to the thirteenth or fourteenth month, after which it proceeds in approximately a straight line. To what the deviation from Eckles' normal curves is due. it is difficult to explain. The animals in this ex - |&gt;eriment made ;i steadier growth tlirtiout and were larger ai two years old than those reported from Missouri. Tlii^ might !&gt;&lt;• due to a greater inheritance for size. Six of the Holsteins are still in the University herd and ;is mature cows they average ap Kind of feed Cow Cow Cow ! Cow j Cow I Cow Cow Cow 229 234 537 539 230 233 540 641 Corn meal 2,290.3 2,124.8 1,677.9 1,682.2 1,075.8 1,039 K67.4 i 751.2 Wheat bran. 919.1 1,040.6 630 672.2 431.3 412.8 346.3 298.9 Oil meal o. p 919.1 1,040.6 630 672.2 431.3 1 412.8 346.3 298.9 Alfalfa hay 7,007 1 7,748 4,654 5,682 7,425 7,012 5,375 4,953 ■The Jeraey heifers were on this experimental feeding for 24 months, while the Holstein heifers were engaged in this investigation for 27 months. Table 8. — Grain mul hay consumption &lt;i,tin emptrmtmtti period. 1 CLASS I Group 1-H Group 1-J Group 2-H Group 2-J KjjhJ j ; ~ I , :__ ' of feed Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow Cow 237 239 532 536 240 241 534 538 Com meal 3,915.8 3,763.2 :),159 2,74:i 1,850.8 1,904.6 1,680 1,334 Alfalfa hay 7,767 6,339.6 5,734 4,810 6,522.5 5,877.6 5,765.3 4,533 i | i ■ ! i_ ' CLASS II Group 3-H Group 3-J Group 4-H Group 4-J </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Growth Studies «&gt;k Dairy Hkikerm 23 proximately 1400 pounds. Three of the Jer9eys still remain and their average weight is 1050 pounds. Tables 6 and 7, represent - ing experimental investigation by Eckles and Sweet of Missouri, 1 are given as a check upon our data shown by Tables 2 and 3 on weights and measurements. Table 8 shows the amount of grain and hay consumed by the Jersey and Holstein heifers thruout the entire experimental period. CONCLUSIONS 1. Liberal feeding of either a corn or a mixed grain ration supplemented with alfalfa hay produced greater height at with - ers in growing Holstein and Jersey heifers than light feeding. 1. The greatest gain in height at withers took place in Jerseys Iwtween Hie second and sixth month and in Holsteins between fourth and eighth month. '&gt;. If gain in height is an index of skeletal development, then ineral metabolism in growing dairy heifers was probably great between the second and eighth month. Liberal feeding of grain, either corn or mixed grains, during first six months, while milk was fed, appears to have been of value in producing additional gain in weight as compared tli light feeding. Limn] feeding of grain, either corn or mixed grain, pro- uced Holsteins that at two years of age were 150 pounds heavier lan the lightlv fed ones. In the case of the Jerseys, the liberally fed one* weighed approximately 50 pounds more than the lightlv ii BIBLIOGRAPHY 1. C. H. Eckles and W. W. Sweet— Missouri Research Bulletin No. 1918) — "Some Factors Influencing the Growth of Dairy Heifers." 2. C. H. Eckles — Missouri Experiment Station Bulletin No. 136 S»15) — "The Ration and Age of Calving as Factors Influencing the owth and Dairy Qualities of Cows." 3. Eckles and Warren— Dairy Farming (1916), p. 122— The Mac - llan Company. 4. P. F. Trowbridge, C. R. Moulton, and L. D. Haigh — Missouri Research Bulletin No. 28—"The Effect of Limited Food Supply on the Growth of Young Beef Animals." 5. C. H. Eckles— Missouri Research Bulletin No. 36 (1920)— "The Normal Growth of Dairy Cattle." 6. S. Brody, A. C. Ragsdale, Jour. Gen. Physiol. 3 (1921), No. 6— "The Rate of Growth of the Dairy Cow; Extra-uterine Growth in Weight." lMiwouri Kmnn-h Bulletin No M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>