<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Manufacture of Neufchatel Cream Cheese</title>
               <date value="18??">1936</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">L.LETIN 303 J OCTOBER 1936 The Manufacture of NEUFCHATEL and CREAM CHEESE EXfREICHARr DEPARTMENT o^ DAIRY HUSBANDRY ¦-;¦".¦: ¦•¦¦¦•¦:••¦-^^ &gt; ¦¦: « ¦- . ¦-¦¦ 4E UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT SIWIGN LINCOLN , . ¦¦.;-:¦ :¦-¦'} :¦• vv ;..¦¦-: ¦:. ,;-v-- ..•¦¦¦:.•:- , W.W. BURR/DIRECTOR ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Review of Methods of Manufacture 3 Experiments in Making Ncufchatcl and Cream Cheese 5 Influence of starter, rennet, and acidity on the body, texture, and keeping quality 5 The effect of fat content of raw material on the body, texture, and keeping quality 5 The effect of homogenization 7 Effect of temperature and length of time of cooking curd 7 Summary of experimental work 8 Commercial Manufacture of Neufchatcl and Cream Cheese 9 Raw material 9 Processing 10 Mixing, sailing, and packaging 11 Cost 11 Flavors 12 Making Ncufcharel or Cream Cheese on the Farm or in the Small Dairy 13 Literature Cited 1-1 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Manufacture of Neufchatel and Cream Cheese ¦'.. . E. L. REICHARf ¦ Cream cheese is a soft, unripened cheese usually made from cnam testing from 12 to 20 per cent fat, coagulated by the development of acidity or by the use of rennet, and then pressed in doth bags. It is creamy white in color, has a fine, smooth texture, and a full, rich, cream flavor. The fat content of the cheese varies from 30 to 40 per cent, with a corre - sponding variation in moisture. Neufchatel is a similar cheese made from whole milk and has a correspondingly lower fat content. The popularity of this and other soft cheeses has grown in recent years because of their palatability, high nutritive value, adaptability for use with other foods such as salads, and the increasing demand for packaged foods. Until recently the making of cream and Neufchatel cheese has been limited to a few large manufacturers. Little has been known by most dairy-products manufacturers about the manufacture of these cheeses, and they have had little opportunity to learn about methods of manufacture without individual experimentation. The investigation reported here was undertaken to determine, if wssible, a practical method of making cream cheese of good quality that could be used by the dairy-products manufac - turer in an average dairy plant. ¦ REVIEW OF METHODS OF MANUFACTURE The origin of cream chose is not definitely known. Probably it wa» developed as a modification of Neufchatel cheese. Several authors (2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 9, 11, 13, 14, and i: I) 1 describe its manufacture in detail. While there are minor variations, Jie general procedure of manufacture is de - scribed by Van Slyke and Price (17) substantially as follows: Pasteurized sweet milk er cream, testing from 35 to 10 per cent fat and usually homogenized, ii placed in a vat at a temperature of 72° F. To each 1,000 pounds of creim, 10 cc. of rennet extract and from 2 to 10 pounds of active starter are added and thoroughly mixed. The cream is then placed in five-gallon "siot-gun" cans 2 and these set in a room or in water at a temperature of 72' F. for from 10 to 14 hours. When the whey acidity is approximately 037 per cent, the shot-gun cans are emptied into draining cloths of unbleached muslin, which are usually fastened on racks so that each can of curd is spread out in a single cloth. These cloths drain on wooden racks for from )l A to 3 hours. ' When the free flow of whey stops the curd is scraped or rolled to the center of the draining cloth, three adjacent corners are brought together over the curd, and the fourth corner is twisted tightly around the other three so that all the edges cf the cloth are either above^r are contained - ' The numbers in parentheses are reference! to literature cited in the back of this bulletin. • Straight-sided cam of about 8-inch| diameter. ; - ¦ \ '.- ' &gt; </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 in the knot thus formed and the curd fills the bag tightly. These bags of curd are then placed in a cheese press and covered with chipped ice to chill them. The whey at the time of pressing usually contains 0.5 per cent acid. The pressure is increased gradually and at no time should it be great enough to cause the soft curd to ooze through the cloth. The pressing is completed when the moisture content is satisfactory and is usually determined by the body and texture of the curd. The bags are then removed from the press and the curd removed from the bags and placed in a curd mixer where from 1 to 2 per cent of salt is added. The salted curd is worked until the salt is evenly distributed and the whole free from lumps. Other investigators report minor changes in the method of manu - facture, but Dahlberg (4) made the most significant deviation. Briefly, his method consists of the following steps: Sweet cream of good flavor, testing 40 to 45 per cent fat, is used to which 5 per cent of soluble dry skim-milk powder is added. Either 1 per cent of high-grade powdered gelatin or 0.5 per cent of powdered agar, free from objectionable flavor and odor, is stirred into the cold cream. This cream mixture is then pasteurized at 145° F. for 30 minutes, if gelatin is used, and at 180° to 185° F. for 10 minutes if agar is used. After pasteurization the mixture is cooled to 110° F. and from 0.5 to 0.75 per cent of common salt and from 0.5 to 1.0 per cent of good com - mercial starter are added. The mixture is then passed through a coarse strainer into the homogenizer, where it is homogenized at pressures of from 3,500 to 4,000 pounds. The mixture as it leaves the homogenizer has the consistency of soft butter or is slightly stiffer than ice cream as it is drawn from the freezer. The cream mixture is immediately placed in the final container and allowed to stand in the refrigerator at a temperature of from 32° to 40° F. for from one to two hours or until the temperature of the mixture is reduced to 70° F. and it solidifies as cream cheese. The cheese is then held at 70° F. for from ten to fifteen hours or until it has developed suf - ficient acid to have a mild acid flavor. It is cooled to 32° to 42° F. and is ready for immediate consumption or is stored at that temperature. This method produces a cheese of approximately the same general com - position as the method of Van Slyke and Price (17). Cheese made according to the first-described process tends to be coarse in texture, to have the defect of whey separation upon standing, and is likely to be variable in both body and texture. Rennet seems to be of little value, since coagulation could just as well be produced by starter alone. Cheese made according to the Dahlberg (4) method has rather a pronounced skimmilk-powdcr flavor and a body that tends to be "salvy" or "livery". The keeping quality of cheese made by either process is not considered very satisfactory. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Neufchatj-l and Cream Cheese EXPERIMENTS IN MAKING NEUFCHATEL AND i ... CREAM CHEESE A series of experiments was undertaken based upon published methods with the plan of testing out and improving the methods used. The pri - mary purpose was to devise s method that would give a product of better texture, body, flavor, and keeping quality. A study of a number of factors was made to determine their effect on these criteria of quality. Influence of starter, rennei, arid acidity on the body, texture, and keep - ing quality.—Comparative trals. using 240-pound batches of 12 per cent cream were made. One serie: of batches was set with 1 per cent of starter, and another series with 1 per cent of starter and 2.4 cc. of rennet (10 cc. of rennet per 1,000 pounds of tream). These trials indicated that the body and texture of the cheese irade without rennet were smoother and less likely to show whey leakage than the cheese made with both starter and rennet. Larger amounts of rennet increased the whey leakage. Table L-^-The effect of acidity o) the curd at draining time on the quality of finished cheese—six trials with 300 pounds of cream per trial, setting time SP. M., and setting temperature 72° F. ' ¦ ; ™ *,; Am , s T , a** tSS."«jss*'SSSR Ko. &#132;c« , a n W acduy ' g P tim / .po^c P.cl. Li. P.'ct. Hrt.' P.tt. '.: Dayl 1 15 •/, 0.75 I 15 . 0.71 Good Good 16 - : 2 14' .1 OMI \S ••' ' 0.93; Koujh Sour 10 3 14V4 54. .'¦ 0.81 :!• MJ4 0.85 Rough Add 12 •( .15 % 0.78 i IVA. 0.73 Good Mild M . 5 . -15. V, :¦ 0.75 , K]i 0.69 , Good Mild \ JO 6 15 'A 0.60 ' 15 ' 0.68 Good Mild 19 ai lactic acid. ; . ¦-- . ¦ - ' ¦ .¦ As the amount of starter, the elapsed setting time, and setting tem - perature are the major factors governing the acidity of the curd at draining time, their effect upon the finished cheese was studied. From the six trials shown in Table 1, which are typical of this series, it was quite apparent thai quantity of starter added and the setting time should be so controlled that the acidity of the curd at draining time will be less than 0.7 per cent, with the best results at acidities ranging from 0.6 to 0.7 per cent. In general, one-fourth pound of starter for a 300-pound batch of cream produced the desired acidity in 15 hours and gave the smoothest texture, mildest flavor, and the best keeping quality of cheese. The effect of fat content of raw material on the body, texture, and keeping quality.—The percentage of fat of the milk or cream will have an effect on the body and [texture as well as the keeping quality of the finished prdduct, because the higher fat content will lower the milk-solids content, which is the major factor in spoilage. What the percentage of </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 fat in the cream used shall be will depend primarily on the maker's choice and the price he can obtain for the finished product. A palatable and satisfactory product can be made from raw material with a range in the fat content of from 4 to 20 per cent. Table 2.— The effect of fat content on body, texture, and f{eeping quality of cream cheese. . Milk Fat Yield Time from prcM - rLl or ' per Body and texture ins to spoilage ""¦ cream '"' 100 lbl. at 40° P. LA. P.cl. L*- Dtsyi J 240 4 24.5 Roush 14 2 250 4 23.6 Rough 12 3 2-10 4 25.4 Rough 15 4 270 12 41.1 Fairly imooth 18 5 330 12 40.0 Fairly imooth 16 « 300 15 43.0 Smooth 20 7 230 12 40.S Fairly imooth 15 I 260 15 40.0 Smooth 18 9 240 20 47J Very iraooth 20 10 200 12 40.0 Fairly imooth 14 11 360 IS 45.8 Very imooth 16 Note that Table 2 represent! typical trials of thil series and ihowi that the smoothest curd it obtained from the higher-fat-content cream. From a quality standpoint 20 per cent cream save the best results. Usually if the original cream contains less than 10 per cent of. fat, the finished product is classified as Ncufchatel cheese, while the product made from cream testing 10 per cent of fat or more is known as cream cheese. Increasing the fat content of the cheese makes a richer, smoother, and tastier cheese (see Table 2). People who avoid so-called "rich" foods are ¦B-^ifl B JisssssH '^issss,,,,^ VBl^issl H' - isß^iflH H^iisssssssss&amp;Sl issssss^^^isssV^^^isssssssss^:^issl issssssP^issl isHL^ls^ ¦ iSeJM BHKM issßi^lsssssß v-~. '^issssssKCC;^isi ißp&gt;^l isssK^U kssssß'V-'¥'9isssssl ksssssT'li^kssi kssßilisssssi ksssssf^uissssssssl^ti^%^ksssssssssKpU^ksssl kssssK^kssfl kssssMf^ ksssV-'^l^ksssl ksssssr^ksssl ksssssM^tsssssssV'^rSijsssssssssssflOM^ksssi ksssK^kssssi ksssssik \&gt; kssssl'-^'^ksfl ksssfJi^kssl kssssT.^ .'^kssssssb^'i v\:^ksssssssssW^&gt;isssssl kssssss'^ksssi ksssssV^f Flo. I.—Note whey separation on the coils. The curd has been heated and is ready far homogeaization. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Neufchatel and Cream Cheese ¦ " ¦¦. ¦- - i . ¦ . - likely to prefer the Neufchatel cheese. As spoilage in cheese of this type is primarily confined to the protein portion, increasing the fat content and decreasing the protein or curd content will naturally enhance its keeping quality. As there is always sufficient protein in the finished product to cause spoilage, a high fat content mil delay, but not prevent, spoilage. The effect of homogenization.—Previous investigators (8* 11, 13) have pointed out that homogenization of the milk or cream before setting helps to prevent fat losses during the draining and pressing process. Experience at this Station has substantiated these claims. It was also found that homo - genization of the curd after the proper acidity has been reached and the curd has been heated makes a smoother and more palatable product. Different pressures were tried but low pressures, from 300 to 500 pounds, were found most satisfactory. It is believed that the homogenization of the curd sufficiently facilitates draining and improves the texture to justify the process where plant facilities and routine permit. Effect of temperature and length of time of cooking curd.—As this step in making Neufchatel or: cream cheese was found to have a decided influence on the finished product^ several hundred experiments were carried on to find the most desirable temperature and time-of heating. As high temperatures and long holding periods would destroy the maxi - mum number of organisms and therefore increase the keeping quality of the finished cheese, attempts; were made to use as high temperatures and as long holding periods as possible without injuring the texture or body of the finished product. j ¦.: . ¦...¦¦ Table 3.— The effect of teniperature of heating and holding time on the body and texture of the finished cheese—l 6 trials with 240 pounds of cream testing 15 per cent fat per trial. Trill T«??-» Tune Bod, and texture'"™fe m xt -*Yin - which t,_|j of the prcuing iffi' I"*"1 fini.hcdchee*: - to.pcilage . . P.ct. DegmtF. Mia. . Dw 1 . - .70 ¦-¦''; fG 30 Coarie and rough - •¦ 20 2, .71 I4S . 0 Coane and. rough U 3 ."-'¦ .68 135. !' 30 Coane and rough 19 - 4 ! - .70 " ¦ . 135 : 0 Coane and rough. -23. 5 .71 .125 30 Sllghllr coarK 20 6 .70 0 Fairly imooch 20 ' 7...¦.••" ' JSI . 115 30 . Smooth . ; M 8 .71 115 0 Smooth : 12 9 .70 120 30 Smooth 18 10 .71 J2O 0 Smooth 20 11 .70 125 15 . Smooth 19 12, .69 120 IS Smooth. U 13 .71 . 125 0 Smooth 23 . H .71 .120 0 Smooth ( v: 20. 15 .70 125 10 Smooth 24 16 .70 120 10 Smooth . 20 Mcidity calculated al lactic acid. \ ! '- - - .' . . ' </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 i Results in Table 3 are typical of many others obtained and indicate &gt;j that a maximum temperature to which the curd can be heated without ; injury to the body and texture of the finished product is 125° F. The ; holding time should not exceed 15 minutes. Over 100 trials were made 1 to check the above results. Temperatures over 125° F. usually produced a curd considerably coarser and less desirable. Holding time had much less influence, especially with lower temperatures. Fifteen-minute holding ' periods seemed to produce satisfactory results when used with tempera - tures of 125° F. or less. Longer holding periods did not increase the keeping quality and frequently injured the texture of the finished cheese. Caution should be used in heating the curd and as soon as whey separation is apparent the material should be homogenized. Summary of experimental work. —(1) Starter proved to be a better coagulant than rennet and starter gave more satisfactory results when used alone than when used with small amounts of rennet. Whenever rennet was used, whey leakage occurred, the amount of leakage being greatest ITJ^ilißE''Bum Fig. 2.—The curd is being homogenized, cooled, and placed in drainage bags. with the larger amounts of rennet. As the acidity of the curd at draining time is an important factor it must be carefully watched. Results indicated that the cheese kept best when the amount of starter used and the coag - ulating time allowed were so controlled that the acidity at the time of draining ranged between 0.6 and 0.7 per cent. Higher acidities usually produced a grainy body, while lower acidities failed to give complete drainage, allowing the curd to retain too much whey and giving the </seg>
         <seg id="p009">: Neufchaiel and Cream Cheese cheese an acid taste. Control ing the acidity accurately is especially im-. portant when the curd is heat:d prior to homogenizing and pressing. (2) The fat content of th: milk or cream from which the cheese is made is an important factor s fleeting the quality of the finished product. The higher the fat content, the smoother the finished cheese and the better its keeping quality and flavor. The only limiting factor in making a high-fat-content cheese is the manufacturer's ability to obtain a suf - ficiently high price to make up for the increased cost due to high fat content. (3) Homogenization of the milk or cream before the setting period lowers the fat losses in the wliey, which otherwise occur during the drain - ing process, and is helpful in producing a smoother product. Homogeniz - ing the curd after .heating facilitates drainage and makes a smoother - nnished product. . (4) Heating the curd after coagulation increases the keeping quality of the finished cheese. Temperatures of 120° to 125° F. have proved most satisfactory. Higher temperatures were injurious to the body and texture of the finished cheese] while lower temperatures proved ineffective in improving the keeping quality. Holding the curd at temperatures from 120° to 125° F. for 15 rninuies seemed to make these temperatures more effective. / . THE COMMERCIAL MANUFACTURE OF NEUFCHATEL AND CREAM CHEESE Raw material. —This cheese, although commonly made from cream testing between 10 and 20 per cent fat, may be made from milk or cream of any fat content. Cream with a fat content of more than 25 per cent is ordinarily impractical and uneconomical to use. If the fat content of BesS HES WiH I Fig. 3.—This method of stacking sacks facilitates draining. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 the raw material is approximately equal to that of whole milk, the cheese is commonly called Neufchatel cheese rather than cream cheese. Care should be taken in selecting the raw material. Milk or cream used in the manufacture of cream cheese should be fresh, sweet, clean, and free from all foreign flavors and should contain as few bacteria as possible. Processing.—The cream is standardized to the desired fat content, 12 to 20 per cent. The higher the fat content, the smoother, the richer, and the better the keeping quality of the finished cheese. It should be heated to 145° F. and homogenized at 2,000 to 3,000 pounds of pressure and held at 145° F. for 30 minutes in a vat. It is then cooled to 72° F. and set with from 0.10 to 0.25 per cent of starter to give it an acidity of 0.6 to 0.7 per cent in from 14 to 16 hours. The material may be set in shot - gun cans, ten-gallon milk cans, or in any vat equipped with an agitating device. Higher acidities make a sour cheese of poor keeping quality, while lower acidities retard draining and make the body of the finished cheese rubbery or stringy. When the acidity is between 0.6 and 0.7 per cent, the entire mass of curd is agitated and slowly heated to approximately 120° to 125° F. or until definite whey separation is noticeable. The curd is then homogenized at from 300 to 500 pounds of pressure, cooled to 50° or 60° F., and placed in draining bags (18"x36") of unbleached muslin or similar material that will allow free draining of the whey without loss of any curd. This last homogenization may be omitted if plant equipment or routine docs not conveniently allow for it. These bags, each holding about 10 gallons of curd and whey, are stacked in a "cooler" (40° F.) either on a rack or a clean tiled floor, and 'mm.X ' f ' '' ' ' " ~I" Fro. 4.—Curd after pressing in a home-made type of small press. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Neufchatel and Cream Cheese • frequently shifted to facilitate draining. If the cheese is made in sufficient quantities so that there are enough bags to allow their being stacked high enough so that their own weight will press them, no other arrangement is necessary to press the curd. If, however, the cheese is made in small quantities, as is the case in most instances, a press made from hard-wood slats V/ 2 "xV/i" spaced from 2" to 3" apart, will serve the purpose (Fig. 4). Under these circumstances it is only necessary to make two trays. The bags of curd are placed between these trays and weight in the form of 10-gallon milk cans filled with water will serve as additional press - ing force. The curd is pressed until it is firm enough to hold its shape. Usually 48 hours from the time the curd is placed in the bags it is suf - ficiently pressed to be ready for salting and packaging. Mixing, salting, and packaging.—Salt may be added either at the time the curd is placed in the bags) or after the curd is pressed. If added when the curd is placed in the draining bags, it should be stirred in, and about three times as much salt must be added to allow for the salt which is lost through whey drainage. [The amount of salt used in either case de - pends a good deal on personal taste. One to 2 per cent is generally suf - ficient when added after draining. Cheese of this type is usually packed in either one-fourth-pound cartons, glass or stone jars, metal-foil packages, or in 3- or 5-pound loaves in wooden boxes. Any protection such as that furnished by the container, a parchment wrapper, or by metal foil which prevents the air from coming in contact with the surface of the cheese will materially reduce spoilage. The packaged cheese should be kept as cold as possible without freezing. If properly made and kept, under re - frigeration this cheese should keep for at least three weeks. Cost—As the yield of ere im cheese per 100 pounds of cream depends largely on its fat and moisture content and as the fat tests of the cream may vary greatly, it is impossible to generalize about costs. The following figures are taken from actual jplant records and will illustrate typical yields of cream cheese on which costs are computed. Table 4.- -Yield of curd from 12 Table s.—Yield of Neufchatel curd per cent cream. ;| ' from 4 per cent mil\. Trul I Am 7! I Yield of I Yield per! 100 lbi. Trial I Ain't I Yield of IVield ptr 100 Ibl. No. I cram I curd I raw material No. I milk I curd I nwmatcrill Lit. Uu. lit. lit. Ibl. Ua. \ 150 48 31.2 1 350 87 . 24.8 3 2» 76 . 31.6: ¦ 1 -- 400 108 17.0 3 140 75 3U 3 400 IOS K3 4 SO 25 JU\ 4 255 60 23.4 5 160 45 28.1 5 400 98 235 « 200 62 31.0 6 240 60 &amp;2 7 140 50 35.7 7 240 69 28.7 8 240 79 ¦ 32.9 8 400 97 24£ '¦¦¦¦¦ Average 31.6 - ' . ' Aicraic 15.4 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 From the figures above, a yield slightly over 31 pounds of curd per 100 pounds of cream may be expected. There are 12 pounds of fat in lOC pounds of 12 per cent cream and if the fat in the cream costs 35 cents per pound, the ingredient cost of the curd would be = -^— = 0.1354, or 13.54 cents per pound. From these figures we may expect a yield of about 25 pounds of curd per 100 pounds of 4 per cent milk. There are 4 pounds of fat in 100 pounds of 4 per cent milk and so, if the {at in the milk costs 35 cents per pound, the ingredient cost of the curd will be—— ==——=.056, or 5.6 cents per pound. " " These illustrations should indicate that the ingredient pJ ;PiK : :\'^3Hffl^M^Mß£C^^^ffiag cost ot Neuichatel and cream pfflfilj|HH H cheese is relatively low. Hn KP Packaging, marketing, and H Hpf? overhead costs will usually M RslPi be equal to the ingredient cost but should not interfere jH MH^lpt^lfff with its being a relatively wP^t ißH^' ~~Tt7 profitable item for the aver- Bfl'ViV Iff ! -*fi»*lj age dairy manufacturing B^.;: &gt;&gt;.^a"'^'^^^^^^Br '-TI plant. Wi \ '&gt;V v V^S^^Ht^^' -'¦ ©I'tfe Flavors.—By adding V&lt;\\ }f y^WKK^^t^^g^ various flavoring materials ¦/ :'i-V/ /'.' K?^RK' ' ; such as pimentos, olives, V^-.j"'}/,' ylE^Bßlwt ¦" czZ~~* nuts, sweet-pickle relish, |L 'Jji\ 'Sm^tMt&amp;tiffi?^^ honey, and similar materials ¦jflKft''" '^iB Kl^^^^K^-^4^ a great many varieties of 11l , / ;''¦7jjH BrWPSI mff&amp;Y' cheeses and cheese spreads K^^^K-''jJ^'ntlßfWwifi may lie made. In making I X .u-'- -'.19 BlU^^^ffi pimento cheese, one No. l'/i H :• •¦&gt;.'/¦ Inß can to each 15 pounds of '-''¦' (¦ I Ho| curd gives very satisfactory H^HCv^ '¦&lt; /^,H BPJPH^Bii^ results. Olive nut cheese can .^B S—lwtJß pft? be made by mixing 2 pounds B ¦ ll^^l 1^ of chopped olives and 1 3^8% fl pound of chopped pecans with 15 pounds of curd. I I Relish cheese is made by I X iVQ Ml I mixing 2 pounds of sweet- I pickle relish with 15 pounds | H of plain or pimento-flavored Fig. s.—Curd in a mixer ready for packaging. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Neufchatel and Cream Cheese These cheeses will find a ready market in most communities and afford an excellent outlet for milk that might otherwise become.a burdensome surplus. Opportunities for developing this type of. cheese business are practically unlimited and depend only on the ingenuity of the dairyman. MAKING NEUFCHATEL OR CREAM CHEESE ON THE FARM OR IN THE SMALL DAIRY A satisfactory product canlbe made on the farm or in the small dairy according to the following method: Clean cream or milk ranging in fat content from 4 to 20 per cent is set in any available container, tempered to 72° F., and inoculated with'o.2s per cent of starter (clabbered milk) and kept at .72° F. for 12 to 14 [hours. This is usually done by setting the container of milk or cream in a water bath and keeping the temperature constant by using a room where the temperature is as near 70° as possible. At the end of this period trie milk or cream should have a dean and pleasant acid flavor and should be in the form o£ a firm curd which shows no wheying off. ' . : The coagulated material is now placed in clean, muslin or unbleached cotton 'draining bags. Heayy white sugar sacks are satisfactory if the stitched seams are doubled over and resewed. The threads in the, cloth of these bags must be close enough together so that the whey that drains away will be clear and not cloudy. Draining is allowed to take place in a cool room and may be facilitated by pressing the curd bags between boards weighted with cans or pails of water or similar arrangements. When the curd is firm enough to hold its shape, usually after pressing 48 hours, it is salted to suit taste (1 to 2 per cent) and is then ready for the addition of flavors and for packaging. ¦¦•¦¦-¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 303 LITERATURE CITED 1. Albus, W. R., and Ayrcs, S. Henry 1928. Gassy Fermentations in Reheated ok. Processed Cheese Products Con - taining Pimentos. Jour. Dairy Sci. 11:175-178. 2. Archibald, E. S. 1925. Cream Cheese and Butter. Dom. of Canada, Dcpt. of Agr. Cir. 23. 3. Archibald, E. S., and Meillcur, J. 1928. Cream Cheese. Dom. of Canada, Dept of Agr. Cir. 62. 4. Dahlbcrg, A. C. 1927. A New Method of Manufacturing Cream Cheese of the Neufchatfj. Type. /our. Dairy Sci. 10-. 106-116. 5. Decker, J. W., and Sammis, J. L. 1924. Cheese Makinc, 7th cd., Cheese Maker Book Co., Madison, Wis., p. 145 - -149. 6. Rsk, W. W. 1925. Unripened Soft Cheese. Cornel! Ext. Bui. 107. 7. Marquardt, J. C. 1930. New Process Neufchatel Adds Marketable Cream Cheese. Milk Dealer 19:51. 8. Marquardt, ]. C. 1927. Studies in Manufacturing Cream Cheese. Butter, Cheese and Egg Jour. 18:80 (monthly cd.&gt;. 9. Matheson. K. )., and Cammack, F. R. 1927. Neufchatel and Cream Cheese, Farm Manufacture asd Use. U. S. D. A. Farmer's Bulletin 960. 10. Matheson, K. [&#132; Thorn, Chas., and Curric, J. N. 1914. Cheeses of the Neufchatel Group. Storrs Exp. Sta. Bui. 78. 11. Messcher. 1927. The Manufacture of Five Pound Loaf Cheese. Butter, Cheese and Egg lour. 17:28. 12. Michels, John 1910. Improved Methods of Making Cottage Cheese and Neufchatel Cheese. North Carolina Exp. Sta. Bui. 210. 13. Parfitt, E. H. 1929. Fancy Cream Cheese. Creamery and Milk Plant Monthly, 18:82. 14. Templcton, H. L., and Sommer, H. H. 1932. Factors Affecting the Body and Texture of Processed Cheese. Jour. Dairy Sci. 15:29-41. 15. Templeton, H. L., and Sommer, H. H. 1932. Cheese Spreads, /our. Dairy Sci. 15:155-62. 16. Templeton, H. L., and Sommer, H. H. 1934. Cheese Spreads 11. [our. Dairy Sci. 17:3.73-78. 17. Van Slykt, L. K. and Price, W. V. 1927. Cheese. Orange Judd Publishing Co., N. V., pp. 249-57. ;8. Warren, Donald H. 1926. A Defect of Pimento Cheese. Jour. Dairy Sci. 9:351. 15M1 </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>