<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00017">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00017</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION, LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A., Press Bulletin No. 17, FEEDING EXPERIMENTS WITH HOGS.</title>
			            <date value="1903">1903</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
THE UNI VERS1 £\ OF NEBRASKA 

Agricultural Experiment Station 

LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A. 

Press Bulletin No. 17 

(Distributed January, 1903) 

FEEDING EXPERIMENTS WITH HOGS. 

Experiment I. 

FAT vs. BACON TYPE. 

The increasedjdemand for pork cured as bacon has led to the development 
of the so-called bacon breeds of swine, by which is meant 
hogs that will produce a maximum amount of lean meat with a 
minimum of fat There are two breeds, the Tamworth and Large 
Yorkshire, that have that conformation of body which makes them 
most suitable for bacon production. They differ from our more common 
fat breeds, Berkshire, Poland China, and Duroc Jersey, in that 
they are longer and deeper in body, thus furnishing more side meat, 
and have much smaller hams and shoulders. They are strong in 
bone and active in habits, making them good grazers, and are prolific 
as breeders, the Tamworth often producing from ten to twelve 
pigs at a farrow. To the western farmer the Tamworth presents an 
ungainly appearance, being long in head and snout, high on legs and 
long in body. 

UThe superiority of the Tamworth and Yorkshire for bacon prostion 
has not been questioned. Their ability to compete with other 
breeds in making gains for food consumed, has been questioned. The </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
In conducting the experiment, Tamworths were selected to represent 
the bacon type. Two lots of Tamworths were uaed, representing 
two litters of pigs. The pigs in Lot 4, ten in number, were 
made immune from cholera when very young by Mm method 
practiced by the Department of Animal Pathology in the Experi- 
BfalHcML The pigs in each lot were givon one-fourth of an acre 
of alfalfa pasture and the same grain ration; namely, ground wheat 
40 per cent, wheat shorts 40 per cent, ind ground corn 20 per cent. 

A predominance of wheat was used because it was cheaper_than 
corn when the experiment was conducted. 

E following table shows the amount of food consumed, the 
gain of each pig in the several lots, and the amount of grain 
to make one pound of gain. 

TABLE I. 

Period I, six weeks, Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds 

K»in consumed to produce one pound of (rain during both periurteen 
weeks : Lot 1, 4.45 pounds ; Lot 2, 4.71 pounds ; Lot 3, 
undi ; Lot 4, 4.31 pounds ; Lot 5, 4.95 pounds. 

¦«Te - «S N "See q« = ? a -3TS 

Aug. 12— Sept. 23. 
Lot 1. — 8 Duroc Jerseys 

71 

114 

1 03 

3.86 

„ 

Lot 2.-8 Poland Chinas 

66 

104 I 

.91 

3.86 

- 

•—8 Berkshire- Tam- 
:h cros8breds 

66 

111 

1 01 

3.86 

„. 

Lot 4.— 10 Tamworths 

75 

118 

1.08 

3.68 

3.5S 

Lot 6.-6 Tamwortht- 

99 

149 

1 19 

4.97 

4.18 

Period II, eight weeks, 
Sept. 23— Nov. 18. 
Lot 1.— 8 Duroc Jerseys 

114 

200 

1 54 

7.62 

4.96 

Lot 2.-6 Poland Chinas .... 

107 

193 

1 53 

7.78 

5.O7 

Lot 3.-8 Berkshire- Tarn- 
worth crossbreds 

111 

200 

1 63 

7.62 

.. 

Lot 4.— 10 Tamworths 
Lot 5. — 6 Tamworths ..._ 

118 
149 

202 
234 

1 49 
1.53 

7.38 
8.45 

= </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
irhe tabulations were made in two separate periods owing to the 
that two Poland China pigs were off feed and were withdrawn 
the experiment at the end of six weeks. This may account in 
for the unsatisfactory gains made by the Poland Chinas during 
ad I. The remaining six which were carried through Period II 
i in good thrift during the fourteen weeks. 

A comparison of Period I with Period II shows that pigs make 
greater daily gain? as they grow larger, but require more food to 
produce a pound of gain. The importance of marketing pigs when 
fat enough to market without carrying them too long is thus empha- 

Ee records made by Lot 4 show that Tamworths are capable of 
g their own with other breeds in the matter of gains.- This 
ment shows them at an advantage but it would not be safe to 
sitively that they make cheaper gains than other breeds until 
r tests have been made. 

The gains made by Lot 4 also go to show that the process of immunizing 
pigs against cholera does not retard further growth. Lot 
4 was the only immune lot. The records made by Lot 5 are hardly 
comparable with those made by other lots, since the pigs in that lot 
were older and larger, placing them at a disadvantage in the economical 
use of food. 

Ehile in this experiment the Duroc Jerseys made a slightly 
gain than the Poland Chinas, a second trial might reverse the 
i. Individuality often counts for more than breed. 

Eie hogs all sold at the same price per pound, since the western 
rs are as yet not willing to pay a premium for bacon hogs. In 
nd and Canada, bacon hogs sell for more on the market, under 
circumstances they would be more profitable to raise. 

Experiment II. 

rD BLOOD ADDED TO A MIXED RATIOX FED TO 
HOGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE. 

The object of Experiment II was to determine the influence ot 
dried blood when added to a mixed ration. 

I wo lots of Berkshire- Tamworth crossbred pigs were used in 
xperiment. One lot was Lot 3 of the previous experiment, 
; the ration fed consisted of ground wheat 40 per cent, wheat 
; 40 per cent, and ground corn 20 per cent. Lot 6 was not ind 
in the previous experiment. They were fed a ration conaist-1 
ground wheat 40 per cent, wheat shorts 85 per cent, ground 
90 per cent, and dried blood 6 per cent </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
I this test it will be seen that 5 per cent dried blood added to the 
m did not increase the gains from food consumed. This is to beatlted 
to the fact that all the lots had a mixed diet, viz. alfalfa paswith 
40 per cent wheat, 86 per cent shorts and 20 per cent corn in 
tion to 6 per cent dried blood, which provided all the food nutrineeded, 
with sufficient protien. So far as one experiment with 
lots of pigs can prove any question, it indicates that the mixed 
&gt;n without the dried blood contains all the variety 'and all the 
ein or flesh-forming elements needed by pigs of this size. 

i experiments conducted at Iowa and Indiana and other Experi- 
I Stations, where only dried blood was added to a corn ration a 
ted increase in the economy of the gains resulted. These expends 
would indicate that variety and a properly balanced ration 
he chief factors in economical gains on growing'pigs and that 
I blood is economical'only when it is the cheapest method of supig 
the protein to make a proper ration. 

I Experiment VIII of Bulletin 76 it required six per cent less corn 
oduce 100 pounds of gain where five per cent dried blood was fed 
corn to Tarn worth pigs on alfalfa pasture, but it increased slighte 
cost of gains. In both these cases the bacon hogs on pasture 
? much better and cheaper gains than in Experiment VII, Bullei, 
where four bacon hogs and two block hogs made up each lot 

E. A. Bcbnbtt, 

H. R. Smith. 

1 ADUr^ lit 

§4 til if 
&lt; &lt; &lt; 
Period I, six weeks, 
Aug. 12— Sept. 23. Pounds Pounds Pounds 

J IS? 8 &amp; 2 a' 
&gt;&amp;ss. sis. 
Pounds Pound* 

Lota— 8 Berk sh ire-Tarn - 
worth crossbreds 86 109 1.01 

3.H6 3.84 

B— 6 Berkshire-Tam- 
orth crossbreds, 
ied blood added 73 118 .95 

3.90 4.10 

. 

Period II, eight weeks, 
Sept. 88— Nov.ia 
Lot 3 109 300 1.63 
Lot6 _. 118 200 1.65 

7.82 4.68 
7.65 4.91 </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>