<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00029.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00029.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">I'liailet* Hunting. President Nebraska. I&gt;airym&gt; iation 1 Hlo-iHi i </seg>
            <seg id="p002">or the EBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE Year 1910 PREPARED BY S. C. BASSETT. Secretary NKB8ASKA DAIRYMBN8 ASSOCIATION YORK BLANK BOOK CO.. Phi stirs York. Nkbbaska </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Dairymen's Association. , Secretary's Office, Gibbon, Nebraska, Feb. 1, 1911. \" His Excellency, C. H. Aldrich, Governor of Nebraska: KSir: In compliance with the law in this case made and provided, reby transmit the Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairymen"* ciation for the year 1910. Yours respectfully, S. C. BASSETT, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE OF CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal 3 Officers 7 List of Members 9 Program of Annual Meeting 14 Report of Treasurer 17 Report of Auditing Committee 18 Address of President, Charles Harding 19 Appointment of Committees 23 Nebraska Dairy Cattle Breeders Association 23 "Duties of a Cream Receiver," J. E. Vogel 25 Diecussin, Prof. C. W. Mellick, 28 "Two Years in the Dairy Commission Office," S. L. Mains '. 36 Remarks, Dairy Commissioner W. R. Jackson 40 Hesult of Douglas County Testing Association, W. C. Andreas 48 Discussion, Henry C. Glissman 49 Address, Prof. John Bower 53 Remarks, Regent George Copland Essay Contest, List of Contestants 58 62 First Prize Essay on the Silo, W. C. Forbes 62 "Silo Construction," J. W. Dawson 66 "Silo Construction," I. D. Miller 71 ••Growing the Corn and Filling the Silo," Prof. C. W. Pugsley 7 4 1 Value of Silage in Feeding Farm Animals," Prof. A. L. Haecker.... 81 Discussion, John Bower 84 "The Silo and What It Means to the Farmer," Geo. P. Bellows 86 Report of Nominating Committee and Election of Officers 88 Resolutions 89 ■ Discussion by H. C. Young, John Sneddon, Mr. Culver, John Bower, T. A. Gierns, A. Wyman, Prof. W. L. French 80 Cow Judging Contest 99 LUt of Creameries and Cheese Factories 101 </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">OFFICERS FOR 1911-1912. PrpciHpnt ........ ........E. T. ttcctor, uniEDE Vice-President W. L. Hunter. Raymond Secretary-Treasurer S. C. Bassett. Gibbon DIRECTORS. Charles Harding Omaha Prof. A. L. Haectcer - Lincoln E. W. Frost ■ Central Clty W. Righter Wood Omaha H. C. Young </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION LIST OF MEMBERS. | ~ I Honorary Life Members. J. H. Monrad _ Naerum, Denmark C. L. GabriUon New Hampton. Iowa W. D. Hoard Fort Atkinson, WU. A. C. Tupper Osage, Iowa Life Members. W. C. Andreas Beatrice, Nebr. D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, Nebr. J. Dixon Avery— care Fairmont Creamery Co Pittsburgh Pa. 8. C. Bassett Gibbon, Neb John Baumer Omaha, Nebr. J. If. Bayley Gibbon, Nebr. W. A. Carpenter York, Nebr. L. S. Coffin Fort Dodge, Iowa, J. B. Uinsmore Sutton, Nebr. W. C. Drury Kearney, Nebr. If. Dabelstein Waterloo, Nebr. Chas. Dabelstein Waterloo, Nebr. Wm. Eiche Station B, Omaha, Nebr. Dr. B. B. Davis Bee Building, Omaha, Nebr. F. S. Fulner Gibbon, Nebr. W. L. French State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. T. G. Furgason Beaver Crossing, Nebr. Germantown Co-Operative Creamery Aaa'n Germantown, Nebr. Henry C. Glissman Station B, Omaha, Nebr. H. C. Glissman Station B, Omaha. Nebr.- E. W. Gunther Albion, Nebr. Prof. A. L. Haecker Station C, Lincoln, Nebr. Hon. E. J. Hainer Lincoln, Nebr. E. F. Howe Fairmont Cr'y Co., Omaha, Nebr. Henry Krumhauer 156 So. 33d St., Lincoln, Nebr. J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, Nebr. Kirschbraum &amp; Sons Omaha, Nebr. Morelle B. King York. Nebr. E. M. Little Route No. 1, Benson, Nebr. J. C. Merrill Sutton, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION J. H. Rushton Fairmont Creamery Co., Omaha, Nebr. E. T. Rector Fairmont Creamery Co., Omaha, Nebr. J. A. Reedy Lincoln, Nebr. J. R. Roberts 1524 N 8t., Lincoln, Nebr. John Sneddon Eagle, Nebr. R. Stouffer Bellevue, Nebr. Win. Sutton Table Rock, Nebr. Cha«. W. Stevenson Sioux City. Iowa. F. H. Vaughn Cheyenne, Wyoming W. G. Wnitmore Valley, Nebr. Prof. H. H. Wing Ithaca. N. Y. W. Righter Woods Station B, Omaha, NeDr. AjuuuU Members, Arnold, R. A Royal Hotel, Lincoln, Nebr Backlund. T. A Stromsburg, Neb. Barber, Bert, North Platte, Neb. BarU, Carl Phillips, Neb. Beach. Irving. J., Quick. Neb. Beckoff. A. H State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. Biglow, A. R Fairbury. Nebr. Biba. A. B Exeter, Nebr. Billiar, W. L Wilcox, Nebr. Bower, John Beatrice Cream Co., Lincoln, Nebr. Brinton. E. H Lincoln, Nebr. Buer, Geo Beatrice Cream Co., Lincoln, Nebr. Buls. rtichard. Burgess, C. N Karbach Blk, Omaha, Nebr Burr. F. H Hastings, Nebr. Camp, R. H Republican City, Nebr. Chase, F. J Pawnee City, Nebr. Chittenden, Z. H 2741 R. St., Lincoln, Nebr. Clark, E. H 1965 Ryon St., Lincoln. Nebr. Clark. C. A Ravenna, Nebr. Clark, L. If Moulton. la. Calkins, H. A Bayard, Nebr. Carlson. Walter Ceresco, Nebr. Chilcoat, R Stanton, Nebr. Cleary, John, North Loup, Nebr. Collier. W. J 413 Nor. 28. Lincoln. Nebr. Conigtock, E. D Comstock, Nebr. Cornell G A R F D 6 Lincoln Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p012">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 11 Culver, Vere, S Albion, Nebr. Davis. J. A Bridgeport, Nebr. Dawson. J. W 1105 Nor. 33, Lincoln. Nebr. Delano, H. C Lincoln, Nebr. Detwiler, R Raymond, Nebr Dinsmore, J. B 156 So. 33, Lincoln, Nebr. Eld red, J. P Kearney, Nebr. Emily, R. K McCook, Nebr. Evans, O. G Lawrence, Nebr. Farrar, W. S Lincoln, Nebr. FauBCh, H. R v Guide Rock, Nebr. Fleury, W. C ". Lincoln, Nebr. Forbes, Will Wayne, Nebr. Fraley, Geo. C Dizon, 111. Frost, E. W Central City, Nebr. Grow, William, Clarkson, N&lt; br. Geary, R. B Innman, Nebr. Giberson, R. H Weeping Water, Nebr. Gierins, T. A Lincoln, Nobr. Gramlich, H 2409 G. St., South Omaha, Nebr. Gregg. A. S Alliance, Nebr. Gross, Frank. Clarkson, Nebr. Gunerud, H 409 Brown Blk, Omaha, Nebr. Griffie, J Lincoln, Nebr. Gubsor, J. L Ulysses, Nebr. Guegan, Theo., 33 &amp; O. St.. Lincoln, Nebr. Guggs, L. D De Witt, Nebr. Harris, C. C Fairbury, Nebr. Holding. T. L Whitney, Nebr. Haageson, O. M Yuma, Colo. Hamer, A. G Lincoln, Meur. Harnley, E. R College View, Nebr. Hanson, L. F. Concord, Nebr. Hunt. John, Baird, Ne-.r. Hunter, Paul, Raymond, Nebr. Hunter, W. L Raymond, Nebr. Huston, H. E Brock, Nebr. Jenkins, S Alma, Nebr. Johnson, J. Alfred,- Erickson Kelley, Fred, Kjar, A. A Lexington, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Lantx, Ray, Kearney, Nebr. Larson, James P Hastings, Nebr. Lasch, A. A Weeping Water, Nebr. Lauridgen, H Mason City, Nebr. Liebers. Otto H Minden, Nebr. Little, Dr. L Clarks, Nebr. Lindburg, E. 8 Lincoln, Nebr. McCarthy, J Spaldlng. Nebr. Mains, S. L _ Crete. Nebr. Marshall, Roy, Lincoln, Nebr. Matthews, H. L Maxfleld, D. D. MeUer. Leo. Moore. V. N Murray, C. A Murray. K. L Beatrice Cream Co. Lincoln, Nebr. McGinnis, Robt Lincoln, Nebr. Nichols, C. S Long Pine, Nebr. North, Carl, Harvard, Nebr. Oline. H. E Lynch, Nebr. Posson, R. J Eureka, Nebr. Potter, W. L Wilcox, Nebr. Pierce, J. H Atlanta, Nebr. Phillips, Geo. .8 Tecumseh, Nebr. Pratt, F. E Fremont, Nebr. Rees, W. H. Carroll, Nebr. Renner, Fred, State Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. Reynolds, S. S Brady, Nebr. Rich. L. A College, View, Nebr. Roberts. W. F : Joy, Nebr. Rolfes. Frank, Grafton. Nebr Rueter, Henry Wabash, Nebr. Rundall, \V. E 439 So. 12th St. Lincoln, Nebr. Rupert, \V. J 1326 Nor. 29, Lincoln, Nebr. Ryan, F 1901 So. 11th, Lincoln, Nebr. Schak, J Box 90, Lincoln, Nebr. Schlegemilch, A.. Seward, Nebr. L Auburn. Nebr. ) 1815 Prospect, Lincoln. Nebr Culbertson, Nebr. University Place, Nebr i El wood, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 Schopbel, E. C University Place, Nebr. Schulte, C. J 1920 J St., Lincoln, Nebr. Schum, Wm Hastings, Nebr. Schundt, Otto Germantown, Xebr. Schwager, C 1812 Farnam, Omaha, Nebr. Severe, H. L Palmyra, Nebr. Severe, O. A Palmyra, Nebr. Snodgrass, L. E Talmage, Nebr. Stelk, W. D Orand, Island. Nebr. Squires, David Ord, Nebr. Streitz, C. W Millard, Nebr. Stubbe, H Central City, Nebr. Svec, Prank A Howells, Nebr. Taylor, L. B 3332 Burt St., Omaha, Nebr. Templin, A. H Palmer, Nebr. Tuttle, O. W Riverton, Nebr. Thomas, Geo Iniversity Place, Nebr. Vogel, Carl, Clarkson, Nebr. Vogel, J. E Beatrice, Nebr. Wentz, Lawrence, Lincoln, Nebr. Warren, K. A .'...Lincoln, Nebr. Weber, A. E Geneva, Nebr. Weinerst, C. C Falls City, Nebr. Williams, R. ('... Lincoln Hotel, Lincoln. Nebr Wilcox, A. W '. North Platte ,Nebr. Wilkenson, H. J 1T.21 So. 22, Lincoln, Nebr. Wilson, Aha Bethany, Nebr. Witt, Bernhard, Scribner, Nebr. Wright. F. C Beatrice. Nebr. Wyiuan, A. L Wood River, Nebr. Young, H. C 33rd and O St., Lincoln, Nebr. Yjuug, C. S 33rd and O St., Lincoln, Nebr. Honorary Members 4 Life Members 43 Annual Members 143 Total 190 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 14 TWKXTY-SIXTH ANNUAL MKKTIXG OF THK . NEBRASKA DAIKYMKVK ASSOCIATION. PROGRAM Wednesday, Thursday and Friday, January 18, 19, 20, 1911. Session? held in Dairy Stock Judging Pavilion, University Farm, Lincoln. 'Wednesday, January 18. Dairy Stock Day 10:00 A. M Address of President Charles Harding Report of Secretary and Treasurer S. C. B asset t Appointment of Committees Judging Dairy Cows William Forbes 1:00 P M Annual Meeting of Nebraska Dairy Cattle Breeders' Association Henry C. Glissman. President; E. M. Little, Secretary. The Co-Operative Dairy Cow Test Prof. W. L. French How 1 Would Conduct Dairying on a Nebraska Farm — Reading of Prize Essay and Discussion of the Subject Thursday, January 10. Cream Producing and Cream Receiving Day 10:00 A. M Duties of a Cream Receiver J. E. Vogel Two Years in the Dairy Commission Office S. L. Mains </seg>
            <seg id="p016">TWENTY-PIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 15 1:30 P. M. Results of the Douglas County Cow Testing Association \V. C. Andreas Discussion led by W. Jessen, President of the Association. Address Prof. John Bowers Friday. January ML Kl Silo Session. Joint Session of Nebraska Dairymen's Associa and Live Stock Improvers' Association. Session held in Stock Judging Pavilion. 9:00 A. M Silo Construction J. W. Dawson, Lincoln Discussion led by I. D. Miller, Alma. 10:00 A. M Growing the Corn and Filling the Silo. Prof. C. W. Pugsley, State I'niversity. Discussion led by R. Hogue, Crete, Nebraska; Prof. T. L. Haecker. Minnesota. 10:45 A. M. Efalue of Silage in Feeding Farm Animals Prof. A. L. Haecker ssion led by Prof. John Bower, Lincoln; O. Severe, Palmyra. 1:30 P. M. Sessions held in the Dairy Stock Judging Pavilion. Report of Committees, Election of Officers. Address Prof. T. L. Haecker, University of Minnesota. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 COW JUDGING CONTEST. Regulations. Open to members of the Association only. Anyone may become * member on the payment of $1.00. Pro rata premium $150.00 KThe pro rata premium will be divided among those scoring 75 or points out of a possible 100 points, in proportion to the number )ints scored above seventy-five. KTen cows will be used in this judging contest and these cows will ept on the experiment station farm the ensuing year and a corn - record kept of the milk and butter production of each. tTo the five (5) contestants in this contest who score the nearest sponding to the comparative butter records made by these cows &gt;g the coming year the sum of five (5) dollars each will be award - addition to the awards from the pro rate fund; these last named b of five dollars each to be awarded at the annual meeting in Janu - 1912. The judging will be done on Friday, January 20, at 3:30 , and every member is most cordially invited to take part in the Remarks KAny person may become a member of this association on payment lembership fee of $1.00. Everybody welcome whether a member iot. All sessions will be held in Dairy Stock Pavilion, University i. Ample street car facilities between the city and the farm. Noon - lunch can be obtained at the farm. For programs or other information in regard to the annual meeting address S. C. BASSETT, Secretary Gibbon, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION- 17 PROCEEDINGS OF THE TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. The proceedings of this meeting were held in the Dairy Stock Pavilion on the University farm. Wednesday. January 18th, 1011. The meeting was called to order by W. Righter Wood, Vice-presi- dent, owing to absence of the president. In the absence of the presi- dent first in order was the report of the treasurer. Report of Treasurer, To the Officers and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: Herewith is transmitted the financial transactions of the Associa- tion for the year 1910, with accompanying vouchers. Respec ff ully submitted, S. C. BASSETT, Treasurer. RECEIPTS Cash on hand January 1st, 1910 S 14.71 Received annual membership fees $1 each 199.00 Jan. 12 State appropriation 239.12 Jan. 21 Six annual membership fees at $5 30.00 Feb. 10 State appropriation 332.95 March 9 Draft sent W. Strand, letter returned unclaimed .SO June 18 State appropriation 432.00 June 22 State appropriation 211.00 September 1, State appropriation &lt;1.00 Total $1580.58 EXPENDITURES — SUMMARY Paid premiums at annual meeting $ 317.70' Paid Stationery and printing 34.44 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Paid expenses of dairy cow test :»5.8J Paid incidental expenses of annual meeting . 47.00 Paid Geo. E. Berg &amp; Co., badges 36.00 Paid salary of Secretary 300.00 Paid C. W. Melick expenses to deliver address at annual meeting • 12.10 Paid E. M. Little expenses to deliver address at annual meet- ing 10.00 »E. \V. Hunt expenses to deliver address at annual meet - «■« H- 00 Paid postage 59.00 Paid York Blank Book Co., — printing annual reports 432.00 Paid Kearney Hub — binding reports 4.50 Paid traveling expenses of officers attending meetings 129.28 Paid express, freight, telephone and office supplies 8.65 Cash to balance 170.08 Total $1580.58 The complete itemized report of the treasurer with aeconipanyirs vouchers was referred to an auditing committee which committee sub- I the following report, the aMM being adopted: ite|K&gt;rt of Auditing Committee. We, the auditing committee have examined the report of tt treasurer, S. C. Hasscit. with the accompanying vouchers and find same to be correct and that the money expended was for the best in- terests of the association. (Signed) PAIL HUNTER JOHN SXEDDON, Auditing Committee. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 19 ••RESIDENTS AVMAI, ADDRESS. To one who has known this Association during all the twenty-six years of its life, and who has attended every one of its annual meet - ings, as Mr. Bassett has done, the thing which must impress him most, it seems to me, is the constantly increasing interest and attendance each year. We hare certainly grown some, and the man whom this Asso - ciation now honors by naming as its President, is certainly justified if his "bosom swells with pride" like the Admiral in "Pinafore." When one looks back over the old reports of the yearly meetings which were held all over the state, before we had the good sense to see that right here at the State University was the only logical place to meet, one wonders how we could have had the patience to listen to discussion of the subjects which at that time seemed to us to be im - portant. Possibly some one will look over this history, that we shall make during this meeting, twenty-five years hence, and say the same things about what we are all doing here. Indeed. I think it is almost certain that some one will for I am convinced that while we are in - clined, sometimes, to pat ourselves on the back feeling that we have done much and left but little still to be done, we shall nevertheless find, if we live through another ten or fifteen years, that what we have accomplished so far, is as nothing at all. to what this good old com - monwealth is going to do in the years to come as the proceedings of this meeting will eventually be printed, bound, and filed away, as a part of the history of this Association, I want to take this opportunity to raise the veil, and peer ahead a little into the future — 1 want to give you a little notion, just briefly, of what I think Nebraska is going to do in the dairy world in the years to come. There seems to be something or other in the air out here on these prairies that makes braggarts of us all. When I am away from home, as I have been a good deal during the past year, and am asked as one always is about how Nebraska is getting along — I throw out my chest as any loyal Nebraskan will do, and tell them modestly that we are undoubtedly "The People." I tell them that the air, the water, the sunshine, the soil, the climate, the nun and women, the young men and maidens, are a little bit — nay, very much better here, judgeJ by any possible standard, than anywhere else in all this universe. After I have told them this in general terms I proceed to particular - ize. — and really, it is astonishing how easy it is to convince yourself, at least, that this is the greattst and the grandest and the most glorious state from every possible standpoint, of all the galaxy of states,— bar none. Cf course, so far as foreign countries are con - cerned, they are not to be considered at all. Pardon this apparent digression. What I started out to say was this: We are inclined per - haps, to lay too much stress on the bigness of things. We boast of the vast extent and inexhaustible fertility of these prairies, — of the siie of our corn and wheat crop. — of the millions and millions of pounds of </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION butter, — of the train loads of eggs and poultry. Much of this is true. — perhaps most of it, (leaving out that statement about the inex - haustability of the soil) but I don't hear much said about the average yield of any of these products per ace, nor do I hear of any one boasting very loudly about the average quality, especially of this vast amount of butter and eggs. Do you know that the average yield per acre of wheat in Italy is about double what it is in this country? Do you know that it is possible to raise 150 bushels of corn per acre, — or in other words, four or five times the average yield in Nebraska? Do you know that the production of butter in that little kingdom of Denmark, — which to about the size of Lancaster county, is — times the total for the whole of this great and glorious commonwealth. — and that practically every pound of that butter commands the highest price in the markets. These are some of the things that I want to em - phasize, and the point I wish to make is this: I We should quit vexing our souls about how we shall manage to ease the size of everything, and turn our attention more to the ition of quality, and to the question of making the best possible of what we have to work with. Which dairyman, for example, do think the more likely to succeed: The one, who on 40 acres of maintains 40 head of good dairy cows producing 10.000 lbs. of per year, or the one who on 640 acres of land keeps 100 head of i producing 10,000 lbs. of fat? These two types are by no means erne. The first is altogether possible, and the latter is altogether common. I Do you realize that it would be possible to increase the value of raska's butter crop at least 5c per pound, and that this increase in e would amount to about two million dollars annually? Don't think that would be a whole lot better for the dairy interest of state untimately, than it would to double the output of butter, if increase bad to come from the farms where 100 pounds of fat cow is the average yi arly yield? Of course you do! Because that itional two million dollars could be had without the expenditure of single hor£( powi r more energy than is now being expended. Ilf all the men who produce this butter fat in Nebraska, and all men who handle it. could just manage somehow to get together agree on handling this product the way it ought to be handled, two million dollars aforesaid, could and would be practically all ■d to the producers cream checks. It has taken me some time to get around to the thing which I started out to say some time ago, but here it is: The dairy develop - ment of the future in Nebraska must, and I believe will be directed towards the saving of that two million dollars. In order to bring this about, it will not be necessary for the farmer to sell all the dairy cows he now has and replace them with pedigreed Guernseys or Jerseys </seg>
            <seg id="p022">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 21 sirable and important both of these things might be. It will not be necessary for the manufacturer to junk all or any of his present equip - ment. It will simply be necessary, on the part of the farmer, to keep his cream clean and sweet until it is delivered for shipment, and on the part of the manufacturer for him to see to it that it is kept in that condition until it reaches the factory. The first requirement on the part of the producer seems, and is, simple enough and easy of accomplish - ment, — and would have been done long ago had it not been for "the other fellow" — or, to be more exact, the other "fellows" for every man buying cream in this state today, has contributed somewhat to the general demoralization. I am not charging any one with having done this with malice aforethought. On the contrary, every manufacturer in the state appreciates the tremendous importance of improving the qual - ity of his output, but he is right up against a stone wall in the shape of unrestrained competition, the slogan of which appears to be, — "Get business at whatever cost. Never mind about the price, or quality, or anything else. Just get the business somehow or other ,and we will take our chances on being able to smooth it out later on." Every year, for the past five or ten years, new concerns have started up, some in the state and some outside the state, None of these concerns has created any new business or developed any new territory- Whatever business they have gotten has been taken away from some other concern already doing business. In order to get that business they, of course, have had to offer inducements of some sort or other. Sometimes these inducements are in the shape of a higher price for butter fat, either through the receiving station or to the individual shipper direct. Sometimes in the shape of higher commission or sal - ary, or other perquisite to the station operator. In no case is this extra price ever based on the requirement that a better grade of cream must be furnished. On the contrary, anything that looks like cream is gladly received and paid for at the highest prices. Do you know of any other business in the world that is handled in that way? Could the grain business, or the swine business, or the cattle business be bandied in that way? I think not. If the above statement respecting conditions is true you will naturally ask "How is it that the creamery business has managed to go along and apparently succeed?" Simply because during the past ten years the demand for butter has been, most of the time, apparently in excess of the supply. Under such market conditions, the question of a slight difference in quality has made little or no difference in the price, but we are right now confronted with an entirely different con - dition. The supply is greater than the demand, and has been for some months past Strictly fancy butter, or in other words, butter that will grade as a technical extra is wanted at the market price. Butter that is fairly good is slow of sale at a discount, and the rest of the stuff </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 NEBRASKA DAIRYMK 'CIATION not wanted at any price, and the storage houses are full of it. Oleo - margerine has taken the place of that kind of butter, and in my judg - ment is going to hold that position. There is going to be in the markets a much wider range of values between strictly fancy butter and fairly good buttter. I do not believe that we are going to see right away, such low prices for fancy butter as we saw 15 years ago, but I do believe that butter which sells for the highest market price in the future, has got to come equarely up to the market standards for that grade. If Nebraska, therefore, expects even to hold the place she now occupies in the dairy world, it will be necessary for every man who has anything whatever to do with the handling of this product to make quality the watchword. If we are compelled to do business in the mar - kets of the world on a five cent handicap, we will not be able to stay in the game. And this is exactly what we shall be up against with respect to a large percentage of our output unless we face about. BI am quite sure that every creamery man in this state will admit truth, substantially, of all that I have said, respecting conditions, the imperative need, at once, of our attention to this question of *oving the average quality of the output. You will probably say that it is May to find fault, bu. the im - portant thing is to find the remedy and having found that remedy, to apply it. Xo reform of this kind can hope to succeed without the co - ation of all the dairy interests working together harmonii through some organization, having that one object in view. If that is true, why should not this Nebraska Dairymen's Association be that organization. 1 have felt for a long time, that the dairy interests were not making sufficient use of their own state Association. If this Association stands for anything at all. it must stand for the upbuilding along sane and reasonable lines of all the dairy interests, an 1 how ran we hope for substantial growth when we are absolutely throwing away such a sum as Two Million Dollars annually, by making so large &amp; per cent of inferior and low grade butter? Instead of this Association meeting once a year to discuss a lot of academic questions, why not get together every month in the ft ar. at the call of the President here in Lincoln, for the sole purpose of making an hontst. earnest, and united attempt to improve the general situation We have a National Association of Creamery Butter Manufac - turer's, the object and purpose of which has been the uplift and im - provement of the business all along thp line. Professor McKay, the active head of this organization, has done a good deal apd I am very cure would gladly co-operate with this Association in every way possible for the solution of this problem which I feel, we are facing right now. Our Pure Food Commissioner has done what he could, with </seg>
            <seg id="p024">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 23 sure that we shall have the active support and sympathy of the present Commissioner, Mr. Jackson, in any effort we may make, looking to the Improvement of the whole situation for the common good of all. I would not have you get the impression from what I have said, that these bad conditions are peculiar to Nebraska. On the contrary, the situation in the states surrounding us is practically the same; indeed, all that I have said on the question of quality, would apply with almost equal force to the dairy states in general, and particularly to all the so-called western dairy states. II hope the committee on resolutions will see fit to consider this jestion, which I have made, and bring in a resolution along the 3 I have indicated, for consideration at the proper time. There certainly be no harm in airing this question fully and freely with view to evolving some plan on which we can all work together to • the evils which now confront us. I take it that we are here for ness. If I am right about this, it furnishes a sufficient excuse for rather unusual form of address from your President. ■ The President: I wish to announce the appointment of Commit - at the present time as follows: Auditing Committee — Sneddon, Hunter, Bassett. Committee on Nominations — Wilkinson, Young. Frost. Committee on Resolutions — Bassett, Mclrilosh, W. Righter Wood. IThis completes the program for this afternoon, and if there is no business to come before the Association we will now adjourn tomorrow at 10 o'clock. XKBKASKA DAIRY CATTLK BKKKDKRS ASSOCIATION. IThe annual meeting of the Nebraska Dairy Cattle Breeders As - tion was held on January 18th, 1911, during the meeting of the linen's Association. The officers elected were as follows: President — H. C. Young, Lincoln. Vice President — Henry C. Clissman, Station B, Omaha. Secretary and Treasurer — E. W. Frost, Central City. Board of Managers — H. C. Young, W. Righter Woods, E. W. Frost, A. Sneddon, Prof. A. L. Haecker, P. C. Hunter. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION List of members of the Association with name of breed handled by Holstein. Badger &amp; Frost Central City, Nebr. E. H. Clark Lincoln, Nebr. Culver &amp; Son Albion, Nebr Wm. Eiche, Station B, Omaha, Nebr. G. Fish back. Orleans, Nebr. H. C. Glissman Station B, Omaha, Nebr. A. A. Luttin Cozad, Nebr. C. F. Kuehl Benson, Nebr. Negley Ansley, Nebr. H. L. Severe Palmyra, Nebr A. Sneddon Eagle, Nebr. J. Sneddon Eagle, Nebr. A. Wyman Wood River, Nebr. Dr. B. B. Davis Bee Bldg. Omaha, Nebr. .ler&gt;ey&gt;. F. H. Burr Hastings, Nebr. P. C. Hunter Raymond, Nebr. W. L. Hunter Raymond, Nebr. S. Jones Westover, South Dakota L. Little Clarks. Nebr. Dr. H. Pritchard Florence, Nebr. A. II. Templin Palmer, Nebr. F. B. Tipton. Seward, Nebr. H. C. Young Lincoln, Nebr. Giiem-eys. G. S. Phillips Tecumseh, Nebr. Ayrshire. W. Righter Woods Station B, Omaha, Nebr STATE FARM. JANUARY 19th, 1911. President Harding called meeting to order and announced that the first number on program was a paper by Mr. J. E. Vogel on the "Duties of a Cream Receiver," and would be rather a sort of text for </seg>
            <seg id="p026">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 25 DUTIES OF A CREAM RECEIVER. J. E. Vogel The cream receiver occupies a place in the dairy industry of Ne - braska, where his work can be made to produce greater results in the improvement and development of the industry than either the territory superintendent or the creamery management. This opportunity is given him through his coming in close contact with the producer on whose success depends the welfare of everyone in any way connected with tin order for the cream receiver to get results he must, of course, lformed upon the work in which he is engaged. He should read f papers, study instructions sent out by his company, bulletins sent by the Dairy Commission and the Experiment station, and read :ever books on dairy subjects he may be able to get. The attention of hie patrons can best be obtained by showing them the losses they are sustaining in their present system of dairying aud how to turn this loss into a profit. He should instruct them in the use of the Babcock test, and talk with them of the necessity of testing their cows and keeping records, not only of their performances at the pail, but of the amount and cost of feed they consume. Explain the advantages of having the cow freshen in the fall of the year, and urge the use of the silo in connection with alfalfa as a cheap and pro - ductive feed. Also show them that it is cheaper to provide a warm, well ventilated barn than to attempt warming the cows with high priced feed. The patron that becomes interested to the extent of ap - plying these suggestions to the management of his present herd, will soon be considering improvement in the breeding of his stock. If but one or two can be interested at first a good beginning will have been made. Assist these as much as possible and point out the resul.g of their work to others. I The confidence of the cream seller is necessary before his patronage be permanently secured, and before any headway can be made ird improvement along the lines mentioned. In order to get this idence the receiver must conduct all of his business with absolute ssty and in as nearly an accurate manner as possible. In these of keen competition, confidence is the principal asset upon which cream receiver must depend to build his business. A feeling of Idence comes into the mind of the cream seller when he steps into clean and inviting cream station. It is the first impression that lasts, so the all important thing is to keep the station clean, not only because the operator is under a moral obligation to the consumer of the product' he handles, and a legal obli - gation to the Dairy Commission, but because it is a means of winning business for himself. A patron coming into a station of this kind will </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION business, and will not be in very much of a mood to question the accuracy or truthfulness of the test, providing, of course, that the sampling and testing have been carried out in a careful and accurate manner. The patron may not understand how to make a test himself, but will be very quick to note any act of carelessness on the part of anyone who is testing. ■ After transferring the cream to the shipping can the patron's cans ild be rinsed with cold water in order to save all the fat. In weather with extra heavy cream it may be necessary to either set can in warm water or pour warm water around the outside, in order :&gt;osen that which is sticking to the inside. This will do away with necessity of using so much rinse water, the use of which increases shipping weight and may affect the quality. After rinsing, tha i should be thoroughly washed with a brush, using warm~water with I tie washing powder, and then scalded with hot water or steam boiler is at band. The average Nebraska cream station does not ire a steam o'utfit. but the larger stations do, and these have been f* generally supplied. The way most of them have been used in ling is to be condemned, however. The practise of turning live m directly into a can, with the idea of washing it. when it has only rinsed, has sent these cans back to the farm in worse shape than ey had never been touched at all. The hot steam cooks the curd to the can instead of removing it, and many patrons do not wash can again for they think it has already been cleaned and as a P: the can within a day or so of hot weather has a very foul odor, i. of course, seriously affects the quality of cream put into it steam should be used only after the can has been washed with a in warm water and then only to sterilize and heat so that it will The question of obtaining an improvement in quality is a most serious one. It is a difficult matter to present this to the patron without giving offense, yet it is one way he has of eventually increasing the price of his own product. The cream receiver should do everythin? in his power at the station to set a good example, for such an influence •s bound to have its silent effect. With tactfulness he can many times make a suggestion that will prove beneficial without causing any ill feeling. For instance, a producer of poor cream may deliver a can that shows improvement over past deliveries. The receiver should always mention this, taking advantage of this opportunity of making suggestions on the care of cream and the good of frequent delivery. Holding crram too long on the farm and not keeping it sufficiently cool arc point* that the receiver should mention particularly. The empty shipping cans should be housed in a clean dry place immediately on their return from the factory. It is beet to remove the lids and lay them on their sides piling them one above the other in this manner. Before filling with cream they should then be rinsed and scalded or steamed if you have a boiler at band. It is well to </seg>
            <seg id="p028">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 27 prepare for the day's supply of cans in the morning so that they will have time to cool before being filled. As far as possible the good and poor cream should be kept separate, for if the two are poured together in one can the quality of the good will be lowered without improving the poor. Keep the cream as cool as conditions at the station will permit and stir frequently until shipment is made. Frequent stirring ip an important factor in the keeping quality as it prevents uneven souring. It also prevents the lumps of sour curd forming which makes thorough mixing and accurate sampling at the factory a difficult mat- IThe receiver should always re-weigh the cream and take a com - te sample before shipping. If the test of this sample shows the i to be either over or short in comparison with the amount of er fat as shown by the individual tests, to a greater extent than one id of butterfat for every hundred in the shipment, the work is being done with accuracy that is possible, and an effort must be e to locate and overcome the trouble. It is not a difficult matter to vork of this kind if one is careful, and carefulness is certainly a of the cream receiver. In case a part of a can of cream is held from one shipment to another do not neglect to record the weight and test on the report. In many cases it will explain at the factory the reason the shipment is over or short. Always make a separate report for each shipment as it facilitates the keeping of the factory records. In case the factory sends you a shortage report and you feel that you have been doing your very best, do not come into the immediate conclusion that your company has a grudge against you. They are giving you the figures according to their records, and if there is a dif - ference it only means that they want your co-operation in locating the trouble. It has been my experience as an inspector, that these records on the whole are very nearly accurate. I also feel that the majority of operators do their work with the best of intentions, so if a difference exists the duty of the operator clearly lies rn making sure he is right, in the testing through the medium of the composite test, carefully sealing his cans on both sides of the lid to prevent loss in transit, and the making of an accurate report. You are then at liberty to call upon your superintendent or the Dairy Commission for further help with a feeling that the trouble will not be found in your station. Every cream receiver wants to buy all the cream he can. for in doing so he increases his earning capacity. The surest way to make an advance is sometimes the longest way around. The sales manager of a large manufacturing concern recently said, in a talk to his salesman, that they would not be capable of their greatest capacity of salesman - ship rntil they could forget entirely their own profit in the transaction and think only of the great good the thing they were selling would be to the prospective purchaser. This idea can be applied to the work of </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION the cream receiver, for I know of no more successful cream buyers in tbe (tate than those who think first of the success of the people with whom they do business. The President: Gentlemen: From a creameryman's standpoint this is a very important subject, and while it may not seem to be, at the same time it is to a cream producer equally important, perhaps even more so, because if, aa Mr. Vogel has pointed out here, the man who produces the cream and the station man who takes care of it, have within themselves the making of good cream. It has been tried a good many times but nobody has succeeded, and I don't think anybody ever will, to make good butter without first class cream. The only way to raise the average quality of butter in the state of Nebraska, is to raise the average quality of cream; and I would like to have a very full and frank discussion of this subject. Mr. Melick is to lead the discussion, and we will now listen to what he has to say. »Mr. Melick:' Mr. Vogel has dealt chiefly with tbe duties of the a receiver at the small station. I will take up the subject from point to the duties of the receiver at the factory. In our system of receiving cream in Nebraska, it has become the duty of the cream receiver to send out literature instructing the cream producer how to handle the cream in a sanitary way. It should not be necessary, but it is. There have been tons of literature on "sani - tation" distributed all over the country, but many of the farmers are rather independent. They don't have to send cream to the creamery; they don't have to milk cows. Indeed, it would seem that too much literature and too much talk on sanitation has been pumped into them. When that is done they will say, "Take your old cans; I will not milk any more cows — I don't have to." I was talking to one of them the other day. I said to him, "Of course, you fellows who own 160 acres of land can live like a lord. You don't have to be dictated to by any - body." "Well." said he, "may be I can live like a lord, but some times I have to work like the devil." That is true too. A person has to work hard to milk cows. Milking is something that is disagreeable to many people, and for that reason you can almost count on the fingers of your two hands all the real dairymen that there are in the state of Nebraska. There are many good farmers, and some of them milking a few cows and sending their cream to the creamery. That is not dairying. That is not taking the care of cows the way they ought to and producing the kind of cream they ought to. It is a hard matter for every person who goes into the dairy business to produce absolutely first-class cream. Consequently it is difficult for the creamery to make a first-class quslity of butter. But where a farmer is doing general farming, and dairying is a side issue with him, as it is with almost all dairymen now in Nebraska, he simply takes time to milk a few cows, separates the milk, and sends the cream to the creamery. In the </seg>
            <seg id="p030">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNIAL CONVENTION 29 They milk a few cows, separate that cream, haul it to the station, where it is picked up by the railroad men and taken to the creamery, may be a hundred or two hundred miles distant. Those people have not time to bother with dairying. They are ranching, raising a little grain and for a side issue do a little dairying. They don't stop to sterilize the milk cans or pails; they don't cool the milk immediately after milking, but rinse out the cans sometimes with cold water. The cream is put in there again and the can stands on the platform of the railway station and is picked up by the railroad company and the cream is perhaps 24 hours in transit. When that cream arrives at the creamery it is generally third grade, and it becomes the first duty of the cream re - ceiver in that event to grade that cream. He grades it first, second and third as the case may be; but when competition is severe instead of paying for the cream one cent less for second grade than for first and one cent less for third than for second and so on, he pays the same price to every farmer for cream. That has became almost necessary because there have been enough creameries to handle all the business, as Presi - dent Harding told you yesterday, but when a new firm comes into the state to do business, it does not create any new business but takes a certain amount of the business that is already there, and that of course, creates more competition. When more competition is created, then the cream buyer seems to think it is necessary to pay the same price, as high as he can, to everybody alike. So it is that much of the cream that comes from the producers in Nebraska is unfit for the production of good butter at the creameries until it is almost entirely renovated. It was my privilge and pleasure last summer to conduct some ex - periments along the line of collecting cream, and I have a few figures here which I will exhibit to you to show you what has to be done by the cream receiver in order to get that cream in fit condition ;o make good butter out of it, because the most of the cream that is received at the creameries is not in fit condition for churning. KThe first duty of a cream receiver is to grade the cream. The first ■ cream is churned separate from the second grade and so on. e are therefore three kinds of cream with which he has to deal. Although fair butter may be made from first grade cream as it is received, a good starter greatly improves it and insures a uniform quality of butter from day to day. Second and third grade cream do not even make fair butter, unless pasteurized and properly ripened with a good starter. The next duty of the cream receiver is to place the different grade* of cream in different vats, warm this up to about 85 degrees F., emulsify the cream, pasteurize at about 185 degrees F. and cool to TO degrees F., and add about 10 percent of good etarter. When the cream begins to thicken, having about 5 percent to 6 percent of acid, it should </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION be cooled to 50 degrees F. and held at that temperature until ready to In our investigations we found that an average of all the cream. which was received at our creamery, contained twenty million bacteria per c. c. when it reached the factory. Of these only 4 5 percent were lactic acid while 55 percent were undesirable. We see from the tables here that pasteurization destroys all of the lactic acid group, and most of the others. The total bacterial content being reduced from twenty million to 3,000 per c. c. by this process. Starter, containing from 60,000,000 to 150,000,000 bacteria per c. c. was added, 9.'&gt; percent of them being lactic acid when the starter was properly made. So by pas - teurization. wiping out undesirable germs even the lactic acid bacteria present, we have a clean field for the new vigorous lactis acidi in the starter. In preparing starter we simply pasteurize skim milk by heat - ing to boiling point, and then cool down to 70 degrees F. and add the the commercial culture. We hold the milk at a temperature of 70 degrees F. until the consistency of thick cream is reached. Ten percent of starter is usually added to cream for ripening; that is, using about 10 percent of the starter after pasteurization of the cream will ripen the cream to proper consistency in the desired time and give the butter the proper flavor when churned. We found that when cream con - tained all kinds of bacteria and held at the temperature of 70 degrees the lactic acid forms grew and destroyed the other forms. If the cream had been held at a low temperature we would have found that a certain other species of bacteria would have developed and crowded out and destroyed the desirable ones. At a warmer temperature we found still another kind developed, producing gas and destroying the desirable forms. An anlaysis of the bacteria in the cream was made :■ hour after adding the starter, and the increase of bacterial growth was almost proportional to the development of lactic acid in the cream. When the cre-ra was churned 20 hours afterwards we had 90 million bacteria per c. c. in our best cream, from 85 percent to 95 percent lactic acid forms. In that way we got rid of most of the bad flavors that were present in the cream when it arrived at the factory. In buying farm products we usually buy something that is fresh and good. If it is not, we pay accordingly, but in buying cream — we buy all grades and pay the same for each. Cream is simply a meiium for collecting of undesirable filth unices it is properly handled but cream is one of the best products of the farm when it is han lie 1 , right. When cream is handled in the most common and ordinary way, it be - comes one of the most undesirable products. Today, however, the creameries, the most of them, are equipped to make the veiy best but - ter possible out of the product they receive. We claim it don't do very much good to preach sanitation to a nan who Is not going to go into the dairy business. What v. t* \\ ill have </seg>
            <seg id="p032">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 31 to do is to get more people interested in dairying and in that way get them to send a good quality of cream to the creamery. II know of a dairyman in Washington, D. C, who ships cream from ia, Illinois, and it arrives in Washington sweet and pure. He es it and delivers it on his wagon absolutely sweet, after shipping er 800 miles. The producer sterilizes milk pails by using boiling r, separates the milk immediately after milking each cow, and it down to TiO degrees Fahrenheit inime liately after separating, it is shipped in refrigerator cars and they have no trouble in ing it sweet. I There is no use of preaching dairy sanitation unless somebody is g to do dairying. When they go into the dairy business then we preach about producing good cream, and from that we can produce I butter. So, I say it is first the duty of the creamery manager or operator to grade all cream and pay for it according to grade. ■n you hit a man's pocket book you teach him a lesson he is likely emember. Question: How can you cool the milk down to 50 degrees. I Answer: In the summer time, by setting the cream cans in cold •r tank, allowing the windmill to run and the water to flow around cans as soon as you can get through separating the cream. That cool it to the temperature of the well water; and by sterilizing with ng water all pails and cans you will send a good quality of cream to creamery. Question: Would a person have to use ice under those conditions? Answer: If you had good cold water it would not be absolutely necessary. It would be better, of course, but a man on the farm cannot always have ice. We do not wish to be unreasonable and request too Question: Would he have to ship his cream daily? I Answer: It should be shipped daily, or else kept in an ice box or aid water tank where the water was almost 50 degrees, and then every other day. But you understand where cream is only shipped &gt; a week, and a man milks only three or four cows, and the cans are scalded with boiling hot water, and the milk is put in those cans out any attempt to cool, and shipped 100 or 150 miles, by the time cream arrives at the creamery it is simply unfit for anything. .merles have to equip themselves to renovate and begin over again i this point to make that cream fit for churning. »Any of you who care to take a sample of this starter I have here do so at any time after this discussion. Instead of having an old taste it has a clean acid taste with a good flavor, the kind that we in developing the proper flavor in cream. Question: Do you put first grade cream through the same pro- Answer: Yes, although it would not be as necessary; it could be churne 1 without that process but we usually do it, and it improves it. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Question: Do I understand you to say, Mr. Melick, tbat these figures you have given us on the board are the bacterial counts that ■were taken from a sample of what you might call bad cream or third grade cream? 1 Answer: These figures are an average of all grades of cream that to the average creamery In the summer time when there is a large ■nt of second and third grade in it. In reply to a question Mr. Melick said the grading of cream really consists of tasting and smelling it. It is no great difficulty to properly grade cream. When you can find the man that can do that, he will tell you whether your cream is first, second, or third grade. All he can do is to smell it when the lid is taken off and if smelling is not sufficient taste it. That is all that grading at a creamery consists of. This is a safe basis if you have the right kind of a man to grade it. Kin further reply Mr. Melick said this man should be endorse 1 by er the State Dairy Food Commissioner or the Dairy Department of University. "I would say that he should be trained iiere, and sent n to the office of the Dairy Food Commissioner, and given an ex - aation." i Inspector Harnley: Right there is one of the important points of whole business — to get a man who has the qualifications with a I sense of taste and smell. If a man is employed who is not clean, does not keep his station clean, farmers will not have as much re - t for the station and the man in charge as they otherwise would. iow of one station where the office is as clean as it could be and farmers are almost afraid to step into it. They are careful about grading and the handling of the cream, and farmers hare more ect for the business. fftfr. Melick: Tbat is an excellent point. It all depends upon the in charge whether the cream is properly graded. If you get the kind of a man he is a valuable man indeed. You do not want to up a carpenter or a blacksmith, or a man in some other busi- He should be properly trained in dairy work. t Question: 1 brought this question rp to a man recently who said the legislature provided that the creamery companies would not llowed to grade cream or in other words to pay more for good n than for poor cream. What do you know about that? IMr. Melick: I am not informed of any such law as that, and that the legislature would know better than to pass such a law. I I there must be a mistake about it. The President: I think the gentleman refers to an old law on our statute books which I believe makes it an offense for a creamery company to pay more for cream at one station than it does at another station, but it does sot have any reference to quality of the cream. That is to say, if a creamery company should pay 25c for first grade cream and 22c for second grade cream, and pay that uniformly that </seg>
            <seg id="p034">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 33 they would be complying with the law, but if it paid 25c for first grade cream and 22c for second grade cream at one station and a different price for those same grades of cream at another station it would not then be complying with the law. IA Member: I would like to state that, in our community there been a cheap man employed and wherever they can find them they being hired. They get so in about three or four days that they can and grade cream. Now if that is the kind of men that are going due ate the farmers and dictate to them how they shall do, I think ill be a long time before we have the quality of cream that is re- Prof. Helick: I don't know where your locality is but I don't believe anybody not passing this examinataion will get a diploma or certificate from the State Dairy and Food Commissioner. Member: Yes, this one did. He belongs to what may be called "loafers." ■ The President: There is of course too much of this kind of help, know it. K Member: Well I can say that I applied for, and got a certificate. I got it I don't know. I was running a dairy and wanted this cer - te for that purpose to test my cream. Prof. Melick: I am glad to learn of these things because her* is the place to start the remedy. We, as an association, should go to work on that very thing in this state, and begin at the Pood and Dairy Commissioner's office, and see that the matter is corrected if it is true that these things exist. tMr. Thompson: I will say that I am interested in a co-operative mery and have been for three years. We put in a good man who taken first prize in Wisconsin for making butter. I can say that i a man brings in a rotten grade of cream he is told that we can use it. Then it is said he would take it to the creamery station , mho is buying for other creameries. When we first started our mery, there were three or four stations there buying cream. The ness men said to these station men, "we now have a creamery here ur own and it is up to us to see that it makes good." We have a things to run up against every once in a while. Prof. Melick: If this matter is put on the right basis we shall get 'id of this kind of work. tl would suggest that the men you employ be competent men and the men that you might pick up at any old place. Select such as have been graduated from the agricultural college and who ! had a course in grading and receiving cream and have received rtlflcate. Then when an inspector comes around there will be no ble. There should not be two or three prices for the same cream le same station. Member' But the cream buyer has got to sot business, he </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION is after the business, and if he is not careful he will be selling his principles. Of course, the farmer will try to sell his cream and per - haps his principles by not taking the proper care of the cream. Hence, the greater necessity for better station agents and better class of oream buyers. There are hundreds of men in Nebraska that can lest cream as well as these station fellows. tProf. Melick: They can not grade it. That is up to the men who l how. Every dairyman ought to be able to test his cream. We : have men at the station who are capable and who can not only but grade cream. Prof. Bower: That may be all right but my solution of the problem is the legislature and it requires education up to the point of legislation. That means that your inspector beside inspecting cream at the station will watch that cream and see that it comes in in good condition, and the law should be euch that he can make a demand on the farmer or producer for a certain amount of quality, if he brings in • quality under second grade. That may mean that we will have to he third grade out of our business. If we do cut out third grade it will be an important improvement. The only solution of this propo - sition of quality is a question of legislataion and it must be put in the hands of men who are qualified and until the people go before the legislature and make this demand we will never have the remedy. It Is up to us to educate them to the necessity of it. kProf. Melick: I presume that one reason for third grade cream it much of the cream is left too long at the railroad station. U Id not be left any length of time at the railroad station. Prof. W made a good point. tit was my privilege to be at the Kansas experimental station for years. I tried to enforce this cream-grading business the way I tion. It would not work in all places, but at the college creamery &gt;rkcd well. We paid for third grade cream about 2c less than for tid grade. We had sort of a monopoly on the dairy business there could do it in all cases. Question: What instruments are necessary in order to make bac - teriological examinations? Prof. Helick: A microscope, glass dishes testing tubes and con - siderable apparatus, but in regard to this testing of the milk I would ■ay that he need not have any bacteriological education; he could grade, taste and smell. If he was not properly fixed by nature he would not be fixed at all. A Member: I remember that about two years ago in Nevada we had an experience very much like this one here in regard to the quality of the cream. The market was very much demoralized, there was no system about the classification of the oranges. They sent good ges and bad oranges to market but they could not get the proper prices. Finally the produceis got together and produced a better grade f\f /■» 1*0 t\ tf/ic o t\ t\ H t-&gt; tt) a t\ H^rl t 'h t* hffit ' 1 T*i pf* 1 v on 1 (\ f a v ttifit it ift </seg>
            <seg id="p036">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 35 up to the farmers of Nebraska to produce the best grade of cream possible and then demand the best price. The lower the average grade of cream produced, the lower would be the average price received. If the farmers would produce a better grade of cream they would get a better price and it would not cost them anything to do it either. (The President: This fruit business at one time was in a worse ition and plight than the dairy business with respect to quali.y and Let conditions. As this gentleman remarked, what did those orange ers do? They got together and produced a better orange, mar - 1 a uniform grade, and when a customer bought a box of oranges new what was in the box. This would apply to the dairy busi - as well as to the fruit business. It gave the customer confidence when he bought a box of oranges he knew he was buying a cer - grade or a standard, and it tended to put the whole fruit business profit basis. It is a good lesson for us. A Member: I simply wish to say Mr. President that the Dairy Commissioner has not been to my place and never made a test. I am in favor of such a law as has been suggested here but it strikes me that the sanitary requirements of the pure food law ought to cover this, provided the inspectors get busy, or else pay them nothing, have them to do the business correctly. I want to say tint conditions, in our neighborhood at least, are abominable. I am silling milk in the com - munity and have a herd and try to comply with all the requirements of the law in producing a first class article of cream; yet I dare say that there are at least a hundred cows in my same town or vicinity whose owners are selling milk for less than I can for the reason that they are not complying with the law, they are not keeping their barns, stables, and cans in a sanitary condition and if the inspectors should visit them I am quite sure they would be put out of business on account of the condition of their cows, stables, and utensils and these conditions reflect upon the man or men who are in the business legitimately. I pass one such place every day on my way to the town and their cows are covered with filth, and people all over that town are buying milk of this man furnished by cows that are absolutely filthy. The owners of these cows feel safe. 1 comply with the law and I believe they should be made to do the same thing. I think we have almost enough legislation but I am not informed and do not know whether we have enough help in the field in the way of inspectors to enforce the present laws. These matters have been open and before the people in my vicinity for three years. I have to and keep my place in a clean con - dition but there are lots of farmers who produce cream, and thjr barns and cattle are in a filthy condition, and their milk pails and cans are certainly very unsanitary. The President: Occasionally such places will be found. There is great necessity for educational work and work of dairy inspectors. Take the three men who are appointed under the dairy and pure food </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION difficult for them to visit every section of the country with any degree of regularity. I presume there may be dairymen, or farmers, who do some dairy business in the State of Nebraska who have never seen the dairy commissioner or any of his field force. I am not surprised. We are sadly in need of a larger force. The present force cannot begin to do this work. They can only skirmish around a little bit. I believe the state of Nebraska could not invest money to any better advantage than to increase the efficiency of this field force and have the commissioner appoint where he could get some tart and satisfac - tory inspection. I think you all will agree with me along this line. I would be pleased to hear from Mr. Mains or Mr. Jackson in regard to this matter. I have spoken to Mr. Mains and his inspectors. We have seen them at our factories. They watch us closely and we are glad to have them ,but it takes lots of time to set around over a state the size of Nebraska. Prof. Melick: I would say that here is the place, at the State Dairymen's Association, to start the proper legislation. There is not a man here who would not admit that our system is wrong. I would suggest that the committee on resolutions draw up such a bill as has been proposed here and present it at the Siate House, and that we try to get these matters on a proper basis. "What is the use of our talking so much about a thing unless we do it." I The President: I would suggest that this matter come before Association in some concrete form or a resolution, that resolution it be prepared embodying the ideas that have been represented »Prof. Melick and Prof. Bower were appointed a committee in inction with Commissioner Jackson, by the President, to draft a resolution along this line and present to the Association. KThe President: Mr. Mains is present and we would all be pleased ;ar from him, in regard to "Two Years in the Dairy Commission TWO YEARS IX THE DAIRY COMMISSION OFFICE. Mr. S. L. Mains. Mr. President and Members of the Association-: II may not be able to speak very connectedly in what I shall have ly for the reason that I have not prepared any paper, and I want to right here before I forget it that I am, indeed, thankful for the k talk given by the gentlemen who preceded me, speaking from upper row there, because I think he has done more than any other ridual who has had the floor this morning to develop the discus - which is close to the Food and Dairy Commission in this state. It is hard for me to give my experience of two years without re - iit st in£ lsrz^lv wb&amp;t we did the ycflr urcvious &amp;s L)&amp; iry Com m iwnionpr </seg>
            <seg id="p038">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 37 about which I told you at our last annual meeting. If I repeat anything I hope that those who were here last year will overlook it. or that they have forgottten all about it. i After assuming the office of Dairy Commissioner I invited all bers of the Dairymen's Association to meet me in my office, and if thought of anything that would be of advantage to the dairy itry to offer amendment to the present dairy law at that time. Id iliance with that request and at that meeting there were several idmnts to the dairy law suggested, and also a law which has since known as the "can" law. was offered and approved by the dairy- The Senator from Cass county was kind enough to introduce the amendment in the Senate as well as the can law. It passed the Senate by a unanimous vote; and the can law had no trouble in passing the House. However, the amendment that we offered to the dairy law at that time met with some opposition, I think not on account of the law itself, but if you remember two years ago the legislature was anxious to divide up the Commission and making a Food and Drug Commission and a Diary Commission. This was rather favored by the dairy men and the drug men were specially anxious to have a Drug Commissioner. There were quite a number of the members of the House that were not in favor of creating any new office and they voted the drug men's bill down. It came up on the amendments that were proposed and the drug men in retaliation together with the men who voted against it in the first instance, on third reading were able to defeat the proposed amendments. Afterwards we secured a reconsideration of the amend - ment, and on final vote we carried the amendments through, but not as originally drawn. The original amendments were to have an assist - ant in the Commissioner's office who would have charge of the dairy business; and to raise the saiary of the dairy inspector to $4 per day, the present salary is $3 per day. I Allow me at this time to draw attention to what Prof. Melick said it the pay of the dairy inspector. As long as you pay only 13 ly you are not going to get the best dairy inspectors because the m stations as soon as they are educated up to the point where they able to deliver the goods, are going to hire them. That is not only case here, but the case in every 6tate in the Cnion. Mr. French, y Commissioner of Minnesota says the same trouble exists there. Dairy Commissioner of Iowa says the same thing. It is an lmpos - ity to keep dairy inspectors. The creamery companies are looking for them. Whenever there is a chance of obtaining a good man ' get him because they want him and can pay him a better price the state paid. theld examinations in June of the first year in Omaha, Lincoln i, Holdrege, Fairbury, Columbus, Fremont, Norfolk, Grand Is - klliance. I was able to hold these examinations and meet with </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION all the different cream receivers excepting in Alliance and North Platte. Mr. Vogt-1, dairy inspector, conducted those examinations. Until two years ago a good thai* of the testing of cream was done at the factory. There were, 1 think, about 800 testers in the country. Last year we issued 3,100 permits from May Iff, 1909, to June 30, 1910, something over 3,100 permits for station agents an! testers, over 75 per cent of these were testers. I think you will find that virtually all of the cream is being tested at the local station instead of being tested at the cream - ery. The amendment that was offered and which passed the legislature made it necessary for samplers, as well as cream testers, to have per - mit from the Department. The advantage is that everybody that is buying cream or is an agent for a creamery company, is directly under the supervision of the Dairy Commissioner at the present time. If he doesn't do the work right, there is a possibility of revoking the permit and putting him out of the cream business, which you will all agree with me is the best thing to do with a fellow that absolutely will not play the game fair. IWe have issued four bulletins on the Dairy Industry, trying to the dairy industry as best we could. I have gone on the theory it was an educational proposition. Two bulletins, (one was ed to the patrons, one to cream operators) on the proper care of cream at the farm and also at the station and proper way of test - it. I believe that the bulletins issued on "Testing," if a man fol - ■■ it carefully, he will be able to make a good and correct test. I believe there is a general improvement in the state in dairying. I believe people are becoming better informed; and that more farmers if i hey find thay are not taking the proper- care of the cream and (polling the quality of it, are trying to do away with that injury. IThie year instead of holding examinations we have written renew - )r permits. We refuse to issue some permits for the simple reason in some instances they were unwilling to obey the law and as as they were unable to be caught they would not obey, and to i a crooked man is'a pretty hard proposition. I Our state is a pretty large one and for that reason we adopt* d plan of allowing a notary public to conduct these examinations, sent the notaries the questions and they have given the examina - i. I think very likely it is true, in fact, I am quite sure it is true cream superintendents have taught their operators how to test. re is no doubt that for the time being they have had to suffer, e of our questions and answers have been carried around in their :ets, and we have tried to change the questions. There had been formed an ice cream association. The standard of ice cream in our state requires 14 per cent butter fat. We found the first year considerable violation of this standard, especially so in Omaha, and farther up in the north east part of the state where the </seg>
            <seg id="p040">39 cream would fall as low as from 7 per cent to 8 per cent butter fat. We notified those people in that part of the state about it and of the results of our test. We told them possibly they were unaware of the kind of cream they were producing but that they surely could not be - lieve that excuse if we found them in that condition again: and if we found in taking samples again at their place if their cream fell below the standard that we would have to file a complaint against them with the county attorney. We sent a copy of that law to the manufacturer of ice cream. When we went over the field again we had no trouble to find the cream testing 14 per cent. The last time we made th of the samples of cream at Omaha there were two that fell below the standard but those two fell below less than 1 per cent showing that all were trying to obey the law. Perhaps I have been open to criticism in a few instances for the reason that I have not been in favor of taking a man into court if it was possible to avoid it. 1 believe when you take a man into court for disobeying the law it is not so much the $10 fine but the disgrace that he has to carry tnrough life that he has at some time been prose - cuted for criminal offense — it matters not the grade of the offense. If you hurt that man in some way in only one respect he never gets cleared with it, and for one I would rather be very careful, and I want the proof that he has violated the law and is guilty before I ever would do such a thing, especially if he is guilty through the ignorance of the §We have collected in the neighborhood of Twelve Thousand Dol - for license fees. The state contributes to the department for in - ors Fifteen Thousand Eight Hundred Dollars for the biennium to for traveling expenses, the salary of the dairy inspectors and for a drug inspector, the traveling expenses of the state chemist and the traveling expenses of the commissioner as well as postage and other ex - penses. I have made an estimate required by law and filed with the state auditor that it would be necessary to have Thirty Thousand Dol - lars for this department for the coming biennium. As far as the salary of the deputy commissioner, state chemist and stenographer, the three people that are in the office, that amount is fixed. I understand that there was an amendment offered to the law this winter, creating a greater number of inspectors especially during the heavy flow of cream in the months of June, July, August and Sep - tember. I think our association last year passed resolutions along this line recommending as far as possible that the dairy inspectors be se - lected, these extra ones, from the senior class of the state farm school. Gentlemen, I am one who believes that you cannot have an inspector go out over the state and do the work that is required of him without he has some technical education. He may receive that education though I think a very large amount of it attending school. I think he could learn it in the creamery or at the dairy school. In that respect however «v a *u yi n t iti n yi v T/\yq^&gt; ponHition t }) &amp; Y) of tipr Rt At £*fl j\ n H en i t vr\ 1 1 fat** </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION I think as long as this matter is left in the hands of the appointing power with politics to govern. As long as that condition exists you are not likely to get the best results. 1 have had handed out to me two men during my term of office, who did not know a thing about the dairy business as dairy Inspectors but we had to admit them. They started out to get educated to the business. One fellow made good but it took about a year to do it and the state paid for it. The other fellow did not make good and the* money we paid him was an absolute waste so that I had to secure his removal. It is a shame that those things exist; it ought not to be. I would like to see an increase in the number of inspectors and would also like to see a better qualified man as a grader of cream and I think Prof. Melick said that would have great influence on the farmers. I hope the time will soon come when we will not only have ten but even twenty inspectors so that we can scatter them over the state and they can visit dairies as well as to take samples from wagons ind Inspect creameries. KThe President: Our ne« Deputy Dairy Commissioner Mr. Wil- R. Jackson is present and we would be pleased to bear a word him. Mr. Jackson: Mr. President and Gentlemen: I appreciate very much this opportunity of meeting you gentlemen here. I trust our relations will be very pleasant and that you can heartily ro-»ierate with the dairy department. I assure that this department will cer - tainly welcome any co-operation that you may give to it looking to - ward the enforcement of our laws. I At the outset I wish to say that it will not be the purpose of the irtment to seek to persecute anyone but our purpose shall be to that the laws are enforced without fear or threat. I believe we accomplish this without persecution. I shall look to you for co - ation in the matter of locating places that need inspection. We certainly accomplish much more if we work together than by (ing at random. §1 wish at this time to publicly thank my predecessor for any pos - courtesy that he has been able to extend to me and has placed me e vantage ground in starting out and I wish to say that I appre - tbis very highly. I trust the things that Mr. Mains has suggested along the line of additional help will be brought about because I believe with the few inspectors scattered over the state it will not be possible to make the record or do the good work that is required. I know you can all help by creating a sentiment in favor of more inspectors. I assure you that I shall use my best endeavors to see that those who are appointed to these positions shall be skilled men in that line of work, that they will be trained men, not only trained in a general way, but a technical training. I should like to see the agricultural department of the dairy business placed on a basis so that we can depend upon the graduates </seg>
            <seg id="p042">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 41 be accomplished. We need men who are true and loyal and compe - tent and who will carry out their convictions. You can help material - ly in creating among the members of the legislature a feeling of sympathy with your particular line of work. I take it for granted that you all agree with me that you are pioneers bo to speak in this business in this state. There Is no line of work engaged in that will build up the state so substantial and enrich the people so much as the very business you are engaged in. Two years ago I visited a community in northern Illinois where I lived some twenty years ago. In fact might as well admit that there was a young lady there who attracted my attention. I used to drive out In the country with her. Corn was rather short, some of it would not run over ten of fifteen bushels to the acre. Oats were so short that they could hardly band them. They started in to the dairy business. At that time the cow was sheltered by an old straw stack on the average farm. I knew of one nan who claimed he could take a lot of cattle and care for them and that they would double every year. He took the cattle and kept them in an open yard without shelter except this old straw stack that 1 spoke of. In the spring they had doubled up, nearly all of them and died. He was trying to feed high priced food to supply the heat and warmth necessary to keep - them from dying, and he made poor work of it. You can go right back to that community today and instead of corn ten to fifteen bushels to the acre there is corn that you will have to get a ladder to reach the ears. Their ground has been enriched. They have splendid crops. They have fields of clover. They have cattle and instead of sheds or straw stacks they have new large modern, well lighted and ventilated dairy barns, sanitary in every particular with modern equipments. They are becoming wealthy. They are con - serving the soil and are the pioneers in conservation work and the dairy products and dairy business are becoming great. In this state, if I am not mistaken, the dairy Interests are second - ary only to the corn products. If this department can have your co - operation I believe we can succeed in securing better products of butter and cream and we shall have them from a sanitary point of view and of such quality that people will not be afraid of our products in other states. I think we have just as good a reason for having our products receive high prices as Wisconsin, or any other good dairy state. If we can do that the demand for our products will increase and the prices will advance. I believe it will be admitted by all that if we put out a good wholesome product there will be a large demand for it. This is from a sanitary point of view and it would increase the demand for that product and it would be agreeable from the standpoint of health and wealth. It is essential that we should have your co-operation. The number of Inspectors is certainly inadequate. Mr. Mains has called your at - tention to the fact that the funds appropriated for our use is wholly </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 iASKA DA1RYMI OCIATION inadequate. It would work a hardship not to have enough funds aa we would not want Nebraska to become the dumping ground (or food that is unfit for use. If we could have a large appropriation or a reasonable one, or a deficiency appropriated eo that we could put men in the field and push matters it would greatly help us out at this time. There is need of a much larger appropriation for the coming biennium and a larger number of inspectors if we expect to do any - thing like the work that should be done in reaching the various | of the state. It is my purpose, as I said, to co-operate with you in &gt; way possible. I believe that you will find that I am not larking in back bone and need the use of some iron tablets to enable me to do my work. I believe I am strong and healthy enough to enforce the law. I shall not seek to persecute any pne but shall do my full duty and I will appreciate if you will give the department suggestions where our services are most needed, not for the purpose of embarrassing or persecuting any one but for the purpose of enabling everyone to live up to the standard that has been set. We have sanitary laws and they should be obeyed by everyone. You can do much in securing these needed things by writing to your representatives and senator or by a perconal interview- and I trust you will use the opportunity of doing so while you are here. I shall certainly see that there is no waste of the funds applied but that they shall go for the good of the dairy associa - tion and the dairy interests of the state and to protect the people. \W certainly have a great state and I do hope the time will soon come when the dairy business will be extensive throughout the state. We have the broad acres, we have the means and we have only to follow the methods of a conservation of soil; and when this condition is reached it will mean thrift, prosperity and happiness for us all. I thank you gentle - mint for your kind attention. Whereupon the meeting was adjourned until 1:30 o'clock. AFTKRXOOX SESSION. President Harding called the meeting to order and announced the first number on the program. RESULTS OF THE DOUGLAS COIXTV COW TESTING ASSOCIATION. W. C. Andreas. tTo many of the residents of our state it may not be known that ive within our own boundaries, one of the largest dairying centers e west; possibly the largest outside of Des Moines, Iowa. The district referred to Is located just west of Omaha, in Douglas county. Here we find a very progressive farming community consisting </seg>
            <seg id="p044">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 43 to a very large extent of Germans, who located there in the early days and through their progressive methods made it what it is today. I In traveling along these well kept roads, and Douglas county witb eventy-five miles of pavement, by the way, boasts of having more d highways than any other county in the state — the outsiders at - on will be at once roused by the small platforms erected in front of tically every farm home along the main drive-ways to the city, l inquiring he is informed that the farmer, or dairyman, places daily product of his cows upon these small stations, where it is ed up by large drays and hauled into the city every morning. kWhen told that the price of land in this community is circling nd the |200 mark, he readily understands why the farmer, who 3 ago could not be clubbed into milking, is now turning to the more isive methods and is making good in the dairy line. KHe is not satisfied, however, in knowing that the dairy herd is ig his pocket-book, but he also wants to know the amount each in - lual cow is contributing. Consequently some of the members of Douglas County Milk Producers Association in co-operation with Dairy Department of the University of Nebraska, have organized iw Testing Association, which is very gratifying to the promoters. I The tester has charge of the testing and compiling of records for erds, comprising some 425 cows. In order to explain this work, ivites you to go with him for one day and see how it is carried on. g to Mr. Johnson's herd today, the teeter stations himself at the -can stand in the barn, when milking begins in the evening, and as cow is milked, he receives the pail, records the weights of its con - i, takes a small sample of the milk and makes a complete notation s note-book. Later when the cows are fed he weighs the grain and h feeds apportioned to each cow. I The evenings are spent in discussing economical feeding rations, work done by individual cows and such matters as pertain to economical production of milk and butter fat. The following morn - he arises with the milkers and again obtains the individual weight sample of each cow. After breakfast he sets up his testing apparatus in the milk-house or kitchen and determines the percent of fat in each sample of milk. Thus a complete record of each cow is obtained for a day, which is representative of the production of milk and consumption of feed for the month. This is recorded on a daily record sheet which gives the name or number of the cow, the weight of the milk given in the evening and morning, their total, their test, and also the pounds of fat for the day. It also shows the amount and cost of feed fed at that particular time. These daily records are transferred upon individual yearly rec - ord sheets. Here the amount of milk and fat and their total value are figured on a fat basis for a period of 30 days or one month and from this the total cost of feed is substracted. A history of the age, breed, date of freshening and sex of the calf is also obtained for each cow and </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION having all records complete the tester is ready to have Mr. Johnson haul him to the next farm to assume charge of the herd test without notifying this party of his coming. So you see by the end of the year we will have figures showing the total amount of milk and fat produced by each cow, her average test, the kind, the amount and cost of feed she hag consumed and the total profit* as well as returns per dollar invested in feed, for each Individual KWe have now conducted this work for a period of ten months and already obtained many intensely interesting figures. For an ex - e, I should like to call your attention to this first chart which s the work of the cows In milk of the different herds for ten suc - re months. Average Per Month For Ten Months Mar. 1, 1910 — Jan. 1, 1911. I f Z o c O o ■ r » ■ ' c t, tr &lt; -i I Q DC o m &gt; H 1 22 23.2 3.94 $2.34 $7.58 i 30 11 32.6 21.6 3.46 5.98 6.41 3.98 3.28 6.34 7 mo. 8 12 21.4 24.2 22.9 23.8 3.74 3.24 3.78 2.36 2.87 3.62 3.47 6.33 5.76 5.63 5.43 • 8 • 2^ 3.42 i II 21.5 3.33 2.36 5.46 : 5 8 18. C 18.8 4.18 J.71 3.72 3.87 3.70 3.77 3.98 3.50 3.29 3.23 5.32 8 mo " B 12 12 19.0 19.1 2.29 2.48 3.23 2.65 2.63 3.77 2.52 5.23 5.22 4.86 4.78 4.73 4.56 9 mo. 6 mo. 16 18.4 " 17 18.6 18.9 18.0 20.2 15.5 17.5 i&lt; 31 31 ' 22 13 I 3.13 2.38 4.26 4.21 4.13 I 3.85 11 3.95 3.24 3.98 2.95 5 mo. 12 K.5 3.55 3.60 3.50 3.39 ■l 10 14.8 2.44 You will average cow ] notice that in herd It produced 23.2 pounds c &gt;r fat. The coat of feed &gt;. l, 22 a if milk pe was $2.34 jwb were e r day, test i, which lei silked. The ing nearly 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 45 age profit of f 7.58 for each cow per month. In comparison to this the herd at the bottom of the list averaged only 14.8 pounds of milk, test - ing 3.6 per cent and leaving a profit of $2.44 for each cow after deduct - ing $3.39 for feed. We notice from these figures that there is a differ - ence of $51.40 per cow, between the two herds. It is certainly an exceptionally good showing made by this first herd and a close study of these cows and the methods pursued in their care is very interesting. These twenty-two cows were selected from a herd of nearly one hundred head by a competent dairy man, who now has them in charge. The extremely low cost of feed for this herd is very largely due to the feeding of silage and better pasture. These cows have consumed from 40 to 60 pounds of silage per day during the entire time, excepting a few months during the summer when they had access to plenty of good bottom pasture. Although both herds are gradts, they are considerably different in type, the former being the offspring of a pure-bred sire, which, in connection with its better care and management, largely accounts for the difference in the profits. IThe difference in the individual cows in a herd is shown in the ■ving table where we have the records of one of the better and one ,e poorer cows of two different herds milking for ten successive hs. DIFFERENCE IN COWS IN SAME HERD. Record of two cows in Herd No. 1, milking ten months. h r r I o X I ~i S c e = r* —. ft _ 7T 11664 3.48 406.2 3840 4.35 167.1 $27.61 21.42 $118.45 Record of two cows in Herd No. 8, milking ten months. We notice that the cow, Spot, in herd No. 1, produced 7,824 pounds more milk, 239.1 more fat and made a larger profit of -78.16 that the cow, Black, although her feed bill is $6.19 higher than the latter cow Again in herd No. 8, we find that the cow. Babe, has out- ... P r o ■ 8 • s o O I o 3 ! 7317 4269 2.81 266.1 120.0 IOT -: K; 23.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">46 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Mi tte cow, Ptt, by a difference in profit of $52.85, and by the way, it Bfftns as though this cow, Pet, is very properly name). There are people who treat a cow the same way they treat a pet dog or a pet cat. They know quite well that this cow does not pay for her keep, but still they have milked her for so long and she is such a nice cow, — well she is the pet and they hate to part with her. Another interesting feature we have observed is the importance of a long lactation period. There is a class of cows (and I dare say we find this class quite frequently among the so-called dual purpose cows) who give a good quantity and quality of milk for a short time after freshening, but have a tendency to stand dry from three to six months out of the year. Am sorry to say that two parties who started out with us in our cow-t€Eting work, declined to stay with us for the simple reason that their cows were practically all dry and consequently refused to continue their records. When I first started into this work one of these men called my attention to the fact that his dual-purpose cows made as good or better showing than the average dairy type herd in our contt s . which I admitted to be the case at the time being. Several months ago, however, his cows went practically all dry which dis - gusted him in a way that he decided to sell everyone of his "beef cattle," as he thtn called them, and get into the dairy type. He con - sidered the advantages of the different dairy breeds for some time and when he was about ready to buy, some of those good old Shorthorns came in fresh again and while fresh gave such a good account of them - seivis that he decided to stick to them for at least another year. KYou will notice ihat in chart No. 3, we have the records of two standing side by side in the same barn, raaatrteg identically the feed and care. DIFFERENCE IN MILKING PERIODS OF TWO COWS STANDING SIDE BY SIDE. t -i z X - — c^ Lady :: TL' 234.3 $23.80 •$37.21 10 mo Lilly 265J 3.47 92.11 23. Mi ••2.y:&gt; 6 mo •Profit, ••Loss. The cow called Lady freshened about February 1st or a month before these records were started and still has 245 pounds of milk and 14.1 pounds of fat marked to her credit for the December month. Judging from this it is cafe to predict that she will not miss the $50 r! |f I * = B I </seg>
            <seg id="p048">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION' 47 profit mark by so very far. The cow to her right. Miss Lilly, however, proves to be quite the opposite and of the genuine star boarder I Lilly freshened on March 24th, started out with a credit of 657 pounds of milk and 20.1 pounds of fat for the month of April. Her activities ceased, however, along the latter part of September, when she went dryer than the city of Lincoln ever will be, and so we have already a bill of $2.95 charged against her and can safely figure that this will be increased to at least $10 besides the care and labor before she will freshen again. The importance of a long lactation period cannot be too strongly emphasized. Xot long ago a cow was called to my attention by her owner, v.ith the remark, "This is a splendid cow. Why, when she freshens she gives a great big bucket full of milk twice a day!" Ipon inquiring ii. gard to her present capacity, I was informed that she was practically dry now. In comparison with her, another cow in the same herd was pointed out to me with the information that that particular bovine was not anywhere near as good as she produced only about half as much as the former cow right after freshening. Further inquiry developed the fact that although both cows had freshened at practically the same time, cow Xo. 2 was continuing to give about the same flow of milk and was doing so at the time being. In spite of this, the owner saw only the large quantity of milk this first cow had given at the start and con - sequently gave her preference although the latter cow was actually making the money for him. ■ Much is being said and written these days in regard to the value profit in feeding silage. VAUE OF SILAGE SHOWN" IX TWO VERY SIMILAR HERDS. r 9 n i 1 5 "• e Feed z ■i I n Xo. XI Silage in ration 19.0 3.7 $2.48 $5.22 Xo. XX Xo silage in ration 16.5 3.55 3.50 2.95 Difference in profit per cow for 10 months, $22.70. We have here a chart showing the records of two herds that are not only very similar in type but are also being cared for in an identical manner. The main, if not the only difference between them lies in their respective feeding rations. The cows in herd Xo. XI receive between 30 and 40 pounds of silage and about 15 pounds of alfalfa per day. A little ground barley or corn has also been included at times. The cows in herd Xo. XX received the same kind of feed, minus the silage, only </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION cost of feed of |1.02 per month, charged against them and a lower profit of $22.70 per cow for the 10 months marked to their credit. § Other points of vital importance, vlt: the value of a pure-bred the importance of kind treatment and "cow-comfort," as well as ary surroundings and regularity in milking and feeding periods, demanded our attention. I It will be very interesting to watch the progress made by the led herds, headed by pure-bred sires, from year to year, and notice exact extent to which they are improved in their offspring. This, ourse, can only be done by a continuation of keeping records, se - •d with a pair of scales and the Babcock test. I The graded herd that made the phenomenal record of 175.80 t per cow is out of a pure-bred dairy sire. The cows are milked fed at regular intervals. They receive their water as well as their right in their stanchions during the zero weather and are curried y day. Their manager does not permit any rough or harsh handling considers it wiser and "money ahead" to throw a "quarter" Into gutter ani let the cow go without a beating whenever she acts a 1 uaeasy during the milking operations; and claims a dead dog to le best kind of a dog around the dairy herd. I But does it actually pay in dollars and cents to know what the ridual cows are doing? A heifer calf of the cow, Spot, who has a it of $118.45 for 10 months attached to her name, was sold for the II sum of $5 when only a week old. After adding up this cow's rd her owner at once made the cross-country drive and "swapped ." the same calf for a matured cow. Today you may offer him a bill for that heifer calf and he very likely will only smile at you. tEach member of this Testing Association is taxed $1 per cow, be - entertaining and transporting the tester. This in addition to an ipration given by the Dairy Department of the University pays is labor and equipment. Is it worth $1.00 per cow to know that herd is returning $2.00 per dollar invested in feed after milking lonths? Is it worth $1.00 a year per cow to know that a few indl - tls in some herds will lose their owners over $20.00 a year? I Such records are worth thousands of dollars because they will ile the dairymen to increase their earnings next year. They will ile the owners to stop the leaks in their business by getting rid of worse than worthless cows in their herds. They will direct the dera in selection and culling and thus be the source of developing a ber of herds of surpassing excellence in one community. But do they actually do this. Between 55 and 60 of the poorer and unprofitable cows have already been sold by the members of the Douglas County Testing Asso - ciation since it began operation* about ten months ago and there is no </seg>
            <seg id="p050">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 49 their yearly records are completed. Most of the herds are healed by pure-bred sires and near additions in this direction are being made con - tinu.lly. BFrom 16 to IS silos have been erected in this community during ast season and others are to follow. Even the owner of herd No. las learned of the -silo's value and from now on his cows will re - silage in their daily rations. Dairying is dependent upon the knowledge of the man. Profitable dairying is only possible where records are kept. Successful dairying is based entirely upon right methods in breeding, feeding and manage - ment. The dairy cow test is the most economical method of bringing about profitable an 1 successful dairying and it benefits the individual, the community and the state at large. t Testing Associations have placed Denmark, Southern Norway and len in the front ranks and have been universally adopted through- Europe. It only remains necessary for Nebraska to take up this i generally to develop the dairy industry and place the state where longs — in the front rank as an economical producer of food stuffs. The President: This is a subject in which there ought certainly to be the liveliest kind of Interest by every cow owner and by a man in any way dealing with cow products; and in order to get ihe best benefit* from this there should be a lively discussion. This discus - sion will now be, led by Mr. Henry C. Glissman. Mr. Ulissman: Mr. President and Members of the Association: This discussion should have been led by the president of our Association consequently I am unprepared to give but a few things that I have learned. But I must say that I am obliged to admit that there are many things in the paper read by Mr. Andreas that are true. We think we have good cows in our barn and that we have many good cattle, and when the prospective buyer comes arounl and asks you about this cow and that cow, how much does she give, we are quite apt to say, 'Oh, a whole pail full,' but sometimes I have to almit it is not quite true at all times. I have been in the pure-bred cattle business and I have found that it pays to live up to the truth. As Mr. Andreas said, 'it brings us to admit that a lot of our cows while we think they may be pure-bred are not giving the amount of milk they should. My records will disclose the fact that within the past ten months I have sold at the South Omaha stock yards, cows that I once had the gall to offer for sale at one hundred dollars. This is the very best kind of a thing for the average cattle man to do when he finds that his cows are not doing what they ought to. When I find that a cow is not paying for herself, the best thing I can do is to sell her, but which I have not heretofore done as frequently as I shall in the future. Another thing, while it is admitted that silage is a great feed. It has never been brought out so forcibly as It has been in these tests on these twenty-one herds represented in the Douglas county association. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 another six or twelve months there will not be a herd in that associa - tion '.hat has not a mIo. 1 believe the best way In this matter in order to get the best benefit is, if you admit the truth that we have been wrong, then to follow the results which we have had brought out here before you. I don't know whether 1 am acquainted with all but I am with some of these different cows and herds mentioned here and while some of these results may look exaggerated ( referring to charts) yet I know them to be true. As Mr. Andreas said, I can not account for it unless it is the breed of cow and the silage feed. The man who owned the cow Pet always thought a great deal of her. He thought she was a great cow but he never had any idea until it was pointed out to him that she was a loser. She was really a star boarder for the owner said he thought she was an excellent cow. This matter of testing and keeping a record as we have done in these herds should have been started long ago. It is true and too plain to be ignored. I can't see why these matters have not been worked out be - fore. I hope our example will be followed by dozens of associations all over the state as it has certainly worked wonders with us in the matter of milk production. The President: The meeting is now open for remarks or ques- ■ Question: I would like to know where they found their market these cows that did not come up to the standard? Mr. Glissman: We have a stock yard market at South Omaha. They were always willing to buy them. When we find cows that are not paying for themselves it is better to sell them. tA Member: I hardly think you have to go to South Omaha to them. Don't you have any neighbors who are buying? (Ap- tMr. Glissman: Those cows that I sold to the South Omaha s I thought I could get from $100 to $200 apiece for them, and ad of doing that I took them to South Omaha. Mr. Gierens: My neighbors bought some cows and paid a high price for them without knowing what they would produce. I have thirty dairy cows, we milk and take good care of them and get as good help as I can and try to feed them the best we know how. We did not know how to feed them properly. There are lots more things to learn about the business. I thought I would sell off some. I had too much stock on the farm and so I advertised a sale and I received so many inquiries and there was such a big crowd that I thought of the men who paid such fancy prices for their cows and I was forced to offer a lot of cows that I did not intend selling. As I say I throw this out as a thought that we do not know, you do not know the value of our cows. It may be you are feeding this one or that one because she Is a good looking cow and it may be she is a pet. I am doing the tame thing out at my place. I am trying to cut out a great many of </seg>
            <seg id="p052">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 51 which ones they are. If you have never tested your milk and kept watch and a record you will never be able to tell exactly which cows are doing the best. There is no doubt the cows you have at the present time if properly and better fed will give better results than what you are now gettin;. I was interested in this last paper by Mr. Andreas. These figures here (referring to charts) are a good lesson for us. Our land costs us from $100 to $150 an acre and we put our money into the land and do not put our money into labpr on the land. We refrain too much from hiring a good man wishing to do all this work ourselves and the result is that we are buying high priced land and letting a good deal of it lay idle or farming it in a careless way. Some of you know how much stock can be kept on eighty acres and some of you are trying to make $1,800 clear on eighty acres. How many come up to it? * With the dairy cow and more work on our part will make this rich land profitable. The President: A person would not think of running his busi - ness without knowing how much it costs to run it. He should be Just as much interested to find out the profit in the article he is manufac - turing. This Douglas County Testing Association has started some - thing in Nebraska. It is a lesson all oug'ut to take home. Mr. Mclntosh: I am interested in these remarks on the last paper and I would be pleased to inquire what the moral and social results of the members of the testing association are or were in the neighborhood where these twenty-one herds were being tested. Do they hold meetings and discuss the subjects for the good of the dairy business? tMr. Glissman: I will say for the benefit of the gentleman that we organized this testing association we also organized our - b for meeting once a month and we pick out a subject for the meeting and discuss it thoroughly and in that way we are getting acquainted with each other. The moral and social features are as might be expected from a busings association. After our ssion we generally have a little lunch and entertainment. While liy have one association of this kind in our county at the present I think within eix months we will have one or two more. Question: What do you consider a good test for a dairy cow, profitable cow? Mr. Glissman: This is a hard question to answer and I hardly think I can answer it intelligently in the short time that would be given me here. You can not judge a cow's value by the pounds of milk she gives per day and the percentage of butter fat in her milk at any one time. It is the pounds of butter fat she will give in the year. That is one of the best reasons why a number of dairymen need to have a testing association. You can not fay now I will find out what this cow is worth by milking her and testing for fat one day for this cow </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION or that cow and then the next morning say I have got it down pat and I will sell this cow or that cow. You may be selling the wrong tMr. Andreas: You can not judge of the value of a cow by one i test. You should run the test for a year. It is too expensive to I the test alone and the best way is to get a number of herds and them together for at least six or eight months. You can not e of the amount of milk or the amount of butter fat in it. If are selling milk, that milk must have so much fat in it. You Id avoid a cow giving a low percentage of butter fat. 1 Question: I would like to know what the average test of a thor - bred herd is for a year, say a herd of twenty-five cows, perhaps :eins. »Mr. Glissman; The average herd in our testing association — I Id judge from what I have seen of the report — the average would &gt;out 3.4. I would judge that a normal Holstein would be around iThe President: I think this question has been well threshed out 11 experiment stations conducting experiments along that line. I k I am safe in saying that the concensus of opinion is that you can appreciably affect the per cent of butter fat contents of milk by You can increase the amount of milk and thereby increase the unt of daily butter fat but you will appreciably affect the test. Is right Mr. Glissman. Mr. Glissman: Yes. A Member: With one exception, that cows are in normal con- IMr. Glissman: It is probably true that nine-tenths of the dairy ■ in this state are underfed and this is probably from the fact the man who has the herd in charge is not a competent dairy er. This matter of feeding is what leads so many people astray which is demonstrated on the cows that are brought here to the Ion and at home testing around 3.1, 3.2 and 3.3. By increasing cows feed you increase her condition. If you improve her condi - and increase the percentage testing of the butter fat that is what lead you astray. tin reply to question from audience Mr. Glissman said: "It is diffi - to get the right kind of a feeder for your cows. It is certain that must study the wants of the individual cow. I think in the case lis cow, spoken of, that her feeder watched her individual re - . The only successful way is to feed the individual cow and not your cows all alike as you would a bunch of steers for the *er." RThe President: The next number on our program for considera - is an address by Prof. John Bower. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNTAL coNVENTioN- 53 Prof. Bower: Mr. President and Members of the Dairyman's As- sociation : I You are entitled as an association that I should come here pre - 1 to speak upon what I shall have to say but unfortunately I am ing throughout the state trying to impart some little dairy ledge to the people and in doing so I have contracted a heavy which will prevent me from giving this subject the thought, at - on and time that it should. As the result I have prepared a little r here which I will read. In choosing a topic for an address before such a meeting of creamery men, dairymen and those interested in dairying one has a variety of topics that would be interesting to you all. No subject, however, has such importance as the cow herself. Particularly is this true when we consider her as a factor in the success or failure of dairying as it is carried on in this great state of Nebraska. With euch an introduction you probably expect a long desserta - tion upon her virtues, and it is probably these will be touched upon in this brief address. You may also expect some recapitulation of the principles of breeding and feeding, and there is no doubt that some of the mistakes of common practice will be noted. Some of you may be expecting a discussion of other phases of dairying and you may not be disappointed. All, or any of these things may come in for consideration, but the chief thought will be the relation of this con - vention and the relation of Us members to the furthering of dairy in - terests of this state. I have before me as an audience, creamery managers, superin - tendents, cream station operators and those interested in the buying, manufacturer and sale of dairy products'. I have also before me dairymen, breeders of pure-bred dairy stock, and other dairymen who have not yet realized the importance of specialization as it spells economy in the production of butterfat. I have besides these, possibly members of the faculty of the university and professors and teachers of this great agricultural college. It is possible there may be mem - bers of our legislature, who through interest have taken time to be present at this and other meetings of our convention. It is fitting, therefore, that the matter of education and the great need for it be here discussed. I If you come with me over the state and note the pitiful ignorance tie first principles of correct dairy practice, as it is observed in non, every day life on the farm, you cannot deny the call for ership and assistance. The childlike simplicity of faith with h the average farmer follows methods and practices of his father forefathers is astonishing even to the most careless observer, dete methods, careless indifference marks much of the labor ap- I to the production of milk, cream, and butterfat. There is need i revolution of method, there is need for realisation of the pos - ities of dairying; there is need for leadership, and where else </seg>
            <seg id="p055">54 NKIIRASKA DAIRYMKN'S ASSOCIATION Ethat leadership come if it come not from this convention, contains within itself men of breadth, ■and men of vision, men lght, and men of action. I Nebraska is essentially a dairy state. No other state equals it. •ted as it is, it has the markets of the east, west, north an 1 south, ls command. It has besides a system of manufacture and distribu - which is peculiarly fitted to Nebraska conditions. Through this em the market for Nebraska butter is being rapidly enlarged with system of buying so extended that any man may become a dairy - i assured that his market wjl be permanent and secure. Each - sees an increased demand for dairy products and an increased e paid to the dairymen, when cost of raw material is taken into lideration and the end is not yet. Nebraska, besides, has natural advantages, second to none in the economic production of dairy products. Corn and alfalfa, the desire and dream of the dairymen are here in abundance. But what is the use of such an advantage if it is not used? Today Nebraska corn and Nebraska alfalfa is being shipped out of the state robbing Nebraska soil of its fertility and adding plant food to other states. Even for - eign countries are enriched with potash, phosphorus and nitrogen of which we seem to have abundance, when we consider the lavish hand with which we give away these necessary elements, And why should this be? Simply because our people have not been educated that they too can feed the corn and alfalfa profitably, conserving our soil fer - tility through the use of the dairy cow, which of all animals is best fitted for this work. The average farmer does not know of these things, and the pity of it is that he does not know that he does not know. This convention assembled is where we must look for some movement, some demand, that the necessary education and inspira - tion of leadership be supplied. In this connection, I would urge upon the members of this asso - ciation the necessity of getting a little closer to the legislature of this state, demanding not begging, for an appropriation for the coming biennial which is commensurate with the importance of this growing industry. The State of Minnesota has provided an appropriation of $25,000, for the coming biennium, to further the dairy interest in that part of the country. The province of Ontario, where I was born, have a yearly appropriation for legislation and education of nearly $40,000 per annum. Our sister state. Iowa, has two men working as part of the extension department of the college of agriculture at Ames, Iowa, whose whole time is given up to the furtherance of the dairy interests. Besides this, the dairymen's association have been voted a fund of $10,000 to be used exclusively for the promotion of dairy interests and the elimination of the three hundred thousand cows that are eating their heads off while the other cows are trying to maintain a place &amp;s a factor in the successful management of the Iowa farm </seg>
            <seg id="p056">TWENTY-SIXTH AXNl'AL CONVENTION 55 This does not take into consideration Iowa's appropriation for the en - forcement of dairy laws. t\\'e, here in Nebraska, will spend, as a state, less than $2000 in ring an industry that is adding untold wealth to the state. Of this int the greater part is used by this association in the proper con - of its business. The only other work done by the state is that t by the department of farmers' institutes, which this year will i less than $800 to foster an industry that has added to the th of this state during the past year, a sum approximating a value 35,000,000. I Nor, is this fault of the department of farmers' institutes. The r industry is not the only industry that is suffering. This depart - :, the extension department of our splendid agricultural institu - the department, whose mission it is to bring the truth and inspir - i to our people is sadly hampered by the penuriousness of a lature which seems to think that economy means progression, i economy really spells failure to grasp the possibilities of agri - ire of this great state of Nebraska, possibilities whose awakening ires only the spreading of truth as it is, appears in the successful ition of the ordinary farm. During the past year the number of cows milked in Nebraska amounted to something over 800,000. In production, so far as we are able to determine the average yield per cow amounted to about pounds of butterfat. To get this average there must be a large number of cows yielding less than 100 pounds of butter and a smaller number yielding 80 pounds or less. When we think of the proJuction of Colantha 4th Johanna, a Holstein cow, with a yearly production of 998.2 pounds of butterfat, Jacob Irene, that little Jersey with a record of 952.9 pounds of fat per year, the equally wonderful Guern - sey heifer, Dolly Dimple, with her record of 906.8 pounds of butterfat as a three year old, of the record lately established by the Ayrshire Matie of Sand Hill, also a three year old of 750.3 pounds of butterfat and think of some of our Nebraska farmers working away with a cow that yields a paltry 80 pounds of butterfat a year, the need is the more apparent. Think of it, men; think of the possibilities of increasing the pro - duction of the Nebraska cow to a point double her present capacity: think of the need of further enlightenment along the lines of econom - ical production. There is nothing sadder than to see a people, a people of whom we are a part, so wedded to obsolete methods that they are wasting precious time and stunting the possibilities given them by their Creator because of a lack of knowledge of the truth. There can be no question but at least 200,000 cows in Nebraska are not paying for their keep, that the profit from the remainder could be easily doubled by proper methods of feeding and breeding. There is necl for a vigorous campaign for bettering of methods in dairy work. Let us, as an organization take steps to see that the hands of </seg>
            <seg id="p057">56 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION E whose work in furthering the spread or agricultural truth hout the state is not tied for lack of funds. Let us demand of lie legislative body that a much more ample provision for the ; biennium be provided. If the production per cow can be in - i from 135 pounds of butterfat to 200 pounds per year there be added $13,000,000 to the yearly income in our state. There question but what it can be done. In extending dairy truth to the people, we, as an organization, are encouraged to believe that besides working for our own interests we are working for the best interests of the state as well. Dairying, properly handled, is not only a source of larger income but results in bettering the conditions of a class of people that require bettering. Show me a Nebraska farmer that intelligently feeds his cows, that weeds out the boarder, and uses the breeds that are specialists in econ - omic milk production and I will show you a man that owns his own farm, or if he don't he soon will. Agricultural progress is truly measured by the per cent of men who own the land. Stability of government depends upon stability in its citizenship. Dairying tends to borne making and home building. It has been frequently emphasized at this and other dairy meet- Ings that dairying is conservative of soil fertility. If we sell enough of corn to sell seventy dollars worth of soil fertility, according to present values of commercial fertilizers, and feed an equal amount of corn to the cow and sell the product in the form of 40 per cent cream we sell but twelve cents worth. Butterfat is practically air. sunshine and water. It is composed of three elements, carbon, ox - ygen and hydrogen. Through the action of the sunshine the chlorophyll granules, supplied by the plant system with hydrogen in the form of water, combine the carbon and oxygen of the air with the hydrogen of the water into plant cells. Some other elements are also used. These cells are, in turn, converted into the butterfat by the cow, so Httle or no fertility is lost where cream selling is practiced. Our heritage is our soil. Let us take steps to encourage an In - dustry that has the reputation of a soil builder by properly educat - ing the people to Its vilue as a factor in conserving this fertility. Let Kvoid the mistakts of those states where farms are now crying against a system of soil robbery that is even now menacing the lanent prosperity of our fair state. Another fact that should be considered in advocating appropri - ations for dairy or general agricultural extension work is that the dairy herd is one of the factors in home making. This has alread} been mentioned in a previous part of this address. The very nature of the woik of dairying calls for continuous attention on the part of owner of the cows. Any system of farming which provides long sea - sons of work and long seasons of leisure is fatal to the develoneuient of the best in that person as a farmer and a citizen. The farmer who </seg>
            <seg id="p058">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNIAL CONVENTION 57 Ptime to look after other things as well and you usually cing for himself a real home. I have but to take you to s of this and other states where dairying is practiced in way to find more homes owned by the man who milks the money per capita in the banks, more contented, happy tizens of the state, that is proud to claim them, than is grain farming or other like systems is chiefly followed. It is my contention, based on actual observation and experience, that the fostering of the dairy industry and building it upon a proper basis, a basis of economical production, is best accomplished by the state through stale workers. The large creamery, the local plant, the cream station, have a place in educational work that is enviable. Much of this work, however, is at best, sporadic, lacks system, and specialization, enough to make it show results. The state worker on the other hand is a specialist whose method of presentation is system - atic and continuous. Besides; he has that prestige as a state worker that is so desirable. His interests are. or ought to be, identical with the best interests of the farmer with whom he has to deal. The aver - age farmer is too intent upon selling his cream to the highest bidder to take much stock in the cry for better cows, particularly if such cry comes from one whom be believes to be in some way financially interested. The creamery manager, the division superintendent, the station operator, must supplement the work of the state, but without active co-operation of the state the crystallization of growing dairy sentiment is very slow. Legislature and education for Improvement of the quality of the cream, and a vigorous campaign for better meth - ods are imperative if this important industry is to develop naturally and normally. The President: Regent Copeland of the Iniverslty has a few words to say to us. I Mr. Copeland — I want to endorse what was said In regard to sxtension work and to say that I don't believe there la any more &gt;rtant business the state has than to get behind the farmers' tute work and the extension work in thie state. Anything you do to further these interests should be done and some influence Id be exerted upon the men who hold the purse strings of the to have them let loose and give the people who pay the taxes a chance at it. I am certain that thie state does not spenl any &gt;y that gives a better return to the people than the money spent rmers institute work. (Applause.) It positively made me ashamed to hear it said here that this state only spent $800 the past year for this work. We have not been able to spend more because we have not had the money. I understand that there is being prepared a bill to be presented to the legislature asking for a more generous provision for this work. I heartily en - dorse the movement because I believe it will give good results on the i n vpst nif*n t If vou h&amp; vc* not. vet don£ it I would 1 i kp to su EEPst i ha r </seg>
            <seg id="p059">58 you as an association heartily endorse this movement for a greater &lt;&gt;|iriation for institute and extension work. This is a very important matter, Mr. President, and I hope every member of the as - sociation will exen his influence by either a personal interview or a letter to their representatives and senator. (Applause) While I am here I wish to speak a word for the paper published by the agricultural students. I am deeply interested in their work. They have been publishing for a number of years a little monthly 'hlet termed "Agriculture." l'rof. Davidson has been editine it for them. His work has become so great that he feels it impossible to further give it his attention. The regents have been hesitating whether they would say the publication should be dropped, but I want to tell you that we do not like to say "Quit." We have from year • ar got behind it and helped the publication along. Prof. I&gt; son as you know has not asked the state to contribute any money for his services in the matter. Now the students are very anxious to con - tinue the publication of this little monthly paper. They believe they ran carry it along without the aid of Prof. Davisson and they wish me to say to you that they would be very glad if you will help get be - hind it, and subscribe for it. It is only $1.00 a year and you will n - reive a great deal of information through its columns and I want you to help them along with it if you possibly can. Subscribe for it and make the boys feel good. They will give you your moneys worth I am certain. The President: The thing for each member to do is to write these letters at once and not delay. ■ Mr. H. C. Young extended an invitation for members to pay a to his barns. Meeting adjourned until Friday morning, at ■:•• A. M., Jan - uary 20. THK KSS.W CONTKST. The Nebraska Dairymen's Association offers $160.00 in premiums for essays on the following question INo. 1. Why is a Silo a profitable equipment for a Nebraska far- First Piize $15.00, Second Prize $10.00, and a prize of • for each of the fourteen next best papers. INo. 2. How would you conduct dairying on a Nebraska farm? Prize $15.00, Second Prize $10.00, and a prize of $5.00 for of the five next best papers. In addition to the above a prize of $5.00 is offered for the best essay on Questions No. 1 (the Silo) written by a student in attendance at a Normal School, a like prize of $5.00 for the best essay on Ques- </seg>
            <seg id="p060">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 59 Agriculture, State University, also a like prixe of $3.00 for the best essay on Question No. 1 (the Silo) written by a student in attendance at a High School. t Students of the normal schools, the school of agriculture, and of schools, need to write one essay only on the Silo in order to com - for all premiums offered on Question Nol. but their essay should the endorsement "Normal School," "School of Agriculture," or h School," as the case may be. Conditions IEach essay must contain not less than one thousand (1,000) irore than one thousand live hundred (1,500) words, in type - en form, on one side of the sheet only. No name shall be signed to an essay, but enclosed therewith on a separate sheet shall be sent the name and address of the author. tAll essays fo be the property of the association and prize essays read at the annual meeting of the association to be held at Lin - on January 18-20, 1911, at which time awards of prizes will be iinced. All essays, in order to compete for prizes, must be mailed not later than January 1, 1911, and addressed to Prof. A. L. Haecker. University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. Literature relating to the Silo may be had, free, by addressing Prof. \V. L. French, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebraska. Any resident of the state may compete for the above prizes. I In all 88 essays were received. Of the total number received 57 &gt; from 6tudents of state normals, 3 from students in high schools 10 from students in the school of agriculture. AH essays in both ects, the silo and dairying, competed in the free for all while e from the high schools, school of agriculture and the state nor - schools, competed among themselves for the special prize. With - any names attached, simply numbered, the essays were submitted disinterested committee of three who made awards as follows: I In the free for all competition for prizes on essays "Why is a silo ifitable equipment for a Nebraska Farmer?" the following awards made: First prize $15.00. Will Forbes, Wayne, Neb. Second prize $10.00, Walter Carlson, Lincoln. Neb. tA prize of $5.00 each was awarded the following fourteen corn - ers not here listed by rank — Grace Morrison, Kearney; Grace ort, Peru; (iuy N. Dixon. David City; Bert M. Barber Lincoln: ird Hoch, Lincoln; Harold Calkins, Lincoln; Anna M. Rose, oey; Inez Havens, Peru; May Mclntyre, Kearney; J. H. Gramlich, &gt;ln; Delina Brown, Peru; Albert Pool, Lincoln; Rose Baler, ; Neola Parsons, Peru. In the free for all competition on essays on "How would you </seg>
            <seg id="p061">60 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION conduct dairying on a Nebraska farm?" the following awards were First prtze |1.~&gt; .00, M. W. Roes, Gibbon. Second prize $10.00, J. A. Harris, Lincoln ■ A prize of- $5.00 each was awarded the following five competitors here listed according to rank: Hortense Inks, Peru; Bertha Scott, Peru; Edmund Erickson Bassett; Norval Pearce, Kearney; Irving Beach, Lincoln. ■ In the high school contest on the"Silo" a special prize of 1 5.0c awarded to Littie M. Tullis, Hebron. In the school of agriculture contest on essays on the "Silo" the special prize of $5.00 was awarded to Edwin F. Hoch, Lincoln. In the Normal School contest of essays on the "Silo" the special prize of $5.00 was awarded to Grace Monfort, Peru. • l.l&gt;T OK THOSK WHO TOOK PART IX KSSAY COXTKST. Clase N) Address Normal High Sch Sch. Agri Martha Greenlee 1 Peru x Cecilia Hachne 2 Peru x Catharine Greenlee x Jessie Snover x Hortense Inks x Grace Monfort x Grace Miller x Mabel Shippard x Cleo. H. Vale x Lizzie Powers x Ella Bellas x Mabel Sherwood x Olive Marley x Margaret Seeck x Grace Gray x G. H. Lamphere x C. Arthur Anderson 17 Peru x George Hanen x Minnie E. Tuchenhager 19 Peru X Maude Alma Miller 20 Peru x A. L. Roberts 21 Peru x Nettie Frances Hattie Fowler 22 Peru x 23 Peru Dorothy Dyer 24 Peru Maude McKittrick x Rose Hansen " </seg>
            <seg id="p062">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 61 Class Sch. Agri. Name No. Address Normal High Sch 1-1 Strand ha Scott ry Fausch tie M. TuHis F. Fausch ). Thompson W. Ross 26 Peru x 27 Peru x 28 Guide Rock x X 2» Hebron 30 Guide Rock 31 Ravenna 32 Gibbon 33 Lincoln 34 Lawrence iHarriss se Gilsdorf la Magnuson \Y. Lundy la Brown iy Shaver Forbes x ti Peru x 36 Peru x 37 Peru x 38 Peru x 39 Lincoln (Wayne) Kilt anor Foreman 40 Peru x (Beatrice) G. E. Heacock 4 1 Peru x (Springfield) Rose Bailer 4 2 Peru x 43 Peru x 44 Peru x 45 Lincoln Ke Sagelhe ez Havens t Pool Maude Berry 46 Peru x (Tekamah) R. B. Walls 4 7 York x 4 8 Fairfield iphine Burghart I Havendick Anna Ross und Erickson Mabel Steufer . Box 87 49 Herman 50 Cedar bluffs 51 Bassett 52 Schuyler 53 Fairfield 54 Trenton 55 Darsly Kley Burd Osborne i Parsons 56 Peru x (Valley) 57 Lincoln Harold Calkins Crystal Warden Guy N. Dixson J. H. Grandlich Ana M. Rose x 58 Peru x 59 David City 60 Lincoln 61 Kearney x 62 Kearney x 63 Kearney x 64 Kearney x 65 Kearney x flifred Harmon lyn Hathaway Mclntyre </seg>
            <seg id="p063">62 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION No. Address Normal High Sch Sch. Agri Sailie Fox 66 Kearney x 6 7 Kearney x 68 Kearney x 69 Kearney x 70 Kearney x 7 1 Kearney x 72 Kearney x 73 Kearney x 74 Kearney x 75 Kearney x 76 Kearney x 77 Kearney x 78 Lincoln Leota Vaugn R. F. Piuer Ollie Whitehtad Myrtle Agnew Maria Palian Ebba Weedlum Ida Ward Alta Hanks Norval Pierce Grace Morrison Grace Morrison E. B. Narr Henny Stubble Edwin F. Hoch Bert M. Barber Walter Carlson Irving Beach Carl Bam "9 Lincoln 80 Lincoln 81 Lincoln S2 Lincoln 83 Lincoln 84 Lincoln S 5 Lincoln 86 Lincoln 87 Lincoln 88 Lincoln ERueter Wilcox Burgess Beach WHY IS THE SILO A PROFITABLE EQUIPMENT FOR A STOCK FARMER? First Prize Essay. W. O. Forbes. For over a quarter of a century the subject of silos and ensilage has been before the American people. At first, extravagant claims were made by some of its most enthusiastic advocates. As a result, many of the conservative and more practical farmers would not give It serious consideration. I But silos and ensilage have outlived their most zealous friends advocates. It has made good, yes more than good in the place of )irth and it is today in a majority of the states of this country, paramount question in economic feeding. All farmers will agree that pastures furnish the most ideal feed IUI all 1 1 AOBtrB Ul II » V ollKh, II1U J 11 Ug I tig 1 1 Ulli lUr t .\ Jlt*I 1 [£1 til Is, luo </seg>
            <seg id="p064">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNl'AL CONVENTION 63 most profitable adjunct of corn and hay in a ration for dairy cows, fattening steers and sheep. I There is no feed like the green grasses of our pastures to tone le system of the aged stock and put the young stock in a condition rift and growth. We all know of the good condition of our young ; when they come into the yard in the fall. They are sleek, fat, have made an astonishing growth during the few summer hs. But, how different the picture when we see the same ani - eagerly push through the pasture gate when spring again comes, are thin, out of condition, and many actually weak. We call this ghing them through the winter," and they generally fit this "iption in every particular. I What a boon it would be if we could have pasture for our stock year around. But this is impossible, so the next best thing we can s to find some feed that is as near like pasture grass as is possible, nd a feed that is palatable and one that can be raised on our farms. tin searching about for winter feeds of this description, we find there are only two such feeds which can be grown profitably, e feeds are roots, corn and ensilage. In comparing the feeding s of the two we find that corn ensilage has a slight advantage in it gives us larger gains and milk yields, but this difference is very 1 and of little consequence. Let us consider then which crop give* largest tonnage per acre and requires the least labor to grow. r we have compared roots and ensilage we are in a position to «ay h of these grass substitutes is the best for the stock farmer. t First we find that ensilage will yield on the average about one - again as much per acre as mangels, the largest yielding root crop an grow. In considering the labor, Armsby of Pennsylvania Sta - say it costs over twice as much to tend and harvest an acre of . as compared with raising and putting into the silo an acre of Drawing our conclusion from these statements corn ensilage far the best pasture substitute of the two. Let us now look at an analysis of pasture grasses and corn ensilage. Pasture grass 80. 9.7 4. 2. .8 3.5 Corn ensilage 7!»1 11. 6. 2. .8 1.7 ("Henry's Feeding," pp. 622 and 623) We see that the two are practically the same with the exception of the protein content, and this can be adequately supplied by clover or alfalfa hay. With these two feeds, which can be so abundantly &lt; B 2 "9 n &gt; ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION with corn ensilage to supply the carbohydrates and clover or alfalfa bay to supply the protein, we have a combination which makes one of the best as well as the most economical winter feeds known. I Now that we have found the best pasture substitute as far aa ■osition is concerned, let us look at the cost. I might add here i further proof of its similarity to pasture grass that a series of •iments were carried on at the Nebraska Experiment Station with ' cattle and a similar experiment at the Indiana station with ning cattle to see whether or not such animals taken off of pas - in Rummer time and fed ensilage would shrink in milk yield or ■ase in gains per day. To the surprise of the experimenters ■ was a slight increase while on corn ensilage over the period on ire. This is proof enough that corn ensilage is a genuine sub - te for summer pasturage. Not only can it be fed to milk cows and fattening cattle but with at much profit to growing stock, sheep, hogs and chickens. Going back again to the cost we find that a hundred-ton silo, a corn har - vester and an ensilage cutter will cost about $600. This first coat is a barrier that keeps a good many of us from erecting silos, either because we do not have the money or because we figure that we have gotten along so far without it and can continue to do so, as it is such iMtly improvement. There are more men in this last condition i the first. Ae soon as one can show these men that the silo will for itself in the feed saved or by the gains of the- stock when used, - will gladly consider the proposition. Scores of farmers who have up silos in the past years will testify that the silo does not owe n a cent and that no improvement put on their farms has paid n such dividends. Many claim that in one year the silo will pay itself. I consider there is no argument that can be urged that is itrong as the findings of our experiment station men. Prof. A.. U Haecker of the Nebraska Station has worked out some interesting data on the cost of producing a ton of silage, figuring in the rent of land, plowing, cost. of seed, planting and cultivating, he found that it cost $0.72 per ton. The cos. of filling the silo, allow - ing a liberal wage for men and teams, he found to be "4 cents per ton. The cost of machinery and storage including all items such as interest on money invested, depreciation and repairs, and even taxes and insurance was 4 8 cents per ton. Adding these three initial costs together, we find that the cost of producing a ton of corn silage to be $1.94. Prof. John Bowers of Iown has another way of figuring it in which he arrives at about the same figures. The next question would be, what is a ton or corn ensilage worth? Since it has no market value, because it cannot be shipped or hauled about, we will have to figure its value by comparing it with other feeds and roughage. On this basis, the best authorities estimate </seg>
            <seg id="p066">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 65 of $5.00 a ton, and deducting $1.94, the cost of a ton of silage, we still hare a margin of $3.06 per ton. On a hundred-ton silo, this would mean a saving in one year of $306 worth of feed, to say nothing of the labor saved and the general good condition of the stock, result - ing from the feeding of silage. So the farmers are right who testify that a silo erected on their farms and filled will pay for itself in No crop will yield as many pounds of digestible nutrients per acre as will an acre of corn placed In the silo. This is admirably shown by the following table: Pounds of digestible One acre — nutrients Corn ensilage (12 ton yield) 3,06« Tame or prairie hay (2% tons)) _ 1.380 Corn (50 bUBhels) 2.209 Oats (50 bushels) 1,092 (Henry's Feeding, pp. 631-634) Another advantage in the use of the silo is the great economy of space. Only fifty cubic feet is required to store a ton of ensilage, while a ton of hay in the mow occupies ten times as much space or five hundred cubic feet. We have been looking at the silo so far from a money-making or saving point of view. Let us now consider its convenience and the labor saved in its use. At the Nebraska Station, where corn ensilage is used in both the dairy and beef barns, one man can get the feed from the silo and feed forty head in less than one-half hour and all this is done under shelter. Think of the time needed and disagreeable work it would be if one were obliged to go into the field twice or three times a week to get this same feed in the form of dry, unpala - table corn stalks. Often the work is made more disagreeable by the shocks freezing to the ground and the loading difficult on account of the high winds. When this dry fodder is hauled to the barn, we are told by the best authorities that it has lost from twenty-five to thirty - five per cent of its food value, while if the same crop had been put in a silo, the loss would not exceed five per cent. In summing up the subject, I would say that every stock farmer should have a silo for the following reasons: First: Because corn ensilage is the nearest and most economi- cal substitute for pasture grass, which is the most ideal of all our rations. Second: That an acre of corn ensilage yields from 600 to 2,000 rds more nutrients per acre than any other of the farm crop*. Third: That there is a great economy of space in its use. Fourth: That its use makes it more pleasant to feed stock and </seg>
            <seg id="p067">66 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Fifth: Because with its use in the winter ration, larger gains and milk flows are the result. Sixth: With its use, practically the entire food value of the corn crop is saved. Seventh: That the silo enables the farmer to keep double the number of head of stock ou the same farm. I Eighth: That our fields are cleared and ready for fall wheat or as all our corn stalks are safely stored in our silo instead of I to waste in the field. I Ninth: And lastly and probably the most convincing of all, is fact that practically every farmer now using the silo would not do lout it. When we can grow and store away for winter use a food takes the place of our pasture and that food can be raitel on farms at a less cost than any of our present feeds, the equipment the storing of such feed should be installed on every stock and y farm. STATK PA KM, JAXIARY 20. 1911. iTBCIAL SIIX) SESSION. Joint Meeting of Dairymen and Liive Stock Improvers' Association Meeting Held in Stock Judging Pavilion. Forenoon 'Session Meeting called to order by Mr. Davis, who introduced as the first speaker, Mr. J. W. Dawson, who spoke on Silo Construction. Mr. Dawson: It seems to me that the point that should be brought out is the value rather than the construction of the silo. I have known men who have taken several years to make up their minds whether this or that form of silo was the proper kind. During the time they lost enough to piy for any kind of a silo, when either one would have done the business satisfactorily. Any kind of a silo is 100 per cent better than no silo — that applies even to hinge silos. The fact is that the silo was a plan that was used long ago in the saving and keeping of grasses. There is nothing new about it. The principle has been in operation more than 100 years. The first silos built were dug in the ground. That sort of silo was used in Germany more than a hundred years ago at beet-sugar works. It was after - wards found out that a round hole in the ground was better; and then it was found better to build on top of the ground, as it was more con- </seg>
            <seg id="p068">67 stone, brick or wood, and were square. Then six or eight sided, and finally round. During the past twenty years great strides have been made in the construction of silos. For a number of years silos have been constructed of wood, built after the Wisconsin plan. About twenty years ago the stave silo made its appearance. That eilo was built on the same principle as water tanks, with staves running up and down, grooved and beveled, and held together by iron rods or hooks. This kind of silo construction has several advantages over the Wisconsin silo. In the first place it is much cheaper to construct and easier to fill, and there has not been any form of silo that has taken its place. Last year in Nebraska there were built five hundred silos. Out of that number there were less than a dozen built with any other material than wood, practically all staves. Yet once in a while in traveling over this state we find a man living back in the generation of • hundred years ago, who has built his silo in the ground. Some - body would ask, "What about stone, cement, or brick for silo con - strruction?" Prof. Haecker has answered that question better than I can, and I will quote what he says. He says, "There are three im - i ortant factors that enter into the construction of the silo, namely: pressure heat and acid." Pressure influences the air. The heat pasteurizes the silage, and kills the mold that forms. Acid is also detrimental to many kinde of silos. Wood, is a non-conductor of heat and cold. k Where brick, stone or cement is used the heat is drawn from the e into this material, which are better conductors of heat thxn . We have a greater amount of spoiled silage around the edge ich a silo. Then another fact is, that a stone, brick or cement silo costs more to construct than a wood silo, and that is quite a consideration with many of us. It is more difficult to construct that sort of silo, however and it must be constructed by a man who knows how to build them because if it cracks it is ruined. In justice to the cement tilo I wish to say that properly constructed a concrete silo will prove a satisfactory silo, even considering the cost. I have seen a good many silos the last four years, but have seen very few properly con - structed. My friend, Mr. Wood, of Omaha, has the best one I have ever seen, a solid concrete silo. In conversation with him not long ago he told me that his silo was perfectly satisfactory, but that when he got ready to build another that he would build a stave silo. Ser - iously, 1 think I have said enough in regard to cement silos here now to stir up the cement silo men. §How to construct a stave silo is a great question. For the con - tion of a silo, we will say 16x30, average size, stick a 2x4 in the nd where you want the center of the silo to come. Extend one above the ground. Take a ten foot. 2x4 and bore a hole in it a few inches from one end. Drive a nail through this hole in the center of the 2x4. Measure off on the 2x4 Tin. as a marker. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">68 Pi blackboard here I could describe this better for you. That lould mark the inside of the foundaation of your silo. Meas - i that 10 inches further out, and make another mark, w out the circles, and dig out the dirt between the lines. words dig a ten inch ditch or tremh two feet deep, in order to go below the frost line. The walls should be cut smooth, and then filled in with a concrete mixture made of one part cement, three parts sand, and five parts broken rock. Then drive a 2x4 stake two Ies from the wall both inside and outside. Bend a 1x6 board, this form would be at least one foot high. It will be necessary to k some of these sticks, perhaps every other one, then fill in the i, giving the top a rich coat of cement mortar. Perhaps the ce - l should be one-half clean sand, then smooth and level off. It ry important to get the top of this wall smooth and level. Before ts hard make a line, and on the center of wall by using a marker and a nail. The next thing is staging. (Here the speaker gives figures in or- der to determine diameter and circumference and directions for erecting staging. I Set the posts in the staging 9 feet apart. It usually takes eight fto go round. I usually erect a single deck scaffold with one row ts. For this purpose I use 2x4'sxl6; set up the posts and brace And next is the girths 1x6x1 Oft. and nail 1x6x10 across this I have a diagram here to show you how those are put up. With this scaffolding we find it unnecessary to saw so much lumber (Here the speaker used a diagram describing how he constructed I carry round first row of girths about 7 feet from the top of the I ad; then another row of girths 6% feet above that. I brace in een each post with the 2x4 across in that way (indicating,) then t another set of cross braces from the top down which may be for the painters. They are laid across the girths in this fashion, -ribing. ) I have the girths, one running this way, 2x4x12, and running that way, and the scaffolding is self-supporting. It i about one-half the amount of lumber that a double rigged or le decked scaffold would take. After the scaffolding is up I a door frame. Level and plumb that door frame and fasten, ust be plumb and true because the rest of the silo is to come to that. Then start with the staves on one side of the top frame, and work round, nailing each one at the top and bottom, plumbing each one as I go, and work both ways from the door frame, and on the opposite side where the last stave goes in As you begin tightening up the hoops it is necessary to remove Eie staves and braces from the corner posts, and in this way your done. I generally leave the roof until after the silo is filled much easier to put on the roof thenthan before. I have some </seg>
            <seg id="p070">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNl'AL CONVENTION 69 photographs here showing the staging and the different periods in the construction of the silo. I Here is a photograph of a silo that was made out of re-enforced ?nt blocks. A man generally learns something about his business r year. I learned something new about the construction of silos summer. This has some advantage over my method of construct - silos (referring to photograph.) The staging is constructed on fame principal as I have stated, with the exception instead of ing it on the outside of the silo the staging is on the Inside, and equently takes less lumber, and there is a difference in the sixe le lumber. You go around and strike each stave and after you go nd if you have any extra staves you can put them in, as you can by reference to these photographs. It has some improvements the other method. Question — Do you leave the staging until you get the roof on? I Answer — Yes, it is better, and you need the staging until you get silo painted, and then it will often be necessary to go over the and tighten the bands during the first summer. Say that you i your silo in the months of July or August, you will seldom ever the band tight enough when you are erecting the silo, so it is od idea to leave the staking and tighten these bands at intervals, until you get it painted and the roof on. Question — What about the floor? » Answer — I would dig out the dirt to depth of about 6 inches the bottom of the foundation wall, then put in a two inch coat - of concrete. Question — Would you make a drain in the center? ■ Answer — It is not necessary. If the silage is put in at the pro - time there will be nothing to drain. Question — Why not cut down four instead of two? Answer — You can, but It is unsatisfactory where you go below that distance. On the inside of a silo at the top there Is a rim sometimes of woods and sometimes of metal, and then there are eye-bolts that go through and sometimes guy-wires that are fastened to an anchor in the ground. 1 would never leave a silo until it was anchored because before you fix it there is nothing to hold it, and if a little wind comes along and starts to moving it, it will soon be off the foundation and go down. So you had better get it braced and anchored. After you have done that and drawn up all the slack you can, the silo should extend about three inches of the edge of the foundation, on a ten inch wall, and you will have about three inches from the inside of the staves to the inside of the foundation which you can bevel off with a coat of cement (indicating) thus making It air tight, particularly under- </seg>
            <seg id="p071">70 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION cement it however until I had drawn it or tightened it up several times, and until I was about ready to till the silo. Question — Would you put a rim of cement around the outside of the .Ho? 1 Answer — No, I would not for the reason that the flret rotting of ilo will be at the bottom of the staves on the outside, bo if you a rim of cement round there you hare a place to catch some r and that will hasten the rotting of the staves. Question — What kind of paint would you use? ■ Answer — I think I would use some thin preserving paint, such by-procuct of the gas plant. Question — What kind of wood would you build your silo of? Answer — That depends aa good deal upon the person building the silo. They are made of almost every kind of wood. Question — Are any silos made of hard pine? Answer — Yes, and there is a company that makes hard pine silos. Question — How long would such a one last? t Answer — That depends upon who owns the silo. If a man takes of his silo there is no reason why a stave silo should not last ng as any other. I know of one silo standing seventeen years. and it is in good condition yet. I have no doubt silos, if properly constructed, standing and being in use twenty years. Question — What do you do with the inside of the silo? Answer — In some instances a coat of hard paint is used with very good effect, but the acidity of the silage will practically preserve the inside of the silo. Question — Would you lath and plaster the inside of the silo? I don't see any advantage to lath and plaster the inside of the silo. If a good material is put into the silo, whether hard pine or any other good lumber, I say if good material is used I content! that the stave silo will last as long as any of them. It never rots from the I Prof. Burnett — For the benefit of anybody that may differ with [ would say that we once bought number two white pine to put silo, but when it got here it was very inferior lumber, and we to throw away about a quarter of it, and then the remainder was as good as it ought to have been. I think a person building a 1 silo should buy number one, the very best grade of lumber that an buy. Question — What kind of lumber do you consider the best? Answer — I don't know, but I have an idea that Or or cypress. I think the white pine that we get now days has too many knots. Of course the best material costs more money but is almost always the cheapest in the end. Put the best material you can get in to your silo. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">TWENTY-SIXTH ANMAL CONVENTION 71 A Voice — It is sold at the same price. I But the great trouble with cypress is that it shrinks and swells, le case of a cypress water tank, it would dry oul and fall to pieces, a silo necessarily must be empty perhaps half of the year. At any constructed of whatever material, the silo requires the tighten - of the bands. There is no question about the lasting qualities rprees, but the trouble is that it shrinks and swells, and I think poor material for silo purposes. tProf. Burnett — While I may not and undoubtedly do not know as l as others about silo construction, but it seems to me that If inside of the silo is protected it would prevent this shrinking 1 the silo is empty. We use a preparation of coal tar. When - the silo gets empty who go over it again with this preparation of tar. If you keep it well painted on the outside and inside with coal think you will prevent this drying and swelling. Mr. Young — I have been putting up ensilage three years. The first year I painted, another one I lined with paper. When you put on paint your ensilage sticks to the edge and don't exclude the air quite as well. Where most people fail in the care of ensilage I think they do not get it close enough and tight enough to the edge of the silo; and you must have the inside of the silo smooth, the inside sur - face of the silo must be smooth so that the ensilage will slip down and pack. Where you use coal tar preparation I am inclined to think that the ensilage will stick to the edge. Around the inside edge of the silo the ensilage must be packed tight. It would naturally settle some of its own weight, but unless the inside edge is smooth it will not pack as tight as it ought to around the outside. The center will settle itself. In regard to the kind of wood or the size it does not make si much difference; it all depends upon the care you take of it. Mr Chairman — We will now listen to a discussion by Mr. I. D. Miller of Alma, on the subject of "Silo Construction." I Mr. Miller: I want to take up the other side of this great tion this morning, the side that you do not hear so very much ?d about. The home made silo. It is not necessary to go into past history of the silo, as most every school boy knows some - % about the silo. There is no place the silo is needed as much 1 the State of Nebraska and especially the western half of the Many times I have heard the farmers say that they would like to have a silo, but felt as though they could not afford to buy one, or that things were so unfavorable. Almost every farmer in this state can afford to have some kind of a silo and the most favorable time to put up a silo and to use it is when crop conditions are the most unfavorable. For that is the time above all times when you will need I am not here to cast any stones at the ready-made silo or the </seg>
            <seg id="p073">72 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION people that are interested in making them. May God bless them in their work and hasten the day when every farm in this old state will have some kind of a silo on it and in use. ■ But I want to talk especially this morning to the little farmer, fellow who thinks that he can not spend three or four hundred ira for a silo. I It would take hours to go over all the home made silos and ex - i them so I will confine myself to two home made silos. First, int to take up the silo built out of a good grade of 4-inch flooring, tlemen, this is not a dream. I have seen this silo several times and ; investigated it and know that it was a success, so far as keep - the feed, but it will not last as many years- as one of the better So. in our imagination let us build this silo. All eilos should be on a solid foundation, and I would reccomend ihat you excavate about four feet below the surface of the ground and start your foundation as that will add several tons to your capacity. Wall that up with cement or concrete and build the wall about one foot above the ground. Next cut 2x4*8 in two foot lengths, and imbed them in the concrete flush with the top of the wall so that the silo will rest on the lumber, take two 2x4's twenty eight feet long and bore two holes through flat way about 2 inches apart, and bore this set of holes every two These holes are for the hoops to so through and tighten the silo up with. Place these 2x4's equal distance apart and from the center of the silo plumb and brace them, then use thin bats soaked in »iur for a few hours so that they will bend easily, and bend them in a circle to make a form size of your silo, but we will say that we are building a silo of 14x28 feet above the foundation. Put these hoop or bat forms up about every four or five feet from the bottom to the top. Now you may begin to put up your wall by placing on the out - eide of these bat forms snug against one of the 2x4's a straight floor - ing board 16 feet long and wi.h a shingle nail tack it from the inside through the form to hold it in place. Ahernate with 10 and 12 foo: lumber making a wall 28 feet high. After getting the bottom half up then put your hoots on. Use % round iron hoops in two lengths each length going half way around, and let the hoops lap at the 2x4 on each side and tighten against the 2x4 pieces. After the bottom half is up and the lower hoops tightened so as to hold the bottom portion in shape solid then put up the top half likewise. When you begin to tighten the hoops it will be necessary to draw out the nails on the inside so that the staves will draw up tight. Those bat forms are nailed on the inside of the 2x4 and on the inside of the stave*, and can be left there until you begin to fill the silo and as you fill up to one take it out, and so on. They will help to brace the silo until the lumber gets set. Doors can be cut out on the side most conven - ient for feeding by sawing the doors, beveling longest on the inside- </seg>
            <seg id="p074">73 end putting a jamb on the outside for the door to rest against when the silo is full. Cut out a door about twenty inchces wide and about thirty long then leave a space and cut out another door, not making • continuous door. Some cheap roof can be put on to keep the snow out. Anchor it well with about four anchors to hold it from blowing over. To build this eilo it will take about 1400 feet of flooring 2x4x28 feet long, 15 pair hoops bats for forms, shingle nails, sand, gravel and cement, with rubberoid roofing. You will have a silo with about 125 ton capacity and a cost of about $125.00. To the man that can not buy one of the better ready made silos, then I would say build one like this to start with, and after using this a few years you will be in shape to get one of the better silos. ■ Another silo that I think very much of, one that is very strong durable, easily constructed, and one that will last many years I don't know but what it is just as good as any of them. In our imagination let us build this silo. We have foundation built for the other silo so it is not necessary to go over that again. But we will use five 4x6 pieces 28 feet long with holes bored through them flatwise for the hoops to go through, we will plumb one of these 4x6 pieces and brace it solid, then about 2 feet from it will plumb another one, and every four feet will put between these two 4x6 pieces, a piece of the same material and spike it fast. This ta to brace these apart and you see that we have our door frame. Next take the other three 4x6 piects and place them equal distance apart from the first 4x6 placed, and plumb them and make them solid, then use the thin barn bats to make your form with and nail this form on the inside of the five 4x6 pieces. These 4x6 pieces are set up edge ways. Flace the bottom hoop in position and partly tighten, using % round iron for hoops. These hoops can be in two or four pieces just as you like, and will be allowed to lap and tighten against the 4x6 pieces, but allowed to pass tnrough the door frame and not tigh - ten against only one of the door post if in four pieces and if the hoops are in two pieces they can lap on the side of silo and not at the door posts. After the bottom hoops are in place, take 16 foot 2x4 fir and place flatvise on the inside ot the iron hoop at the bottom, and outside of your forms, and edgewise against the 4x6 piece on one side of the door, using six inch spikes dipped in soft soap, or oil, nail this 2x4 to the 4x6, driving the nail through edgewise, and nail as often as you think best. Next take a 12 foot 2x4 and nail it to the first one placed and so on aTound the silo alternating with 16 and 12 foot lengths. Continue so around your silo. When bottom half is up place your hoops around and tighten them up to hold the bottom half while you put up your top half. With this silo you have the continuous door, you can make these doors any length you want but would suggest that they be about two feet long, and you can use any of the many ways to fasten the doors with It is not necessary </seg>
            <seg id="p075">74 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION to bevel the edges of your lumber, and would recommend that you use fir on this as it will not split so easily, when nailing. IA ladder will be very easily fixed to the 4x6 door frames, and e cheap roof can be put on to keep the snow out and the feed in. about four anchors to brace the silo against high winds. As •d before, this silo is very strong being supported by the five 4x6 bs and every piece nailed, it will not dry out and rack in dry wea - , is easily constructed and very durable. The cost of such a silo be about $225.00 with a capacity of about 125 tons. But friends, question is not so much what kind of a silo to get as it is to get e kind and use it. There are several kinds of ready made silos several kinds of home made silos, and they are all good. I And just one word more to you who are here. Take home to your hbors that are not here, the many things that you have seen heard talked about here, take them home to your own farms and our neighbors. Let us join hands with our neighbors, and with experiment station, and raise this grand old state up on a higher e of agricultural living. IThe President: We have now arrived at the time for taking up next division of this subject, which is "Growing the Corn and ng the Silo." This discussion will be led by Prof. C. W. Pugsiey. Mr. President and Gentlemen: I thought best to put upon paper what I shall have to say concerning this matter. The widt-spread interest which is being aroused in this state in reference to the silo and the uses of ensilage warrants the thorougu discussion which te planned by a session of this kind. The part a3 - signed to me is one about which a great deal has been written, but concerning which few actual facts have been learned. It is easy to theorize and to even advance what seems to be plausible reasons for taking certain Elands, but it is harder to demonstrate that these ■tands are right in every respect. The demand for agricultural knowledge has been so great during the last few years that agricul - tural writers have been tempted to give out to the public as facts what seems reasonable. Some things which look nice upon the face at a distance will not bear close inspection. It is only by careful and painstaking work that we will be able to get down to the bottom of matters and build agriculture upon that solid foundation which it deserves. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">75 GROWING THE CORN AND FILLING THE SILO. By Professor C. W. Pugsley, University Experiment Station. The matter of growing the corn, and of filling the silo is one of the subjects which will come in this class. In order to get some statistics which would be of value to you, I wrote to twelve experiment stations in an effort to find out, if possible, some absolute facts in reference to the things pertaining to the growing of the corn. The first thing to be considered should be the variety of the corn. Of the twelve states responding, those in the east all favored large and late varieties, and a number of them mentioned St. Charles White as being grown extensively. One state said that St. Charles White was shipped in carload lots from Missouri and was known in that state as silo corn. In all of the central western states the varieties used were tile same as those grown in the localities where the silos are located. In fact the stations recommended that the farmers should use the same varieties as they were using on their farms for the production of Last year an experiment was started by the Department of Ag - ronomy and Farm Management, and the Dairy Department, to deter - mine if possible what variety would prove best here at the Station for ensilage. It is planned to have all of the samples analyzed both at the time of filling the silo and when they are taken out and fed to to stock during the winter. Naturally, we do not have the analysis of these varieties at hand, for the Dairy Department is Just now begin - ning to feed the ensilage used for this test. There were sixteen varieties grown and there was quite a considerable difference in the yield* from the different plats. A half acre plat was taken as the standard. Allow me to call your attention to the chart here given showing the varieties of corn used, the yield per acre, the per cent of water, the dry weight, the total number of stalks, including </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Variety Test Fur Knsilage. tit will also be noted that there is no apparent correlation n the amount of dry weight produced and tbe number of stalks plat. The percentage of suckers also gives quite an inter' The work of other Stations in the central west, and one year's ex - periment here at the Station, seem to indicate that the variety best adapted to ensilage purposes here would be the one grown longest in the locality. The Hogue's Yellow Dent, which so far seems the best, and the beaming, which is high up in the scale, are both corns well adapted to this section of the country for grain purposes. The rate of planting is the next thing to be considered in con - nection with the growing of ensilage. The Stations report on this particular point range as follows: Nine states plant U thicker than for grain purposes; two states plant Vi thicker; and one state plants •&lt; 3 S 7 z. p ■ x 2. &gt;? li Name of Variety Hogue's Yellow Dent Loin Ing Flour Kansas Sunflower McCauley's White Dent Ried's Yellow Dent Iowa Silver Mine Chase's White Dent St. Charles White 29220 24340 2*7V" 70.8 70.6 76.2 74.6 8530 7155 6850 6715 7388 7740 8928 5867 II i 26440 » 25960 22280 71.5 6490 5868 3, 6350 6684 ., 28160 77.8 6250 5925 I Nebraska White Priie Johnson County White 23200 22540 21680 73.6 72.9 72.1 73.4 73.4 72.4 6125 6110 6050 5810 5665 6336 5754 4380 5118 7040 21840 Golden Row University No. 3 Mammoth Golden Yellow White Flint Roseland White 21300 200S0 19000 71.1 5540 5490 8418 4866 13420 63.8 4925 4775 11550 4, 15600 69.4 5804 I. I Whether the variety yielding the 1 e best for ensilage purposes cannot . The feeding tests with the cows I quite a considerable difference. 1 I a variation in the per cent of w ted for by the fact that not all vs ■ of maturity. If they had been ha ces are that the per cent of moisti largest amount of dry weight : be determined by the data at and the chemical analysis may It will be noted that there is rater. This can be partly ac- arieties were cut at the same .rvested at the same stage, the ure would not have varied so </seg>
            <seg id="p078">TWKXTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 77 H thicker. This particular point will be taken up by this Station next year in connection with the continuation of a test carried on last year. The varieties used will be the most promising of the sixteen tested during the last season. The following quotations from Hoard's Dairy - man, may throw some light on this subject. "Professor Haecker of Minnesota Experiment Station gets admirable results by sowing corn so thickly that small or no ears develop. The analysis of thie corn is about the same as that which has developed ears, and can be accounted for in this way: the plant takes up its nutrients from the soil and when the ears start to form the elements are taken from the stalk for the purpose of forming the ear, and very little, if any, nutriment is taken from the soil after this period." From what has been done at other Stations, and from the ex - perience of the majority of practical farmers, it seems safe to con - clude that corn for ensilage purposes may well be planted somewhat thicker than where it is wanted for grain. In producing corn for market, the yield of grain is the test of its usefulness. In producing corn for ensilage, the yield of nutrients in both stalk and ear will :mine the value of the variety. There is considerable feding value in every stalk and blade of corn, and it seems quite probably that it is more economical to produce digestible nutrients by growing more of the stalk and leaf than by attempting to get a variety of corn which will yield a large number of first class ears. The next thing to be considered would be the time of planting. This would depend somewhat upon the use to which the ground was to be put after the corn was taken off. If it was desired to seed winter wheat, early planting would be advantageous. A corn plant usually has a definite time for maturing, depending somewhat upon the con - dition of the season. Lack of rain will make the plant mature earlier, but the time of filling the silo will depend largely upon the variety of corn used and the date at which is is planted in the spring. From the replies received from other Stations, eleven of the twelve states recom - mended planting at the same time as for field corn. Cne state far - ther south, Kentucky, plants the ensilage corn three weeks later. It is the custom among practically all Nebraska farmers to plant the ensilage corn at the same time as the corn for' grain purposes, and with our present information this is to be re'eommended as the best method. K Ensilage corn should be planted as close to the silo as possible, this will reduce by quite a per cent the labor of filling the silo. iort haul will enable one or two less teams and drivers to be used. t Formerly, it was thought that the corn should be quite green i used for ensilage purposes. It is now realized that the best ige is made from corn which is well along toward maturity, i the ears are glazed and beginning to dent, is probably the best If cut before this period there is not so large a proportion of stible nutrients in the plants. If cut very much* later, some of </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION the digestible nutrients have been transformed into crude fibre, which is not so degestible. The plant has also a certain amount of that sub - stance which gives to ensilage the thing sometimes designated as "pal - atable succulence." Succulence is, of course, one of the chief assets of ensilage and corn should always be cut early enough to insure this condition. The silo can be filled with corn which is quite mature. In fact, here at the Station, one year the corn was past the best stage by one or two weeks and was quite dry, due to lateness of cutting and dry weather. A small stream of water was kept running in the blower and this gave the dry stalks and ears sufficient moisture to make a very good class of ensilage. It was probably not as valuable as if it had been cut at the proper stage, but it was worth a great deal more for feeding than the fodder would have been, especially when used for dairy cows. The machines used for filling may be of any type, although per - haps the blower type gives the best satisfaction. The blower type, however, takes considerable power. One great advantage of the blower comes in distributing the corn in the silo. There is a certain force, resulting from the blast of air, which enables the silage to be packed to better advantage if a distributor is used. A distributor can be purchased for from $12 to $25, and in many instances will pay for itself in a single season's use. The distributor is merely a series of joints of pipe fastened together with snaps in a manner to make it flexible. The ensiiuge is thus evenly distributed all over the silo, which is not the case when the corn merely falls from the top of the silo either with a blower or chain carrier. The heavier portions of the emilage, such as the kernels and pieces of the ears, will fall closest to the distributing point, while the lighter portions, husks and stalks, will be scattered farther away. This makes it necessary to go to con - siderable labor by forking over the ensilage, and with the greatest of care the corn and stalks are not evenly distributed. Success in feeding depends to quite an extent upon the uniformity of the food used. The distributor will give an absolutely uniform distribution and will save the labor of one man, at least, in the silo. I In filling it is well to keep the out-edges a little higher and to nost of the packing at the outside edge of the silo,. In tramping, feet should be placed next to the staves and the entire weight of body thrown on it. This will pack the ensilage on the outside . manner that will very often prevent the loss of a good many ids. The packing is best accomplished by men constantly tramp- Very often it will pay to keep an extra man in the silo for this &gt;ose, although with a distributor it is probably not necessary to &gt; more than two. One man can do the work better with a dis - ltor than two can without it. The ensilage may be cut in almost any size desired. From one - fourth to one-half inch is probably the best size. The customary size is about otie-half an inch. If much larger than this it is not </seg>
            <seg id="p080">TWENTY-SIXTH AXXTAL CONVENTICX 79 quite so palatable, and pieces are often left in the mangers, especially if the corn is rather mature and the pieces happen to include a joint of the stalk. It is well to have everything in readiness for filling the silo by the first of August. It is much better to be a month too early than a week too late. It may be also that a drought will come, and in order to save the corn crop it will have to be put in the silo. An early frost may also come, and if everything is in readiness the ensilage can be made, if, however, it will take several days to prepare after the frost, and especially if another one follows with some severity, the corn will be greatly damaged. From the farm management standpoint it is always a great deal better to have things all ready long before they are needed. It doesn't take any more time to see that ihe knives of the cutter are sharpened, and that the binder is in good working order at one period of the year than it does at another, and it may mean a good many dollars to the farmer. No money is saved in tilling by attempting to get along with too little help. Filling the silo at the best is rather heavy work, and, as a rule, farmers do not like that part of it which demands the handling of heavy bundles of corn. If teams and men enough are on hand to complete the work in a short time, less trouble will be experienced in getting help. One of the heaviest expenses in connection with tilling is the cost of an engine and engineer, where one is lifted. It is hard to get a man to come with his engine, in most sections of this state, for less than $8 or $10 per day. If the cutter is of large enough capacity to fill a 100 ton silo in a day, every effort should be made to do so. Very often by the addition of one extra man and team in hauling from ihe field this can be done. I Some farmers favor getting a smaller cutter and letting the nil - period extend over a larger portion of time. In some instances is probably an economical arrangement. 1 1 now of one man in i who uses a small cutter with a chain carrier, the type that de - ds the least power, and runs it with his farm gasoline engine. He the help of the farm, with perhaps an addition of a few men, and extend the period of filling a 100 ton silo over a week. This, of se, has the disadvantage very often of allowing a portion of the to become too ripe, while the portion which was put in first may little green, especially if some bad weather intervenes (There is no need of getting a cutter with an extremely large :ity if the purpose is to fill one or two medium sized silos on one's farm. I have a 12-inch cutter with a traveling feed table and a capacity of 10 tons and the boys reported last year that the r was plenty large and would take care of the corn as fast as they 1 get it to the machine. I made a trip at the season of the fillings was surprised at the manner in which the cutter would handle the les without cutting the bands. In no case were the bands cut the cutter would take the entire bundle. I am satisfied myself. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 ter, that if I were purchasing another machine I would get one a larger to enable the man at the feed table to get along with a less work and worry. The cost of filling will vary a great deal upon different farms. The value of a ton of ensilage will depend to quite an extent upon the methods employed in growing the corn and in filling the silo. If a man is a good farmer and raises a large crop of corn and the coat is based on the cost of producing an acre of corn it will be seen that his ensilage will cost a great deal less per ton than the ensilage produced by his neighbor who uses a small amount of corn. Last season 1 saw one farm where 8 acres filled a 100 ton silo, while on another farm not more than three miles distant it took 25 acres to fill a 100 ton silo. The market value of the land was about the same. It can thus be seen that estimates on the cost of production will vary greatly; probably due more to the amount of ensilage produced per acre than to the cost of filling, although that is no small item. The variation in estimates will not be so great if it is figured on the basis of the bushels of corn produced per acre, at market value. Professor Mum ford of Illinois, states that corn yielding 42 bushels per acre and worth 35c on the market will give ensilage at |S.7i per ton. In my own instance last ytar where it took 18 acres to fill two silos of 110 tons each and with an estimate of the corn at 60 bushels per acre, at 35c per bushel, and with the labor of'fllling extending over a period of four days, and costing $110, and allowing the stalks to be worth $1 per acre on the market, the cost of ensilage per ton was $2.59. Mr. Rusk of Union county, Iowa, produces ensilage at $2.49 per ton for a 100 ton silo. This makes the average of these three estimates $2.61. Professor Haecker bases bis estimate upon the cost of grow - ing the corn an ! Mates that ensilage can be grown at $1.94 per ton. Mr. Richardson, of Scott county, Iowa, says that it costs him for cost of growing and filling, $1.15 per ton. I have no doubt but what care - ful farmers can easily produce ensilage figuring the cost on the markft value of the corn if it had been harvested and sold, at $2.50 per ton, and at this rate it is one of the cheapest and best foods in connection with alfalfa or clover hay that can be produced in the corn Question: What length do you cut the corn? Answer: I cut mine about half an inch. ■ Question: What kind of a carrier do you recommend to carry corn from the cutter or field to the silo? Prof. Haecker: There is a very good way of using a low wagon, and by using a heavy plank with two hooks so as to hook on to the back part of the wagon. The bundles can be thrown on to the wagon. Question: How much corn is cut down? A Member: I cut down a whole field of silage Question: What if a heavy rain comes on? </seg>
            <seg id="p082">TWKNTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 81 Ption: Well, suppose you cut down enough to nil a 100 ton it turns around like it did this season and rains, the corn iply sour. I had some cut down and had left it until the and the next day I did not get to it, and before I could these bundles soured and I didn't consider them worth any- ■ Answer: I don't think a little rain will hurt, I don't think it hurt the silage. Question: The question of getting the corn on to the wagon it IK proposition, when you have to hire men, it takes about four or men to load a wagon properly. If we could get a machine to pull corn on to the wagon it would be the biggest kind of economy, re is no question about cutting it. You can cut twice as much as you can get ready for the silo. The President: I understand there is a machine that they use in Louisiana for loaiing the sugar cane. With some modification it might meet the requirements for hauling the silage. But that machine costs $800. and I hardly believe you are yet prepared to ex - pend that amount of money for that purpose. 1A Member: I start by binding about an hour before the men ready, and I start the wagon following right up as soon as it is I improvised a wagon with low wheels. I take the trucks and Iron pipe and with boards I make a frame, and in that way I ■ a very convenient way of hauling the silage to the silo. I The President: We were to be favored with a further discussion lis subject by Mr. Hoge of Crete, but as he is not present I will on Prof. A. L. Haecker to discuss "The Value of Silage in Feeding n Animals." Prof. Haecker: Mr. President and Gentlemen: As the hour is getting late I shall detain you but a little time: This silo subject is of interest to every one who feeds stock and the time is now ripe for its introduction into our state. I have been ad - vocating the use of the silo in the state for fifteen years but I now think I might as well have saved my breath for the times were not ripe for it to come. In the year 1885 we had one on our farm in southern Wisconsin a home-made silo: we built it square, about eighteen feet each way and sixteen feet in depth: I do not what it cost but I know half the silage spoiled: it was constructed wrong; built on a wrong principle. I do not wish to discourage any one who wishes to build his own silo but I would advise him to carefully study his plan before he starts his building. tVVhen corn was 25 cents a bushel and hay $5 a ton it required skill or brains to place our live stock on the market with </seg>
            <seg id="p083">82 I'sed to Laugh at Science. "It was not rurtssary to understand the principles of scientific feeding. Protein and carbo-hydrates were laughed at by the suc - ceasful feeder a* scientific nonsense. Just as our forefathers burned off the fine timber to clear the land, having no regard for the timber value, so in past years our farmers on the fertile western plains have naturally drifted along the easiest course in their husbandry. I "During the last few years the high price of grain and forage rendered stock feeding, as carried on by the old methods, un - table. While a few feeders through shrewd buying and experienced g have realized a profit in the business, the great majority of who accounted for their labor and efforts in their work found were making little or no profit in growing beef. Where the open e and cheap land were utilized this condition of affairs did not place, but on land with a valuation of $30 or over the feeder inclined to find his profit lacking. Dairy Farmer Gets Profit "'Almost the same conditions have taken place with the dairy farmer except he has found profit in spite of high feed values owing to the very high price of butter and the economic advantage of the dairy row over the beef animal. However, with a low butter market and high priced grain and forage, the cream producer will be forced to adopt better methods if he wishes a fair profit from his business. "In simple word6 we have come to the time when it is necessary to produce animals and animal products more cheaply or quit the busi - neas. As this is a stock country it would be absurd to think of les - sening our stock production. So we must turn to the wiser course of cheapening production, and then maintaining our wealth and pros - perity. Silo Important Subject. t"As times are ripe for economic feeding, the silo as a means of penir? r.nin.al production is one of the paramount subjects before farmeis. At a meeting of various agricultural socittits held re - ly in Lincoln a special silo day was put on the program in order ill attention to the importance of this subject and also to give pportunity for discussing the methods of using corn silage to the advantage. K "Nearly 1 ,000 farmers attended this meeting and it was pro - iced by all to be one of the best meetings of the convention. has Nebraska foreseen this silo necessity, but also the neighbor - states. Iowa, South Dakota, Kansas and Missour: are all taking he silo in an earnest and serious way. ■ "And why should not the silo be considered as a profit maker for farmer? "When we review the mass of authentic experiments published </seg>
            <seg id="p084">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 83 by our different stations, all demonstrating beyond the question of a doubt the economy of the silo, we should not be slow to avail our - selves of their benefit. Experiments Are Made. "The following is the meat of several experiments which have been conducted by our various states: Missouri found in a steer - feeding experiment where corn silage was compared with hay. $1.07 for every 100 pounds of beef was saved by the use of silage. Illinois station in bulletin No. 73 found corn ensilage worth 31 per cent more than corn fodder when all costs were considered. KOhio station found that they could produce butter fat 9 cents ■r per pound by using ensilage than the could when using hay. difference was found in milk production. Indiana Adopts Silo. KThe Indiana station found the silo the most economic means oducin? both beef and mutton in three well conducted experl - i. They also found corn ensilage to be worth from $5.50 to $6.50 )n when fed to fattening steers and sheep. "This in the light of the fact that corn ensilage will not cost the farmer more than $2 a ton should be convincing argument. "The Mississippi station found corn ensilage in the south the most economic means of producing both milk and butter. t "Pennsylvania station found good results in feeding steers silage realized a value of $6.20 a ton when used in this way. They also d silage superior to hay and much more economic in ihe raising oung stock. Massachusetts found in a steer-feeding test corn e to produce meat cheaper than where hay was use!. Ontario Saves Much. "Ontario experiment station found they could save $63 on every $200 invested in feed if they used corn ensilage in preference to hay in feeding cattle. Kansas experiment station not only produced beef cheaper with silage in the ration, but also the silage fed steers sold at a higher price on the market than did the dry fodder steers. ■ "They found corn ensilage when put in the silo would keep for and six years and retain its feeding value. I "Michigan experiment station has been using silos since 1881 has found in several experiments ensilage to be the most eco - c form of feeding the corn plant to live stock. Silage Producing Mutton. "Silage when fed in conjunction with alfalfa or clover produced mutton more cheaply than when hay was used. tMany other station have tested out the economic use of the id one and all have endorsed it as a practical economic equip- For tne stock farmer. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 84 "Thousands of farmers and stockmen all over the country have been demonstrating for the last quarter of a century the economic use of the silo, and practically all who now have such equipmeni are firm in their praise and endorsement." The President: We would like a demonstration of the value of silage from Prof. Bower. Prof. Bower: I don't know that I have anything further to add along the line of feeding silage to stock. I came from the East where we feed silage to horses, feed it to cows, feed it to sheep, feed It to hogs, feed it to hens — and I heard it has been said out here by one man that they feed it to the hired girl. It is a surprise to me to come out here and have the question eternally brought up, "Is silage good for this, that or the other thing?" It is difficult for me to understand why this question should be so often asked. The corn plant is given by nature to supply the demands of nature as an economical producer of fat, and there is no question but that the corn plant is the king of all plants. The great reason why corn land has such a high value today is because through the corn plant we can grow more fat than by any other plant. Now if we can by conserving that plant and the value of it in a silo, placing it in a palatable and digestable feed for stock, we have something that can't be beaten, There is no question but that it is good for the cow. and Prof. Haecker has told you that it is good for the beef animal as well, and it has been proven by the dairymen that it is a practical fodder to feed to the herd. I have had practical feeders in this state tell me that their silo has paid for its cost the first year after its erection, and that surely is evidence enough of the value of the silo in Nebraska. The silo has been found to be a most desirable and profitable adjunct to farming in the East, and there is no question but that which is good for the East is good for the West, and there Is no question but what the silo is absolutely necessary in the state of Nebraska. The silo is the solution of all economical and cheap feed. There are two ways in which you can make money. One is by economical production of feed, and the other is by getting high prices on what you sell. You are anxious to get high prices and the silo is an economical basis for obtaining high prices and upon it rests the welfare of the farmers of this state. You have the two best products here in Nebraska for the success of the farm, and the two that are the cheapest that can be grown — corn and alfalfa. They make the best ration for the dairy cow, and separately they are each the best plant that can be raised by the farmer, and they together furnish the best concentrated food for any farm animal. Another point is, that with the silo we avoid the dangers of the corn stalk disease. I have not yet known of any animal becoming diseased from the corn stalks that have gone through the silo. An - other advantage in having the silo for corn ensilage, as soon as you have taken off the stalks you have the land ready for the planting of wheat. It distributes the labor of the farm throughout the year, </seg>
            <seg id="p086">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 85 and by the use of the silo you have labor that you can depend upon the year round. By using the silo for corn stalks you save in the loss that would follow by leaving the stalks to dry out by the sun, and wind, and freezing — the weather has decreased the value of those stalks a large per cent. There is no question, men, that the silo is the solution of the pure feed problem. We frequently read some very queer stories, but I had a man ask me the question just recently, "if silage did not spoil the inside of the cow." He said, "I knew of a heifer that died from eating silage. When opened the vitals were all eaten to pieces." All sorts of ques - tions like this may be asked by those who don't know what the silo will do. Don't condemn the silo until you know what harm it does. Gen - tlemen, there is absolutely no question about the value of the silo, and those who say it is not profitable have not tried it; those who have tried it give it unqualified recommendation. I thank you. (Applause) ■ The President: If Mr. O. Severe of Palmyra is in the audience would like to hear from him. Mr. Severe: It is getting late, and this subject has been thor - oughly discussed. I simply wish to corroborate every word that has been said here this morning concerning silo, and silage and the use of it, as far as my experience goes. We have two silos. My son has one, and he fed the silage-to sheep and lambs, and I wish to etate that they have grown splendidly without any other feed except clover hay, and they made a gain of twenty-four pounds in ninety days. They didn't have a kernel of corn except corn ensilage. That settles that question. We have lots of alfalfa and lots of clover. I am usually feeding from 100 to 150 head of steers at this time of year. At this time feeders were so high I left my hay in the stack. I Now just one more word about feeding this silage to horses. I say that it is excellent feed for them. All they get through the ter is silage, and all the other fodder they have they get through rack and I want to tell you the horses and colts look fine when they turned out in the spring to grass. A member: For those who contemplate building a silo I wish to give a bit of my experience. If you have too small a herd you don't want to build too big a silo. He careful about that, or else you will have to increase your herd. You must feed a certain amount each day. If you do not you will not get the best results. For in - stance, if a man has ten cows and puts up a silo 14x30 he will have more feed on hand than he will know what to do with, and he will have to go out and buy more cows in order to keep the silo down to the proper amount. The silo for a herd of ten or twelve cows should not be over 12x30 feet and 4 feet in the ground, and then you feed enough to get the full benefit, and your stuff don't sour and mold. Question — What do you do if silage spoils or molds? </seg>
            <seg id="p087">86 NEBRASKA DAIRY. MK IC'IATION Answer (from the audience) — What you don't use this year it will keep over and be just as good next year. It will keep like canned fruit if you keep your silo tight. THK SILO AM) WHAT IT MEANS TO THK FARMER. By Geo. P. Bellows. I Farming is the biggest business in the world. It is also one of most respectable and dignified. The farmer who puts mentality enthusiasm into his business receives the plaudits, respect and iration of all classes of people, and a good return on his invest - [ and his brain. I After eighteen years of travel, studying agriculture and lire k conditions in all parts of the United States, Canada and Great ain, I can say with truth that the farmers of this section will com - ! favorably with those of almost any other locality. I hold how - '. that it should be the ambition as well as it is the duty, of every aer to make the best of his opportunities. These consist of a irally fertile soil, equitable climate, good markets and other fav - ile conditions. By improving his opportunities he can put himself ahead of the average farmer as found the country over. My ob - ations lead me to suggest that the farmers throughout the corn can bring about great Improvements in their business and ma - illy increase their profits by giving more thought and attention to E scientific, but simple and well established principles, namely: ion of crops, economy of production, elimination of unnecessary and the marketing of the finished product instead of the raw lal. But you ask, "What has all this to do with the silo?" It has every - thing to do with it. The use of the eilo is a strong determinating factor in bringing about the reforms above suggested. I firmly be - lieve that the most successful and prosperous farmers of the future will not be those who simply grow grain and haul it to market, but will be those who handle their land along scientific lines and keep a plentiful supply of live stock on the farm. It is a lamentable fact that under present prevailing conditions the producing value of many farms has been falling off and the fertility of the soil in many cases seriously reduced but this fertility can and must be replaced if we ere to hold our proud position as the leading agricultural section of the country and make our lands yield a good return based on the increased value thereof. There are two ways to do this and both should at once be put into practice. They are rotation or crops ana the keeping of more live stock on the farm. These two things intel - ligently applied, will not only increase our direct profits, and maintain the present fertility, but add to the actual value of all lands thus handled. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">TWENTY-SITH ANNUAL CONVENTION 87 Many of our fields need a rest from corn and are crying for clover and manure that will put back into the soil those elements which the continuous cropping to corn has robbed it of, viz: rogen and humus. But some will say, "Our present acreage of corn is not now yielding enough for our supply." Grant this fact. I know that our average yield per acre has fallen off, but my contention is that the land should be so built up by the liberal use of clover and manure to where the average yield per acre will be doubled and then, by the use of the silo, almost again double the feeding value of every acre. This system spells not only economy of production, but elimination of waste. Under the eilo system of farming less acreage is needed for corn and more land can be kept to grass, more stock can be better and more economically kept and along with other advantages the fields made less subject to waste by washing. More stock means more manure and more manure means bigger and better crops. An acre of corn put into the silo has a feeding value equal to almost two acres handled in the old way. Besides almost doubling the feeding value, the palatability of the feed thus supplied is greatly enhanced; and, still further, ensilage is a succulent food, more like green summer feed, than any other winter feed, and is more easily digested and assimilated. Ensilage cannot be too strongly recommended for milk cows, fattening steers and all young growing cattle. It is good for horses sheep, hogs and chickens. When corn is put into silage p'ery particle of the nutriment contained in the stalk, blades and grain is preserved Just at the time when the plant is at its highest feeding value, and by "canning" it, fully 40 per cent waste is eliminated. In other words, wasie is turned to gain. Another advantage with the silo is that the crop is harvested at a time when weather conditions are favorable, and every farmer knows what it means to employ a system that will prevent his having to drive over his land in all conditions during the winter and spring months. After the ground is cleared it can be sown to fall grain and in the iolowing spring clover can be sown therein, thus facilitating the much desired crop rotation and soil upbuilding. tWhen the corn crop is in the silo it is in the most available, com - and convenient form for winter feeding, with exposure and labor indling reduced to the minimum. After carefully studying this question from every angle for several years I built a silo on my farm and after four season's use have purchased the second one and can conscientiously recommend them as the best and most profitable farm improvement I ever made. In the light of my own experience and the experience of hundreds with whom I have talked I can advise that the gain from, feeding silage will return the cost of the silo every two years. When it is t.gurr 1 that a silo built of Oregon fir, full length, single stave, will last at least twenty-five years, it does not require a shrewd business farmtr to see that the investment is about the most .sensible and </seg>
            <seg id="p089">88 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION profitable one be could make. A well constructed up-to-date silo of good material, with the much improved hinge door, adds to both the appearance and selling value of any farm. It is the key to more stock on the farm, more grass,, more manure, better farming and larger profits, and as well the key to a richer heritage in the way of well preserved fertile farms for those who are to follow. The silo is beyond the experimental stage. Every agricultural experiment sta - tion recommends it. Every farmer, feeder, breeder and dairyman who has tried it approves it. There should be thousands of them erected in each of the corn states within the next year, and after these have been in operation a short time the intelligent farmer would no more return to the old way of handling his corn crop than he would substitute the sickle for the harvester, the flail for the thrasher, or the fine carriage and spanking bays for the ox carts of our fathers. (Read at joint session of Dairymen's Association and Improved Stock Breeders Association.) ■ Afternoon Session: The President stated that the first busi - to be transacted would be the report of committees. The President: The first is the report of the Nominating Com- KThe Nominating Committee, by Mr. H. C. Young, made the fol - ig report: Lincoln, Nebraska, Jan. 18, 1911. To the members of the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association — Your committee on nominations, after due deliberation, beg to submit ihe names for officers for the coming year as follows: Mr. E. T. Rector, Omaha. President. Mr. W. L. Hunter, Raymond, Vice-President. Mr. S. C. Bassett, Gibbon, Secretary-Treasurer. Directors Charles Harding, Omaha. Prof. A. L. Haecker Lincoln. E. H. Frost. Central city. \V. R. Wood, Cmaha. H. C. Young, Lincoln. Respectfully, A. E. WILKENSON E. H. FROST H. C. YOUNG Committee. Mr. Toosg: I move that the report of the Committee b« adopted The President: If there are no other nominations to be made </seg>
            <seg id="p090">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 89 we will proceed to adopt the report of this Committee, which ia vir - tually electing those candidates. ■ The motion to adopt the report of the Nominating Committee seconded and carried. I Prof. Bower: I have a resolution. Mr. President, which 1 wish lace before the convention relative to the work of extending and mraging dairying in this State. As I said yesterday, we have it $35,000,000 worth of dairy products annually in this State with •xpenditure or appropriation of about only $800 to encourage the tie along better methods and better lines; I believe if we shall have better dairying we must have better facilities for instruct - the people. I have, therefore, prepared the following resolution, h I wish to introduce. t "RESOLVED: That the Nebraska Dairymen's Association tily endorses a more liberal appropriation for the extension of ultural teaching through the medium of farmer institutes of the ; and that at least $5,000, annual appropriation, be asked for by association for the use of the extension department of the agricul - college to teach good dairy practice and encourage better ods throughout the state. Mr. President: I move the adoption of the resolution. The resolution was adopted: The President: We will listen to report of the Committee Resolutions: Resolutions. "Resolved, That it is the senee of this association that the Food and Dairy Commissioner of Nebraska should make a thorough investi - gation of the methods of the production of commercial cream, and the methods employed in collecting and transporting the same from farm to manufactory, with a view to making such regulations in the busi - ness as will insure the highest possible sanitary conditions of Nebras - ka's creamery butter. » "Resolved, That it is the sense of this association that the Food Dairy Commissioner be given the power to employ a sufficient ber of competent dairy inspectors whereby this department will icreased in efficiency and the state profited thereby." The President: We will listen to the report of any other coin- Prof. Melick: §Mr. President, after some heated discussion, in regard to the npetency of testers of cream over the state, and some incompe - work being done, and the causes of bad cream etc., there was a committee appointed composed of State Dairy Commissioner Jack- </seg>
            <seg id="p091">90 XKBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION proposed amendment to the present dairy law, and place it in the hands of the proper legislative committee to be incorporated in the state dairy and food law. We have hastily drawn, in rough form, the following amendment, which is intended to be an amendment to Sec - tion I, which I will now read. Section '«. No person shall offer for sale any miik or cream in an unclean or putrid condition. The dairy inspector's judgment shall be authority on this point. A fine of not less than five nor more than twenty-five dollars shall be imposed upon the offender for a violation of this section. Cream testers shall be required to pass an examination not only in the use. of the Babcock test, but also in cream grading. k After January 1, 1912, all dairy inspectors shall be recommended ppointment by the dairy husbandman of the state agricultural Mr. Melick: 1 move the adoption of this amendment by this association. I The President: I think this is a step in the right direction. We hope to take some steps to see that something is done along this to secure more efficient work and I hope this resolution or idment will be adopted. Resolution adopted. Silo Discussion. The President: We have on the program an address by Prof. T. L. Haecker, of the Cniversity of Minnesota. I am very sorry, indeed to announce that Mr. Haecker is not here with us today. The most of us have heard him, but he is always such a good visitor and we always get so much entertainment and instruction from him that we regret he is not here. I hardly think we have exhausted the subject of silo and ensilage, and I think there must be in this audience a number of men who are actual users of the silo, whose testimony at this time would be important, that others who are here, considering the subject, may be informed. 1 would be very glad if any one here will give us his experience. Mr. Young: 1 will say that any man, who keeps dairy cattle or any other cattle, unless he has a silo or can get ensilage I don't see how he can very long compete with those who have a silo. I have been interested in ensilage three years, and I hardly realize how I ever got along without it. If I had had as many cattle two years ago as I have now I could not have got along without one. I could not run a dairy now without a silo. If I was deprived of my silo and could not get ensilage 1 would go to work raising alfalfa, and quit dairying. I believe a great many people keep putting off the building of a silo thinking they will build it next year. They figure the cost of building </seg>
            <seg id="p092">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNIAL CONVENTION 91 money back the first year. I did not try to economixe. I put off building it until late in the year, and had to hurry around in order to build it, but I figure it more than paid for itself the first ysar. I get a good price for my milk, and every quart counts in my business, i figure it does not make any difference whether the man is in the dairy or live stock business, twenty acres of corn ensilage will go as far as 6iity acres of corn used in the old way. ■ Mr. Sneddon: Mr. President, I will go the gentleman one better, say that I believe twenty acres of ensilage will go further than hundred acres put up in the old way. tThe President: There are a good many users of ensilage here, I would like to have that point brought out, and I will ask Mr. er. the gentleman who won the prize essay on the silo last year, ■cat home and built a silo after winning the prize, to give us a now that he has used it and used it with dairy and beef cattle horses, and I don't know what all. Mr. Culver: We found out that we could use another feed to good advantage, cut ensilage, and we fed it to all the animals; and calves that we raised on ensilage and skimmed milk, are equal in weight to any others raised on additional feed. We used to, in the old way. let the calves run with their mothers and that was about all the good we got from the cows, was keeping the calves. At the present time our calves are raised on ensilage and skim milk and they excel in weight and quality and are much more thrifty than in the old way of raising calves. Question: How soon do you begin feeding ensilage to calves, Answer: As goon as they will take it. Put it before them and they will eat it when they are a month old. Question: How about feeding it to pigs? Answer: Why, they squeal for it every time. Question: How do you feed it to them? Answer: Simply throw it out on the ground and they clean it up every time. We don't expect them to have that all the while. They get other feed besides, but they clean up the ensilage every time. They look more thrifty this year than any other year we have used it. We feed it to the colts and horses also, in connection with other fodder, and the colts look thrifty and healthy as they would in July. If they hear the rattle of the basket that we carry it in, — they will hear that for half a mile or so, — they will run for the feed and snatch the en - silage out of the basket before we can get it out to tiiem. I will also say, as Hr. Young said, I don't see how any man can run a farm without feeding ensilage. We feed it to chickens and they relish it as much as any other animal. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">92 NEBRASKA DAI HYMEN. S ASSOCIATION Answer: Yes, sir, and we feed it to mares with foal with good results Question: How much grain do you feed? I Answer: The horses that we work do not get any other grain pt • few nubbins of corn. We feed ensilage to horses at noon i alfalfa hay. We give to the cows corn fodder in the morning, ng off all the large ears except a few nubbins, the pigs manage to most of the large ears. They get a small allowance of bran and , and all the alfalfa hay they want. As I was saying, we only have six head of calves and they eat several bushel baskets full of it a day. ■ Question: Do they eat as much alfalfa hay as they would wlth - the ensilage? Answer: No, not as much, probably about half. tThe President: In conversation with a man from the north - ?rn part of the State of Nebraska, where they can nofrais? alfalfa where this is an important question, I suggested that there t be other crops raised that would be rich in protein. Can you some experience along that line? Mr. Culver: I hardly feel competent to answer a question like that. Much depends on locality. The President: (To Prof. Bower). What would be your sug - ge,tion? KHe would have to have protein, and the cheapest food he could would be alfalfa hay. I believe they can grow alfalfa up there, n't know whether there are any gentlemen here from Alliance would tell me that was not true, but I have seen alfalfa hay was grown as far away as Harrison. They do not need to grow a hundred acres at the start, but begin with a less number, say ten acres, and in addition to their other feed they might add about a jonnd or one-half of oil-meal, which would aid very much in balancing that ration. ■ Question: Is there any way of getting a balanced ration without use of alfalfa? ■ Prof. Bower: Clover has a value almost equal to alfalfa, but you balance it by usiirfe a little oil-meal and bran. KA Member: While we are not getting a high price for our milk gure that our cows are paying us 50c a bushel on corn, whereas rould otherwise get but 32c by putting it on the market. ■ A Member: I notice Mr. Theodore A. Gierens in the audience, for one would like to hear from him on this subject. Mr. Gierens. Mr. President and Gentlemen: I was not here at the opening and therefore do not know what all has been said about the silo. I might say that I have not used a silo for any great length of time. 1 have one on my farm east of the city. I have read a great deal about the use of the silo, and so have the most of you, I dare say, how- </seg>
            <seg id="p094">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 93 ever I bare had some little experience. It has seemed to me for some time as though I needed a silo, and I would say that almost every farmer needs a silo. It is needles to say though that there are farmers who have no business with a silo. For instance, the man who is Accustomed to nail up his corn-crib, and let stock roam out during the winter season would have no use for a silo. It is quite evident that he would not fill it nor use the silage if he had it. And then there would be another man who did not keep hardly any stock, it would be folly for him to erect a silo. But for the farmer who keeps a lot of cattle, or a lot of hogs, or a lot of horses, a lot of stock, who has a 40 or 80 acre farm, ought to have a silo, if he will post himself as to what to do in the use of the silo. I put up a silo 16x34 and 30 feet high. I wintered on my place last year from 30 to 50 head of cattle, 125 head of hogs, and 10 to 12 horses and mules. Of course I have only a little farm, and did not have very much stock to feed, but the question arose in my mind how to utilize and care for this stock in the best possible way. Some of you who tried to care for lots of stock last year know what it means if you don't have any hay. I commenced using my ensilage sparingly because I didn't think I would have enough. I fej it to the cows, and calves. We commenced feeding it to calves as soon as they can nibble at it, wben they are about four weeks old. I didn't keep it away from them, and I had in the barn a pair of mules and a pair of colt*. I told my man — as the most of you know I am not out very much myself, but do my farming by telephoning — not to keep the ensilage away from the mules and colts. I said it would not hurt them. Give them a little. They will relish it, and the fact was that it made them t °ow, and they look slick and fine. Most of you will put up a silo - and feed ensilage and never lose a head. I have talked with a person who fed 800 head of cattle. He pays 50c a ton for the silage in the silo, and fed nothing but straw in connection with it. He gets his straw for $1.00 a ton, and he considers those a balanced ration for making beef. We feed no grain to cows besides what they get from the silo. I was advised to use something else besides the ensilage. Stock relish a little straw, it is good for them. I have alfalfa hay and give it twice a day, but not all that they want, and also feed it to horses. Wken in Germany I noticed that they fed horses just a little hand full of hay, and they were just as thrifty as they could be. A hired man will reach down and get all the hay he can lift and put it in the manger. The horses eat what they want and nose the rest back under their feet. As Americans I think we are wasteful, and so because we have so much of everything. As to the effect of ensilage upon my herd, some of you know that I had a sale of stock last fall and sold off some of my cows. There is not a person here who will say that those cows were not as thrifty as they could be. My calves were thrifty as they could be. A </seg>
            <seg id="p095">94 Nt'HRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION large crowd came to the sale. These cows brought on an average a handsome price. Their general appearance and thrift had much to do with it. t There is a point that I would like to call your attention to. If nil your eilo with cockleburrs and sunflowers mixed in, it will not e good silage. I am quite sure that the next year if you are wise will see that there are no burrs and sunflowers growing up with corn, and you will have your silo filled with a good quality of en- t Another advantage which appeals to me is, just as soon as lac is cut and taken off the field you can go to work and sow your wheat. In that way you have your corn ground clean without 1 labor, and soon you will have a crop growing instead of the nd being bare, If you don't want to sow wheat you can sow it to which makes a most splendid winter pasture, which you can plow r as a fertilizer for your soil if you wish. 1 did not wish to repeat the good things that may have been said about the silo, and this is about all that I can say, however I might speak of the cost of building the silo. The average farmer staggers at the figures. He figures he can put up a barn a great deal cheaper. It is the lack of means that prevents him. The same as when he does build he never builds large enough. We will suppose that a silo is built that costs {400.. I am not selling silos, but I believe from what I have seen that one of these silos will last twenty years, if you take care of it. That is the way I figure it myself, and if you can put up e silo for $400, and it lasts twenty years, then that silo has cost $20 a year. The question arises, can I afford, if I want to keep a lot of stock, and you can't keep stock without having a lot of feed, to do without that silo? IAs the farmer boys grow up they will have newer and perhaps r habits, and know how to go at it better than we. I feel certain will not have the cattle go out in the cornfield in the morning, out any disrespect, whatever, but I well remember my father to drive me away from the breakfast table to go and turn the out in the cornfield. I think I used to ask, "What for?" but I to go and turn those cows out to the straw and cornstalks. I say that one of my neighbors last year lost some very expensive by turning them out in the field to eat cornstalks. In regard to filling the silo— that is another big proposition. We used to think it was a terrible hard thing to have the threshers come around and thresh the grain in the fall, but lately we don't think so much about it. The threshing used to be a hard proposition for the women folks, they did not like it, nor we did not like it either. Rut we got accustomed to ii. I believe that the time will soon come, and perhaps quicker than we have any idea, when we will have greater facilities for doing farm work. I remember when we were filling our </seg>
            <seg id="p096">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 95 and says, "Isn't it a shame to see those good big ears of corn going into that silo — to spoil?" That Is what he thought about it, I could see that from his standpoin. He kept only a v ery limited amount of stock, and never kept a cow or pig around his place. What would be the result to our country if we all worked on that plan? Yet he told me his corn yielded 35 bushels to the acre. Well, it should have yielded twice that. I Another point that I might mention is, I hardly had time to fill silo the first year, and nobody wanted to help me, but last year e were some fifteen or twenty silos around in my neighborhood about two weeks before time to fill it they commenced calling me ind wanted to know if I wanted help to fill my silo. Just as soon here is a number of them in the neighborhood everybody will be ly to help, and some of them may be selling a silo cutter. The ; is coming when the man who has a threshing machine and engine own an ensilage cutter, and will go from farm to farm the same he threshing machine does today, and there will not be so much ible in filling the silo, and by having a silo and having an ensilage er the farmer will hare an immense amount of feed at an outlay of Ery small amount of money. There are many farmers, I might today, who use a shredder and feed shredded fodder instead of ige. I think this shredded fodder with ensilage would be the r way. tlf we expect to be able to clear from $1500 to $1800 a year on an ?re farm, we must practice something along the line of the above od, whereby we can keep a larger number of liVe stock. We can ase the fertility of the soil so that it will grow perhaps one - or one-half as much more grain, and can increase the income the farm exceedingly by judicious handling of a larger number ve stock. With land at such high prices, from $100 to $150 an acre, we must plan to employ more labor, and instead of expending from $100 to $500 a year for labor we should expend from $1,000 to $2,000. in other words an investment of $30,00 in land and $500 in labor is unreasonable in order to get the best results. By this course of farming there will be less trouble to give our boys employment at home, and when we have means to make an in - nent instead of making it in Texas or Canada, an aljacent of land can be purchased for the boys, and in that way they will soon learn to live nearer home. I believe this idea, if carried out, will cause the boys and girls of Nebraska to cherish the home and home surroundings, which will surely tend not only for their own good but as well to build up our own great state. By making home life pleas - ant and getting the boy interested in farm life, deeper interest in the production of pure and thoroughbred animals, and in the economical </seg>
            <seg id="p097">96 fluence toward building up farm life. Too many young men are leav - ing the farm for what seems to them an alluring life in th° city. Farm life, heretofore, hcs n&lt; t been as cheerful and inviting for the farmer's son. He should be given an interest in these things, and by making the home life and farm life attractive he will stay there, and will prac - tice farming in a much more thorough an 1 scientific manner than his forefathers. In this way our farms will become more productive, and our state will be built up and strengthened an 1 become foremost of all the agricultural states. In regard to the time for cutting corn to be used as silage, the proper time is Just about when it is usually cut for shocking. I thank you. (Applause.) The President: That was a splendid talk and I trust you all en - joyed it as much as 1 did. That is the sort of talk we want to hear. IMr. Wyman: Mr. President, I will say that I built a silo last I didn't have it quite finished when there came a hail storm, destroyed almost all my corn. We went to work and completed iilo, and put in the &lt; orn that was not destroyed by hail. I put it ■ in good shape. While it was not in the very best of shape I d it with cornmeal and gave the cattle a dose of it, and they were r for it afterwards. My neighbors never got anything from their crop, not even any fodder, the consequence was that they had to It at (16.00 a ton. This only goes to show the great benefits to be erived from having a solo. They told me I was foolish to put my away in that shape, but it proved otherwise. I The President: I would like to hear a little more in regard to ing of silage to horses. It must be good for them as well as for dairy cow. KA Member: — I have been an importer and breeder of horses, and I ensilage to horees, and to bogs and to cattle. I feed it to colts, feed it to brood mares, and I believe it to be the best feel yet if fed •ially. KI know of a farmer who undertook to fill his silo, and he put up corn too green and it became sour and reminded me of pickles, t incident caused a damper to be put upon the building of silos in community. Mr. Gierens: Mr. President, that reminds me that years and years ago they used cisterns, which they used as a sort of silo for grasses, alfalfa or clover, or any grass that had a solid etem. It was found that they could not use such grasses as had a hollow stem. This cistern was made to be air tight. They used to chop up these grasses, and it was kept a long time for future use. The use of silos for preserving grasses and plants for feeding is not a new principle. They used it many years ago. In 1882 there was something over ninety silos in the United State*, while today there are over 3,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 97 The use of the silo is becoming better known, and it is being more extensively used. The President: I was about to say that thirty years ago there was just one silo in Nebraska. I happened to know something about it, because I helped to fill it. They cut the corn too green, as often occurs, and it turned out more than 90 percent water. Tou can imagine what kind of ensilage that was. That was the kind of ensilage that was largely put up all over the country at that time where silos were in use. That had a tendency to demoralize business, ss it affected the value of the cream. You could smell that silage all over the place. You could detect that smell in the cream easily. You could detect it in the butter. It is no wonder that Gale Borden, manufacturer of condensed milk, absolutely refused to accept milk or cream that was produced by the use of that kind of ensilage. The only reason for that concern taking that attitude was because they got some of that milk. Within the last year or two they have taken that ban off the milk from silo fed cows, and are earnest advocates of the silo, and are now trying to get farmers and dairymen to furnish milk from silo fed cattle. A Member: It took me a long time to decide the advantages to be derived from the use of the cream-separator. I had to acknowledge it, and now I acknowledge that I am going to have a silo, as I believe it is the most profitable way of feeding dairy cattle for the economical production of milk and cream. I A Member: I think one of the greatest mistakes with farmers lie corn belt is that we have not enough cattle on our farms. I !ve the time is coming when we will be able to keep one hundred I of cattle on 160 acres of land, with the use of ensilage, alfalfa clover. I don't think the fact that a man has only six, or eignt or head of cows should stand in his way of erecting a silo, becaif.e the silo he could handle probably three times as many cows, and t with more economy. The President: Put in a silo and then get more cows, and stock, to feed the silage to. ■ Prof. French: My experience is that a farmer could keep twice number of cattle with a silo as he could without one. Prof. Bower: In regard to the palatability of ensilage, we can't measure its value, particularly in its good effects upon the digestible apparatus of the animal. It calls to my mint! what was said by a student who had been attending Cornell College, and thought he had some experience. He called on a Scotch farmer, who was feeding roots to his cows. I believe in Scotland that they fatten cattle on roots, chaff and straw. This young man said to the farmer, "What's the use of feeding these roots to your cows? They are over 90 percent water. Why don't you feed water entirely?" The Scotchman answered </seg>
            <seg id="p099">98 him thus, "Why, mon, I have been, but I have come to the conclusion that these make dam good water." 1A Member: In regard to the time of cutting the corn. I would that my idea of it is that about the time the stalks turn yellow jgt before frost comes. 1 want to add a little testimony as to the profit of the silo, as I think that one of the things we are interested in is to learn how to get the profit out of it. Last year I put up a silo. I had twenty head of cows, I had only 25 acres of pasture, and as most of you know, that is not enough to feed twenty head of cattle, and I had to have some pas - ture, but with the aid of the silage I fed the whole bunch of cattle very nicely. It was all due to the use of ensilage. This year when corn season came on I had a good field of it, say 34 acres. Early in July there came a few days of hot winds and took off a foot and a half of the top of my corn. It was in the tasselinr stage. 1 hardly think that corn would have produced more than 200 bushels for the whole 34 acres. What would I have done for feed had I not had a silo to put up that corn? To be sure I could have cut it up and fed it, but what would 1 have had at this time? At this time I have got, or did have when the silo was filled, in the neighborhood of 280 tons of ensilage made from a crop of fodder that would not have pro - duced at that time $75 or $80 worth. The profits to be derived from the use of the silo are immense. If I bad cut that corn up and put it on the market we will suppose it brought $80, but as it is I have got 280 tons of good ensilage feed worth somewhere about from $4 to $6 a ton, and 250 tons at $6 would be $1,500. I would say that my neighbor cut up his 80 acres of corn fodder, and he is now having the fun of hauling it in to the barn yard by wagon. Question: I would like to know what the average acre in this locality will produce in ensilage. Answer: Well. I bad 34 acres. I have approximately 280 tons and that figures out 8 tons to the acre, of ensilage made from corn without any corn on it. I The President: If there is nothing further we will have to brin? talk to a close pretty soon. I don't think this Association has spent a more profitable day than in the discussion of this subject, have had a large attendance, rni the interest shown has been trkably enthusiastic in the matter of silos. We thought we had [ day last year, but this year we have more people who have had l experience. I hate to bring this meeting to a close. We could on, and profitably so. until dark, but we have arranged for a cow ing contest, that will come off in a few minutes, and I don't feel lough we should linger here any longer. IThe cow judging contest will take place out here by the dairy inf. It is a contest that has been given by the Association every We line up ten cows, and every number of the Association has pportunity to judge the qualities of those cows. There is $150 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL.' CONVENTION 99 set aside by the Association as a prize for the winner in the contest. The President: There being no further business before this meeting, I hereby declare the same adjourned sine die. cow jiik;ix« contest. One of the most interesting features of the last annual meeting of the dairymen's association was the cow judging contest; this kind of a contest originated with the Nebraska dairymen's association In 1905, and has not only added much of interest to the annual meetings, but has proven most profitable as an educational feature. The ten rows used in this contest are without records for butter production and are cows sent from farms in the state to the state experiment station to be kept for one year in order to demonstrate what dairy cows on our farms can be made to produce when properly fed and cared for. For the purpose of this contest these cows are passed upon by an expert who places them in numerical order, the best cow No. 1, and the poorest cow, from the point of butter production No. 10; each cow is given a Jetter by which she is designated in the contest: her rank given by the expert and her letter is as follows: ten (10) points and a perfect score would be 100 points; if not cor - rectly placed deductions are made according to the following rule: for instance If the cow letter G were placed No. 1 credit would be given, for 9 points and if she were placed No. 5, credit would be given for 7 points: the minimum number of points to score in order to receive any portion of the pro rate fund it 75 points. In this contest a score of 75 counted one point above the minimum and was worth 24 cents; a score of 80 counted six points above the minimum and was worth $1.45; ninety took part in the contest of whom 85 per cent scored 75 or more points. In five of the aix contests which have been held the per cent of those who scored 75 or more points out of a posaible 100 points is as follows: 1905, 67 per cent; 1907, 68 per cent; 1908, 68 No. Letter N'o. Letter 1 C 6 ... H ==5 j ===: ! If a contestant places a cow as did the expert credit- is given for </seg>
            <seg id="p101">100 NEBRASKA DAIRYMK &lt;&gt;CIAT1O\ XAMKS OK OONTK8TAXT8 \M&gt; KfORK. Name Score Name Score Name Score Name Score Anderson. W. C, 84 Anderson. W. C, 84 Lindburg, E. S., 86 Lindburg, E. S., 86 Arnold. \V. A.. 78 Arnold. \V. A.. 78 Land, Clarence 68 Land, Clarence 68 Bartx, Carl 90 Barti, Carl 90 Larch, A. A Larch, A. A 74 Barber, Bert 74 Barber. Bert 74 Letters, O. H-, 78 Letters, O. H-. 78 Bigelow. A. R., 86 Bigelow. A. R., 86 L. Little 78 L. Little 78 Biba. Albert 74 Btba. Albert 74 Lantz, Ray 82 Lantz, Ray 82 Billiar, W. H. P., 90 Billiar, W. H. P., 90 McCarthy, Jas., 84 McCarthy, Jas., 84 Beach, 1. J., 82 Beach, 1. J., 82 Murray, A. A., 88 Murray, A. A., 88 Bower, John 78 Bower. John ., 78 Moner, V. N , Moner, V. N. 71 Beckboff, A. H., 66 Beckboff. A. H., 66 Maxfield, Don Maxneld, Don 72 Brinton, E. H., Brinton. E. H.. 72 Mathews, H. L., 80 Mathews, H. L., 80 Burgess. C. \V 80 Burgess. C. \\\, 80 Marshall, R. E Marshall, R. E., Buls. R. H., 78 Bull. R. H., 78 North, Carl 84 North, Carl 84 Coupe, H. A., 92 Coupe, H. A., 92 Nichols, C. L., 7" Nichols, C. L., n Carlson, Walter 76 Carlson. Walter 76 Oline. H. E., 90 Oline, H. E., 90 Carr. J. C, 86 Cary. J. C, 86 Posson, R. J., 86 Posson. R. J., 86 Cbilcoat 84 Chilcoat 84 Potter, W. S., 86 Potter, W. S., 86 Culver. V. S.. 76 Culver, V. S.. 76 Phillips, Geo. S 92 Phillips, Geo. S 92 Clarke, E. H.. 86 Pierce, J. H., 78 Clarke, E. H.. 86 Pierce, J. H., 78 Clark, P. J., 68 Clark, F. J., 68 Roberts, W. F., Roberts, W. F., Camp, B. H.. 72 Camp, B. H.. 72 Rolfers, Frank 86 Rolfers, Frank 86 Calkins, Harold 84 Calkins, Harold 84 Rueter, Henry 76 Rueter, Henry 76 Detwiler, Ray 86 Detwiler, Ray 86 Rees, W. H., 72 Rees, W. H., 72 Dinsmore. J. B., 78 Dinsmore. J. B.. 78 Renner, F. S., 82 Renner, F. S., 82 Delano, H. C, 82 Delano. H. C, 82 Rice, H. W., ...80 Rice, H. W., ...80 Rich, L. A.. 86 Evans, O. G., 78 Evans, O. G., 78 Rich, L. A.. 86 Fraley, Geo. C, 70 Fraley, Geo. C, 70 Rupert, W. J Rupert, W. J Fautch, H. R.. Fausch, H. R.. Stelk, W. D., 82 Stelk, W. D., 82 Gramllch, J. H., 80 Gramlich, J. H., 80 Schoenleber, L. R., 82 Schoenleber, L. R., 82 Gross, Frank Gross, Frank 70 Sneddon, J., 82 Sneddon, J., 82 Gunerud, L., 80 Gunerud, L.. 80 Rvec, F. A., 78 Rvec, F. A., 78 Geary, R. B ...80 Schulte. C. J., 86 Geary, R. B ...80 Schulte. C. J., 86 Griffis, J. C... Griffis. J. C. Stubbe, Henry, 82 Stubbe, Henry, 82 Gierens, T. A., Gierens, T. A 82 Squire?, D. H., Squire?, D. H., Giberson. R. H., Giberson, R. H., Taylor, L. R.. 74 Taylor, L. R.. 74 Gross; Wm.. 82 Gross; Wm.. 82 Thorns. George 80 Thorns. Oeorge 80 Kjar, Albert KJar, Albert Tupper, Oscar 80 Tupper, Oscar 80 Huston, H. E . 84 Vogel, Carl 68 Vogel, Carl 68 Huston. H. E .. Wilkenson, H. J.. 86 Hanson. L. F.. 78 Hanson, L. F , 78 Wilkenson, H. J.. 86 Holding. T. L 82 Holding. T. L . 82 Wilger, A. W Wilger, A. W Huntley. J. E.. 86 Huntley. J. E.. 86 Warner, K. F., 80 Warner, K. F., 80 Wentz, Lawrence Hagenow, A. M., 82 Hagenow, A. M., 82 Wentz, Lawrence 78 Witt, Bernhard 88 Witt, Bernhard 88 Krumhaer, H., 82 Krumhaer, H 82 Young, H. C, 84 Young, H. C, 84 Kuska, J. B., 76 Kuska, J. B.. 76 Lawridsen, H., 80 Lawridsen, H., ... 80 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">TWENTY-SIXTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 101 List of Licensed Creameries and Cheese Factories In Nebraska— 1011, Alamito Sanitary Creamery Omaha Adams Center Creamery Archer Arcadia Co-operative Creamery Co _ Arcadia Alliance Creamery &amp; Produce Co Alliance Alderman Creamery Co Deweese Beatrice Creamery Co Lincoln Chapman Co-operative Creamery Co Chapman Carleton Creamery Co Carleton Columbus Creamery Co Columbus Clarinda Poultry, Butter and Egg Co Lincoln Crab Orchard Creamery Co Crab Orchard Comstock Co-operative Creamery Co Comstock Coyner Silas C Keystone Cadams Creamery Co Cadams David Cole Creamery Co Omaha Franklin Creamery Co Kranklin Fontanelle Creamery Co Fontanelle Fairmont Creamery Co Omaha Fairmont Creamery Co Crete Fairmont Creamery Co Grand Island Frost and Cox DUnay Farmer's Co-operative Creamery and Supply Co Omaha Farmer's Creamery Co Burton Golden Rod Creamery Fremont Germantown Co-operative Creamery Aes'n Germantown Geneva Ice Cream Manufacturing Co Geneva Henningsen Produce Co Superior Hermes P. H Falls City Kirschbraum &amp; Sons (Incorporated) Omaha Lexington Creamery and Cold Storage Co Lexington Lyons Creamery Co Lyons Loup Valley Co-operative Creamery Association Dannebrog Lincoln Pure Butter Co Lincoln McGinnis Creamery Co O'neil McGinnis Creamery Co Amelia Norfolk Ice Cream And Cone Co. (Butter) Norfolk North Loup Co-operative Creamery Ass'n North Loup Nebraska Cream Co Central City Omaha Cold Storage Co Omaha Orleans Creamery Co Orleans Pierce Creamery Pierce Pleasant Dale Creamery Fremont Ravenna Creamery Ravenna Ravenna Creamery Loup City Ravenna Creamery Ord River ton Creamery Co Rivertofl </seg>
            <seg id="p103">102 St. Libory Creamery Association St Libory Switzer Creamery Co Newman Grove Spring Creek Creamery Co Leigh The Kearney Creamery Co ,. Kearney The Hygenic Dairy Fairbury Webb A. F Valentine Waterloo Creamery Co Omaha Wayne Butter Co Wayne Wat Point Butter and Creamery Co West Point (Note— A creamery known as the West Point Creamery Co. was established at West Point in 1877 and believed to be the first creamery established in Nebraska. John J. King was manager. A silo was also built, probably the first silo erected in the state.) </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>