<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA PART ONE, PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR FEBRUARY 1, 1905</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">EIGHTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT r tbi Agricultural Experiment Station JK XKBRASKA PAKT ONE Presented to the Governor February 1, 1905 </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Stat The University of Nebraska. Sir — In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the general assembly of the State of Nebraska approved March 81, 1887, establishing ind regulating experiment stations, I have the honor here - 'ith to submit the Eighteenth Annual Report of the raska Agricultural Experiment Station. E. A. Burnett, The University of Nebraska, February 1, 1905. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE. State of Nebraska, Executive Department, Lincoln, February 1, 1905. .)//•. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Aij station: Sir — I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Eighteenth Annual Report of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Statiou. John H. Mickey, 7b Hit Excellency, J. if. Mich </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVE] I JOHN L. Teeters, Lincoln, President .Term expires 1906 Edson P. Rich, Omaha Term expin Elisha C. Calkins, Kearney Term expir. Carl J. Ernst, Omaha Term expires 1908 Charles S. Allen, Lincoln. . ..Term expir- William G. Whitmore, Valley Term expires 1910 Dales, Lincoln, Financial Secretary THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE John L. Teeters E. Benjamin Andrews E. a. Burn THE VISITING COMMITTEI Z £ ?E£S, B^wSffie -The BUt. Board of Agriculture E. F. Stephens, Crete The State Horticultural Society THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. Burnett, B. Sc — T. L. Lyon, Hh. D Wm. W. Marshall THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith. B. Sc Animal Husbandman A. T. Press, D. V. M Pathologist kry. Ph. D Chemia A. L. R, B. Sc. A Dairy Hi Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc E E. H. Barbour, Ph. D Qm\*§ut Emerson, B. Sc II' P. Stout, C. E.. Irrigatio G. D. Swezky, MA J. H. Gain, M. D. C Ami W. P. Snydek. M. s S. W. I*erin Farm Ft/reman *By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska approved and in effect February 1"&gt;. 1899, the State Treasurer became ex officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">EXPERIMENTAL WORK. Ework of the Experiment Station has been in oper - under its present organization for the past eighteen During the earlier years it had little assistance from the State, but in more recent times the Station has profited largely by the cooperation of the University staff and by State appropriations. Feeling that a review of some of the results of experimental work carried on by this Station since its organization may be of interest, I submit a brief report of some lines of investigation which have had a marked in - fluence in shaping agricultural intelligence and practice in Our Station, early in its organization, conducted experi - ments to foster the sugar beet industry. Before any factories were built, the Station proved the adaptability of our soil and climate to beet raising. The results of these experiments were important factors in the establishment of three beet sugar factories. Since that time the Station has by its experiments confirmed the results of other stations Kthe adaptability of alkali soils to beet growing and has ed on experiments indicating that beet seed may be d in this State, but has not succeeded in producing seed a commercial scale. This Station has been of service in pointing out the best annual forage crops and in determining the amounts of feed produced by each. The value of sorghum as a forage crop in this State was early established by this Station. The winter wheat growing area of the State has been largely extended through the efforts of this Station. In 1900, the seed of hardy strains of Turkish Red and Big </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 Nebraska and in southwestern Nebraska west of the 100th meridian. Reports have been collected from year to year and published. These experiments proved that the two varieties of wheat mentioned were almost universally successful where tests were made under reasonably good conditions. The increase in winter wheat production of 10,000,000 bushels per year in this State since these ex - periments were undertaken has. we believe, been largely due to the results secured from these experiments. In cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture a large acreage of macaroni or durum wheat has been grown in central and western Nebraska with quite uniform success. These experiments indicate that the growing of macaroni wheat on farms which produce grain in western Nebraska will prove profitable. This Station some years ago commenced experiments with brome grass (/•'. miiis) and distributed consider - able quantities of this seed for the United States Depart - ment of Agriculture. The results of these tests have shown that brome grass is a valuable pasture grass in nearly all portions of the State. More recent experiments indicate that fall seeding upon a well prepared seed bed furnishes the best conditions for securing a stand in central and east - ern Nebraska. The Kherson oat, a variety imported by the Station from the province of Kherson in Russia in 1897, has been shown by experiments during the last four years in cooperation with several hundred farmers to yield an average of several bushels per acre more than any other variety grown in central or western Nebraska. The only variety which will yield within ten bushels per acre of the Kherson is the Texas Red, the color of which is objectionable for market. Extensive experiments with corn undertaken by this Station to secure varieties adapted to the different localities of the State and to secure seed of the proper character, have resulted in a very largely increased interest in the growing of corn with increased yields. Among the most progressive farmers the practice of the methods advocated by this Station has resulted in increasing the yield as much as ten </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 bushels per acre It is not too much to say that a continu - ation of this process of education will result in an average increase of five bushels per acre throughout tl This will mean approximately '00 bushels of corn, worth $10,000,000, every year to the farmers of the S Experiments'undertaken at this Station to determine what methods will best maintain and increase the humus in the soil indicate that increased production is secured and greatly increased profit in the operation of land results from the application of manure at regular intervals and the placing of farms under a rotation in which grass shall form one of the important ctods. Laying land down to grass for a series of years has resulted in securing profitable returns from the land while in meadow or pasture, and h;i creased the yield of corn from I I per cent above the yield secured on land continuously cropped with corn or other grains without manur This Station has demonstrated that apple scab can bf trolled almost perfectly by the use of two sprayings with, Bordeaux mixture. This is in line with experiment many other States. The fruit growers of the State, how - ever, have been slow to adopt proper methods of spraying to hold this disease in check. The results of the Station's work as exhibited at the summer meetings of the Horticul - tural Society and at the State Fair have attracted wide at - tention and must surely result in the production of better fruit This Station has shown that cedar rust of apple trees, a serious disease of certain varieties of apples, for instance such excellent varieties as the Wealthy and Jonathan, can be controlled by spraying with Bordeaux mixture in spring at the time the cedar apples on cedar trees are becoming E" sous and orange-colored. This is of practical import - since some of 'our horticulturists are advocating the al of cedar trees near orchards containing susceptible ies of apples. Eie Station, by tests carried on fora number of years, shown quite conclusively that cover-crops are of great e in making more hardy such trees as peaches, Japan </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 plums, etc., which'have a tendency to grow too late in the fall. A cover-crop, such as oats, millet, or sorghum, is sown about August 1st in a soil 'which has previously been thoroughly tilled and consequently contains sufficient mois- Ere to germinate the seed. The cover-crop, by drying the rface soil, checks the growth of the tree and causes it to iture its wood earlier in the fall. It has also been shown that cover-crops aid materially iu preventing injury to the roots of trees during severe winters by protecting the ground from freezing and by holding snow against drifting winds. Experiments in mulching garden vegetables have shown that a straw mulch increases the yield of certain vegetable crops like cabbage, tomatoes, beans, cucumbers, and potatoes over yields which would be secured only by the most intensive methods of tillage. The quality of the prod - uct is also improved, especially with tomatoes and cucumbers. With potatoes the quality of the product is likely to deteriorate. With most vegetables the necessary labor required in growing with a mulch is less than that re - quired to produce them by cultivation. Where mulching is practiced, nearly all the work can be done before the middle of June, the vegetables requiring absolutely no care during the busiest and driest part of the summer, when farm gardens are usually neglected. Prom a study of the forests and forest trees of the State the Station many years ago began to urgu the planting of trees on the sand hills, resulting in the establishment at the present time of two large Government reserves on which trees are now being successfully planted. A study of the grasses and other native vegetation of the State, commenced many years ago, resulted in the Station advocating the introduction of clover and alfalfa, which are now common forage crops. Eich careful study has been given to the soft rot of the r beet, original investigations concerning which are rted in the Seventeenth Annual Report. This Station has conducted experiments in the extermina - tion of prairie dogs and has found that light hydrocarbon </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 by-products of Pintsch gas, which costs seven cents per gallon, will take the place of bisulphide of carbon, which costs the farmers about "ill. 10 per gallon. The experiments described in Bulletin No. 86 will result in reclaiming for grazing and meadow land many of the best valleys in sec - tions of the State which are now infested with prairie dogs. This Station was the first in America to discover the cause of the killing of cattle by sorghum when allowed to pasture upon it. many cattle having died from eating green sorghum which contained prussic acid in poisonous quantities. (Bulletin 77.) Further experiments proved that this sorghum, which was poisonous in its green state, became harmless after being cut and cured for hay. As the result of these experiments, the growth of sorghum, which was being discontinued by many farmers in the western part of the State, has again been taken up and the amount of available forage for cattle in the range country is thereby ereatly increased. In 1899 the Station was requested to investigate a peculiar disease in Boyd County which caused many animals to lose their hair and hoofs. This disease was so extensive in that county that it threatened to annihilate the stock raising in - dustry. After careful investigation the Station found that a peculiar fungus growing on the corn and other forage produced this disease, the symptoms being similar to those produced by ergot. The disease was remedied by the soaking and washing of the corn or by carefully sorting out the ears which were affected and destroying them. This investigation enabled the farmers to suppress the disease, saving large sums of money for that county and enabling the farming industry to prosper where before land was be - ing sold at a sacrifice, many farmers being discouraged at the prospect. Eie disease known as calf cholera, which was formerly alent in many sections of the State, has been very ely suppressed through the application of disinfectants he navel of the newborn calf and the removal of the lg calf from infected quarters. The use of a very thick </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 sugar syrup has been effective where other disinfectants could not be conveniently secured. This Station was one of the first to demonstrate the success of treating milk fever by inflating the udder with air. This treatment is now commonly used and is success - ful in saving 95 per cent of the cases treated where formerly very few cases recovered. K'or the past four months the Station has been using the owing prescription to destroy disease-producing bacteria : ce one cake of either compressed or dried yeast, add enough water to moisten the same ; then allow it to stand at least twelve hours, or preferably twenty-four hours. To this is then added a pint to a pint and a half of lukewarm water. This is used as the cleansing fluid. This treatment -pecially promising in case of cows suffering from abortion. The animal to be disinfected is first washed out with lukewarm water, and after being thoroughly cleansed the disinfecting fluid is applied. The same method is pur - sued iu the bull. This treatment is being tried on barren cows also. Knowing that the vagina of barren cows is ex - ceedingly acid, it is hoped to overcome this acidity by re - peated injections of fermented yeast germs before service. In 1894 the Station ascertained by circular letter to what extent blackleg existed in the State. The figures showed an annual loss of about 17 per cent in the range country. In the spring of 1895 efforts were made through the agri - cultural press to enlighten the farmers and stockmen on this disease, and a bulletin was published on this subject. The Station advocated that stockmen vaccinate their cattle. This Station became the distributing agent for the Bureau of Animal Industry, sending out hundreds of thousands of doses of vaccine annually to the stockmen free of charge. In 1901 inquiry revealed the fact that the loss from this disease was reduced in our State to about one per cent. To - day all intelligent stockmen insure their cattle against blackleg by vaccination. Feeding experiments with different rations have proven the economic value of alfalfa and highly protein foods when fed with corn. Experiments at this Station have </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 shown 110 pounds greater gains on yearling steers ii months where alfalfa was fed than where the same grain ration was fed with prairie hay. This different attributed to the greater amount of protein in the alfalfa hay. Other experiments have shown a difference" of 100 pounds greater gain on steers when 10 per cent oil-meal was added to the corn ration, the steers receiving prairie hay for roughness. This experiment again indicates that th creased gains were due to the protein supplied by the oil-meal, corn and prairie hay not furnishing a sufficient amount of protein to secure the largest or the most economical j_ r In both these instances the selling price of the cattle was also increased at least 25 cents per hundred through the superior condition of the cattle when mark' upon prairie hay and corn produced practically no profit, while similar steers fed upon a better balanced ration pro - duced a profit of nearly $8 per head. Experiments at this Station also indicate that oil-meal or cottonseed-meal can profitably be fed with corn to steers which are being fattened on pasture. Steers receiving ground corn on pasture made a gain of 348 pounds per steer in six months, and when ten pounds of oil-meal was fed with ninety pounds of corn the gain was increased to 433 pounds pi The cost of gains with corn alone was 13 per cent greater than with corn and oil-meal. With corn at 33 cents per bushel the steers paid $44 per ton for the oil-meal consumed. Experiments in feeding alfalfa hay to hogs in winter in connection with a grain ration have proven that the cost of pork production by this method can be considerably re - duced and this practice is being followed by a large pro - portion of the pork producers in the State. Experiments in feeding alfalfa hay in comparison with prairie hay or sorghum hay to lambs with corn as a grain ration have shown a gain at least 50 per cent greater where alfalfa hay was fed. £etins have been published dealing with the feeding of on the by-product skim-milk. From such data the raisers of the State have been given a simple but </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 dollars by raising calves upon skim-milk rather than allow - ing them to suck the cow. This method, when commonly practiced, will very greatly develop the dairy interests of the State. Hand separator dairying has been encouraged by the Station, and its success in the State is well shown by the wonderful progress made in cream production and cream separator dairying. Since the establishment of a Dairy De - partment at the Experiment Station, which covers a period of only six years, the State has advanced from twentieth place in the Union to tenth place, as a dairy State. The farmers now receive twice as much money for their dairy products as they did six years ago. During this period over 18,000 hand separators have been purchased by farmers, and the number of cows used for dairy purposes ha» increased about 200,000. The lines of investigation to control insect pests have in - dicated that bird protection is essential to prevent serious ravages from insects. The Station has sent out upwards of 2,000 leaflets on bird protection, indicating what birds should be protected and how these birds prevent insect ravages. A bulletin has also been published on the Hessian fly, advocating the destruction of stubble and all rubbish on the fields which will harbor the young brood. This bulletin also advocates the late sowing of wheat on lands which have been thoroughly cultivated to retain mois - ture and produce a perfect seed bed. All volunteer wheat, rye, and barley should be destroyed before the wheat crop is sown, so that these shall not furnish a breeding place for the fall brood. Experiments have been carried on in cooDeration with the United States Department of Agriculture to determine the duty of water in the several irrigable sections, the nature and amount of loss of water in transportation through canals and laterals, and the available natural water supply of the country. COOPERATIVE EXPERIMENTS. With the United States Department of Agriculture in plant breeding to improve the strain of wheat for this </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 region; in testing forage'plants and garden vegetables; in the study of plant diseases affecting general farm crops, garden vegetables, fruits, and fruit trees; in the distribution of blackleg vaccine. Bh 1700 farmers in the growing of winter and durum s, oats, soy beans, and corn. PROPOSED EXPERIMENTS. Et is hoped to extend the experiments in crop rotation to ermine methods by which we may increase the humus in soil. Experiments in drainage should be conducted on soils that dry out badly on account of their compact structure. Experiments are in progress in the crossing of two stand - ard varieties of corn in an effort to produce a variety that can readily be molded to suit the needs of different localities in central and western Nebraska. Experiments should also be undertaken to study the adaptability to this State of different varieties of corn which are most successful in States farther e; It is proposed to continue the study of heredity in plants, with the idea of getting a clearer insight into the principles of improvement. The plant which has been the object of most study at this Station is the common bean. Careful records are kept of the principal characters of certain parent varieties and of the hybrids obtained by crossing these varieties. The characters of the parents and the combination characters, or the new characters which are found in hybrids, are traced through several generations. Some work is being done along the same line with the summer squash. Work is in progress to produce improved varieties of fruits and varieties better adapted to our climatic con - ditions. The apple, peach, cherry, raspberry, and straw - berry are receiving special attention. E:periments are in progress to secure a hardier stock for cherry and plum; also to study hardy ornamental »rs, shrubs, and trees. Experiments are contemplated to study the effect of late fall and early winter irrigation upon orchards and small </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Sits. If funds can be secured it is the purpose of the tion to make extensive investigations of the disease of rry trees which has caused widespread loss in Nebraska, the crown gall, the rusts of wheat and oats, and the &gt;ases of the cottonwood tree. I is proposed to test the efficiency of copper salt in ying reservoir waters and the waters in water tanks, utral solution of copper salt has been prepared for this tigation which it is believed can be used by the ordi - farmer under the instruction of the Station. ■ are preparing to make an exhaustive study of the istry of the lime and sulphur dip. It is proposed to make an extensive study of the influence of the yeast plant in destroying bacteria and cleansing animal wounds; also to study the intestinal diseases of sheep and of horses, and the effect of feeding a balanced ration on the strength of bone in the hog. periments are in progess to determine whether it is profitable to purchase protein feeds like oil-meal to balance the ration in feeding steers; also whether roughage with a high protein content is a satisfactory substitute for protein furnished in the grain ration. Bulletin 85 reports progress on this subject. There is urgent necessity for data concerning the average production of butter per cow by the farmers' herds in different sections of the State. It is proposed to send an agent to make accurate tests of the production of average herds of cows to secure information on this subject. There is also urgent need for experiment! to determine the life history of the Hessian fly, the grain aphis, the ox warble, the codling-moth, the apple curculio, the melon louse, the cankerworms and budworms in order to determine what remedies will be effective in destroying these p« Eich of this new work will be contingent upon the ability of largely increased appropriations for Station Be legislature of 1903 appropriated $15,000 for the lishment of a substation west of the 100th meridian in THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 Nebraska. The site for this Station was finally selected and came into possession of the Regents in March, 1904. Nineteen hundred and twenty acres was secured four miles south of North Platte, consisting of bench land, table-land, and rough pasture land, and furnishing an admirable location for the carrying on of experimental work. The peot)le of North Platte subscribed about $8,000 to the pur - chase price of this Station and left available to the Regents about $6,000 of the original appropriation to equip and oper - ate the Station for the year 1',h&gt;4. About $850 was expended for tools and implements, $1,000 for teams and harnesses, $600 for cattle and swine to be used for experimental pur - poses, and about $800 for fences, buildings, and repairs, the balance of the fund being expended for labor in growing and harvesting crops and in th° general improvements of the During the present winter fifty head of calves have been purchased as the basis for a breeding herd of cattle which Cill be maintained on the farm in connection with pasture id feeding experiments. t There are also on the farm at present 100 head of hogs hich are being used for breeding and experimental pur - jses. Experiments were carried on during the past summer to termine the influence of dehorning steers upon their growth the following summer. On March 31, 1904, 150 two - year-old steers were carefully selected and divided, and 75 of this number were dehorned with a saw, their weights being taken before dehorning. Weights were also secured one month after dehorning, on May 1. All the ■ showed a loss during the month of April. They were placed on pasture the second day of May and remained there until December 1. The steers which had not been dehorned showed a gain from May 2 to December 1 of 266 pounds per head. Those which were dehorned on March 31 showed a gain of 253 pounds, or a gain of 13 pounds per head by the horned steers over the dehorned steers. These steers had run together during the summer, having ample range of about ten acres per steer with an abundance of salt and water. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 Ee the number of steers employed is relatively large, results ought to be considered very accurate for a experiment. An experiment was undertaken with pigs to determine the relative amount of corn which can profitably be fed to grow - ing pigs while on alfalfa pasture. There were three lots of pigs with 17 pigs in each lot; average weight at the begin - ning, 52 pounds; number of days in the experiment, 91. Lot 1, with 2i pounds of corn daily per 100 pounds of live weight, made an average gain of 48 pounds in 91 days, and a daily gain of 55-100 pound per pig. »Lot 2, with 1$ pounds of corn daily per 100 pounds of live eight, made an average gain of 36 pounds in 91 days, and daily gain of 40-100 pound per pig. Lot 8, with pound of corn daily per 100 pounds of live weight, made an average gain of 27 pounds in 91 days, and a daily gain of 30-100 pound per pig. In this experiment it required 326 pounds of corn to pro - duce 100 pounds of gain in Lot 1, 207 pounds of corn to pro - duce 100 pounds of gain in Lot 2, and 108 pounds of corn to produce 100 pounds of gain in Lot 8. It will be seen, how - ever, that the gains on Lot 3 were so small that this method of feeding young pigs is not likely to be profitable. P yearling sows, averaging 194 pounds each, were put alfa pasture with no grain, on August 20, shortly after ng their litters, and continued for 63 days on pasture at grain. At the end of this period they weighed 221 is, showing an average gain of 43-100 pound per day. In testing varieties of oats, local grown oats produced 29 bushels per acre, 60-day oats 48 bushels per acre, and Kherson oats 48 bushels per acre. Experiments with emmer on the table gave a yield of 36 bushels per acre after one-fourth loss by hail. Ex - periments with barley gave a yield as follows: Local barley, seeded at the rate of 2 bushels per acre, yielded 41 bushels; Telli, seeded at the rate of 1£ bushels, gave a yield of 334 bushels; Beldi, seeded at the rate of 1£ bushels, gave a yield of 33 bushels per acre. The barley suffered sev from a hailstorm while standing in the shock. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 Psts with local and macaroni wheat, four varieties of mi wheats gave yields varying from 16$ to 22^ 3 per acre. Black Don producing 21f, Velvet Don pro - 22£. The local varieties of spring wheat grown equally good conditions produced only &amp;} bushels per LThe Substation farm is still onlj partially equipped with ols, teams, and live stock necessary to carry on experi - mental work, and is practically without buildings for this purpose. The further equipment and maintenance of this Station, if it is to be carried on, must be supplied by legis - lative appropriation. STATION STAFF. Bbere have been no changes in the Station staff during past year except the promotion of Mr. W. P. Snyder to position of Superintendent of the Substation at North ;te. IMPROVEMENTS. During the past year no new buildings have been con - structed, but the Dairy Barn, constructed during the pre - ceding year, and the greenhouses in the Horticultural Build - ing, constructed at the same time, have been available for use. The School of Agriculture building, which will house the offices of the Experiment Station, will soon be com- farmers' institutes. Ten members of the Station staff have assisted in Farmers' Institutes during the past year. Ninety-two Insti - tutes were held, with 330 sessions and a total attendance of 26,000 people. Institutes were held in 57 counties. The addresses at these meetings have furnished a means of disseminating the results of experimental work among the people and an opportunity for the Station men to become acquainted with the needs of the farmer. Six thousand dollars per year are appropriated from University funds in support of the Farmers' Institutes. Various agricultural societies meet with the University each year, including the State Board of Agriculture, State </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Horticultural Society, State Dairymen's Association, State Live Stock Breeders' Association, State Swine Breeders' Association, State Veterinary Medical Association, State Poultry Association, Duroc-Jesey Swine Breeders' Associ - ation, and this year the National Duroc- Jersey Swine Breeders' Association. About "2,000 people were in attend - ance at these meetings between January 16th and 20th in - clusive. PUBLICATIONS To accommodate the mailing list, bulletins are now pub - lished in editions of 22,000, which edition is becoming too small to meet the demands of the people. The Annual Re - port, containing the financial statement and some of the more technical experimental work of the departments, is published in an edition of 2,500 copies. The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Seventeenth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February 1, 1904. Bulletin No. 82 (Vol. XVI, Art. III). Kherson Oats. By T. L. Lyon. Distributed March 7, 1904. Bulletin No. 83 (Vol. XVI, Art. IV). Cooperative Variety Tests of Corn in 1902 and 1903. By T. L. Lvon. Dis - tributed April 21, IS Bulletin No. 84 (Vol. XVI, Art. V). Pasture, Meadow, and Forage Crops. (Cooperative Experiments with the United States Department of Agriculture.) By T. L. Lyon and A. S. Hitchcock. Distributed June 1, 1904. Eletin No. *5 (Vol. XVII, Art. I). Feeding Experi - with Cattle. By E. A. Burnett and H. R. Smith, buted October 11, 1904. Ketin No. 86 (Vol. XVII, Art. II). Destroying Prairie By A. T. Peters and S. Avery. Distributed October ►4. • Press Bulletin No. 19. The Hessian Fly. By Lawrence Bruner. Distributed September 12, 1904. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">E3ss Bulletin No. 20. Fattening Pigs and Wintering d Sows on Alfalfa and a Grain Ration. By 1 ett and H. R. Smith. Distributed September 12, I ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. E various railroads of the Scate have furnished con - &gt;le transportation to assist in carrying on experi - work located outside of Lincoln. Re agricultural press, especially those papers located in the State, have shown their appreciation of the work e Experiment Station by giving a liberal amount of space to the experimental work reported, and in every way facilitating and extending the usefulness of the Experiment </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF FINANCIAL SECRETARY RECEIPTS ■ived by the State Treasurer from the Treasurer •he United States appropriation for fiscal year ling June 30. 1904, as per act of I ap- March 2. 1*87 $15,000 00 Publications. &lt;\ge and stationery d express. plies Seeds, plants, and sundry supplies -tuffs. - . implements, and machinery Furniture and fixtures •ific apparatus Traveling ex\f Buildings and repairs. Total $15,000 00 $16J J. s. Da liary. SUPPLEMENTARY STATt Receipts from other sources than the United States and disl&gt; ments of same. RECEIPTS Balance July 31, 1904 $ 783 93 Received for the year ending July 31, 1904 6,753 83 DISBIRSEMEXTS $372 Of, Labor 996 91 Publications 90 50 Postage and stationery fit and express aoo B lical supplies Seeds, plants and sundry supplies. Feeding stuffs "•«» •»* j Tools, implements and machinery Furniture and fixtures Scientific apparatus . . Live stock Traveling expenses. . . Buildings and repairs Balance July 31. 1904 J. S. Dales, EXPENDITURES 666 M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>