<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Some Factors Affecting the Cost of Milk Production</title>
               <date value="1919-06">1919-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1919 Extension Bulletin 55 June, Some Factors Affecting the Cost of Milk Production W. B. XEVKX8 EFFICIENT COWS ARK AX IMPORTANT FACTOR IN ECONOMICAL MILK PRODUCTION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE 2 &lt; SUMMARY In this bulletin some of the more important factors affecting the cost of milk and butterfat production are discussed briefly and more efficient methods of production are suggested. Cows of equal size require approximately the same amount of feed for maintenance. The value of the product of many low - producing cows barely pays for the feed consumed, hut as the scale of production rises returns above feed cost increase many times. Feed forms from 50 to 70 per cent of the total cost of milk production. Improved methods of feeding and the raising of feeds suitable for the ration when this is practicable help reduce the expense of production. Labor constitutes the second largest item in the cost of milk production and is influenced by convenience of the stable ar - rangements, distance from market, cleanliness of the milk pro - duced and the use of mechanical milkers. Small herds are especially suited to general farms in Ne - braska, since they may be fed largely on unmarketable feeds anil surplus roughage and cared for by family labor, but in whole - milk sections the larger herds may be more profitable. A larger amount of feed anil labor is required in the winter months than during the summer season. Holstein cows produce milk more efficiently than either Guernseys or Jerseys, but in economy of butterfat production conditions are reversed. Large cows eat and produce niDre than small cows and are more efficient producers. Young cows do not yield so great a quantity of product a mature cows. Cows produce milk and butterfat most efficiently during tht first part of the lactation period. High values obtained for calves, and manure reduce the cos of producing milk and butterfat. i i </seg>
            <seg id="p003">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION Some Factors Affecting the Cost of Milk Production By W. B. NEVENS, Assistant Professor of Dairy Husbandry Extreme and rapid changes in the prices of farm products during the past few years have caused a demand for authorita - tive information concerning the costs of production. Extensive surveys and researches have been made and the results of the work published. From a study of such investigations an attempt has been made to deduce some truths which will apply in a gen - eral way to dairy conditions in Nebraska, with the object of pointing out some ways in which milk and butterfat may be produced more efficiently. It is not expected that application of all the suggestions given can be made to all farms on which milk is produced, on account of the wide range of conditions under which dairying is carried on. The bulk of the dairy products in Nebraska are pro - duced on diversified farms by herds ranging in size from three to ten cows, the product being marketed mainly as cream for buttermaking. In the eastern part of the State proximity to whole-milk markets makes more intensive dairying possible. HIGH PRODUCING COWS MOST EFFICIENT When a study is made of the production of dairy cows one of the striking features observed is that the amount of product yielded for each unit of feed consumed is much greater in the •"se of cows producing large amounts of milk or butterfat than with cows producing small amounts. Within reasonable limits the greater the production of the cows the greater the efficiency with which milk and butterfat are produced from the stand - point of amount of feed eaten. Cows of e(iual size require practically equal amounts of feel for maintenance, but with low producing cows a much larger proportion of the feed eaten is used for maintenance of the body than in the ease of high producing cows. Investigations with the object of determining the nutrient requirements for milk production were «carried on for nine winters by T. L. Haecker of the Minnesota station. It was found that 46.5 per ?ent of the feed eaten by the cows in the experiments was used for body maintenance. These cows were of good dairy type </seg>
            <seg id="p004">NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE 4 and produced daily as an average about 25 pounds of milk test - ing 4 per cent fat. Twenty-nine and one-tenth per cent of the total digestible nutrients in the feed was returned in the milk, leaving 70.9 per cent of the nutrients which was expended for maintenance and as energy for the production of milk. 1 SO /OO /SO 2OO JSO 300 Fl*. 1. INCREASED BUTTERFAT PRODUCTION MEANS INCREASED PROFITS The chart illustrates the steady and rapid rise in income over cost of feed in the case of cows producing increasingly greater amounts of butterfat annually. It is apparent that a production of less than 100 pounds of butterfat would fail to pay for the feed consumed. (From U. S. D. A. 1917 Year Book.) - The feed bill which the dairyman has to pay each year simply to keep his animals in normal condition is a tremendous one. The total feed cost, however, does not vary in direct pro - portion to the amount of milk produced for the reason just stated, namely, that an efficient cow uses a smaller proportion of her feed for maintenance, while there is little difference in the economy of production after maintenance is deducted. There - fore, the greater the production of milk by an individual cow the smaller the amount of feed expended for body maintenance for each pound of milk produced. In a study of the records of forty cow testing association! in various parts of the United States, McDowell tabulated thf 2SO 300 SX&gt; 4KK? +SO JBt? </seg>
            <seg id="p005">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION records of 5,587 cows, this number including all the cows which were on test for the entire year and whose breed and age were given. He found that as the annual production of butterfat in - creased, the income over cost of feed became very much greater. As butterfat production increased from 150 pounds to 300 pounds, or doubled, the income over cost of feed was trebled Considering the cows producing 150 pounds and those produc - ing 450 pounds of fat, or one group yielding three times as much as the other, the income over feed was five times as great for the cows yielding 450 pounds as for those yielding only 150 pounds. McDowell says: "A further study of the records showed that the cost of roughage was about the same for all groups, regardless of pro - duction. The cost of grain was considerably higher for the more productive cows than for the low producers, but it was much lower per pound of butterfat. The increased income, therefore, tho it should be credited in part to better feeding, was evidently more largely due to better cows." 2 Figure 1 was prepared from the tabulation of one year's records of the 5,587 cows mentioned above, and shows graphi - cally the relation between yearly production of butterfat and income over cost of feed. Thee cows are all purebred Holsteins rnd ar.' owned by the University of Nebraska. The average production of the com in this group during a 365 day period is 17.200. 9 pounds of milk containing 637.67 pounds of butterfat. According to the thirteenth crsus the average production of the milch cows in the United States in 1909 was 362 wllons, or 3.113 pounds of milk per cow. The amount of butterfat in this milk is not stated but it would probably approximate 125 pounds per cow. FEED THE LARGEST COST ITEM The largest single item in milk production is the cost of feed. Under normal conditions the cost of feed forms from 50 to 70 per cent of the total expense. Flit. t. A GBOl'P OF HIGH PRODUCING COWS </seg>
            <seg id="p006">NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE 6 Pasture is one of the cheapest feeds when h is abundant and furnishes a large part of the feed for five to six months of the year. When milk is produced largely during the summer months on pasture, the feed forms a proportionately smaller part of the total expense. Pasture does not furnish a sufficient amount of nutrients for the cows producing large amounts of milk so that some grain must be fed in addition in order to main - tain the milk now and body weight of the cows. Consequently, under these conditions, pasture provides a smaller part of the total feed for high producing cows than for low producers. Woll found that pasture furnished approximately one-eighth of the total nutrients required by the highest producing cows entered in the Wisconsin Cow Competition, while in the case of the lowest producers it furnished one-fourth or more of the total feed. 3 There is a great difference in the cost of feed under condi - tions of intensive dairying, that is, where a large proportion of the farm receipts are derived from the dairy herd, and under circumstances in which a few cows are kept as a side line to other more important enterprises on the farm. The difference becomes still greater when farms like those included in the former class produce market milk and those in the latter class produce cream for buttermaking. The larger the number of cows being kept on a given farm the smaller the amount per cow of the non-marketable feeds and surplus roughage available. When the farm business is primarily that of producing a high grade of market milk non-marketable feeds can be used to but a limited extent and the cost of feed is comparatively high. On the other hand, with a small herd whose produce is sold as cream, advantage may be taken of the pasture on the roadsides, fence rows, stalk fields and other crop residues. The cream market does not demand such a steady supply thruout the year as does the retail milk market, so that in producing cream for butter - making the cheap feed furnished by pasture may be utilized to a greater extent. It has been estimated that when extensive use is made of the unmarketable roughage as feed for a small herd of cows </seg>
            <seg id="p007">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION 7 the cost of feed per cow is less thau half that in large specialized dairies. HOME t.KIIWN KKK1IS K( ONONIK \l It is usually found that a dairy herd can be fed more econ - omically where a large proportion of the feeds can be raised on the farm where they are consumed. In this case the value of the feed is the market price less the cost of marketing. The saving of this expense of marketing is in itself a large item. Where all Fie. S THIRD CROP OF ALFALFA ON A NEBRASKA FARM A falfa h»y is one of the most desirable feeds for dairy cows, sine? it contains *arxe mounts of piot?in and mineral matter and is usually a cheaper source of protein vhan is nrain. feeds must be purchased and hauled a distance of several miles to the farm in addition to the expense incurred, great inconveni - ence is often experienced in getting such work done during rush seasons and bad weather. Nebraska is especially adapted to the growing of corn and alfalfa and a large surplus of these crops is usually produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE The prices of these feeds are considerably less than on the central markets of the east, the difference being largely that of trans - portation. As far as these two crops, which constitute a large part of dairy rations, are concerned, milk production costs less in Nebraska than in the eastern states. The following table which gives comparative prices for farm products in various states indicates that there is a much wider spread between the prices of the bulky feeds than in the case of a concentrated product like butter. In Nebraska the relative - ly cheap feeds may be used to advantage in producing butter which sells at a price only a little less than that which is secured in the eastern markets, while butter production in Massachusetts, for example, is practically out of the question when a consider - able proportion of the feed must be purchased. It must be re - called also that several carloads of grain and roughage are re - quired to produce one carload of butter, making the spread in price still greater. Average Price Received by Farmers for Produce Per Nebr. Per Nebr. Per Nebr. Per Nebr. 1 Lb. | Price | Bu. I Price I Bu. | Price | Ton | Price Nebr. I I .40 I 100 ] » .59 I 100 I % .39 I 100 I $8.16 I 100 .4+ 110 .73 124 .43 110 11.96 147 Wis. .48 120 .91 154 .52 I 133 14.56 178 N. Y. Mass .49 123 .98 166 .58 149 20.30 249 (Price of butter Dec. 1, 1917; other prices, ten-year average, 1908-1917. From United States Department of Agriculture.) IMPROVED METHODS OF FEEDING PAY The selection of economical feeds, the intelligent compound - ing of rations and the feeding of each cow in proportion to her production, constitute the principal factors in economical feed - ing. Prices of feeds vary greatly from time to time, so that in choosing those most economical the cost per pound of digestible nutrients in various feeds should be considered. Under normal price conditions, roughage usually furnishes digestible nutrients more cheaply than concentrates; and feeds high in protein, such as cottonseed meal and oil meal, furnish digestible protein much State" "|" " butter ~ I Corn 1 _ Oats Hay I Price I Price I "We Price | % Price 1 % </seg>
            <seg id="p009">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION 9 more cheaply than low protein feeds, such as corn and oats. Two important causes of failure to make larger profits from cows are a lack of sufficient feed and too small a proportion of protein in the ration. The production per cow could no doubt be easily increased from 10 to 15 per cent thru better feeding, with a re - sultant increase in profit. The amount of protein required by a cow in milk is very large. To maintain at constant weight a 1,250-pound dry cow receiving 15 to 20 pounds of prairie hay or corn stover daily, the equivalent of about one pound of cottonseed meal or linseed oil meal must be fed in addition. A ration consisting of only 30 pounds of corn silage and 8 pounds of alfalfa hay is sufficient to maintain a cow of the same size. Thus the use of liberal amounts of alfalfa hay or other legume roughage in the ration may reduce the amount of high protein concentrates necessary. As an illustration of the saving due to the use of rations balanced for protein content, the results of a feeding trial at the Illinois station may be cited. A group of 10 cows receiving a balanced ration* maintained their body weight and produced nearly one - third more milk than the 10 cows receiving an unbalanced ration which greatly reduced their weight. 4 LABOR THE SECOND LARGEST COST ITEM In large herds labor is usually the second most important item in the cost of milk production. From the keeping of cost accounts in many sections of the country the amount of labor required in caring for a cow has been found to range from 100 to 175 hours per year. Under average conditions the care of a cow for a year may be considered equivalent to about 15 days' work. On general farms where only a few cows are kept no addi - tional labor is hired for their care. The work is performed either by the farmer at the time of day when it does not interfere with the field operations or the cows are cared for largely by the chil - dren of the family before and after school hours. Thus the keep - ing of a few cows provides employment for unpaid labor, contributes a considerable portion of the family living and adds to the farm income. The amount of labor expended depends </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE upon several factors, among which the size of the herd, conven - ience of barn and milk house, distance from market, and cleanli - ness of milk produced, are important. Kir. 4. Sll.OS AKK DEMISABLE A&lt; CKSSORIKS TO DAIRY BARNS A well filled silo is like a good lenk account. It may be drawn upon during winter months for a steady supply of feed and is especially helpful in tiding over e gencies in summer such as dried up pastures. CONVENIENT BAKN AKKAX.KM KNT HELPS The arrangement of the dairy barn and its relation to other buildings has considerable effect upon the facility with which the barn work may be accomplished and thus upon the amount of time spent per cow. Some conditions which cause the expendi - ture of more time than necessary are : Location of milk house too far from barn — a distance of 4 to 10 feet is usually sufficient, provided it is also properly located with respect to silos and barnyard ; location of silos and other feed storage at some distance from the barn ; lack of litter carriers, feed carts and other conven - iences for doing the barn work ; location of pasture at a consider - able distance from barn ; barn inconveniently arranged with re - spect to alleys, access to milk house and other buildings ; barn too large, e. g. having feed alley too wide, causing extra labor in feeding and sweeping; and keeping cows in box stalls instead </seg>
            <seg id="p011">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION 11 of stanchion*. In some dairy barns there is need lean investment in money, but in most cases the investment of more capital would provide a type of construction which would make the animals more comfortable and reduce the amount of labor necessary. DISTANCE HllIM MAHKKT AN IMPORTANT FACTOR When milk is hauled to market by the producer the distance is an important factor in determining the amount of labor neces - sary for this purpose. In many cases there would be a consider - able, saving in hauling costs if two or three farmers living near each other would take turns in hauling each other's milk, or if the dairymen of a neighborhood could hire a hauler to draw all the milk from that particular locality. In several of the whole milk districts of Nebraska the companies buying milk send out trucks to gather it. There is very little expense in delivering cream to the shipping station since it is generally hauled when the fanner goes to town on other errands. CI.KAM.INKS&gt;. MKANS I.AHOR The cleanliness of the milk produced is closely related to the amount of labor expended in the case of the cows and in the handling of the milk after it is drawn. In the production of cer - tified milk the large amount of labor required in cleaning the cows forms a considerable item of expense. Market milk of good quality also requires the expenditure of more labor, both in the care of the cows and the milk and the hauling of the milk than the production of cream for buttermaking. At Northfield, Min - nesota, the additional cost of labor in producing market milk above that of producing cream for buttermaking was $16.20 per cow for the year, or 29 cents for each 100 pounds. 6 Mil. KIM. MACHINES Ml LABOR COST Under most conditions the use of a milking machine enables one person to milk a number of cows in less time than is required to milk the same cows by hand. It takes as long or longer to milk one cow by machine as by hand. The saving is effected thru the use of several units, whereby three or four cows are milked at the same time under the direction of one operator. The amount of time saved is largely dependent upon the total </seg>
            <seg id="p012">NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE 12 number of cows milked and the convenience of the stable arrange - ments. The larger the herd and the more convenient the stable, other things being equal, the less mil be the average time re - quired to milk one cow. There may be no time saved in using a machine in small herds, since the time of washing and caring for the machine may offset the time saved in milking. With the aid of a machine the operator is enabled to milk a greater num - ber of cows than is possible by hand, since he can spend more hours per day in operating machines without becoming unduly tired or suffering from cramping of the fingers and arms, which occurs when a large number of cows are milked by hand. On account of the difficulty of securing not only a sufficient amount of labor but also men who are willing to milk cows, milking ma - chines are becoming popular even in very small herds, since many farmers wish to be independent of hired labor for milking. SIZE OF HERD MUST BE CONSIDERED There are many advantages in keeping a small herd of cows on general farms which are especially adapted to the growing of large crops, if there is a market for the surplus products within reasonable distance. Surplus roughage, much of which is un - marketable, may form a large proportion of the total feed re - quired and but little grain need be purchased. A few cows and young stock may readily be cared for by the boys and girls or by the farmer without the necessity of hiring additional labor for the purpose. Milk and cream are provided for family use and the products sold help increase the total income from the farm. Under such conditions the keeping of a few cows is to be recommended. When the number of cows in a community has become very large, condensaries or other whole milk markets may be established, but the production of cream for buttermaking will, for many years, doubtless prove a profitable sideline to gen - eral farming in Nebraska. In sections close to the larger cities and other markets for whole milk, larger herds may prove much more profitable. There are several items of expense in the production of milk which are materially reduced with an increase in the number of cows kept. Among these may be mentioned the amount of investment </seg>
            <seg id="p013">COST FACTORS IN MILK PRODUCTION 13 per cow in buildings and equipment, amount of investment in bulls, cost of hauling milk per cow, and amount of labor per cow. There are many operations in caring for a herd which are performed much more efficiently in a large than in a small herd. For example, the time spent per cow in cleaning stables, driving cows to and from pasture, preparing cows for milking, carrying feed to the cows from haymows and silos, and carinj? for the milk after it is drawn, is considerably greater in the smaller herds. When milking machines are used, milking cows and car - ing for the machines take less time per cow in the larger herds. FEED AND LABOR VARY WITH SEASON The amount of feed and labor involved in the production of milk varies with the season of the year. This has been studied in detail by Pearson. He says : "From the results of the data secured from 18 farms in the district tributary to Chicago, it was found that the following amounts of feed and labor were required to produce 100 pounds of milk containing 3.47 pounds of butterfat Winter Summer Yearly season season average Hours of labor 2.41 2.15 2.29 Pounds of grain 43.9 17.6 32.4 hay 53.0 14.2 36.4 dry forage 42.1 4.3 25.9 silage 183.2 11.5 154.0 Corrective factor 86.3% 61.9% 77.8% "The expenses not presented above are much larger than the return not milk. The winter cost of feed and labor represents 86.3 per cent of the net cost, the summer cost 61.9 per cent, and the yearly cost 77.8 per cent. "More" labor and barn feed are required in the production of 100 pounds of milk in the winter months than in the summer months. Pasture is largely responsible for this reduction. 'Pas - ture milk' is usually cheap milk. Milk produced from barn-fed cattle is usually expensive." 6 There is relatively a greater difference between summer and winter prices of milk than of butterfat. Altho it may cost more to produce milk in the winter its greater value then may make its production more profitable than in the summer. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE BREED AND SIZE COUNT FOR EFFICIENCY In a study of the records made by the cows entered in the Wisconsin Cow Competition, it was found that the Holsteins were the most efficient producers of milk and total solids. The Guernseys and Jerseys were about equally efficient as producers of butterfat, and both breeds were slightly more efficient in this respect than the Holstein. 7 The maintenance requirement of cows is proportionate to body surface and not to live weight. The larger cows thus have a slight advantage in amount of feed required per 100 pounds of live weight. Large cows eat and produce more than small cows and are more efficient producers. MATURE COWS PRODUCE BEST Under ordinary conditions a cow reaches maturity at a Out 5 years of age. Up to this time she must use part of her feed for growth, so that a young cow may not prove to be as efficient in producing milk as a mature animal. According to the require - ments for entry into the advanced register of the breed associa - tions a 2-year-old is expected to produce about 70 per cent, a 3-year-old about 80 per cent and a 4-year-old about 90 per cent of the amount of milk and fat that she will produce when mature. The annual yield of milk usually declines after a cow reaches 8 or 9 years of age, so that old cows may not be as profitable producers as the younger members of the herd. STAGE OF LACTATION FIGURES IN COST The efficiency of production during a particular stage of lactation has little effect on the yearly cost of milk production, but it may very materially influence the cost of production dur - ing different seasons if nearly all the cows in the herd freshen during a particular season of the year. It was found in a study of the records of Ohio dairy herd* that, as a rule, cows make the largest return in proportion to food consumed during the first part of the lactation period and that there is a gradual decrease in efficiency as the lactation period advances. During the first month of lactation 116 Hoi </seg>
            <seg id="p015">COST FACTORS IN MILK FRODUCTIOi; stein cows producing 30.3 pounds of milk and one pound of fat daily as an average returned in the milk 19.2 per cent of the digestible nutrients consumed. In the eighth month of lactation the production had fallen to 14 pounds of milk and half of it pound of fat daily, and there was likewise a decrease in efficiency, but 10.7 per cent of the digestible nutrients consumed being re - turned in the milk. During the tenth mouth of lactation the return of digestible nutrients was only ti.H per cent." WELL-BRED CALVES VALUABLE Calves from low producing stock are worth little more than their value for veal, but those from high producing strains must be assigned much greater valuations as they command excellent prices as breeding stock. Hi. ft. A (.Kin I- OP iimio CALVES MHOWIMG (.Km PBOMIME The raising of well-bred dairy calves is n commendable practice anil one which may offset a part of the cost of milk production. In the keeping of high producing animals there are, of course, added expenses such as increased depreciation and risk, increased labor in caring for the animals, and expenses of ad - vertising and selling; but it will generally be found that the value of the calves produced from such stock will more than </seg>
            <seg id="p016">NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE 16 offset the added expense of raising them over and above that involved the keeping of common stock. This increased revenue will thus reduce the cost of milk production. MANURE SHOULD BE CONSIDERED The amount of manure produced per cow varies from 12 to 15 tons annually. Perhaps two-fifths of this is produced at pasture. If the remainder is all saved and applied to the grow - ing of crops its value approximates $15 to $30 per year. The value of the manure depends upon many factors, chief among which are : The character of the ration, productive value of the land, value of crops grown, character of the soil, amount applied per acre, manner of caring for the manure. The manner in which manure is cared for is usually the most important factor in determining the ultimate returns secured from its use. When the liquid excreta is saved, preferably by the use of a sufficient amount of bedding to absorb it, and the manure applied directly to the crop areas, or, if stored, not al - lowed to leach, the maximum income will be obtained from its use. Losses due to improper handling of the manure at the stable should not be charged to the cows. REFERENCES 1. Haecker, T. L. — Investigations in Milk Production. Minn. Exp. Sta. Bui. 140. 2. McDowell, J. C. — Butterfat and Income. U. S. Dept. of Agr. 1917 Yearbook. 3. Woll, F. W.— Wis. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 26. 4. Fraser, W. J., and Hayden, C. C. — Balanced and Unbalanced Rations for Dairy Cows. 111. Exp. Sta. Bui. 159. 5. Peck, F. W., and Boss, Andrew.— The Cost of Milk Production. Minn. Exp. Sta. Bui. 173. 6. Pearson, F. A. — Cost of Producing Milk. Department of Dairy Hus - bandry, Univ. of 111. 7. Nevens, W. B.— Breed and Size of Cows as Factors Affecting the Cost of Milk Production. Jour. Dairy Science, Vol. 2, No. 2. 8. Grady, R. I. — Nutrients Returned by Dairy Cows. Ohio Exp. Sta. Mo. Bui., Vol. 2, No. 11. (3 Mi Distributed in furtherance of cooperative agricultural extension work. Acts of May 8, 1914, and June SO, 1914. Extension Service of The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture and U. S. Department of Agriculture cooperating. W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>