<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twelfth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA Biennium Ending November 30, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home AT MILFORD, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. Chester H. Aldrich Governor Hon. Edward B. Cowles Land Commissioner Hon. Walter A. George State Treasurer Hon. Addison Wait Secretary of State Hon. Grant G. Martin Attorney General ADVISORY BOARD Mrs. J C. F. McKesson, President Lincoln Mrs. Callen Thompson, Secretary Lincoln Mrs. Clara Carscadden York Mrs. Dr. Wilcox Hubbel OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION Lena E. Ward Superintendent H. J, Wertman Physician Sude B. Ward Matron EMPLOYEES M. Evelyn Meyer Secretary and Teacher Mrs. Nora Benz Sewing Teacher Myrtle Geyer Nurse Owen York Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            
            <seg id="p005">twelfth biennial report of the Nebraska Industrial Home. And I trust that the facts here in recorded may show some- what of the nature, extent, and results of our work. General Information Erhis Home has been supported by the state for twenty-four , yet we find so many who do not understand its purpose, it seems almost necessary to give a little general informa - n regard to it. g[t is the object of the state in supporting this Home to pro - unfortunate, homeless, penitent girls. The girls who come are not girls who have been wilfully bad, but are girls who been lead astray or who are in danger of being lead into » of sin and shame. And it is for the purpose of leading these girls into a life of rectitude and uprightness that the state supports this Home. Realizing that it is much cheaper and better for the individual and the world at large, to correct a fault in the beginning, than to allow it to continue until it becomes a crime and must be punished as such. Entering The Home Upon entering the Home each girl must sign an agreement to remain in the Home for a period of one year, to abide by the rules of the Home, and to perform such work as may be assigned her. And during this t me every effort is made to teach her how to become a good, useful woman. Domestic Department The work of the Home is divided in the following depart - ments: Kitchen, laundry, house, nursery, hospital and sewing- And as far as possible each girl, who is at all capable is given a detail in each department while in the Home. We always have a few who are mentally or physically unable to take all the work, but just as far as possible, we give every girl training </seg>
            <seg id="p006">280 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT time the girls are in the Home to give them all the training that we would like to, yet it is very gratifying to see the interest they take in their work and the great improvement there is in most of them. A great many of them have never had an opportunity to learn to do work as it should be done, but they are anxious to learn and it is a real pleasure to teach them. Kitchen Euring the past two years ninety-four girls have received rtion in the prepairing and cooking of meats, vegetables, , care of milk and butter, care of the kitchen and dining rooms, serving meals, washing dishes, canning, preserving, pickling fruit and vegetables and doing the many other things, which come up every day in the regular kitchen work. During this time they have prepared and served about 142,400 meals; baked 18,822 loaves of bread, 3,740 light rolls, 7,930 baking powder biscuits, 350 sheets of corn bread, 242 sheets of ginger bread, 1,203 pies, 507 cakes, 207 coffee cakes, 1,304 graham gems, 812 doughnuts, 1,030 cookies, 302 tea cakes, 37 roll jelly cakes, 327 puddings. Have canned 1,249 quarts, preserved 844 quarts, pickled 346 gallons, made 232 quarts jelly, 463 gallons butter, 32 quarts meat relish, 2 barrels sauerkraut, 532 pounds sausage, 75 pounds pressed meat, 39 quarts mince meat, 1,165 pounds lard, 227 pounds butter, cared for 12,777 gallons milk, and gathered 800 dozen eggs. Laundry We feel that our laundry is the poorest equipped department that we have, as the building is small and not in good condition for the purpose for which it is used. We do not have any of the modern conveniences, except a metallic dry room. The ma - chines are all run by hand, and a part wash with the board, while others use the machines. The ironing is all done by hand and no electric irons are used. The work in both the ironing and wash room is under the supervision of monitors appointed from among the girls. While it is impossible for them to acccomplish as much in this department without a teacher, as they would had they someone of experience who could be with them all the time to direct them; yet the work as a whole is very satisfactory and we think they do very well. During the past two years ninety- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">281 INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD eight girls have worked in this department. The average number of pieces washed and ironed each week is 1,628 dozen. Sewing Department In this department we are more fortunate in having some one who is always with the girls to instruct them in their work. A 'great many girls, upon entering the Home, know practically nothing about sewing; some have never learned to wear a thimble, nor have ever learned to run the sewing machine. So they have to begin at the very bottom and work up, and at times they be - come very much discouraged, but in time this is overcome and by the time they are ready to leave the Home do remarkably well. Others have been more fortunate and have had some in - struction before coming here so that, with what they receive while here, they are able to care for their own wardrobe as well as to support, or help support themselves with their needle. Some fancy work is also taught in the sewing room and most of the girls enjoy this. During the past year they have made some very nice pieces for the Home and a number have made some pieces to send home for Christmas. But some who have never attempted such a thing before were so pleased over their work that they could not wait until then, so have sent them long before time. In a number of their rooms the carpets were badly worn or entirely gone and we were not able to buy new ones, so we decided the only thing was to make some and the girls went to work, and in just a short time we had 112 yards of new rag carpet and only cost $24.94. This made their rooms nice and neat and they were very proud of them. The following is a list of the work done in the sewing room the past biennium : Table cloths Sheets Curtains Drs. robes Broom covers Tray clothes Ironing sheets Laundry bags Tea towels Roller towels </seg>
            <seg id="p008">282 » LAND COMMISSIONER S REPORT Pillow shams 60 Pillow slips 62 Carpet rags . . . 220 pounds Pads, large size 20 Hand towels 60 Pinning blankets 54 Bands 144 Blankets, nursery 54 Boys suits 18 Gowns, infants 186 Rompers 25 pairs Napkins, infants 841 Pads, nursery 60 Bibs 25 Skirts, infants 211 Bonnets, infants 16 Shirts, infants 294 Dresses, infants 363 Coats, infants 4 Capes and hoods, infants 36 Towels, nursery 36 Pillow cases 60 Quilts, nursery 36 Sheets, nursery 75 Napkins 200 Belts 60 Comforts 22 Sleeved aprons 70 Pastry aprons 12 Dining room aprons 12 Kitchen aprons 51 Dresses, girls 80 Skirts, girls, serge 80 Skirts, girls, sateen 70 Waists, girls 69 Gowns, girls 89 Corset sovers 87 Bonnets, girls 22 Number of pieces mended 1 .454 </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            
            <seg id="p011">283 House Work The house work is under the supervision of the matron, and the girls are taught to make beds, sweep, dust and how to care for the rooms. This, too, is a great revelation to many as they have never been taught to pay much attention to the little de - tails which go so far in making a home neat, clean and homelike. Hospital In selecting girls for this department, only those who have been faithful and conscientious about their work in other depart - ments, and who have a natural liking for the work, are chosen. During the past two years fourteen girls have served in this de - partment. Some, of course, we found were not at all fitted to become nurses. And these we did not encourage to go on with the work. Others proved to be very capable and everything we could do to help them along the line of nursing was done. Upon leaving the home some have gone as practical nurses and have given splendid satsif action. One, who was to receive one dollar a day on her first case, gave such good satisfaction, that when the parties for whom she nursed settled with her, gave her a check for ten dollars per week; and said, that they felt that she had well earned it. The doctor in reporting her work to the Home said that her work was in every way most satisfactory and that he would be glad to recommend her to any one in need of a practical nurse. Three upon leaving the Home entered hospitals to take a nurse's training course. And we have had good reports from each of them. Nurseries The children are in two nurseries, according to age; in the nursery where the smaller children are we have three girls to care for them, and in the other where the older children are, two girls. The nurseries are under the supervision of the matron and nurse. The nurse visits the nurseries each morning, and two or three times during the day to see how the babies are, and if there is any that are sick, they are taken to the hospital and cared for until they are able to go back again. We usually have from twenty - five to thirty children in the nurseries. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">284 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Educational Department In this department excellent work has been done by our girls, during the past two years. Our school work begins at 2: 15 every afternoon at the close of the regular detail work, and closes at 4 : 45 o'clock. Reading, penmanship, spelling, grammar, arithmetic, physiology, drawing and music are the subjects taught. A 1 grades are represented in our school, as some have never been given the opportunity to attend school of any kind, while others have completed the high school course. In order to meet the demands of all, a great deal of individual work must be done. The girls show their appreciation of this by applying themselves very diligently to the work assigned. Stress is laid particularly upon penmanship, reading, spelling and correct speech, and most of those instructed have shown marked improvement. Spelling seems to be the greatest bug - bear to the girls, with a few exceptions, and in order to arouse a E' er interest, we have resorted to the spelling match ; the ;r receiving a prize. It is surprising to note the improvement in this one branch in a few weeks. Our class in physiology has been exceptionally good. We have made the study of the body and how to care for it a spec - ialty. Some excellent drawings of different organs and parts of the body have been made, giving us a better idea of how our bodies are constructed and the work required of them. After being out of school for a number of years, or never having been encouraged in the effort made for obtaining an education, it is no wonder that the girls dislike to start to school upon entering the Home. However each girl who is able, is expected to attend regularly, and it is certainly an incentive to work with them, when they show the eagerness to learn what they can, as has been exhibited by the majority of them. The girls realize that K 1 school days will end, at least in most cases, when they leave institution, so wish to make the most of the opportunity ed. Religious Training R great deal of attention is paid to the religious teaching in ome; for we fully realize that upon this depends their . Every effort is made to give them a better understanding it our Lord has done for them and what He is still waiting </seg>
            <seg id="p013">285 INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD to do. Some have had none or scarcely any church privileges, others having never even read a chapter in the Bible. While some of course have attended church, Sunday-school, and Young Peoples' Meetings. But all enter heartily into the chapel exer - cises which we have each evening at 7 : 30. The teachers each having their night to conduct the meetings. P/e want especially to call attention to the Christian En - r, for we are greatly pleased with the interest the girls shown in the Endeavor work. These meetings are con - ducted by the girls themselves. The society meets Wednesday evening of each week, and the subjects discussed are those found in the Christian Endeavor World. The past year the topics have seemed to be the ones most needed by the girls and each one has contributed something on the topic every night she was able to attend. Many of the girls had never attended Young Peoples' Meetings of any kind until coming to the Home, and have felt backward about taking part, but the majority have overcome all obstacles and give expression to some splendid good thoughts. Not only does this spirit exist in the meetings, but we can notice efforts many are putting forth, to make their daily life become better from these studies. It is gratifying, indeed, to know that what the girls learn from these meetings has a lasting influence, for a large number, since leaving the Home send a Bible reference, some clipping or poem, which bears on the lesson. These are heartily welcomed by all. Sunday mornings at 9:45, we have our Sunday-school and we feel safe in saying that there is not a class of girls in the state, who go into the class room with better prepared lessons, or give better attention to the lesson during class hour than our girls. A daily record is kept of each lesson, studying the lesson; read - ing the Bible each day; responding to questions; having a verse of Scripture or practical thought gathered from the lesson to give at roll call ; and attention; each counts one point. And last quarter over one-half of the class stood above ninety. In the quarterly review a number received 100. We also have in con - nection with our Sunday-school, what might be called a home department for those who are on duty in the nurseries or who are not able to be in class. They prepare their lessons and send their reports into class. We also send the quarterlies to the girls who have left the Home that they too may keep up with heir work </seg>
            <seg id="p014">286 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT E report to the class at the end of the month. This we had not ught of doing until we noticed one faithful creature leaving Home with her quarterly in her hand. Government We have but very little trouble with the government of the Home as most of the girls who come to the Home, have already begun to realize the mistake of waywardness and are anxious to live a better life. We use the credit system and always appeal to their womanhood. We keep them employed most of the time and in this way avoid a great deal of trouble. At 5: 30 the whistle blows and all get up, put into order their rooms, make their beds and are ready for breakfast at 6: 15. As soon as breakfast is over each one passes to her detail work and there they work until 11:30, when dinner is served. At 1: 00 all go back to detail work and work until 2: 15, when they go into the school room and are there until 4 : 45. Some have detail work until 5: 30, when all have supper. Chapel at 7 : 30 ; after chapel all go to their rooms, where they may read or do fancy work and visit with their room mates. But no visiting is allowed in the halls or other rooms. At 8 : 45 the whistle blows which is a signal for silence and to prepare for bed and at nine the lights go off. Immediately after Sunday-school, on Sunday mornings, the library is opened and all who wish to, get books or papers, and these they take to their rooms and the rest of the day is spent in reading, walking about the grounds or visiting from one room to the other, as long as they are orderly. They may also go into chapel and play and sing. We always have some who love music and are able to play for the others On special holidays we always have a program suitable for the day and these they enjoy preparing, and for weeks after they are over. We also give parties occasionally in the evenings, which are very much enjoyed by all. Another thing which they enter into heartily is the trips to the woods to gather wild fruit, as gooseberries, plums, and grapes. This year they went one day and gathered six bushels of gooseberries then in the evening they all sat on the back lawn and sang and stemmed gooseberries. This was a real pleasure to the girls as well as a help to the Home. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">287 INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD Another afternoon they went for wild plums and gathered nine bushels. Ke try to make the Home just as near the ideal home as i. We do not want it to have the air of an institution, but home, which a great many of our girls have not had. And a great many of the girls upon leaving will say that they just feel like they were leaving home. And in writing back will refer to it as Home or the '"Only Home I ever had." The girl's people or friends are allowed to visit them once in eight weeks, on the last Thursday of the month, between the hours of one and five P. M. They have their mail given to them every evening at the close of chapel, and may write home, or if they have no home to some good friend, once in two weeks. We do not think it best to keep up correspondence with any but their own people, or those who are really interested in their welfare. Leaving The Home When the time comes for a girl to leave the Home, if she has no home to go to, or if the conditions are such that it would not be best for her to return to her home, a place is found in some good private family, or some place where we feel the influence will be good and where some one will take an interest in her. She is given plenty of good plain clothing to last her until she can earn money enough to get some more. Records of the Girls After They Leave the Home We have tried to keep as close record of the girls, who have left the Home in the past five years, as possible and while in a number of cases we have been very much disappointed, yet as a whole they have done well, as the following report will show: Of the number who have left the Home the records of 17' , are unknown, W% are not living as they should, or we are doubtful about them, 81.6% nave married and are doing well, 27.2' ( are supporting themselves or at home with parents or relatives and are making good. Of the remaining 4.2* , two have died, one has been sent to the hospital for the insane. The others are feeble minded girls, some have been sent to the institute for the feeble minded, and others are with their people. I would like to especially call attention to the l-ecords of some of the girls, who have left the Home and are making their </seg>
            <seg id="p016">288 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT way in the world, and by their own efforts are supporting them - selves and child. One of these is a little girl of sixteen, who is a natural born mother and could not give up her child, so she kept it. And, as she was especially handy with the needle, she decided to support herself and child in that way. A place was found for her where she could work for her board, and with the work she was allowed to do in the school, where she took her E', and at such times as she was not needed at her boarding she was able to pay all her expenses. She has now com - her course and has all and more work than she can do. Another went out as cook and has been employed as cook in the same place for four years at from $30.00 to $35.00 per month. She has not only supported herself and child, but carries a good life insurance with which to care for the child in case anything should happen to her, and has saved and deposited in the bank $724.00. Another is a poor foreign girl, who when she entered the Home, could hardly make herself understood, and who knew practically nothing about house work. She has just worked in two places since leaving the Home and has given excellent satis - ttion, she also is laying by something with which she hopes to able to educate- her child. r Another is a little crippled girl who has supported herself child and has saved $165.00 in three years. Another who was left without a mother, when very young and who came to the Home at the age of sixteen, is now em - ployed in an orphanage and has twenty-four children under her care. She is loved by all the children and is held in the highest esteem by the superintendent and all in the orphanage. E Another completed her musical education in one of our uni - ties and is now director of music in one of the city schools is state. There are so many doing well that we feel that the time, money and labor has been well spent in caring for them at a time when they felt that they had no friend or place to go. It is apalling how little sympathy and charity there is in the world for the unfortunate girl, and how hard it is for her to get a start Sin in the world, especially if she be a poor girl, and without ier and mother, or what is worse with a father and mother ) are not what they should be. v If there was more respect consideration shown the poor working girls, and if little </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">THE GREATEST WORK t built a house: time laid it in the dust wrote a book, its title now forgot; He ruled a city, but his name is not On any tablet graven, or where rust Can gather from disuse, or marble bust. He took a child from out a wretched cot, Who on the State dishonor might have brought And reared him to the Christian's hope and trust. The boy, to manhood grown, became a light To many souls, and preached for human need The wondrous love of the Omnipotent. The work has multiplied like stars at night When darkness deepens; every noble deed Lasts longer than a granite monument. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD 289 girls were taught that they were nothing but little girls, and not young women, there would not be so many unfortunate girls in the world. Repairs and Improvements !One of the first things to receive our attention in the way of •rovements was the hospital. There are three good sized tns which are used for this purpose, but they were in bad dition, as the old plastering was broken and falling and it i impossible to keep the rooms in anything like a sanitary dition. This trouble has all been remedied by placing steel ings and side walls in all the rooms as well as the bath room ich is used in connection with the hospital. These were all ?ly painted. New beds and bedding provided and everything he rooms received a fresh coat of varnish, and we now have a le hospital of which we are not ashamed. Inmates' Rooms New stQel ceiling were put on all the rooms, which are oc - cupied by the girls on the floor with the hospital. And both walls and ceilings also the woodwork received a good coat of paint. This is all the repairing we have been able to have done in the girls rooms, except the placing of radiators in the rooms on fourth floor where there had never been any way of warming them. Nurseries I The walls, ceiling and woodwork in the nursery where the iger children are kept, were all newly painted. In the ery where the older children are were newly papered, a new ceiling put up, their bath room also has new ceiling and walls. These with the woodwork were all painted so that lurseries are now in good shape. Dining Room and Kitchen I The girls' dining room has new steel ceiling, was newly red and painted and the old tables, which for several years been wired together,- have been replaced by new ones. The kitchen, supply room, pantries and refrigerator room were all given a new coat of paint as well as some other much needed repairs. Our kitchen range is in a very bad condition and will have to be discarded soon. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">290 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Library The institution had never had a library so, when the legisla - ture made the appropriation for libraries in all the institutions, we began to look about for a room which we could use for this purpose, and decided upon one just across from the school room which had been used for a store room This we had papered, painted and carpeted. We also got a large bookcase, library table and chairs, so that we now have a very pleasant library and a splendid collection of books, papers and magazines carefully selected by the State Institution Librarian, Miss Florence Waugh. It would be impossible for me to tell you how much the girls have enjoyed them. Before we had this library of our own, we had been getting books from the circulating library, which was much better than going without them; but yet so many times we had books that were not suited to the girls or of any special benefit to them. And a great many of them did not take much interest in reading. But now it is very different, nearly all the girls call for books and papers every week. School Room Enew ceiling was put on this room and walls, ceiling and ork all painted. The school room is badly in need of a ite black board, but we could not get this now. There also be a new organ for the school room. Besides the rooms already given, three large bed rooms were papered and painted and steel ceiling put on one of them. Steel walls and ceiling put on one bath room, and four large halls papered and painted and one new ceiling. There are a number of other rooms that should have new ceilings and be papered and painted, but this is as far as our money would let us go. The two large porches on both buildings were each given two good coats of paint. Cbttage The cottage, which is occupied by the engineer and his family, has also been repaired and improved by the addition of a kitchen, pantry and bath room and all the rooms newly papered and the pntirp huildinp insidp and out nninfpd </seg>
            <seg id="p021">291 IMHSTRIAI. HOMK, MILKORI) Screens New screens for all the windows and doors in the cottage and a number of screens for both doors and windows for the two main buildings were made as well as screening in the back porch on the north building and the back porch of the cottage. Laundry Our laundry is still in such a bad condition that we hesitate to speak of what has been done, and yet it has been made more comfortable to work in. The walls of the wash room were plastered, also a new ceiling put up and steam c &gt;ils put in so that the room will not be so cold. A new floor was laid in the ironing room and new lights put in the windows. New Buildings EA nice neat little vegetable and meat house has been built, rge hay barn in which we can care for all the hay and alfalfa need to feed the stock. Also a good comfortable stable n :h to feed and care for the cows in stormy weather. Power House Near the close of the last biennium we built or partially built a new power house, but could not complete it for lack of funds. This we have completed also built a small addition in which we have placed a new pump, which handles the condensed steam and feeds the boilers. Khe old dynamo was too small to generate the amount of :ity needed, so this was removed and a much larger one BPhe buildings were wired years ago and by a man who had ad much experience in that line of work, so that the wireing a a dangerous condition; this has all been taken out and all uildings rewired. The heating system was also in a very bad condition requir - ing almost a third more coal to run it than should have been used, and then the buildings were not comfortable, so this has been gone over to quite an extent, though not completely, and a number of new radiators put in so that it is greatly improved. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">292 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Sewerage K'or a number of years the sewerage has caused a great deal uble, but we believe this question is settled now, as we have ompleted a sewerage disposal plant and will do away with d cess pool. Other Improvements Several hundred feet of cement walks have been laid, a smal' pasture for the cows has been made, new chicken yards, some new posts and wire around the old pasture and hog lots, a new shed for the carriage, and some repairing on the barn. Farm There are only thirty-seven acres of land belonging to the Home so that it is impossible to do much farming. Of this seven acres are in lawn and yard, fourteen acres in pasture, seven acres in alfalfa, about seven in garden and two in orchard. On account of the dry weather we have not received much from our farm land this biennium. We sowed three acres of alfalfa about a year ago, but did not get a very good stand as so much of it winter killed, and then the dry weather was hard on it. We also sowed some clover which either froze or dried out during the dry weather. Our pasture did not furnish enough feed for our cows during the summer months, so that we were compelled to feed nearly all the alfalfa we had before the cold weather set in. We rented eight acres which were planted to corn and cut up for feed. The garden furnished us our summer vegetables, but not much to put away for winter use. Last year our little orchard bore bountifully and we had all the summer and fall apples we could use, and put up enough to last all winter. But as most of the trees are summer and fall apples we had to buy our winter supply of fresh apples. The cherry trees also did very well, but there are only about six good trees. This summer we did not have apples enough to supply the Home. But about the same of cherries. Live Stock Khe stock of the institution consists of a small dairy herd, good horses and one that is not so good, a few hogs. We aise what hogs we can feed without having to buy too much. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">293 These we kill in the winter and in this way furnish the institution with almost all the lard we use and a quantity of nice meat. We have just had our cows tested and found one good Holstein affected with tubercular trouble, so had to kill her. Chickens We also have ducks and chickens and while we have not been able to supply the institution with all the eggs we use, we have in the course of the two years gathered 800 dozen, and have had ducks and chickens for the table use. Repairs and Improvements Needed EThe first and perhaps one of the greatest needs of the Home, tunnel between the two main buildings and to the boiler 1. The pipes are now just laying several feet underground, this is not only a great inconvenience and expense whenever i is any trouble with the line, of which there is always more ss but is very hard on the pipes. En going over the heating plant we found that it was impos - to do as much of the work as should have been done, on nt of so many of the pipes being too badly worn to allow of any work on them. These will all have to be put in new before another winter. If while this was being done we could have the tunnel put in, it would save a great deal of expense later on. Another thing, so many of the pipes have no covering, that a great deal of heat is ost long before it reaches the rooms that are to be warmed. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">294 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Vegetable Cellar PWe have no way of keeping our winter vegetables or canned only in the basement of the main buildings, through which steam pipes run. Each year we lose a great deal of fruit and vegetables, because we do not have a suitable place to keep them. Therefore we are going to ask for an outside cellar, there these things can be cared for. Am sure it will pay for its If in a very few years. Plumbing Five years ago we had the plumbing gone over as far as our funds would allow, but it was impossible to get a great deal of it done. The old lead pipes are constantly giving out, the fixtures on the bath tubs and stools are worn out and it is mpossible to t repairs for them, as they are old style, and the supply houses lot carry them, so there is nothing to do but take them out get new ones. Out Side Walls These buildings have been built from twenty to twenty-five years and were built of soft bricks. A great deal of the mortar is out and the moisture soaks right through the bricks, ruining the inside walls and rendering the rooms unfit for use. We have at times, had to move the beds out into the halls as the rooms and bedding were too damp for anyone to sleep in. This will have to be remedied in some way. The doors and window frames have never been painted since the buildings were first finished, so are badly in need of paint. The side walls and ceilings in a E'ler of rooms are in bad condition and must have attention ce. Also a number of floors are worn out A new slate board is needed in the school room. Laundry Elhe old laundry building is entirely too small, has no con - snces and can not have for lack of room. It is so cold that almost impossible to get the washing done in cold weather, the only way to remedy this is to have a new building. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">295 INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD Barn The foundation of the barn and floor are in bad condition, the watering tank is a most past usinij Orchard KJur orchard is badly in need of attention, the trees need ng, and a number of them have died and should be replaced, mber of winter apple trees should be set out as the apples are here are summer and fall apples with the exception of trees. There should be also some cherry and plum i mt. There are no grapes on the place and it would be such p to the Home if we had a nice little vineyard. Salaries (inother matter to which I would like to call the attention legislature, and which I hope they will give due considera - is the question of salaries. That they may get a better standing of this matter, I am going to give a brief account at is expected of those employed in this institution. As the object of the state is not only to care for the girls physically, but to show them the mistakes they have made and to teach them how to live so that these mistakes and others may not be made in the future. Also to care for the ( innocent child and to see that he be provided with a home where he may be trained up to be a good, useful citizen. It is not only necessary that those employed in the Home be able to do the work, and to teach the girls to do the work, but they must be women of good Christian character, those who have sympathy and charity for the faults of others, and are able to show them their faults, in a way in which they will realize that it is all for their own good, and will make every effort to correct them. Many a woman is a success in our public schools or as a nurse in private work, who is not a success with the unfortunate. They not only need the same amount of care and instruction that the more fortunate girl needs, but they must have the wisely directed love and sympathy of those who work with them. Without this, nothing in the way of reform and betterment can be accomplished, and the time and money spent has been in vain. While the work is very p ant in many ways, it has many unpleasant features. So </seg>
            <seg id="p026">LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT 296 much sadness and sorrow, and there is so little opportunity for getting away from it. No regular hours for working; simply on duty or subject to call every hour in the day and every day in the week. I am sure there is no line of work in the state, where there is more responsibility or more expected of those employed, than there is in this Home, and I trust that the legislature will investigate this matter and be more liberal in their appropria- Population December 1, 1910 to November 30, 1912 Male Female Total Number inmates present at beginning of the biennium 12 40 52 44 117 161 35 99 134 20 59 79 Number received Number discharged and died Present November 30, 1912 Average daily attendance Dec. 1, 1910 to May 31, 1911 57 Average daily attendance May 31, 1911 to Nov. 30, 1911 76 Average daily attendance Dec. 1, 1911 to May 31, 1912 76 Average daily attendance May 31, 1912 to Nov. 30, 1912 80 Average daily attendance for the biennium 72 72 Financial Report Paid for permanent improvements $4,182.31 Expenditures for biennium not counting permanent improvements Average cost per inmate 436. 8? Average cost per day each inmate .06* ,6 Cash Fund Balance on hand December 1, 1910 Received first year Received second year On hand December 1, 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">297 Estimated Requirements for Coming Biennium Conclusion EPo those associated with me in the work of the Home I to express my sincere gratitude for their earnest efforts and service. And to you, Governor Aldrich, m mbers of the i of Public Lands and Buildings and Ladies' Advisory Board, e uniform kindness and consideration I have enjoyed, I to express my appreciation and heartfelt thanks. While we have not accomplished all that we had hoped to, we have worked earnestly for the advancement of the institution and the strengthening and upbuilding of its wards and we know that a great deal has been accomplished, and hope that greater and better success will be the reward of the next two years' ser- ■ Thanking you for the many courtesies shown, this report is ?ctfully submitted. Lena E. Ward Omcers salaries $6,800 Employees' wages Maintenance 6,520 Repair and improvements 12,000 Total ■ balance lyil 1909 Ap- Appro- propriat'n priation Total Paid Reverted to Balance Treasury Officers' salaries $773.36 $4,400 ! Employees' wages 840.13 5,080 Maintenance ] 5,448.58 17,000 Repairs | 55.3€ 6,800 ! $5,133.36: $4,400.01! 5,920.13i 4,981.03 22,448.58 20,395.41 6,855.36' 6,297.66^ HUM 2.98 2,050.19 2.62 555.08 ■■ ■ 1 1 I Total '$7,077.43! $33,280 ! $40,357.43 $36,075,111 I $11.43 $4,270.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">298 REPORT OF THE PHYSICIAN Milford, Nebraska, December 6, 1912. To His Excellency, Chester H. Aldrich, Governor of Nebraska: Kirs: It is a pleasure as well as a duty to report to you the ;ion of the health of this institution for the past two years. The general health of the inmates has been exceptionally good. We have had no epidemic except a socalled epidemic of bronchial pneumonia, which occurred among the smaller and weaker infants during the winter of 1911 and 1912. This, I think, was due in a great measure to the fact that on account of insufficient appropriation no night fireman could be kept, con - sequently the rooms were warm when the babies were put to bed and by morning the temperature had changed 50 or 60 r ; . This was too much of a change for the weaker babies, and should be looked after before another winter, especially such as last, has commenced. I would recommend that the legislature make provisions for a night fireman for such time as he may be needed. Ehe sanitary condition is exceptionally good and we, as the , owe a large part of this to the careful, vigorous work of the ; Ward and their assistants. During the two years we have had sixty-nine births, of this number forty-eight were normal and twenty-one abnormal. Four were still born, two premature and five died within forty - eight hours. We have had one death among the adult inmates, due to diabetes with which she was affected when she entered the Home. It is evident from the amount of work done at the institution and the skill required to handle the inmates, calls for a greater compensation than the superintendent and matron are receiving, and I earnestly hope that the legislature of 1913 will correct this Respectfully submitted, H. J. Wertman, M. D. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>