<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Third Biennial Report OF THE AGENT OF THE Home for Dependent Children Successor to "The Home of The Friendless" To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">L { it &lt; i o-« I] O i 9J </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Third Biennial Report OF THE AGENT OF THE Home for Dependent Children Successor to "The Home of The Friendless" LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1014 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">520 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS Miss Etta Caton. Miss Amy V. Stevens.. Mrs. Ida M. Snowden Mrs. Lillie McGoogan Miss Mary Hollahan Dr. Inez C. Philbrick. Dr. S. E. Cook Miss Erika Ericson. Mrs. Annie Sinner.. m. &gt;n Agent tevens Assistant Agent owden Secretary Googan Matron llahan Governess ilbrick Physician Specialist EMPLOYEES icson Cook nner Laundress </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 521 INTRODUCTION There is nothing in all the world so important as chil - dren, nothing so interesting. If you ever wish to be of any real use in the world, do something for children. — David Starr Jordan. I love these little people and it is not a slight thing when they, who are so fresh from God, love us. — Dickens. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">522 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF t THE NEGLECTED CHILD Look at the matted hair whose tangled strands Were never washed and brushed by loving hands, The skin, whose texture none has ever seen, That might be fair and clear were it but clean. The flesh so pinched and weazened, lacking food, The eyes so dull or shifting, lacking good. No gentle speech of manner here to show, Since none has ever yet been his to know. Well, if he be not stained and steeped in sin, Who knows the mire he may have fallen in? Yet he has future. What then, shall it be? I say the answer lies with you and me. He stands before us marred — to be re-made. Upon us each and all the charge is laid. And how? The only way that yet is known, Is to regard him as you would your own. Suppose your child were wearing that old shoe, Feet cramped and sore through soggy holes in view, And that his clothes were fastened with a pin, No underclothes — the others ragged, thin. Do you believe earache and toothache, too, Reserve their visits for the well-to-do? Or that the lavished love and cuddling, Are nothing necessary in Life's spring? Your boy so precious, how intense your prayer That he grow good and useful. Give this one a share Surround him as your own far as you can, With influences that shall make a man. That fragile, dainty girl you call your own, Imagine in the street she stood alone, How you would rush to save her little frame! This child stands in life's thoroughfare the same. Unknown the threatened danger's awful powers, This child, I tell you, standing by, is ours. — Mary Bailey. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 523 V To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : Herewith, I submit report of the work of the Home for Dependent Children for the Biennium beginning De - cember 1, 1912, and ending November 30, 1914. Since the Legislature of 1909 changed the plan of the State work for homeless and dependent children from the institutional to the boarding system, so many other changes have been made that there has been no settled condition of the work. In 1909 the Board of Control for Dependent Children was created and the name "State Public School" took the place of "Home for the Friendless," but, instead of doing the work of a state public school, the children were placed as rapidly as possible in family homes in the city and its suburbs and their board was paid by the State until such time as free homes could be secured for them, although the large institutional building at Tenth and South Streets was still maintained. April, 1911, the house at the corner of Tenth and H Streets, the only place that seemed avail - able at that time, was leased for a period of two years at a rental of $50 per month, the State to make necessary repairs. The house was wired for lights at State expense, several rooms were papered, and much other repairing done. A part of the old Home furniture and office equip - ment was moved to the new location, the greater part of the furniture having to be sacrificed because there was no room for it. The house was old, hard to heat, and in no way fitted for the needs of the work. In 1911, the name "Home for Dependent Children" was substituted for "State Public School." A few other minor changes were made at the same time. The boarding system was still continued. January, 1914, the Home was removed from 944 H </seg>
            <seg id="p007">524 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Street, to 1425 F Street, an eleven-room, brick house, a resi - dence property in good condition but just as unsuited to our needs as the other. This building was leased for two years at a rental of $65.00 per month. May 1, 1914, the work passed from the control of the Board of Control for Dependent Children to the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions and is at present under this Board. That it is impossible to conserve either the best inter - ests of the State or of the homeless children with so much changing and so much uncertainty, no one familiar with such work will question. The boarding-out plan has been given a fair trial for more than five years. In some loca - tions and under some conditions it might be far preferable to the institutional plan of caring for children. It has both its advantages and disadvantages. In favor of the boarding plan may be stated the fol - lowing points : 1. Some of the older children are not so sensitive about being state wards; 2. The children are, at least, temporary members of families ; 3. They go to the pubic schools with other children; 4. They go to Sunday School and to church with the family (if the family attends church) ; 5. There are a less number of deaths due to con - tagious or infectious diseases sweeping through an insti - tution. These advantages, however, are more than offset by the disadvantages: 1. The expense to the State is greater for the board - ing system than for the institutional system. (a) The cost per capita for boarding children is $3.00 per week for approximately normal children. For those in need of especial care the cost varies from $4.00 to $20.00 per week each. Some of the children are so un - desirable that it is difficult to find boarding homes for them at any price. (b) The clothing costs more than it would if the children were kept in an institution. The average board- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">um DJ Kv " o DO J fed f i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 525 &gt; ing-mother demands a better grade of clothes, but she does not handle the clothing so carefully as do the institution workers. She wants the child as well-dressed as the rest of the family, but she is not so particular about caring for his clothing because it costs her nothing to provide it. (c). The medical expense is greater. There would be many things done for the children in the institution that are not done in the boarding home, thus making a saving in doctor bills. By one call at the institution the doctor could see all of the children at one time, whereas, now she must make calls to all parts of the city as well as out-lying districts. Moreover, many of the children must go to the office of the physician or specialist day after day for treat - ment; not only must car fare be paid for the children but also for attendant. Street car fare alone, mostly for the transfer of children, amounted to more than $300 for the last biennium. 2. The difficulty of securing good boarding homes. At the rate paid, only those persons who are very much in need of the little money earned in this way, will board children. Hence, some of them cannot give the children the wholesome, nourishing food they need ; others are in - different as to the care they give the children. They are not over-zealous as to correcting bad habits and preparing the child as quickly as possible for a permanent home. Hence, in many cases, the child is kept day after day at the State's expense without any especial effort being made to discover and correct the bad habits and physical ailments which tend to prevent placing the child in a free, perman - ent home. Out of over 400 applications to board children, we have been able to find but about six first-class boarding - mothers and these we wish to commend in highest terms. 3. Children cannot be placed in free homes as rap - idly from the boarding home as from the institution : (a) Because it is more difficult for those persons wanting children to see them, the persons having, perhaps, but a short time in the city and the children being scat - tered all over the town and its suburbs ; (b) The institution workers do not have the oppor - tunity of becoming acquainted with the children and hence </seg>
            <seg id="p010">526 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF *» cannot fit them so well into permanent homes; as a result there are many more children returned after placing; (c) The children are not brought into a condition of sound health and correct morals in the boarding home such as they would be in the institution. 4. The school question is a serious one. It is one of our greatest problems. Most of the children received by the Home, though mentally normal, are below grade in school. They have either been kept out of school or have been moved from place to place so often that their school work has been interrupted. The constant changing to and from their boarding homes also causes them to lose their grades in the public schools. They are thus kept back of their fellows of the same age until they are unwilling to go to school. Had we an institutional school, we could, by special attention to the individual child, compensate for much of the early neglect. The education furnished by the State will be one of the greatest assets many of these children have when they attain their majority, so if this be deficient they are handicapped indeed. 5. The constant call upon the time and service of the institution workers ; that is, the institution must still bear the responsibility and much of the labor of the train - ing of the children in the boarding homes, although they are out from under the direct supervision of the insti - tution. Sample telephone calls from boarding-mothers are about as follows: "Johnnie tore the whole sole off his shoe and it will have to be repaired before he can go to school." "Sammie fell and cut his knee severely ; it will be necessary for the doctor to sew it up immediately." "I need a new dress for Mary. The ones she has shrunk in the washing so that she cannot wear them." "Little Alice died this morning ; please arrange to care for the body at once." "I just can't do anything with Hazel; she is so saucy and ugly. Can't you come out and talk to her?" "Jennie is in need of paints and brush for school. The teacher says she must have them before she comes to school again." </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 527 &gt; "Jimmie set fire to a neighbor's haystack and destroyed it; the neighbor says the hay is worth from $75 to $100. What shall we do about it?" "Edwin and Charlie have run away. I thought I would tell you as I didn't know what else to do." "I simply can't stand Harry any longer. You must take him away tonight; his habits are simply unbearable." "I am going away for a little visit and will have to give up the children for awhile. Please take them away tomorrow." "Willie needs a new suit and Mary needs some mit tens." "The baby cries all the time ; I don't know what to do. Can't you come and get it? I don't want to keep it over night." "These children are so bad that the neighbors are com - plaining; you will have to do something." "Susie has diphtheria and I cannot let her stay here. We don't want to be quarantined. Please take her away at once." These are all real troubles that fall upon our ears day after day from our boarding homes ; they come at any hour of the twenty-four; it is a continual program. And yet we have to attend to all of these things at long range or transport ourselves as quickly as possible to the scene of action. 6. One pernicious effect of the boarding system is that many people who would otherwise give children free homes, want and expect pay because "the State pays others." Lastly, the superintendent cannot exercise the same supervision over the children and the many women who are caring for them, scattered as they are over so large a district, as she could over children and workers in the institution. The boarding plan is growing more and more compli - cated and difficult to handle successfully, because of the larger number of children being committed to the State </seg>
            <seg id="p012">528 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF V Home and because of the increased number being boarded owing to the greater difficulty of placing from the board - ing homes. In the small building which we now occupy, we cannot keep the children long enough to get them clean and whole - some before they must be moved out to a boarding home in order that we may have room to receive the next who come. Many children received by us have been exposed to contagious or infectious diseases, — scarlet fever, diph - theria, mumps, measles, itch, etc., before coming to us, and sometimes a child is stricken with one of these di - seases the day after being admitted to the Home. We have no isolation rooms. We must either be quarantined, which would mean to stop our work for a number of weeks, or we must move the sick child at once and fumigate. Hospitals will not take such cases ; private homes that will take them are rare, and then only at a cost to the State of $15.00 to $20.00 per week, not including doctor's fees. It is even more difficult to secure a means of conveyance for the re - moval of a case of contagious disease. Ambulance owners refuse ; so, also, do livery and transfer companies. It is an admitted fact that the family home is the ideal place for the rearing of a normal child. The welfare and continuance of our nation are rooted and grounded in the family home. "The home is the most sacred of all institutions." But, as we have shown, there are few homes in which the child that is ill or defective physically, mentally or mor - ally, can receive the medical care, attention and training that can be given that child in a hospital or an institution equipped with all the provisions necessary to care for the needs of that child. Especially is this true if the child is a stranger in the home. And since, as statistics have proven, about 90% of the children committed to the State Home are defective physically when committed and an equal, if not greater, per cent, defective morally, and since the normal child can be readily placed in a permanent free home, it is safe to conclude that the institutional plan of caring for the home- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">A GOOD HOME SECURED Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 529 less children of the State is better suited to our needs than the boarding plan. However, I wish to repeat that for the normal child I do not recommend the institution life as a permanent thing or even for a long period of time, the purpose of the institution being the means to an end, that end the se - curing of a permanent home for each child just as soon as he is physically and morally fit to be placed in a family home. The work grows heavier each year; that is, the num - ber of children committed to the State is gradually in - creasing and, as the older children are rarely adopted, the average number in the custody of the Home grows larger. But, "if all child-caring agencies are to have adequate su - pervision, it must be provided by the State." "The first duty of a state toward the dependent children within its borders is to know where they are ; second is to know how they are treated." Statistics cannot show the amount of work done by any institution ; in fact, the work which cannot be reduced to figures is greater than that which can be. For instance, as shown by Table XIII, out of 489 applications for ad - mission to the Home, 200 were received. Others were as - sisted in various ways. Where parents were found mor - ally fit to have and rear their children, every effort has been made to enable them to do so. Some of the applicants were aged people, without friends and without means, en - tirely dependent upon the charity of strangers. It has been a real heart-ache to inform these, who are nearing the end of the journey, that for such there is no state home, and to see the hopeless dejection and despair darken the seamed, old faces, when they realized that there was noth - ing else but the county "poor-house." Many of the little children committed to the state are now enjoying the first real homes they have ever known. They have also learned for the first time what comfort and happiness mean. More than one little child has exclaimed "I have all I want to eat now" and the change from pale, sallow faces and thin, anaemic bodies to round, rosy cheeks and plump forms, goes to prove that the little one has not </seg>
            <seg id="p015">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 530 ■» always had the nourishing food which he needed to build a strong, healthy body. The children also enjoy immensely the removal of the filthy rags, which is all many of them have in the way of clothing when admitted, and the sub - stitution of clean, comfortable garments; and a bath, to which many of them are strangers, is to some a fear, to others a delight. "Children may be born free, they may have equal rights, but not all are placed equally at the start - ing of life's race." The officers and employees of the Home are all keenly interested in the welfare of the homeless children, feeling that upon them rests largely the future happiness and success of the child. Our physician, Dr. Inez C. Philbrick, has been untiring and generous in her good work and our children soon show marked improvement under her care. Dr. S. E. Cook has had charge of our cases of eye and ear disease and, to - jrether with the surgeons of the Orthopedic Hospital, has performed the surgical operations for adenoids, etc. Other physicians have aided us in emergencies. "Childhood is the battle-ground where victories against poverty, disease and crime count most." We feel that there is no greater work than the saving of these little children just entering upon life's journey, many of them already handicapped by physical weakness and disease and the blight of bad habits, to lives of happiness and usefulness. "When you save a man or a woman, you save a unit; but when you save a boy or a girl you save a whole multiplica - tion table." Many of these children still under the 'teen age are well-started on the road to crime, but by being re - moved from their old environment, turned "right-about - face," and surrounded by good influences, show remarkable change and the beginning of a different life. "A neglected childhood is the secret of a criminal career." Though with a vision of the child's future before our eyes, the path of duty may appear to lie clear and straight, yet sometimes the censure of those who do not understand or who have other interests at heart than those of the child is hard to bear. On the one hand, we are responsible to the courts and to the State for making the welfare of </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 531 the child who has been committed to our care, our first con - sideration ; on the other hand, are we often misjudged and criticized for being "unfeeling" because we do not return the child to the parents and the surroundings from which the court has seen wise to remove it. Our reward comes from the gratitude of children in after years. One young girl, now fourteen years of age, taken from her parents by the court about five years ago, recently said, "I am so glad that I was taken away from home, because I would have had no education and no training had I been left there." Someone has said, "It is a crime to break up homes and take children from loving parents who are doing their best to provide for them. But it is no less a crime to leave children with progenitors who have lost their love for their children or who wilfully neglect them, drink up their earnings and let their children go hungry, lie down in the morass of immorality, or abandon them to the tender mercies of strangers." On the whole, the public has been kind to the work of the State for its dependent children, showing a deep appre - ciation of the many and diverse problems which must be solved and the difficulties which naturally arise from the breaking of family ties. We wish publicly to thank the many persons throughout the State who have become warm friends and supporters of the work, who have given words of cheer and encouragement, and who have devoted time and labor assisting in the care of these helpless ones. "Let us remember the children of today are the potential parents of tomorrow," hence, if we save the children of today we are saving the generation of tomorrow. "To help a boy or girl is the greatest thing in the world. At one and the same time you are helping not only the child, but the man or woman, the community, the whole world, — and yourself." That we may do our work successfully and well, we should have a permanent location owned by the State. Be - cause of our much traveling on many roads for the purpose of placing, transferring and visiting children, Lincoln i3 the most suitable and convenient place, being the capital of the State and a railroad center. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">532 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF We need grounds and a building or buildings, con - structed to suit the needs of the work. The grounds and buildings should be arranged for play-grounds, housing of the children, for school, for segregation of boys and girls, and for isolation, if necessary, of those morally or physic - ally diseased. I MAKE THE FOLLOWING RECOMMENDATIONS That- such grounds and buildings as are needed be pro - cured; That the law governing the work for dependent chil - dren be revised or amended, so that it may be definite, clear and concise; That the title of the head officer of the Home be changed from "agent" to " superintendent," as more ex - pressive of the position and as more uniform with other State institutions. Respectfully submitted, Etta Caton, Agent. Lincoln, Nebraska, November SO, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 533 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 Ending , Nov. 30, Dec. 1. 12 to June 30, '13 1 , 1913 For Year July 1, '13 ending to Nov. 30, Nov.30,'13 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T ' M F T i , 'resent at begin- ning of period... 99 67 166 . Admitted : 'or first time 31 27 58 Leadmitted 3 2 5 Returned from trial homes in which • placed before be- ginning of per- iod 2 7 $i 20 14 34 47 50 97 2 13 3 3 10 11 21 20 28 48 99 67 166 98 91 189 8 3 11 I 'otal under care 205 161 366 205 161 366 Discharged: Returned to par- ents or friends... 18 12 30 6 1 7 11 13 24 35 26 61 Adopted ..._ _ 4 15 19 8 7 15 13 9 22 25 31 56 Transferred to oth er institutions.. 2 2 112 3 3 6 17 Died ..._ _ 2 2 1 ..... 13 2 5 4 4 8 Married _ 1 1 ' 1 1 2 2 Attained majority 22 538 55 10 Placed under con- tract and not re- turned during period ..._ 4 4 _ _ _ Placed in trial homes and not returned during period ..._ 22 21 4.&lt;l 18 15 33 52 49 101! _ . , Total removals _ ; — -..- 75 69 144 75 69 144 Remaining at end of period - - ..._ - - — 130 92 222 Average number under care 102 70 172 112 55 167 119 76 195 111 67 178 Absent in trial homes at com- mencement of oi during period and later discharged without return- ing to Home 4 18 22 8 9 17 21 10 31 33 37 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">534 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE II. AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year AGE AT ADMISSION Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Under 1 month... 12 4 16 2 4 6 7 8 15 20 17 37 1 and under 3 mo 1 4 5 1 1 4 2 6 6 6 12 3 and under 6 mo 2 2 11 134 167 6 and under 12 mo 1 2 2 112 13 4 1 and under 2 yrs 1 1 2 2 3 3 3 3 6 2 and under 5 yrs 3 5 8 4 2 6 7 4 11 14 11 25 5 and under 10 yrs 13 4 17 9 4 13 19 46 35 42 23 65 10 and under 15 yrs 4 7 11 4 4 8 10 13 23 18 24 42 15 and under 18 yrs 1 1 ..._ 1 1112 Totals. _... 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 200 TABLE III. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, '12 July 1, 13 ending Total EDUCATION to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFTMFTMFT MFT None ..._ - - I 1 1 -._ 1 ...... I Below 3rd grade... 30 21 51 15 8 23 37 40 77 82 69 151 4th grade 2 2 44 2 69 110 15 520 5th grade ..._ 156 123 167 3 13 16 6th grade _... 112 1 12 2 4 4 3 7 7th grade 8th grade - - | 1 1 ..._. 1 1 2 2 9th grade i 1 11 ..._. 1112 10th grade _ 1 1 _ -. 1 1 Totals 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 200 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">535 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE IV. SEX AND RACE OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 Dec. 1, '12 July 1, 13 endinjr Total RACE to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT White _.._ 32 27 59 22 15 37 49 47 96 103 89 192 32 27 59 22 15 37 49 47 96 103 89 IS 2 2 4 13 4 3 5 NegTo Totals 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 20 NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium NATIVITY MFT M 30 24 54 20 FT MFT MFT Nebraska 12 32 44 38 82 94 74 168 3 5 4 7 11 10 15 25 U. S., other than Nebraska 4 5 9 2 Total native born .... 34 29 63 22 15 37 48 45 93 104 89 193 Bohemia Canada . Germany 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Total foreign bom Unknown 12 3 12 3 13 4 13 4 Totals _ 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 200 ■&gt; _ 3 :!4 14 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 2:i 63 94 200 "ABLE V. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED </seg>
            <seg id="p021">536 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year NATIVITY OF l Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total PARENTS to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium M F T M FT MFT MFT U. S., both parents 24 23 47 16 12 28 41 43 84 81 78 159 Foreign, both par - ents ! 213 325 213 74 11 Mixed _ _.... 6 3 9 1 1 1 1 2 8 4 12 Unknown 224 21 3 65 11 10 8 18 Totals...- , 34 29 63 22 15 37, 50 50 100 106 94 200 TABLE VII. PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year PARENTAL I Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total CONDITIONS to to Nov. 30, for to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Both parents dead 1 1 1 1 Father dead...- 112 1 1 7 6 13 9 7 16 Mother dead 3 6 9 2 3 5 8 2 10 13 11 24 Parents living to- gether 14 5 5 2 7 5 5 10 11 11 22 Parents separated. 13 7 20 Parents divorced ... 2 2 4 6 1 7 13 12 25 32 20 52 213 268 69 15 Has stepfather 1 1 213 47 11 69 15 Has stepmother 112 112 Unknown 112 112 Parents living but unmarried 12 10 22 6 6 12 10 16 26 28 32 60 Totals 33 32 65 24 15 39 50 55 105 107 102 209 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 537 TABLE VIII. AGES AT DEATH OF PARENTS For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total AGE OF CHILD Nov. 30, to to for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 ! 1914 Biennium MFT MFTjMFT'MFT Age at death of father Under 10 years 1 1 2 2 7 6 13 8 8 16 10 and under 15 yrs 1 1 I 1 1 Age at death of mother Under 10 years 3 3 6 2 3 58 2 10 1 13 8 21 10 and under 15 yrs 3 3 1 1 ..._. 4 4 Totals _ 4 6 10 3 6 9 15 8 23 22 20 42 TABLE IX. ADMISSION FROM DEFECTIVE OR DELINQUENT HOMES For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total CLASS Nov. 30, for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Feeble-minded: Mother _.. ! 1 1| 2 1 3 3 14 Brother _ i 1 1 ..._. 1 ..._. 1 Insane: Father ...._ I 1 1 _ 1 1 Mother 1 1 _ 1 ..._. 1 Intemperate: Father 16 11 27 3 3 13 10 23 32 21 53 Both parents 1 2 3 , ...- 2 2 3 2 5 Delinquent: Father ..._ 57 12 145 336 9 14 23 Mother 2 2 2 2 8 5 13 12 5 17 Both parents 20 15 35 16 8 24 28 36 64 64 59 123 Brother 2 2 1 1 ' i 3 3 Sister 1 1 1 1 : 2 2 Unknown _... i 2 2 2 2 Totals... : 48 35 83 27 14 41 54 57 111 129 106 235 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">538 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF B1ENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All Dec.1,12 July 1, 13 ending Total Remaining COUNTY to to Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, Jub.30,13 Nov.30.13 1914 Biennium 1914 MFTMFTMFT MFT MFT Adams 12 3 2 2 4 2 .... 2 5 4 9 2 13 Antelope _ _... j .... 1 1 1 1 Blaine 1 .... 1 1 1 Jefferson 2 2 4 1 .... 13 2 5 3 2 5 Johnson 2 2 _... 112 13 4 Keya Paha .... 1 1 1 1 1 i Lancaster 10 12 22 2 1 3 1 3 4 13 16 29 6 7 13 Lincoln _ _ .... 1 1 1 1 l l Madison _ ...„ 1 .... 1 1 ...„. 1 1 l Otoe ..._ _ 8 .... 3 11 3 1 4 ' 2 2 Pierce ..._ _ 1 1 1 1 1 1 Polk ..._ 3 14 415 729 516 Red Willow 1 .... 112 3 2 2 4 112 Richardson 1 .... 1112 1 .... 13 14 1 1 Rock 1 .... 1 1 ..._ 1 1 1 ..._. 1 Scotts Bluff ! 1 1 2 I 1 1 2 1 1 2 Seward ..._ .... _... j .... 8 8! 3 3 2 2 2 2 2 ..._. 2 1 ..... 1 1 1 12 3 North Dakota ! .... 1 1 1 II. 1 1 South Dakota _... .... 1 1 ...... 1 1 1 1 Canada I ..._ .... 1 !!..._. 1 !,..._. 1 1 Totals 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 200 64 60 124 Box Butte... 1 .... 1 _.._ 1 Buffalo 1 1 1 Butler 2 2 2 Cedar _ 2 4 6 2 4 Cherry _ 2 .... 2 1 .... 1 3 Cheyenne 112 11 Clay _ ..._ 213336 5 4 Custer 12 3 ..._ 1 .... 12 2 Douglas 4 15 3 .... 3 6 13 19 13 14 Dundy 1 .... 1 ..._ _ 1 Fillmore _.._ 4 .... 4 4 Franklin 14 6 i 1 4 Gage 1 .... 1224516 8 3 Garfield 1 1 .... 1 Hall 2 13 4 1 5 10 8 18 16 10 Hamilton ..._ _.._ 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 _ 6 2 4 6 3 2 112 9 3 3 6 4 1 ..... 1 27 10 14 24 1 1 ..... 1 4 4 ... 4 5 ... 2 2 11 3 2 5 1 26 11 8 19 1 1 1 .herman ..._ ,_ ..... I 1 .... 1 ! _... ; Sheridan 1 1 j 1 .. "hayer - I _ 2 2.. "hernias i _ _ 2 13 fork _ 1 .... 1 i Wisconsin _ .. 1 .... 1 _ _ .. Cansas 12 3 ...- _... Missouri _... 1 .... 1 1 ..._. 1 ...-. 2 2 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 1 2 3 1 1 3 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 539 TABLE XI. CHARACTER OF ADMISSION For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Permanent — by de- cree of court 25 18 43 14 11 25 40 42 82 79 71 150 Temporary — by contract: With parent 9 9 18 3 2 5 6 4 10 18 15 33 With county. By order of court 22 527 448 98 17 Totals..- 34 29 63 22 15 37 50 50 100 106 94 200 TABLE XII. DISTRIBUTION OF CHILDREN AT END OF BIEN- NIUM NOV. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium Dec. 1. '12 to A. ending Nov. 30, 14 MFT In home building.... i 112 In boarding homes _ _ - I 37 19 56 In trial homes _ _.._ - - - 92 72 164 Totals. _.._ _ - -.- 130 92 222 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">540 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIII. APPLICATIONS FOR ADMISSION Applications for admission.... _ _ j i I 489 Admitted _..... 50 ! Males _.._ 27 . I . I Females _ _ 28 Not admitted ..._ _.._ 171 Parents persuaded to keep i 72 Family homes secured under parents' supervision i 19 Position secured for mother with child | 10 _ Referred to county commissioners 25 Referred to court...- ! 2 - _. . . Referred to Orthopedic Hospital i 1 Placed with relatives...- . 4 — Pregnant women - 11 ~~_ __ Sent to Milford Industrial Home 4 . I Family home secured 4 _. Marriage _. 1 [ — Referred to C. O. S 2 | Applications withdrawn ~ 27 | ' I — 'ermanent care _. ..._ 288 Admitted _.._ _ _ 160 Males _.._ _ _ TO Females _ _ 71 Not admitted j . 118 . Parents persuaded to keep _ _ | 68 Family homes secured under parents' supervision „ 4 .— ... __ __ Referred to court _ 8 Referred to C. O. S „ _. 1 Sent to other institutions _. 11 Placed in homes by court _ _. 9 Aged people— information and advice given in securing homes _. 12 .'. _. Applications withdrawn after being advised _ _ _. 10 ""emporary care 223 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 541 TABLE XIV. PHYSICAL CONDITION OF CHILDREN WHEN ADMITTED Normal — _ - 25 Normal — _ - 25 Indigestion (acute) 1 Indigestion (acute) 1 Adenoids 89 Adenoids 89 Jaundice 1 Jaundice 1 Anaemia ..._ _ _ 46 Anaemia ..._ _ 46 Kidney (congestion) 3 Kidney (congestion) 3 Bladder (congestion) 46 Bladder (congestion) 46 Leucorrhea _ _ 1 Leucorrhea _ _ 1 Bowel (inflamation)..._ 1 Bowel (inflamation)..._ 1 Measles _ _... 1 Measles _ _... 1 Birthmark 3 Birthmark 3 Pediculi capita..... 41 Pediculi capitis...- 41 Bronchitis 4 Bronchitis 4 Rupture 3 Rupture 3 Catarrh _.._ _ 2 Catarrh _.._ _ 2 Rickets _ _ 3 Rickets _ _ 3 Chorea _ _ 1 Chorea _ _ 1 Scabies _ 2 Scabies „ 2 Cough (chronic) 2 Cough (chronic) 2 Scarlet fever _ 2 Scarlet fever _ 2 Club feet _ _ _... 1 Club feet _ _ _... 1 Spinal curvature 2 Spinal curvature 2 Defective speech 8 Defective speech 8 Syphilis ..._ 4 Syphilis ..._ 4 Teeth ( bad condition; cavities) _ 22 Teeth ( bad condition; Enuresis 4 Enuresis 4 Erythema ..._ 11 Erythema ..._ 11 cavities) _ 22 Eczema _ 2 Eczema _ 2 Tuberculosis (bone) _ 1 Tuberculosis (bone) „ 1 Enter-colitis _ 1 Enter-colitis _ 1 Tonsils (enlarged) _ _ 14 Tonsils (enlarged) _ _ 14 Ear (chronic discharge) _... 4 Ear (chronic discharge) _... 4 Thrush _ 7 Thrush _ _.._ _... 7 Eyes _ _.._ 31 Eyes _ _.._ 31 Operations Adenoids _ 80 Operations Amblyopia 1 Amblyopia 1 Blepharitis 1 Adenoids _ 80 Blepharitis 1 Appendicitis 1 Appendicitis 1 Conjunctivitis 10 Conjunctivitis 10 Bow legs _ _ 1 Bow legs _ _ 1 Cross 1 Cross 1 Broken arm _ 1 Broken arm _ _ 1 Ophthalmia neonatorum 6 Ophthalmia neonatorum 6 Circumcisions ..._ 6 Circumcisions ..._ 6 Strain 8 Strain 8 Clipping tongue „ 3 Clipping tongue „ 3 Specific Keratitis 2 Specific Keratitis 2 Ingrowing toe-nail „... 3 Ingrowing toe-nail „... 3 Trachoma 2 Trachoma 2 Lancing of glands _ 2 Lancing of glands _ 2 Glasses supplied 29 Glasses supplied..— _ 29 Loosening adherent fore - skin _.._ 17 Loosening adherent fore- Goiter _ _.._ 6 Goiter _ _.._ 6 skin _.._ 17 Gonorrhea ..._ _ 2 Gonorrhea ..._ _ _... 2 Sewing incised wounds 2 Sewing incised wounds 2 Heart (organic and weakness) 34 Heart (organic and weakness) 34 Tapping hydrocele 1 Tapping hydrocele...- 1 Herpes zoster 1 Herpes zoster 1 Tapping spinal canal 2 Tapping spinal canal _ 2 Intertrigo 8 Intertrigo 8 Total operations 119 Total operations 119 "A child's whole physical future is usually determined by the condi - tions surrounding its first few years of life." — The Child. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">542 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XV. APPLICATIONS TO TAKE CHILDREN M F T Boys _.._ _ _ 63 63 Girls _ _ _ _.._ _ _ 74 74 Baby boys - _ _ | 31 3t Baby girls _ __ i . 47 47 Totals _.._ _ ! 94 121 215 TABLE XVI. FIELD WORK DURING BIENNIUM Traveling — Number of miles traveled by rail and livery 73,007 Rail _ 68,927 Livery _ „ _... 4,080 Railway fare and livery expense | $ 2,077.00 Incidental traveling expense 346.88 Street car tickets „ 230.00 Cash street car fares i 65.65 Total _ i % 2,720.47 M F Total Children — Placed in homes for adoption 97 106 203 Placed in free home* _.._ \ 3 9 12 Returned from homes 30 42 72 Removed from homes 1 1 Transferred from one home to another 2 1 3 Left homes in which placed j 2 1 3 Visits to children _ I 2710 Homes etc — Number visited in which children have been placed 1677 Prospective homes visited. 312 Special cases investigated _ I 471 County or Juvenile Court Sessions attended 71 Schools visited 131 Other institutions visited in interest of work _ I 27 County officials visited in interest of work. _ j 98 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Asylum for the Insane of Nebraska, Ingleside _ 201 Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, Lincoln 1 Girls' Industrial School, Geneva 123 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln 519 Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk 299 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney 365 Institute for the Blind, Nebraska City 465 Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln 245 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 447 Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, Beatrice 101 Nebraska School for the Deaf, Omaha 499 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Burkett 161 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 369 Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford 189 State Industrial School, Kearney 139 State Penitentiary, Lincoln 401 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>