<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirteenth Annual Report of the State Fire Marshall for the Year 1921</title>
               <date value="1922-01-01">1922-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">• 1 ! STATE OF NEBRASKA i • ; Department of Trade and Commerce • DIVISION OF KIRK PREVENTION THIRTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT of the I State Fire Marshal For the Year 192 I I C. E. Hartford State Fire Marshal E. E. Hayduk F. F. Dowling L. J. Butcher Inspector Inspector Eva V. Anderson Clerk and Stenographer i i H. J. Hauser Deputy Fire Marshal E. E. Hayduk Inspector </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">THIRTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE FIRE MARSHAL OF STATE OF NEBRASKA Office of the State Fire Marshal State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. January 1st, 1922. To His Excellency. S. R. McKelvie, Governor of the State of Nebraska : Dear Sir: — In compliance with the law in this state, I herewith submit to you the thirteenth annual report of the Division of Fire Prevention. During the past year this department has used every effort to reduce the fire loss of Nebraska. We understand fire prevention is a subject which must be popularized with the people before the best possible results can be obtained. Our aim has been to so popularize the subject as one of vital im - portance to every one in the state so each individual will feel a personal responsibility in conserving life and property from destruction by fire. First of all, by bulletins published each month on preva - lent causes of fire and how to prevent them, we have endeavor - ed to awaken an interest in the unnecessary fire waste, and have tried to have each community work with the end in view of having their town take pride in having the lowest fire record in the state. A total of 314 cities and towns have been thoroughly in - spected during the year. A small number of these towns have been gone over the second time. If our inspection force had been sufficient each town could have been inspected at least twice during the year and in my opinion, the more often inspections are made, the greater the good accomplished. During the year 22,016 inspections were made and 13,419 orders issued for the correction of minor defects that appeared necessary to the inspector. The gasoline and kerosene haaard </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION is the most deplorable of all fire dangers because in nearly every gasoline or kerosene fire, lives are destroyed. A report of the work in the Division of Fire Prevention is hereby respectfully submitted for your information. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. INSPECTIONS b Three regular inspectors are employed by this office who vote their time to inspection of business buildings in towns roughout the state. In addition to the regular inspectors, we have employed two men to do inspection work only a por - tion of the year. Each inspector has a territory to cover and fills out the regular inspection blank for each building in - spected. When the hazard is particularly disastrous or dan - gerous, or the owner or occupant, refuses to comply with the order of the inspector, or the conditions seem doubtful that compl ance will be effected, special notice is sent from this office, upsn recommendation of the inspector. During the year 1921, our i«cords show 314 cities and towns were in - spected. This made a total of 22,016 inspections, and fire prevention orders were issued during the inspection work, amounting to 13,419 orders. E. E. Hayduk, our inspector at Omaha, after inspecting places of business and issuing orders, makes a reinspection a couple of weeks later to see that all orders are complied with. During the past year Mr. Hayduk made 4,853 inspections in the C ty of Omaha, and issued orders on 1,134 inspection trips, all of which were reported complied with. FIRE CHIEFS REPORT FIRES The promptness of the fire chief in reporting fires to this office assists us in our work of investigation and their interest in attend ng to many matters which we request has done much to make this department a success while the law provides a penalty if fire chief or mayors where the town has no fire chi«f , </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 5 do not report promptly to this department, every fire occurring in their city or village, yet in many cases these officials are not reporting fires to this office as the law provides. However, I do wish to report that we have been furnished with reports of fires on 1,481 fires during 1921, aggregating a total loss of $2,164,042.09. This is over $500,000 less than the fire loss reported for 1920. NEWS BULLETIN This office issues a news bulletin each month giving the items of interest in connection with this work which is pub - lished and circulated to the fire chiefs, newspapers of the state, special agents of insurance companies, the fire insurance com - panies, all the fire marshals in the U. S., and a large miscel - laneous list of interested parties who have requested that their names be placed on our mailing list. Last year this time our mailing list totalled 1,200. At this time it totals 1,800. While the time has been limited to prepare copy for this bulletin, we have endeavored to compile some tables each month showing the inspections made, orders issued and totalling the number of fires and the amount of losses, as well as loss of life, etc. In addition to this, a list of the buildings on which complaint has been filed in this office requesting condemnation or extensive repair, is also published which furnishes information to the insurance companies regarding property on which they often find they have policies. We believe that the people have a right to know what is being done and from reports received from numerous sources, we feel it is appreciated. FIRES INVESTIGATED We have been called upon during the past year to make investigation of what were reported to be suspicious circum - stances in connection with 90 fires. In addition to the arrests made, there are many cases still in the hands of the county attorney for consideration as a result of the investigations made by this department. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 6 In the matter of gathering evidence, we have exercised the greatest care that no innocent person should suffer but when we are satisfied a crime has been committed, we have done everything within our power to bring the guilty ones to justice without fear or favor. We have also made it a prac - tice to not burden the county attorney with evidence gathered unless there is evidence tending to show that a crime has been committed. The request for the investigation of suspicious fires the past year have been many more than ever bef ore and is causing alarm all over the state. LI desire to call your attention to the great number of fires unknown origin in which the loss was more than 16H per ,t. This should awaken the people to the great importance of eliminating gross carelessness, better fighting facilities, and also, the great need of a larger department for investigation and inspection purposes, especially during the readjustment FIRE ESCAPES We have been successful in having installed quite a num - ber of fire escapes during the past year. The fire inspector serves a notice on the party responsible for non-compliance with the law and sends a duplicate to this office. All school buildings, two or more stories in height, hotels, stores, fac - tories, etc. should be equipped with proper fire escapes as re - quired by the Nebraska statutes. A special effort has been made during the year to require the school buildings of this state to be safeguarded as the statute inquires. CONDEMNATION AND REPAIR OF BUILDINGS Nebraska is not yet an old state, however, owing to the rapid and experimental growth of a great many of the cities and villages, and on account of lack of funds to have a more substantial building during the past year, a number of the older buildings have become badly dilapidated and dangerous </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 7 from a fire standpoint. Whenever we have found this class of buildings, if they can be put in reasonably safe condition we hi.ve ordered th«m repaired, but where they were not worth repairing and could not be made reasonably safe, we have ordered them condemned. Not however, until the in - teiested parties have had due notice and an ample opportunity given them to be heard, has this been done. After the finding has been made by personally inspecting the building, the owner is gent a notice of finding which notifies him just what must be done with his property and the amount of time allowed for compliance. Alter the time for compliance has expired and the owner fuses or ignores the order, the papers are placed in the hands the county attorney with instructions to commence prose- cution During 1921. 635 complaints were filed requesting con- demm:tion or repair of buildings. Out of this number our record shows 191 buildings of this number which have been oved or wrecked, 132 buildings repaired and put in good ■tape and 5 complaints dismissed as complaints were unwar - ran' «d and unjust. There are remaining on our books 307 complaints which are still pending by reason of unexpired time, unreported ;:ction, or by reason of finding not yet having been made. I, OSS OF LIFE AND INJURIES I regret to report that during the past year our records show that 28 lives were lost through fire in this state, and 21 persons were reported to have been injured through fire. Most ot these accidents and deaths have been through gasoline or kerosene explosions. Detailed accounts of these casualties will appear later in this report. I herewith respectfully submit the thirteenth annual re - port of the Division of Fire Prevention showing the work ac - complished during 1921. The preceding topics touched on give a synopsis of the various phases of the work and the following part of the report </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 tdeal in further detail with these subjects as well as other prevention articles and suggestions. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal FIRE PREVENTION tFire Prevention should be studied from infancy. The ndation of fire prevention is through inspection followed good housekeeping which tends to eliminate gross careless- blf we would follow the practice of the foreign countries ? closely, we would soon see the fire waste reduced one - of what it is today. Lin the United States the yearly loss is about $3 per capita, following table shows what it is in the foreign countries : t What's the reason? The law of France provides that ry individual is responsible and liable for any acts of his which any other person sustains any loss by damage or in - y, through carelessness or negligence. This means that if a fire starts on any premises through gross carelessness or through fault of the owner or tenant, all damage done to neighboring property by that fire must be made good. There is no limit to the liability which may extend to an entire block in case of a conflagration. Belgium ? &gt;1.02 iussia .97 France .74 England .64 Norway .55 taly .53 rapan .51 Sweden \ustria .42 .32 Germany .28 Netherlands .11 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 9 In Germany they even go further than that. The owner or tenant and also the previous owner or even contractor is held. If the fault is in the construction or was known to exist by the former owner and sold without knowledge to the owner of the property at the time of fire, and if it can be proven that the present owner or tenant had knowledge of defects and they failed to remedy same, they are also held responsible. They not only forfeit their insurance but are made to pay the expense of extinguishing the fire and an extra penalty for their neglect. A like law applies to other foreign countries In this country the general practice is, to write all the in - surance the assured requests and when a fire occurs the com - pany often rushes to the loss and pays it without any question and frequently advertises the fact of quick settlement to sell more insurance. Why not hold a person liable for damages if he allows a fire to start through his own carelessness, the same as though he injures someone by some other act of carelessness. Make the same law apply to the owners of fire hazards that you do to cities or corporations and you have solved the problem of Fire Prevention. FARM FIRE WAGONS On any farm where there are a number of valuable build - ings or where considerable quantities of grain and hay are stacked within moderate distance of the barnyard, a twenty - five or fifty gallon chemical tank, mounted on wheels and pro - vided with a good length of hose, would be a valuable asset. A push cart or an old cultivator would furnish inexpensive running gears, if a suitable tank could be procured to mount upon it. This fire wagon should be located as centrally as possible and on a moment's notice could be run to the scene of the fire. SPECIAL GARAGE HAZARDS Many of the garages are of the poorest sort of construe- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 UiVioiOrJ Or rIKK PREVENTION tion, old livery barns and store buildings and buildings of every conceivable kind, which have hastily been commandeered so to speak, in order to meet the needs of the hour. Many of these have wooden floors which in time become thoroughly saturated with oil. It has been part of our work to try to eliminate these hazards as quickly as we can reach them, but as I said above, due to the excessive demand for housing Eilities of the ever increasing automobile industry, many ke shifts have been resorted to in the way of buildings and lipment. All garages should be of fire proof construction with either cement or dirt floors which should never be lower than the end of the grade that all wiring therein should be in conduit and that every precaution should be taken to safeguard these places where so much value is accumulated. Because of location to the business center of the community, we very often find living apartments, moving picture theatres and other places of public assemblage over garages with very inadequate facilities provided for in case of emergency. DRY CLEANING ESTABLISHMENT In many of the smaller towns and some larger ones the ork of cleaning is done in a very crude way, without the wners or operators having provided modern machinery or laving taken any of the ordinary precautions to safeguard leir work, with no apparent realization of the danger they lave brought to themselves, and those surrounding them. I lave gone into dry cleaning establishments and found tubs of asoline used for washing clothes standing in the open. FILLING STATION The automobile industry has brought another hazard which it would be well for us to look into, that of the ordinary filling station. Most of the tanks however, I am very glad to say are of metal buried in the ground and the filling is done in the open, through the pumps. This type is probably as safe as it is possible to make them. All motors should be </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 stopped while cars are being filled with gasoline. Neither is smoking or matches permitted around the filling station. We have a supply of these cards printed, and will be glad to fur - nish them to any garage or filling station that will request them. GASOLINE DISPENSERS The gasoline dispensers must meet the requirements and bear the underwriters' label. They should have an inter - locking device concealed in the body of the pump where they cannot be reached or tampered with. We favor an air pres - sure filling device. All motors should be totally enclosed It should be moisture and liquid proof. A totally enclosed cast iron housing which is liquid and vapor proof should be provided for both motor and light switches. INSURANCE COMPANIES The business of fire insurance is simply that of collecting money from policy holders and distributing certain amounts to those sustaining loss and the only way to reduce the pre - miums is to reduce the losses which can be done by real Fire Prevention activities. The office of the state fire marshal is devoting all it's time to inspection work and the prosecution of those who set fire by design. While there is a close relation - ship between the insurance companies and state fire marshal's office, there is also a close relationship between the state fire marshal and the property owners as the ultimate results will be and must be the reduction of the fire premiums or assess - ments paid. As the liability decreases, the cost of insurance must also decrease, and we know that fire conditions have changed for the better all over the state through the effects of this office. Over-insurance is the cause of practically every case of arson that we have investigated. We absolutely know that every fire insurance company pays it's honest losses gladly but we have deplored the fact that they have so often been called upon to pay dishonest losses. For the maintenance of the fire marshal's office, every insurance company with the ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Eition of Farmers Mutuals are required to pay to the state asurer of Nebraska annually three-eighths of one per cent their net fire premiums realized from business written in braska. This year the amount of fire marshal tax paid for &gt; maintenance of this office amounted to over $24,000. CARELESS NEIGHBORS tlf your careless neighbors knowingly harbor a defective raney, a rubbish filled basement, a trash laden attic, defec - s electric wiring, stoves installed so as to endanger wood - •k, or are careless in using gasoline or storing of oils, oily ste and rags, then he is not interested in the safety of his 1 property and family and the lives of the firemen. It is refore, your duty to warn him and to notify the proper horities. Such a man needs discipline, not sympathy in e he has a fire. WHY TAKE A CHANCE WITH GASOLINE I Why take a chance ? Gasoline vapor is heavier than air. lsequently, it will float along on the ground and may carry rty feet or more and under favorable conditions, ignite. e gallon of gasoline has substantially power equal to eighty - ee to eighty-three and two-thirds pounds of dynamite, soline will give off 130 times its bulk in vapor and when wrized will convert 1,560 times its volume of air into an ex - sive mixture which will ignite from a flame or spark. Five Ions of gasoline will generate 8,000 cubic feet of gas or •ugh to fill a room 20x40 feet and ten feet high. When ited, it immediately expands to four thousands times that ce. This would cause a most terrific explosion. FIRE PREVENTION DAY November 4, 1921 E November 4th was observed in Nebraska as patriotic Fire vention Day. Governor Samuel R. McKelvie caused to be •ed a splendid proclamation which is reproduced here. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 State Fire Day Proclamation by the Governor Fire and water are two elements that are of the most im - portance and the greatest blessings to humanity ; when prop - erly harnessed and controlled, they contribute to the welfare of society and without them we could not exist. But when permitted to escape /rom proper environments they soon begin the work of destruction and consume and destroy without mercy. Conscious of these facts, organizations have been formed in order to overcome as far as possible the spread of these destructive agents. The enormous waste by fire each year calls for sounding the alarm in order to arouse the people of all classes to the necessity of greater care in preventing fire. It is much easier and very much more expedient to prevent a fiie than it is to extinguish it after it has once started. The State has set apart a day for the special study of fire prevention and the State Fire Commissioner issues and distributes each year a pamphlet or bulletin giving instructions on the subject and rules for fire drills in the public schools so that people are left without excuse if they suffer as much from the fury of the flames in the future as they have in the past. NOW THEREFORE, I, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of the State of Nebraska, do hereby call special attention to the day which the Legislature has set apart as State Fire Day, which occurs this year on Friday, November 4, and urge its observance by all the people, especially by the schools, public, parochial, and private, throughout the State, as provided by law and made mandatory on the part of school directors and trustees. Let us do everything possible to save ourselves from the awful destruction of life and property by fire. Witness my hand and the Great Seal of the State of Ne - braska, this twentieth day of September, in the year of our Lord, 1921. By the Governor: SAMUEL R. McKELVIE, DARIUS M. AMSBURY, (SEAL) Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 14 I This department sent out thousands of pamphlets and letins for use on November 4th. They were sent to mayors, : chiefs, school superintendents and teachers, business men's ranizations, etc. Besides serving the purpose of general )lic education, the observance of fire prevention day, should the starting point of some definite activity during the corn - year. Let it be an agitation for an ordinance requiring ;ular fire department inspections and removal of rubbish, ter fire fighting equipment, improvement of water supply, the adoption of a fire prevention by-law, carrying with it the appointment of an official who shall be empowered to en - force it or whatever is necessary according to local require - ments. tThe holding of Fire Prevention meetings, the public in - tion of property by members of the fire department, boy ts and other citizens, and the observance of fire prevention by appropriate exercises in the schools, were urged as a part of the general plan for a state wide 365 day fire prevention year. The clergy cun be of inestimable value in the fight against careless fires and can help reduce the enormous loss of life. A half hour can be pleasantly as well as profitably spent at Cetings cf woman's clubs. An address by an insurance man y elucidate the perplexing questions why our town is rated in a certain class and what should be done to reduce the pre - mium rate. Presidents of social, labor, public and private organizations, fire chiefs, boys and girls, can all help in the interest oi fire prevention. You can help to save life and property from the needless fire destruction. In 1021 fire caused more than 15,000 lives and $500,000,000. Clean your premises. Remove rubbish, correct your hazards and cultivate carefulness. Most fires are preventable. Begin now upon a plan of action and con - tinue to make every day fire prevention day by assuring in - divually the responsibility of removing or preventing con - ditions which may cause fire. Aggressive action is needed. Almost all towns and cities put out questionnaires through the </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 15 schools for home inspections and the day was spent in cleaning up and in many instances the fire department assisted in moving the rubbish after it had been conveyed to a convenient place. Most of the public schools observed the day with suit - able programs or addresses. C. E. Hartford, State Fire Marshal, lined up speakers fot 45 Nebraska towns and cities to speak to the school children regarding fire prevention on Fire Prevention Day, November 4th. The speakers were as follows : C. E. Hartford, State Fire Marshal, Nebraska City H. J. Hauser, Deputy Fire Marshal, Wahoo K. B. Hayduk, Fire Inspector, Plattsmouth F. F. Dowling, Fire Inspector, Long Pine L. J. Butcher, Fire Inspector, Lexington Eva Anderson, Bethany Rev. W. C. Rundin, Scottsbluff C. R. Frasier, North Platte John Martin, Scribner 0. W. Rhoades, Bridgeport H. A. Webbert, Kearney H. A. Graff, Seward F. B. Tobin, Sidney J. W. Guthrie, Alliance L VV. Hague, Minden H. C. Boyes, Hebron Chas. McCloud, York W. P. McCune, Norfolk Royal C. Smith, Chadron A. W. Sprague, Crawford Floyd M. Berry, McCook E. H. Lutt, Niobrara W. R. Bruce, Fire Chief, Broken Bow Roy H. Boyd, Fire Chief, Central City Prof. Saunders, Thedford V. A. Nenow, Pierce A. J. Shirley, Fire Chief, Ord </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION R. D. Flory, County Attorney, Albion M. Miller, David City S. M. Darvis, County Judge, Arthur F. R. Hogedorn, County Judge, Stapleton T. W. Hull, County Judge, Venango Tom Dillon, Fire Chief, Grand Island Harry Whiteside, Fire Chief, Beatrice J. C. Elliott, County Attorney, West Point John McKay, Blair F. M. Herrington, O'Neill T. O. Ringer, Fire Chief, Tilden E. Jno. Slaker, President Woman's Club, Hastings . L. B. Curron, President Woman's Club, Palmer . M. Douglas, President Woman's Club, Elmwood Mrs. E. J. Mitchell, President Woman's Club, Deshler Mrs. Edna E. Gake, President Woman's Club, Beaver Crossing On October 26th, Mr. John M. Matzen, State Superin - tendent, mailed out the following letter to the superintendents of schools ; in the towns designated to have speakers : "My dear Superintendent : Someone has said, h 'Every boy and girl who would be a good citizen should to protect his community and his country against loss If we can impress upon the school children the importance of exercising care and consideration in fire prevention and the causes for most of the fires, it will materially lessen this public peril and to this extent make of them good citizens. In compliance with the State Fire Day law we mailed under date of October 15 suggested programs and literature to county superintendents from whom you no doubt have re - ceived the same, to be used in the observance in the schools of Fire Prevention Day, Friday, November 4. tMr. C. E. Hartford, State Fire Marshal, has arranged to speakers, who will address the school children on Fire ention on the day named above in forty-five towns and </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 cities, and yours has been designated as one of these. The speaker named for your locality will take up this matter direct with vou. The purpose of this communication is to let you know that this department is heartily in favor of Mr. Hartford's plan. I bespeak for him your hearty cooperation, and trust that Fire Day, Friday, November 4, will be fittingly observed in your schools. Yours very truly, JOHN M. MATZEN, State Superintendent. SPRING CLEAN UP The 1921 clean up week was without doubt the most suc - cessful in the history of the department. The first week in April was spring clean up week. Nebraska had a good spring house cleaning and thousands of dollars worth of rubbish, worthless and useless in attics, cellars and store rooms, were sold and the proceeds in many instances devoted to the pur - chase of seeds, flowers, paint, etc. SUMMER FIRES Watch your outdoor fire. Engine sparks, bonfires, cigarettes, cigar stubs, and flying brands reap their summer toll. Weeds are cut and burned. Corners are cleaned out, and outdoor fires lighted by campers, fishermen and land owners. Keep weeds and grass cleared away from elevators, barns, etc Railways should do their part and farmers should plow furrows between their right of way, fences, and the ripening grain. Keep the children away from the outdoor fire. Remember that a grass fire will outrun a horse. A fire during the summer is more serious possibly than at any other season of the year. Guard all roofs from sparks. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 The fire proof roofing is coming into prominence more and more. OVER INSURANCE I It is well known by the underwriters that over insurance r en indiscriminately is a breeder of arson, says Fire Marshal rtford. The Fire Marshal holds to the theory that agents, &gt;kers and solicitors play an important part in every insur - :e transaction, and that in fixing liability, upon companies, sy owe a duty to the public which should not be overlooked the race for the little commission on the premium. Arson 'estigators for the Fire Marshal's department have been tructed to examine under oath, agents, brokers and solici - ■s, responsible for placing over insurance, and to determine whether they either intentionally or negligently aided and abetted in crime by granting insurance above values. The facts of such investigation are to be made a matter of record in the Fire Marshal's office. Publicity such as this, would tend to reduce the crime of arson. No smoking should be permitted around the oil filling station, and all automobile drivers should stop their engines while their cars are being filled. This office has on hand Some printed cards to be placed in filling stations and will be glad to furnish same to all parties requesting same. Hand chemicals should be kept handy and every precaution taken to make a station safe for life and property. • Secretary Meredith says. Nearly 80,000 cigarettes and 500,000 matches are consumed each minute, day and night by the American public. Never neglect precautions. Put out your matches and your smokes before throwing them away. Hunters, fisherman and woodworkers of all kinds smoke in the forest while the automobilist tosses a bit of fire from the cars and speeds thoughtlessly on unaware that they have left an incipient conflagration behind them. A single glowing cigarette stub may cost the government thousands of dollars SMOKING </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 19 for fire fighting, to say nothing of the value of the timber destroyed. SPECIAL WARNINGS 4th of July — Safe and Sane One Celebration for Independence Day, generally speaking, was a success as reports all show and the number of comments from various sources throughout the state regarding the noticeable change and the scarcity of fires as well. There has been very little if any reports of fires from this source. However, we regret to report that firecrackers caused two children to be injured. One June 29th, little Wilma Johnson, living near Burchard came very close to death's door as a result of putting a torpedo into her mouth and exploding it be - tween her teeth. The six-year-old girl was playing near some boys who were shooting off fireworks of various sorts when the accident happened. She found a hand torpedo which had been thrown by someone, but had not exploded. Innocently, she put it into her mouth and bit it, causing the cap to go off. The force of the combustion mutilated her lips badly and forced a stone down her throat and she swallowed the poisonous smoke. For over 24 hours she lay hovering between life and death, but the efforts of those at hand finally saved her. She is now well on the way to recovery. On July 1st, Raymond Wiegand of Petersburg was severe - ly injured when hit by a ball of fire thrown from a Roman candle. He was playing on the street corner and the boys were shooting Roman candles. In order to frighten the young fellow, Vern Claar held a Roman candle toward him with the result that one of the balls of fire struck him in the left eye. Claar was arrested and placed under bond to wait develop - ments. Raymond was taken to Albion where the injured eye was dressed, and this probably resulted in the loss of his eye. FIRE PREVENTION DURING HOLIDAYS It is our desire to call to your attention certain hazards increased by the holiday decoration. Merchants decorate </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION tir stores and windows more elaborately than any other e of the year and nearly always these decorations are of inflamable nature. The Christmas tree should be set up securely so that it will not easily topple over and it should be located several feet away from your heat or light fixtures. Toys involving the use of alcohol, gasoline or kerosene, should be avoided and low priced electrical playthings should be viewed with suspicion since they often are insecurely wired and flimsily constructed. Another important safeguard is to re - move all evergreen immediately after Christmas before they become completely dried out. Only one accident has come to our attention during Christ - mas of 1921, resulting from candles igniting a Santa Claus robe. This occurred at Pleasantdale when Prof. N. Clav Null, superintendent of the Pleasantdale schools, was sei at the close of a Christmas program given in the school \ for the grade pupils, while playing the part of Santn Claus s 1 Is robe catching fire from the Eth candles. To avoid a pan ilding, Prof. Null walked ou' flames. He was badly burned before teachers who came to hi Christmas tree whicl t- UK Miss Riley and Mrs. Eberspachei 1 displayed great hero t ht when they hurried to the aid of the superintendent their efforts the flames were put out, but the two received painful bums. So cooly and quickly did the superintendent act, that scarcely anybody in the large audience knew what had haj pened. A serious panic might have occurred but for the cool- headedness of the superintendent. Prof. Null was cared for by Dr. Williams, who said later that his patient would recover and would be able to resume his duties within a few weeks. "My advice to other schools," said Prof. Null, "is this: 'don't light candles on your Christmas tree when you have a Santa Claus around.' " During the past year thousands of the little Safety First cards were sent out as warnings to guard against fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 21 SAFETY FIRST Better Safe than sorry by keeping the "Home Fires from Burning. The cost of fires each year in Nebraska averages more than $2,O&lt; &gt;().(►(&gt;(». Lives lost in the U. S. 15,000 per year. Have you taken every precaution to safeguard your home ajrainst fire? Don't permit rubbish to accumulate in basements, work - shops or anywhere about the premises. Clean propertj seldom burns. Don't burn trash, brush or rubbish near buildings, fences her property, nor permit children to do so. Don't keep ashes in wooden boxes or deposit them against ien buildings or partitions. Keep in non-combustible re- eptacl Don't change your electric wiring without consulting ompetent electrician. Don't hang electric light cords on nails. Don't fail to take precautions with electric irons and al - ; use with signal light. Don't fail to place metal protection under all stoves and &gt;rotect woodwork where stoves or furnaces are close to walls. Don't pass stove pipes through ceilings, roofs or wooden partitions. Don't neglect to have all flues cleaned, examined and re paired at least once each year. Don't fail to provide screen for open fireplaces. Don't connect gas stoves, heaters or hot places with rubber hose. Don't use gasoline or benzine to cleanse clothing near an open flame, light or fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Don't use kerosene, benzine or naptha in lighting fires or to quicken a slow fire. Don't use liquid polishes near open lights. Many such compounds contain volatile inflammable oils. Don't thaw frozen water pipes by applying a torch or open flame of any kind. Wrap pipes loosely with cloths and pour on hot water, or send for a plumber. I Don't allow children to play with matches. Keep matches closed metal box. Don't go into closets with lighted matches or candles. Don't fail to remember that there is always danger in the discarded cigarette and cigar stub. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal, Lincoln. STOP BURNING UP HOMES The housing problem is one of the greatest issues of the day. All unnecessary construction was forbidden during the war and now that the restrictions have been withdrawn the high prices of materials and labor and industrial troubles have tended to reduce the amount of building. In many industrial centers newcomers are unable to get houses to live in. Rents have increased and the situation has become so serious that state and municipal commissioners are seeking a solution. Why not stop burning up the existing buildings, since there are not enough to go around and more cannot be built under existing conditions. Thousands of homes are burned each month, most of them through carelessness. If housing is so important, and homes so hard to find, why not be careful about matches, smoking, lighting and heating apparatus. Also gasoline, rubbish, flues and the shingle roof. Conservation is the order of the day and if the shortage of dwellings will cause householders to be careful about the fire hazards of their homes, our criminal cause of that shortage will be greatly re- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 23 HEATING About 65 Tr of all fires that occur in our nation annually, are dwelling house fires. More than 40% of these fires are strictly preventable and 12.4% of these originate from de - fective flues and another 7.3% from stoves, furnaces, boilers and their pipes. Remember that these fires are strictly preventable, that their origin is due to carelessness, ignorance and neglect, be - cause somebody failed in their responsibility by not inspecting and keeping in repair the heating plant, stove, flues or chimneys. Free your own home from these hazards by making a careful inspection of all heating devices. Examine all metal smoke flues running the heater and the chimney to see that they have not rusted through from corrosion and see that all joints are tight. If found defective they should be repaired or replaced at once. LAST LEGISLATIVE SESSION A great portion of the time of the officers of this depart - ment has been devoted to the investigation of the sources of fires in several of the prominent as well as the smaller com - munities, which have suffered from fiery visitations. How - ever, we have inspected and investigated the origin and cause of these fires and have felt keenly the limitation which has been placed upon us by the failure to provide adequate ma - chinery to cover the vast scope of our duties, the meagre statutory provision to fully safeguard the lives and property of our citizens. Earnest and sincere effort was made by the department during the past legislative session to induce that body to en - act measures drawn and presented to it for the purpose of af - fording additional security arising from the use, transporta - tion and storage of gasoline, and other volatile oils, the opera - tion of motion picture shows, dry cleaning and dry dyeing, changing date of State Fire Day, electric wiring, etc., but we </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 found our efforts nullified by opposing interest and the pro - posed measures were cast aside as of no importance even though practically every other state in the union has enacted tatutory protection governing these forms of risks. Though these efforts were put forth subsequent to the period covered by this report, we have felt that in all justice and fairness, we should be given opportunity to disclose our interest in serving the people of this state and an honest at - tempt to obtain legislation beneficial to everyone, and in par - ticular to those who were so actively engaged in opposing legislation which might entail a slight expenditure, but no less surely protect the very interest they represent. THE FIRE DEPARTMENT We have viewed with pleasure #le increasing interest manifested by cities and towns in their fire fighting organiza - tion and equipment and have endeavored to aid by suggestions and advice a great number of those, adopting new methods of discipline and equipment. While the men are the heart and spirit of the department, suitable equipment must be provided or their efforts are retarded and limited. A group of husky firemen with a syringe hose wound on a spool, do not constitute .•&gt;. fire department. And yet with a department so limited, some municipalities wonder why some of their fires are not tre speedily extinguished. The boys can't fight fire with iir bare hands. Give them a chance. STREET OBSTRUCTION BY AUTOMOBILES tThe choking of our street area by parking automobiles I the difficulty for the fire department in case of a large, ck-spreading fire, is a matter which must be seriously con - ered by municipals, officials, and citizens. Most cities prohibit parking at the curb within 25 or 30 feet of a hydrant but this does not relieve the street of congestion which often dangerously delays the fire apparatus in responding to down town fires. Nor does it relieve the firemen of the necessity of wasting precious moments in moving parked cars to make I c om for an effective handling of the apparatus. This matter </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DIVISION Or rIRL PREVENTION 25 of street congestion is one to which the traffic police may very well give most careful attention. There is untold danger to every city. FIRE CHIEFS — NOTICE We would be highly pleased to receive from the chiefs throughout the state, monthly news letters on general con - ditions in their locality, with respect to fires occurring in their respective cities, condemnations effected, results of inspections, new fire apparatus installed, and any other notes of interest in connection with their department. WARNING TO FARMERS AND GRAIN MEN e approach of the threshing season reminds the State arshal that many hundreds of thousands of bushels of e lost every year through carelessness with fire around Failure to guard against sparks from the ng outf _\ carelessness upon the part of smokers in throwing cigar and cigarette stubs and matches, neglect of the ltor machinery, allowing bearing to run dry and become I or to throw off friction or sparks, are common ailments. We would suggest that no smoking be allowed around shing outfits under any consideration. All these causes and other minor ones put together, take a heavy toll of grain and threshing machinery every year. A great deal of grain every year through fire. We would suggest that when is stacked that the ground be cleaned off from around these stacks for at least 200 feet. BUILDING AGAINST FIRE The surest safeguard against loss by fire, is a building constructed so it cannot burn. Investment. — The cost of a building, whether it be for commercial purpose or for a home, may be secured as an in - vestment or as a speculation. If property is built of fire proof materials, it is an investment. If constructed of com - bustible materials it is undoubtedly a speculation. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Owners Iuterest. — Insurance premiums are an investment to provide for reimbursement in case of loss by fire. Money paid by an insurance company can only reimburse the owner 1 or a part of his fire loss. This money does not prevent fires. Provide against effect of fire on strength of life of building-. In - surance is not fire prevention. It effects only the loss occasioned by fire. Insurance rates can be materially reduced by a building with a material which offers the greatest possible degree of fire prevention. Fire safe constructions check conflagrations. The fire loss adjustments made by insurance companies in the U. S. and Canada during the past fourteen years, amounted to $3,410,752,600. The average yearly loss was $243,625,200. PREVENTABLE FIRES From whatever standpoint it is examined, it must be realized that every preventable fire, little or big, is to some degree an aid and comfort to the enemy. This is a matter of individual responsibility. Each one must take it to himself as a personal matter. There are fifteen hundred fires each day or more than one per minute. What right has anyone to assume that all of these will occur upon the premises of other people. Unless he resolves this day that there shall be no such occurrence in property controlled by himself, and un - less he make this resolve effective by means of an immediate inspection and correction of all fire hazards, he cannot be con - sidered a true patriot, no matter what may be his profession. AUTOMATIC SPRINKLERS The automatic sprinkler is a mechanical fire extinguishing system which works on much the same principle as does the automatic fire alarm. In fact, most all automatic sprinkler systems have automatic alarm attachments, so that when the sprinkler begins to work an alarm is sent to the fire depart - ment or wherever desired. The automatic sprinkler is un - doubtedly one of the most important factors in fighting large fires — when the heat in a room where these are installed reaches a dangerous degree the sprinkler head automatically </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTIO] opens and begins to throw water on the flames, at the san* time turning in an alarm that the building is on fire and askinj for outside assistance. FIRE INSURANCE RATE* In naming the cost of a certain amount of insurance on a particular piece of property, two hazards or dangers are taken into consideration, the physical hazard and the moral hazard. The physical hazard is apparent to the eye. The nature of the property and its surroundings, disclose this hazard at once. The moral hazard is hidden. It lies in the character of the assured, his business methods, his habits and his honesty or lack of honesty. Frame shingle roof buildings take the highest building rates because wood is the greatest fire food in the world and fire devours it greedily. Shingle roofs are a terrible menace. The general outside condition of premises and property is also considered in rate making and if individ - uals would keep their yards and alleys free from rubbish and inflammable material and keep their property in good repair, they could reduce their rates or the cost of their insurance. The heating and lighting plants of both dwelling and business buildings play a part in rate making. The fire protection of a city is also taken into consideration when fixing the cost of insurance. A town with high water pressure facilities and well equipped fire department can obtain insurance at lower rates on the different classes of risks than can a town where the water supply and fire department are inadequate. THE LIFE HAZARD As grossly extravagant as in the loss of property caused ay preventable fire, it takes a second place to the appalling loss jf human life, if there could be any excuse for the performance jf any act or maintenance of any condition that results in the destruction of property by fire. There can be none for per - sonal thoughtlessness or personal carelessness that may result in the burning to death or injury of a human being. Yet 15,000 people are sacrificed every year as a burnt mutilation is the result of the American bonfire, the study of which </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION !ves at least 90 per cent to be due to some form of careless - s that could have been prevented by the exercise of sufficient sthought. The crisp bodies of the countless thousands of ortunate victims of fire is a gruesome monument that will ;ver rebuke the American people for their carelessness, s Fire Marshal's office is giving serious consideration to visions for the safety of the lives of the people of Nebraska doing all within it's power to help reduce the loss of life. public buildings such as theatres, moving picture houses, els, rooming houses, school buildings and hospitals are given most careful inspection, not only for fire hazards but for pro - tection devices such as fire escapes, exits and self releasing file exit latches, also to other precautions as fire drills, rescue drills and inside protection. Public show houses and motion picture theatres are required to maintain properly constructed metallic booths nith protected openings, sufficients structed exits, and exit doors to swing outward, and t space to have the proper amount and arrangement of i Hotels and rooming houses are inspected not only fo hazards, but as to the provisions for the safety of the pants in case of fire. The adequacy of fire escapes, fire e lights, and signs, doors made to swing properly and any suggestions that might in any way effect the life hazar&lt; being closely watched. Hospitals where sick and helpless people are confined are the subject of most careful and exacting inspection. In the school inspection, close attention is given to the kind and adequacy of fire escapes for the use of children of various ages. Many teachers meetings have been held and these phases of the drill discussed with the idea of bringing it to a higher point of efficiency. YORK CONVENTION annual state convention of the Nebraska State Volun- Firemen's Association was held at York in January, 1921. tThe registration was the largest in the history of the or - zation. The feature of the convention was an exhibit by State Fire Marshal's office on fire fighting and fire preven- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DIVISION OF FIRK PREVENTION 29 tion methods. A number of interesting speakers were on the program. Papers wei* read by Marshal Hartford and Miss Eva Anderson, clerk and stenographer, in the office of the Fire Marshal, which were both interesting and instructive. All the deputies or inspectors from this department were in at - tendance at the convention. The last night, Governor S. R. McKelvie, honorary member of the State Association, gave a strong and stirring address. His presence in our midst brought forth much enthusiasm. 1922 CONVENTION TO BE HELD AT NORFOLK The 1922 convention of the Nebraska State Volunteer Firemen's Association will be held at Norfolk, on January 17th, 18th and 19th. The convention will open under the most auspicious cir - cumstances and the fire boys of Norfolk will use every effort in their power to make the stay of all visiting firemen an en - joyable one. The features of this year's convention will be a larger exhibit than at the 1921 convention by the Fire Mar - shal's office, and an address by Governor McKelvie and Mr. L. L Wolf. Physical Director of the Cincinnati Fire Department, who has been secured and will lecture and give demonstrations of physical training, ladder scaling, rescue work, first aid work, hose exercises, and the use of the modem apparatus and ap - pliances. There will also be lectures on the use of gas masks and other subjects peculiar to the profession. The National Board of Fire Underwriter! have devoted considerable atten- tion to the production of a motion picture entitled "The Danger that Never Sleeps." This picture in addition to "America's Greatest Crime" and "Women Fire Fighters" have been se - cured to make the convention interesting as well as beneficial. ATTENTION THEATRE MANAGERS We wish to call to the attention of the theatre managers that a personal responsibility rests with them regarding con - ditions existing in their theatres. If your theatre does not meet specifications or orders issued by this office are disre- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Kled, and an accident occurs, you are making yourselves e. This fact has been emphasized during the past week when the coroner at New Haven, Connecticut has found City Build - ing Inspector Joseph E. Austin, Lawrence E. Carroll, manager of the Rialto theatre, and Alfred S. Black, president of the Enecticut theatres corporation, which owned the theatre, linally responsible for the death of nine persons in the to theatre fire of November 27th. The coroner says that the direct cause of the fire was the burning of incense to give "atmosphere" to a motion picture, flimsy stage draperies being ignited from the incense. He finds that violation of the law in the theatre included the absence of the following safeguards : An asbestos curtain, water curtail, an automatic sprinkler, casks of water on the stage, hose connections, fire proof scenery and woodwork. The coroner says that had Building Inspector Austin done his duty in applying the building code the fire could not have occurred. »By disregarding the requirements of theatres in Nebraska, is office is also placing itself in a position to become criminal - liable in case of accident, so it is plainly seen how important is that we all do our part. NOTICE We have succeeded in having small booklets printed con - taining the laws, rules and regulations, etc., pertaining to the Division of Fire Prevention. These have been compiled by this office with the assistance of the attorney general's office. All laws pertaining to fire prevention are included, with the exception of a few pertaining to fire departments which were overlooked. These booklets may be obtained from here upon request. We have already mailed them out to all the fire chiefs whose names appear on our list, and will mail them out during January to the fire insurance companies and special agents for insurance companies. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 31 WORDS OF APPRECIATION For the splendid aid and cooperation that the Division of Fire Prevention has received from the fire chiefs as well as members of the fire department, the district attorneys, sheriffs and from all fire prevention organizations in the interest of the elimination of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fires, I wish to express my sincere appreciation. Also, to Governor S. R. McKelvie and Secretary of Trade and Commerce, J. E. Hart, who have assisted us in this work, I wish to express my thanks. Very respectfully, C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. LOSS OF LIFE IN NEBRASKA THROUGH FIRE DURING 1921 Monica Sallo of Superior, died from burns she received from a gasoline explosion on January 14th. On January 21st, a teacher near Miller, was found by the roadside near the school house with her clothing in flames and parts of her body burned to a crisp. She could not explain the cause of the fire but it is thought she had used kerosene to start a fire and an explosion had ensued. Physicians reported she could not recover. Her death followed shortly. Bons Trexler, 13, of North Platte, was electrocuted while in the motion picture booth of a local theatre on February 12th, 1921, 2,300 volts passing through his body. He leaves a mother, sister and brother. Elsie Irene Wharton of Omaha, age five, died on March 19th of burns received when her clothing caught fire while she was playing with a bonfire. On April 11th, Owen Goble of Hastings, age 21, was fatally burned when the can out of which he poured kerosene on the smouldering coals in a heating stove, exploded. The can was blown to pieces and burning oil was scattered about the room. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 He was so badly burned that he only lived six hours after the accident. On April 12th, the three-year-old son of Thomas Olin, living at Madison, was burned to death when a box of matches, with which he was playing, fell on the stove and ignited his clothes. On April 4th, the four year old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. F. W. Johnson of Peru, was fatally bamed, when she picked up two or three matches from a table and took them to the barn, setting fire to her doll. Her clothing caught fire and was almost entirely burned from her body. She died six hours later. kOn April 26th, while using her apron to lift a kettle of itoes from the stove, Mrs. Leonard Heine of Fremont. \v;us illy burned, as her apron became ignited. She died a few rs later. On July 16th, Lawrence Guilzow, age 15, was seriously urned at Grand Island, about the hands and chest in a most nusual manner. The boy had been in the cellar at his home nd suddenly emerged from it with his clothing aflame. He ated to his mother that he had struck a match and that, im - ediately, his shirt was afire. He rushed from the porch to le garden, lolling on the dirt. His sister. Doris, assisted in utting out the flames, quite badly burning her own hands. tie lad was taken to the general hospital where his condition as said to be serious, though not necessarily fatal. He is the on of Wm.' Guilzow, a member of the city fire department, n July 27th, we received the report of his death. On July 18th, Mrs. Leland Rapp, of Broken Bow, was burned to death, when a bolt of lightning struck the garage at their home. The family was awakened by a blinding bolt, and a few minutes later the garage was in flames. Mr. Rapp went for help and cautioned his wife to keep close watch for fear the flames would communicate to the house, as he knew there was a barrel of gasoline and a half barrel of kerosene in the garage. He returned with several neighbors after he had run </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 33 a quarter of a mile to the nearest neighbor. During his ab - sence Mrs. Rapp had entered the building almost at the mo - ment the barrel of gasoline exploded and when her body was found it was burned to a crisp. Just why Mrs. Rapp entered the building will remain a mystery. One supposition is, that she tried to rescue some puppies kept in the garage. Another is that she did not understand that her husband had gone for help and thought he had entered the burning building and had followed him in an attempt to rescue him. On July 28th, Mrs. Clara Hotchkiss, of Nelson, was burn - ed to death in a fire at the home of her son, Orville Hotchkiss. Mrs. Hotchkiss was an elderly lady and was alone at the house hen the accident occurred. It is presumed that she had uhted the gasoline stove which caught fire to her clothing and an adjoining room in the hope of being able to smother :e with some blankets. Being unable to do so she t of doors screaming for help, her clothing all ablaze, e anyone could get to her, she was literally burned She did not regain consciousness and died a few hours August 7th. John Oakes was fatally burned when the ■vhich he was riding with two companions caught fire. taken to Crete \\ here he died. It is supposed the car caught fire from a lighted cigarette which had been thrown into the top of the car which was down. It is reported the men had been drinking. Another theory is that Oakes was not burned fatally, but tried to get out of the burning car and was internally injured from his jump from the car. On August 10th, the two-year-old baby of Mr. and Mrs. Wm. Coulber of O'Neill, was burned to death, and Mr. Coulber was fatally burned in an attempt to rescue the baby, and the Coulber ranch house is in ruins, as a result of the children playing with matches. It is stated the mother and father were out in the fields when they saw their house burning. They rushed to the rescue of the three or four children who they knew were in the building. It is learned that all but the two - year-old baby had left the building and Mr. Coulber dashed in- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 DIVISION OF KIRK PREVENTION to the house, which by that time was burning like a furnace, Iirched in vain for his baby which was thought to be asleep one of the bedrooms. After the futile search and suffering &gt;m fatal bums, the heroic father finally emerged from the ilding which was burned to the ground. The baby's body is never recovered. The two children of Oliver Garner, living 15 miles south - east of Franklin, perished in the flames when a large barn and it's contents burned on October 6th. The father was away from home at the time and Mrs. Gardner is an almost helpless invalid and was unable to rescue the babes from the barn. The little victims were three and five years of age. An automobile, several horses, grain, harness and machinery were destroyed by the flames. It is supposed that the children playing with matches started the fire. Mrs. Louise Emil, aged 80, living in McCool, was seriously burned when her clothing caught fire from a coal oil burner on October 6th. The burns were from the knees down. She was taken to a hospital at York and succumbed to her injuries the following day. On November 1st, Walter Huffman, age 4 and Lawrence Day, age 5, of Scottsbluff, were burned to death in a chicken house adjoining the Huffman home. It is said that the chil - dren had matches, and were playing near a can of gasoline. tth bodies were burned beyond recognition before they could gotten from the burning house. Mrs. Huffman who tried vain to save them, was prostrated by the sight. The body of a man so badly burned that identification was impossible, was taken from a burning hay stack at North Platte on October 31st, in a field three miles southwest. The discovery was made by several farmers who were attracted to the field by the blazing stack. tOn November 14th the two-year-old daughter of Henry :thast, residing near Deshler, was fatally burned, while ying with other small children in the house. The mother s attending to some work outside and returning found the </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 child in flames. A physician was called and later the child was taken to a hospital in Hebron where she died. On November 15th, Mrs. M. B. Tracy of Greeley Center, poured kerosene from a five gallon can on a smouldering fire and an explosion followed. Mrs. Tracy was fatally burned, dying 20 hours later. Mrs. J. Baden, eighty-two, was burned to death at Omaha, when an oil stove on which she was preparing dinner over - turned, setting fire to her clothing. She ran into a bedroom evidently in an attempt to smother the flames with a blanket. The house was also set on fire and partially destroyed. This occurred on November 17th. On November 23rd, Betloff Stegelman, 72 years old, a prosperous farmer of Stanton, was found on his farm burned to death. His clothes were burned from his body and it is believed that the fire caught from his pipe which it is thought he had in his pocket. On November 27th, Katherine Perdue, 17, was fatally burned and her brother Lawrence was severely injured in an attempt to extinguish the flames that enveloped his sister, following the explosion of a kerosene can, the contents of which the girl was pouring on a smouldering fire. Her home at Pawnee City. On December 20th, Leta Oldfield, of Tecumseh, aged 14, was fatally burned while pouring kerosene into a cook stove. The can exploded, burning the clothing from her body, and her mother's hands and arms were burned quite badly helping the daughter. Leta died the following day. On December 28th, the nine months old baby of Mr. and Mis. Earl Cummings, of Nebraska City was fatally burned in an explosion which occurred when Mrs. Cummings poured kerosene on the fire. The mother ran into the yard and Mr. Cummings extinguished the flames which enveloped her and then rushed into the house to rescue the children. One child escaped without any burns, but the helpless "infant lay in a mass of flames. The baby died the following day. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION On December 30th, Mrs. Lavina Eahart, 82 years old was burned to death. She was found at her home at Columbus, lying behind the heating stove. Early in the morning the granddaughter, Miss May Eahart, had started a fire in the heating stove and had then gone to visit her parents. It is the supposition that the dead woman, had opened the stove door, and that the newly kindled wood had exploded in her face and that her clothing caught fire. INJURIES FROM FIRE DURING 1921 I Last January an employe of a local garage at Pierce was 'erely burned in a kerosene explosion while pouring contents can on fuel in a stove. The can proved to contain gasoline 1 adding a lighted match resulted in the explosion. t Charles Krabel, 16 year old boy at Ayr, was badly burned &gt;ut the head and face when a heating stove exploded while was building a fire. Fireman Clarence W. Brewer, of Engine Co. No. 4, Omaha. was badly burned by an explosion of a pail of gasoline, which had been placed back of a counter, on February 19th, when an attempt at arson was committed. Joe Lagarco was arrested in connection with the crime. Mr. Heinricks of Tilden, was badly burned about the face and hand and had his left shoulder broken when he fell out of the pop corn wagon onto the cement walk. The gasoline tank exploded. Last April the two Wellensiek boys of Cook were anxious to find out how much gasoline was left in a barrel, and lit a match and peeked in to see. Two badly burned faces was the result. tLast April Mr. Elton Tennant of Tecumseh was badly ed when attempting to pour kerosene on a smouldering I Last April Mrs. Charles Glasson of Tecumseh was severe - burned about the face and body when the oil can with which i was filling an incubator lamp exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 37 On June 29th, little Wilma Johnson, living near Burchard was severely injured when a fire cracker exploded in her mouth. On July 1st, Raymond Wiegand of Petersburg was severely injured when he was hit in the eye by a ball of fire thrown from a Roman candle. On July 16th, a rubber hose came loose from a can of mixed gasoline and kerosene, causing a fire which severely burned the right arm of Elton Cornelius of Fairbury. During July, Ben Roberts, wife and small son were driv - ing to Grand Island when their auto took fire and was com - pletely destroyed. Mrs. Roberts and son managed to escape the burning car, however, Mr. Roberts sustained slight burn During October, Urbe Schultz lit a match to peep into his jras tank at Fremont. An explosion resulted, covering the occupants with burning gasoline. One man was painfully uned while others escaped with minor injuries. Lydia Spott of Fremont, aged 22, was badly burned when )thing caught fire while she was throwing a burning oil hich had exploded, out of the house. Oll'e Joiner, aged 4, of Nebraska City was severely burned on the forehead and right arm on October 12th, when he poured the contents of a bottle, he supposed contained water on a bon - fire. It happened the bottle contained kerosene and an ex - plosion was the result. On October 15th, J. F. Romig, a moving picture man of Kansas City was severely burned about the face and hands at Chadron. when an explosion took place as he was filming the city. During the county fair at Hebron, the little daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Taylor Wilson was severely burned when a piece of flaming stick fell on her during a fireworks exhibition. On October 19th, Arvilla Anderson, 8, of Fremont, was painfully burned when her dress caught fire while she was playing with other children around a bonfire. She had re- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION cently left the hospital after a long stay following an automo - bile accident. On November 3rd, Mr. 0. O. Fessenden, who rescued Dale Threlkeld, 4, from a burning shed where he and a little five year old companion had been playing with a jack-o'-lantern in which they had tried to light a candle, sustained burns on his face and h:ind,;. Tlie child was uninjured but badly frighten - ed. They reside at Alliance. bMr. Wilson Heister of Wayne, was badly burned on De - ber 23rd when fire started from an oil stove in his room, r he had retired for the night. On December 23rd, Prof. N. Clay Null, superintendent of the Pleasantdale schools, was severely burned when his Santa Claus robe caught fire at the school building. His coolness as he walked out of the building probably averted a serious panic. Miss Riley and Mrs. Eberspacher also, received pain- ful bums in extinguishing the flames FIRES INVESTIGATED During the past year, we have been called upon to in - vestigate over ninety fires which showed indications of in - cendiarism. However, owing to the nature of the crime and the circumstances surrounding them, it is a very difficult crime to detect. In most cases evidence could not be secured to justify arrest and prosecution of parties where indications seemed to point to incendiarism. UOur record shows investigations were made at the follow - towns for incendiarism, during the past year. Atlanta (2) Andrews Lincoln (2) Lexington Monroe Albion (2) Arthur Mattsville Boone Martinsburg Mitchell Benkelman (3) Beatrice Minden North Loup (2) Berwyn </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 39 Colon (2 Columbu; Calhoun Norfolk (2) Newport Nelson North Platte Omaha ( Imum Cozad Petersburg Plattsmouth Primrose \or !) Ewin Fremont (6 Fairmont Parks Pleasanton Ruskin Fail-field Fairbun &lt; lurley Stamford South Omaha Sidney (4) Silver Creek Sterling (2) Syneoaa Trumbull Uehling Utica (2) Valparaiso Virgin'a Wauneta Winside Waverly Wymore Francis J. Hartman of Nelson, signed a written confession to setting fire to his art studio at Nelson on October 1st. He stated he was heavily in debt and was unable to make ex - penses. He states that his desperate financial straits led him to commit the act. His case came up in district court the latter part of December and he pleaded guilty to the crime. The court paroled him for 3 years to Charles E. Day at Hebron, where he now resides, and Mr. Day as well as Mr. Hartman are required to report regularly to the court. Mr. Hartman who is a young man was married a little later, following committing his crime. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 DIVISION OK FIRE PREVENTION Louis Whiteaker of Columbus, was arrested for setting his house on fire in five different places on October 28th. Mr. Whiteaker had the household goods all packed up preparatory to move. He had been asleep for two hours and claimed he was almost overcome with smoke as fire started while he slept. The trial will come up at Columbus in January, 1922. Mr. Tom Henderson of Wymore signed a confession at Wymore, stating that he deliberately took kerosene, climbed up a ladder and poured kerosene between the roof and ceiling and lighted a match setting fire to a two story brick building at Wymore on May 22nd, 1921. This was done while he was in a drunken condition. Mi-. Henderson was sentenced to the penitentiary to serve 30 days for his crime. Fremont has suffered a loss of $153,354.63 during the past year including fires outside of the corporate limits of the city. A large number of these fires are the result of incendiary fires and the officials hope to bring this condition to an end. Fire Marshal Hartford, Deputy Hauser and County Attorney Cook as well as Chief Morse are investigating conditions. kRuskin has had fourteen buildings on main street /n during the past year. It appears the stores ha ken into and then set on fire. On December 6th, fire destroyed one-half block of build - ings in the business part of Virginia, the loss being estimated at $60,000. The fact that half an hour before the alarm was turned in parties passing through Virginia saw nothing to in - dicate a fire, seems to point to the fact that thieves started the fire to cover up robbery. October 6th, one-half of a city block of buildings was troyed by fire at Albion, the damage being estimated at ,000. Very peculiar circumstances surround it, but there i insufficient evidence to justify indictment. tFire of unknown origin completely gutted the Strand tre at Grand Island on November 18th. Loss estimated 50,000. The fire was investigated but there was in - dent evidence to warrant an arrest. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 41 Minden had the most disastrous fire in it's history on December 5th, the loss being estimated at $80,000. It also appears in this case that first a robbery had been committed and the fire started to cover up the robbery. On May 30th, at Beatrice, a moving picture theatre fire occurred, which appeared to be the work of an incendiary. A wire had been placed on the switch, causing a short circuit. This was in the front part of the building. In the rear was a five gallon can of gas, being located under the stage and set on tire with a rope of film running along under the stage next to the wall to a large barrel of oil. Harry Moss of the National Board of Fire Underwriters from Chicago, and C. E. Hartford, State Fire Marshal, investigated the fire, but were unable to make any arrests. On October 1st, the hardware store of Fritzinger, Bock &amp; Co. at Valparaiso, was completely destroyed by fire. The fire )ioke out about 15 minutes after inspection by the night watch - nan. The owners of the store were heavily in debt, but in - sufficient evidence to connect anyone with setting the fire 1 be obtained. Investigation of a fire at Sterling on October 8th of a dance hall owned by Max Wamke was found to have been set on fire. Porches on the north and west side had been saturat - ed with coal oil. However, there was insufficient evidence to warrant an arrest. The general merchandise store of J. J. Andre at Peters - burg was discovered to be on fire by F. Andre on August 16th. He saw a man running away but the description was too gen - eral to be able to detect the guilty party. Shingles had been soaked with oil and set outside of the building. It appeared to be spite work. On August 30th, the general store of Mike Shaheen at Arthur, was destroyed by fire, causing a loss of $12,000. The cause seemed to be the work of an incendiary and thought to be revenge, but there was insufficient evidence to arrest any parties. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRE ESCAPES In compliance with the law passed in 1911, specifiying the kind of buildings that should be equipped with fire escapes, we herewith submit the following list showing the school buildings and other buildings which have complied with the law by reason of order issued from this office during the past year. Public Schools Wellfleet Waco Bartley Bushnell Vutan Ben kel man Bloomfield Cambridge Chambers Clay Center Omaha Public Schools Dundee School Brown Park School Horrigan School South Lincoln Schoo South High School Central High School German Home entral School Saratoga. 24th &amp; A Fairmont (High and Public) Holdrege (Public, High and West Ward) Indianola Long Pine (Grade and High) Manley Maywood Osceola Palisade Potter Benson Central. 61st &amp; Ma S*s. Plainview Peru Lothrop, 24th &amp; Lothrop Sts. Monmouth Park, 33d &amp; Ames Parks Sts. Springfield Scotia Howard Kennedy, 30th &amp; Bin - ney Sts. Venango Waverly Western Edward Rosewater, 13th &amp; Phelps Sts. Windsor, 34th &amp; Martha Sts Kosehill. 56th &amp; Corby St Franklin, 85th A: Franklin i Columbia. S8th &amp; Urn Vinton. 22nd &amp; Vinton Sts. Central Park. 12nd &amp; Gnu Sts. Cm*, 14th i: Can Sti Benson High, 66th &amp; Sts. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 43 ( ( 1 Jungman. 20th &amp; Q Sts. Building 18th &amp; Castellai Sts. Gretna, picture show &amp; danoe hall 'omenius. 15th &amp; Pine Sts. Pacific. 1 lth &amp; Pacific Sts. Train, tith &amp; Hickory Sts. Hastings, Hagar Candy Co. (factory) Ktarney. Opera House build - ing llth &amp; Center Sts. Lodge Pole, picture theatre over garage Parochial Schools »n — St. Maiv's School Lincoln. E. R. Deputy Co., 327 No. 9th St. &gt; Joseph's Schc Lincoln, Weber Block. North 14th St. St. Patrick School Heart School Osceola, Union Stores Co., Inc.. telephone exchange &amp; office building red Heart High School Mary's School ■celia's School Peru, State Normal Shelton, Academy Other Buildings South Sioux City, Normal School Island, Business College University Place, Wesleyan University C.eneva State Bank CAUSES OF FIRES DURING 1921 Lincoln Omaha Bal. of State Number Number Number Ashes, hot Backfire 9 26 14 ■i •i •&gt; rt 4 Bonfires 24 a Blow torch Candles i 0 I 1 0 6 Chimneys, defective Cigars or cigarettes Communicated :J4 87 M M 17 12 1 s I Electric or gas irons 2 4 34 2 Electric wiring, defective Fireworks 13 2X 0 I I Fire place, defective 1 •2 Uon College \uroiii. Hotel, Leonard Carroll </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Furnace, defective _ 12 3 Gasoline and kerosene . . Grease 49 9 Incendiary, presumably 27 Inflammables, too close to fire Lightning 4 0 16 1 6 0 Matches _ H2 32 7 Smoking meat 0 1 1 Erks from chimney __ rks from engine ntaneous combustion /e 111 162 1;» 3 0 S2 ll 24 2.", » ') 12 Thawing out water pipes Unclassified (I •j u 66 L5 .-&gt; Unknown 1H 158 223 595 66: FIRE LOSSES Dl'RING 1921 LThe total fire loss from December 1st, 1920, until D 1st, 1921 is as follows: No. of Fire Lincoln Omaha Balance of state Total 1,481 $2.164.(i42. Note: — Our December 1st, bulletin showed the Lincoln loss to be $75,032.00, and this report $64,214.00. In explana - tion, we wish to state that Fire Chief Olsen notified us that the loss on the Galion Iron Works was excessive, and $20,000 should be deducted for salvage on contents of the building. 223 $ 64,214.0 436 424.2rtt.:&gt; 663 1,675,563.5 )S 3S1 ESF FOP R 12" YEARS 1910 __. .$2,181,058.00 1911 _ 1,788,123.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 45 During 1921, our regular inspectors, inspected 314 towns ind cities of Nebraska. During this time, we are pleased to report that over 22,000 inspections were made, and nearly rders made in the interest of fire prevention. nspection record shows the following orders issued: Also, Mr. Hayduk sends in a monthly report showing that all these orders were complied with, as he returned to all places 1912 1913 2,251,774.33 - 1,715,676.10 1914 1915 1,873,071.25 1,789,269.00 1916 1917 1,908,297.46 2,895,935.00 1918 2,158,204.81 1915) 1,422,943.62 1920 2,679,029.71 1921 2,164,042.09 INSPECTIONS DURING 1921 Kerosene and gasoline 771 Clean up 3,703 Chimney 860 Electric wiring 3,296 Metal, asbestos and stove 1,660 lied light and fire escape 345 Miscellaneous 1,942 Repair building 334 Recommend condemnation 508 Total orders issued 13,419 Total inspections made 22,016 Files investigated 90 Buildings condemned and in process of condemnation 635 Our record shows a total of 4,853 inspections made in )maha by Inspector Hayduk, and 1,134 orders were issued. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION t where he had left orders to ascertain that they had been com plied with. Mr. F. F. Dowling of Scottsbluff, is our inspector for tht northwestern part of the state, and we are pleased to repon that during the past year. Mr. Dowling made a total of 7,o6: inspections and issued orders in the interest of fire preventioi on 4,075 inspections. f&gt;uthern part of the state, and we are pleased to report tha r. Butcher made 6,339 inspections during 1921. and issue&lt; 137 orders in the interest of fire prevention. The remainder of the inspections were made by inspet who have worked only part of the time, these inspections ing been made in the eastern part of the state. In addition to the large number of inspections our regular inspectors, they have assisted the depart! investigation work in their territory, so the expense ing out a man from the office has been curtailed. TOWNS INSPECTED The following is a list of cities and towns that hi tpected during the past year. The figure in par lowing the town indicates more than one inspectio Ainsworth Albion (2) Alexander Alliance Atkinson Benkelman Atlanta Bertrand Aurora Big Spring Bancroft Bladen Alma Bartlev Blah Amherst Anoka Bassett Bloomfierfd (2) Battle Creek (2) Blue Hill Bayard Blue Spri Blue Springs Ansley (2) Arapahoe Arcadia Beaver City Brady Beaver Crossing Bridgeport Belgrade Bristow (2 Arlington Arnold Bristow (2) Belvidere Broadwater Ashton Bennington Broken Bow (2) Mr. L. J. Butcher of Kearney, is our inspector t </seg>
            <seg id="p047">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 47 ( Brunine Deshler DeWitt Dickens Diller Grant Brunswick Greeley Burw Greenwood Gretna Bushnel Butte Doniphan Dorchester Eagle Guide Rock Gurley Callaway Cambridge Haigler Eddyville Edison Hampton Harvard Edgar Hastings (2) Hs;velock Elgin (2) Elkhorn Elmwood Elsie Hebron Henderson Hendley hadron Chapman Chappell Elwood Endicott Emerson Eustis Herman Hershey Hickman Hildreth Holbrook Holdrege Holstein Homer leston Chestei &amp;y Center Ewing (2) Exeter Clearwater (2) Cody Fairfield Fairmont Farnam Fanvell College View lumbus Hubbard Hubbell Comstock Cortland Cowles Foster Humphrey Huntley Franklin Fremont Friend Cozad Huston Hyannis Imperial Inavale Indianola Inman raig Crawford Creighton Crete Fullerton Geneva Genoa Gering Gibbon GJltner Glenvil Gordon Culbertson Curtis Irvington Ithaca Dakota City Danbury Jamaica -Tuniata Dannebrog Davenport David City Deweese Gothenburg Grafton Kearney (2) Kenesaw Grand Island Kennard Campbell Caileton Carroll (2) Cedar Bluffs Cedar Rapids Central City </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Kesterson Kimball Nelson Red Cloud Reynolds Riverdale Riverton Rogers Newman Grove (2) Niobrara (2) Lawrence Lebanon Leshara Lewellen Lexington Lincoln Norfolk Norman North Bend North Loup Roseland Rushville Saltillo North Platte (2) Oakdale Lindsay Sargent Lodge Pole Long Pine Loomis Oakland Oconto Ogallala Ohiowa Omaha O'Neill Orchard Ord Saronville Schuyler Scotia Louisville Loup City Lynch ft) Lyons Scottsbluff Seneca Seward Shea Madison (2) Madrid Sheltoi Shickley Marion Maxwell Maywood McCook McGrew Smithfield Sidney (2) So. Sioux City Spalding Spencer (2) Sprngue Meadow Grove (2) Melbeta Palisade Palmer Papillion Pauline Paxton Pender Stamford Stanton Stapleton St. Edward Stoddard Memphis Merna Merriman Milford Millard Miller Milligan Minatare Minden Phillips Pickrell St. Paul Strang Stratton Pierce (2) Plainview (2) Platte Center Pleasanton Stromsburg Stuart Moorefield Morrill Sumner Superior Powell Ragan Mullen Sutherland Sutton Murdock Neligh Ralston (2) Randolph (2) Swanton Orleans Osceola Oshkosh Osmond (2) Oxford Page </seg>
            <seg id="p049">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 49 Tamora Valentine Valley Wellfleet Western Wilber Tecumseh Tekamah Thompson Thurston Tilden (2) Tobias Venango Verdel (2) Verdigre Waco Wilcox Williams Wilsonville Winnebago Winside Wolbach Wallace Trenton Trumbull l T nion Washington Waterloo Wauneta Wausa (2) Waverly Woodriver Wood Lake York Uehling University Place Upland Wayne (2) Yutan Utica Weeping Water </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>