<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00035.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00035.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">CHAUI.KS F S( I1W </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1912 PREPARED B1 S. C. BASSETT, Secretary Nebraska Dairymen's Association </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">l&gt;uir&gt; mi. i! h AsMM-m Nebraska. Feb. 1st rnor ol Nebra use inailt- .unl pro&gt; Nebraska 1 »nir&gt; mei - Res| c BA8SETT. Secretar </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">I li I n Nebraska .1 II Kranilsen Will ForbM H I NcmrislmiK Product Us relation la the \\ McGinnii K M Lilt] I Nit-la I' Ha Wo Kadetr IS ! ; : Farm Demonstration Work V Cattle ui a coin- H Mortluad • oil Resolution! :iii£ Team with illustration — Kilw H •&lt;;t iii K H" Booska ultiirc Ft iliTiilion M;inufa&lt; umr s ftiwlll i &gt; &gt; i • rj SuptTi iittiultnr .1. K. Vo^el Nebraska Dairymen c; I. Prof .1 II Krandsen, Regent Wluiinori and Dtiiti K. A </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Earn Manufacturers' km Creamirif:- and Whol.r - ;hiiiK Local. Indrpendei [a Dalr) i 'onditiona • i P Niinilit Hilt*, also ct Popu Th&gt; I &gt;.i i r&gt; Industry m U i onditioiu ■ i Nebraska I'ODgrfBuional l)t o\\ .) 1 1 &lt; I k &gt; i &gt; K Conti'st </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Norfolk IHHKI I: HO </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">9 i i- i oi mi mi;ki;&gt; l.ilt- MciiiIm-i Beatrice. Gibbon, Nfbr I'ittsbnrK. I'a Cibbon. N.-Ih Omaha. X«fcf din (' reamer j C&lt; Waterloo ate Farm. Lincoln. Xebr reamery Ass n Uermantown. Xebr Fairmont Cr Silver Crec-k. S Pierre. Bo Dt Fairmont C Fairmont ( Lincoln, Xebr J4 X St.. Lincoln. Xebr Xebr H' ii&lt;ii.u\ I . ■ I • - M«miiIkmn Nmriini, DMlBMrfc New Hampton. |OW« Fort Atkinson. Wis Gifebm, V-br Kort Dodne, |OW1 Lincoln. Kearney, Xebr Waterloo. Kcfef Station B, Onialia. Ii.m- Building. Omaha, Sebi Gibbon, X&lt; br Station IS. Omaha. N&gt;l&gt;r Station It. Omaha. &gt; Omaha. N- :&gt;r Lincoln, N.-l.t IJlll Hill imtrv (ii . ()nwih;i. Nilir i 33d St., Lincoln. Xefcf l.iiu dIii. Omaha. V •. York, W&gt;i Omaha. Nebr aiiHT.v Co., Oniahii. N&lt; uit'ry Co., Omaha. N*-ln </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 Win. Button ■ s F. Sell wager IV . St»'\ t'MSOII F II VauKli 11 \V G. Whltmor* 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 2741 K Lincoln. Nt-lir Lincoln, X« Arden. NVhr Beatrice. Nebr ( imbridKe. Xebr \ irth Loup. Xebr Concord. Xebr Kdison, Nebr Tecumseh. Xebr Peru. Neln Kinite "&gt;, Lincoln, Nebi Kimkf X« in Lincoln, XeUf I. Cream l):ll.r. Xebr Division. Washington. l&gt;. ( :l v Route .".. Lincoln, X LaPlatte, Xebi Havelock. Xebr rural City. N 1 :!" C St., I. in. oln. X Cozacl. Xebf Mt&gt;nroe, Xebr Aurora, Xebr X Allintu p. N Aurora. Xebr I n ma ii. X Fairmont Creamery. Omaha, Xebr 1 lain! v i '.i . Limoln, Xebr Kt / iff. .Win hnstown. X Hiikota Cltj Whitney. Xebr .' T St., Lincoln, Xebr lihnlen. Xebr Harney St., Omaha. Xebr Omaha. \e Laurel. Xebr Omaha. Xebr Lyons. Nebr St. I'anl. Xebr Omaha. Xebr </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 V i), &lt;;. i. KiiKlig. Fred . I I! •v. Fre l»r I. Murphy. T. Maniuardi Middletoa. \ Louis .all. V. V ll.-r. V \ n lin Llo; Bger. 01 II X out, M. I) H. .1. ''•"■"■ '■ *" PMraon, E. .1 Er. Fnmk \ m, Alli.ri . .loll n ■ham, K A i. P. T ell. LouU - n. \V \ »■. 1(. .1 rsoa. .1. \ Philips, Ceo s Bait. Arnold . F K. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 CaiiMol Iniv atrice ( Kami, Lin. oln Xebr Norfolk Carrol Nel.r i\ T 1 ', Lincoln N.I) Nel. km Neb Neb Neb Joy ilroken IIdw Falls City Xebf niversitj I'lit NVli N&gt;l. NVI. NVIi Neb Smith Held HarliiiKton. Talma Palmyra Palmyra i : raft on Cfinral City WhiiiiHj Millard Koutc 7. Lincoln Central City N.,,r Nebr Minimi I'alniHr Nebr ward Pa ivnee ( Blair Nebr KhiiIi.iU Neb Beatrice Creamery, Lincoln. Xel •aveni on Xebr Knlo Xeb Neh Nel&gt; Net. Net, Nell Neb Nel. Net. Kriend ty Farm, Lincoln ribner, Harvard Harvard reamery, Lincoln Heat rice. Mi Coed Junction Wood Kiver Ki'il clninl Norfolk, liiviiiinnluim MuiltliiiK. Lincoln Naimni- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">\ .,. A w. ber. A. E Ziirl.i.k Annual M&lt; To! KTt. Charles en, a r. , MB. BM, .1. W I, \Vil.\v ht. F. C Ymmmt. H. C. Cliail.-s K </seg>
            <seg id="p016">CONVENTION 15 mxIMIUIIII WSl \l. MHKTI\(. O» THK NKIIIiASk.t MAIItYMKVH \«.«.« (( I ATldN I'rof G. L. McKay \\ i'iliic«ilii&gt; . I Inn -da) ;inil I liilat I. ui&gt; I . l«M:t </seg>
            <seg id="p017">FKIHAV. I AM A I () Pi 01 ( Bust 111 I l);iir\ I \nyni T t.m an in Every bod ■ a it in the dis Ample stred par Xo.iM-ilay ltiucli can The l.inil. II hol.l ■ For pi-oKrams •ddn </seg>
            <seg id="p018">I- 17 \t »re look till growtl Nebraska. 1 think per u be other brand II (Mi imhi ;m arre. At the rost of $1 by efficient DianaKenieii re Ian I an w nn our farmers •nil z. his count! ir son Cliai Karl iy know that al 1 iiut-'hi iiny other brand rful awakening in a ;ii ck'al about sri. -until 1 niaiiui!* tlif land has l» by liiinliuu in din ami (oil from I and practice ap-ti &gt;arison with the i-ondittona ex ictice dairying mi smli ins; Wlit-r. handlii that rai </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I lt i \ &lt; ii a lieu spot i ac the tlii s off mul ilia ink. thereby saving the vii AIM iii ami Impr niiiiirv oiis f.irm and b Anoi :,ci'. ill I) f ■ tion sliowir I!«-|m.i i &lt;it I i en-Hi M .l.l.uai irer. All niil « ill show il red ai all. en bigheml amuunl of m ■nuts •&gt;[ i; ■ p no ii m in* &gt;' in t in t r </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 iletillittl&gt; il*" - r agricultnrkl irodm NVbnisku Farmer's C:p? . at ion. stati-il that in ri dairy produrta in Ne- l)iitter in i I decrease in the number of us disclose tluit in tli» twenty per rent in the ase of more than ■ctured in </seg>
            <seg id="p021">1 1 Is a common remark t me; carrying the ii minion t&lt;&gt; dairying than ia&lt; Nebraska is .1 Monde ill V V. it nil »i tion "i da ■Practi&lt; all -d in the ■ vcnti ,inl factories! manufai iimimI In tlicsf twn dixjsid Tattlt- shows tin- average n ItWal l'o|Mll;ll Ic.ll &lt; •'lli|&gt;;il)'&lt;l With I :;&gt;!!&gt; low l'.|illl.i( n I Ivrrajcr ViiiiiIht uf l»air\ I ■&gt;«- IVi Si|nHif M K;ist N'orth I </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 I .im Soi ih &lt; enlral Average number of ii : K|aarc mile IT "• is? \ \\ i-i North &lt; ••iitrsil. I'M). Average iiuiuImt ol covi per square n \ •are mil* &gt;akota 4.J Dakota ■» a In 1 . i I ipulated ImiiIi with people and listed luith with people .m&lt;l i why it has been possible iial reason why it lias been powi stablish and maftataln local anil &gt; nil maftitain local and veragc ol twenty-six i ige of twenty-six I a ■ of twenty-rive, N.w York with an average of twenty-ive, N«w York Be. these states can anil im ni with twenty-nine, tkeae Btatei can and do i-atneiies and so could *mt Irs and so could and rative cream ler like average conditions i&lt;- i onditions c delight in railing attention t;&gt; the t in &lt; allitiK atlrntion la the nil in Denmark and to inc that Ne mark and to urs&gt;- thai ire some things ini; item thereafter: there are some thinss lmpoa [ Nebraska patterning after lesirable, and Nebraska patterning times as many people per squnr as many people per H s as many dairy cows per Denmark to estabPsh and many dairy cows per i uiiark to estahPsh and in iti\e ireameriea within easy reach oi ivithin easy reach of e\erv a le so to do. in a general way, at this lo. in a general way, at e connected with the dairy nnected with the dairy otl thy of mention in this connection, and that is this connection, and t!&gt; kl&gt; settled rural communities lot l.-d rural ionininnitie&gt; i most pronounced example, having ironoMiiceil example, haviim n per square nnlei ir is often a qm - nile i it is often a question people and hence it i.- often tn market in the most &lt; on- the people and hence it Is often market in the most ™n- i make use of the maximum A I </seg>
            <seg id="p023">iuiM- in Wisconsin, \Y« York ami turned. In Nebraska quite the revi :■ (lii'-sticm of (indiiiK help to do hence dairying is done with the i amciiin ! of lahor. that is. in&gt; nhole milk at a kx-al rreamerv t ii-s have Imi'h fariut-rg to »e &gt;m and eo-operative en IV |ll </seg>
            <seg id="p024">XVEXTION : the Nebraska Dairymen V a ■ ••in of such creamery plants ha\' .mil to date «&lt;* have only forty ry plan's have vith thirty-eight IB MlMWW twe: torturing butter is n|NMh nee twenl •■r is expensive but ili-r existing dairj conditions n seventy i iid will, under sw» such - increase the ntunber of dairy CO iry herds. I'niler this systi-m the nuin - twent) ]ier cent from 1 Hun to !•!• anil \ inditions in seventy a onie such - he n ninber of dairy co I'ntter this system the iniiii- ii r li urn 1 nun to 1*1(1 :iiul i it&lt; ameriei (la the same peri.ni • in- an time period &gt; in- wish tn criticise Mr. Bassett's pa loes not pay to put labor into the eowa ilnction of milk, even though we ha\e to i the old country, it pays to put lal ell us that it pays to curry the row. ami that it pays to curry the cow, ami mil rather than let their cows rim over ih* rather than let their cows run over the v get more feed per acre and more milk ore t'ei-d per acre and more milk hat &gt; milked four times a day. that is milkeil four times a day. || us are milked that often. That might 1«&gt; »r&gt;' milked that often. That inistit bp . bill it has hei-n found to he profitable us he. ii found lo be profitable ay. And they carry water to them, and \. And th.-&gt; carry water to them, and So although it is hard to get labor in ih it is hard to net labor in t i put a lot of labor on tii.. &lt; dws, i . ■ i ' &gt; w o tin- report of H« &lt;retar&gt; Baiartl with retain Hassett with ell pleased with the way m which h. -.isi-d with tin- way in which he pn itioned that then- had bet&gt;n ronsiderable ii ■fit s west of tli,' Missouri riv. i-i and there ha\&gt; • matter of volume and pricei paid Oaw M ut. and on,, of the fr&gt; i|iifiu misrei i aid in this country. Our president in is country. Our president in lit showing that the prices paid tor milk aid her products if State* I i.-partnient of A« r l&lt; on ivli.i its that ent. &gt; Vi the prin ii t </seg>
            <seg id="p025">thai is time valtin You know that ; bundanre cf It. For Instance roal is mi!) \. \. :i Yuune. \ w. I'm. I \ ii- iistral ili tin- young i In- older It. Mr. Kraiil Tweni win ii yon in-fd ii than when ii i li«- Year H&lt; ■ i: 1. k I'M &gt;l \M»V&gt; I M'l i;il \( I IN I \KM III \H»\«.|K\ run-down condil onsili!.- for tlic n have niki </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 than ten |iei cent of the farmers net tht- in of farmers read them, ami in I them when they do read them they have n ds presented; it is a part of the work t- fails before the farmers and 1111)11 r w;iy they will follow tl &gt; li &gt;dj is more or 1 farm demonstration work mil He labor saving work we dl retary, in itterei i.v for tlie com in) :ilso have a suli ha\t a illK ill the lOWl iililv The readily. Tlu mitieg. We wil We Wl with the rountj unt is simmi ;is w." ili soon as we dt it and fall wt nic-r nml fall ui tionml value ain i! i'\ i-utivf com ■ liDdl work Ebon I ;i year an &gt; am! I In- i l«a&gt; an I henerils. t;&gt; !)•- VI rk That da) .1 11 Pettng and an organization ally ■ iiail small he- 1 hi rk frnni thi iniilille of April, Lu( 1 and had been sour wluit limiteil ii. D :i buslncM ;ii!il t-&gt;|ic. ially aiiyihinjj i ml Biompliah as tniiili as we would Miik dow is being carried on in man) • rountrjr, and three rountlea in Ni-- VI rk. I had little 1&gt; n taaa $1 .•»»»•&lt; to aunty. I Fouad thai I be nun oa iIih ild nf ibJ were anzloai to learn aboal iiiiiiiiiii good anil lii-m-lit. As ■ il the • \|&gt;ei inieiii station are helping . ami t!:.- fartni-rs are takins up the rapldl The only means they ha\i- better wajn is throngl </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Th»- work car ■ plenty of fund had "iih &lt;&gt;r two far I would si&gt; ;i Inqiiir il n ii mid will rolling ami lirrak This li;is increaw would !•■](• |ihul • nographer ; i . e you ■ little Ides Iliow is detlnil ■1 if a 1 1 1 a i ii j in it' In' </seg>
            <seg id="p028">There is hardly aw- tiftv-si ven men in tlif inic men \\ ho don t \ are inter In KiiitiK over t! an who objected to mv work, that a testing . siikI some in ev • ni mow ins icinte anything lint omit of tillniK tai no r will . ertalnl] irj sm» the atiKini and iliere is sonn- agiti ;i lit ;i at iai I and mow II v&lt; the lertill :l Ij l.i-aiiiniiic farmers lia\ ■ hinted !«■ arniera ami leed &lt; i &gt;r 11 It is ;i hit inntallv or uhyslcall) '!&lt;■ You are |in&gt;bal&gt;ly liahly tlif oldest slate along lat on null Ilil to pOMibilil alfalfa will grow in Meriick liis to tr&gt; ami . i&gt;iiii&gt;.n. i better lliai lain tin- ral I'll Mfiiick count ad : anil has lie. n of mnr ounty; tlu- pulilirity nought out ill' </seg>
            <seg id="p029">x ' s mill inn ■ iii the county demo iiy the demonstrator ollar and « i' li (it her ■ ■way. As Prof, r profit out of the ill. Snin.- v.ry mnili H'»&lt;&gt;&lt;1 • a&gt; of extending « ;t&gt; than iiy ■*•! </seg>
            <seg id="p030">29 XTION ilil likt- to know OO. I Iwr here llftUiil ■■&lt;] - K'iat vni is rj a i inly splendid 1.1 thai our . oinin il iiml rs. unil farmers th&gt; will lie in i am Kiiriin i 's V K 1 nit •• I (1 a hill for th. this work. It is being e this ass(x iati in appre - in his work in Xlirr . k ;ely lijiin th:' man Iginated the i&lt;lea of this mil that : s tht thin our a«so&lt; ial wink. I li;i\ i- alwa ii |in'_ mini: thine. W rii. k iier*. whenever proper Interest bankers' as.-oi ation t's in an •■ffoit i&lt; Diintv be </seg>
            <seg id="p031">KCulve y. am Ber at »k ck eoun \ this far I \\ I i Tl Sol oppini lnwiii :ir An tin win bUHhel I beliei daiiv herd on r.dit of t A ried on ilii (lll\ 1 .mil. &lt;&gt;i-i k ITIMi \ i&gt; \na i \i;m \m&gt; is i i;tn&gt;i ( i\&lt;. HAllti &lt; \ i i l\ \ ( OMMl M I \ rper cfin. ami hai in&lt; normal *dvan&lt; t These thiims i ha I I </seg>
            <seg id="p032">\ t mrv | tii r alTunl ndatii IU*1 II •pecially adapted to our Xel ■ I a hen «»■ ;ir th&gt; stock and, above all, lack of Interest hired in- a ild-tlnii (|iiit. lint th aver*|(e Nebraska I a mint nki' u tti \ II H hoth milk lolstei .in. a :i Ml "iicirniiii; our t today, in M.-rrick county. «. have ilu 11. it; liiy • ;• 1 T kin nilil ac&lt;- wt- r;t is.-. :i lid w liicti terfat. Ana it SfllillK liiltte-rfat u ■ )ff tin- far him that it it almost impossible to hirt- iiihii « l.c The reasons for this arc: Poor lows, long hours .veil ii K l,t,.,i ;,,„! well rentllatrd ham. mak w&gt;rk. us*- ■ milk sh.^i and mlM at sons. k*-i jrour men ini. n-shil, ;mil ymi will ii. lull that you ih&gt; rt«r steady * in 1 1 1 o v in*- n r herd &lt;&gt;f sir ctlv dairy cow in. I to inaki- ;i A-SIM i;|t or &lt; I • • x ilonint ii ulum </seg>
            <seg id="p033">K. II II ne »il hk II VVKDNI F. . linn ( :;\\ TKSTI\«. \»mu l\Tln\s is NKItKASI !J\ .1. II. I -i-jiimI- iaiin </seg>
            <seg id="p034">I I used from 4 n ! ii' r I fr rotations have to a large degree been &gt;airsh dairy farmer in making Don- i ations in the world from an agr rt time that thev have led in raisins the butter-fat ippioximately lmi pounds. The farm« r milking in the neighborhood of 700.00 iniiids Of butterfat per year ag iiaiity of the average cow is so low st be many cows in the stale yieldinK \aiuia. owned by the linversity of Nebraska, mils of butterfat; the little Jersey. : ne of our Nebraska dairymen, produce. 1 I rful Ctiernsey heifer. Dolly Ilimple. of Ma— of butterfat marked to her crdeit when mil ird to realize that Mine Nebraska farmers at producing only 80 to 1 imp pounds of butterfat miM they paid attention to some of the r or rive times this amount. Thei i rows in Nebraska today are not pay at the profit of the other 500,000 ran t hardly a iiurstion but that the production in an average annual production of 123 nonndl millions of dollars u ilts ran be an mplislied by work . &gt;t o many farmer - and testing the milk inderstand just wh keeping recordi h. in to disi over and \v&lt; ed out of their ■onsumes about as much feed as any mu y enough butterfat to pay for a fraction a iissary. nor even desirable, that the ule cows with high-priced, pure-bred Ayrshire*. However, for BUCi lolutely tit i i ssarv that he realize the t* ve rapacity of the individual cows in th are cared for by the same man and ar line amount of feed generally tell the difference between eowi ■ parity, but very few jiu'.gis. if any. can mis of butterfat per COW oiililfil. by proper methods of feeding an ■ . thus adding &gt;f (iwr stati lie rciw prodlH- UK 1W0 pOUDdl </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 iily accurate way of discoveries and Babcoek teat. The truthfn Bus mi r«cordi of her production, coi ml sold her for an ordinary price H Slll.T r her i&gt;w her took he remarkable fa&lt; an a yea I. int. r I C(l\\ lusi w 1 I. liroiigiit out in many instance Tli </seg>
            <seg id="p036">ABl BEST AND POOREST COWS Herd X«.. i ■ X 4-i 44v 4 - - $4.1 i,3«2 1.18,191 i ;i ::i 18.22 4;s &lt;&gt;:• ; SS7.3 $ tl.lt llt.Tt * 8«.4t I H.-i&lt;l No. H. I 0 $123.19 $30.59 ■ 4 :: x 1 9 257.3 1 »1.1!« $10.70 « S0.4W $1*4 :• H.-i&lt;l No. K. 27.0 $lL'2.2!t $ :..:.:.«::.•»:! lHii.:. 7J.lt St.71 4.: 4:: S.3 4:! 1 HO .: v:7 I3t.5&lt;$ "."I"* I \:&gt;. f til. 37 $1.4 - :,» \i&lt; t 1 B3 I 4v -JT - i t H.i.l So. 1J H.i.l \... IS. 0.0ft*. 3.4 1341.4 $118.11 &lt; ::■ :.7 - 4 1 :'.4 I 4 $118.16 * 1.797 1.82 '.i'. 7 17.4 1 31.14 • 13.73 TUT 2.82 .Mi. 7 17.4 1 :'. I 1 4 • IS.73 7 $ I M.75 * 7.45 - 1 II. Id Vn. | | "..44^ 4.25 231.3 $ •..•in $ .".■ I4L' 4.2.i 231.:: $ $26.0(1 $ 2,412;4. 33 191.7 3C.*I 37.«« ».»8 12».« $ 4!».1« $ I.Cd J .".' 412 4. 2S 101.7 ;:ti.»;!i 27. CM ».»9 1.32 12!t.« $ 4 !♦ . 1 »i $ l.«0 t .*.0.7« *1 _•:&gt;".:&lt; 3.4&lt; 448.4 $l(3.afl $3t.t2 $123.51 $4.1 159 3.4« 44&gt; 4 $162. "i« $38. »2 * U I.7t7 J sj »«.7 17 4 1 31.14 »13.i Mi.7 17 4 1 :!I14 *lH.7:i 1.1(2 3»7T$145.e»t 7.71 $137.31 $3.&lt; $14 $i::7.:;i $ isnn tins been mail&gt; t ami on ir In r.ls. These rotri arc all niatnrt' ami wer «s ;ire all maturr ami were ■iir The tables also indicate the difference i butterfat produced, as well as the diff. r - &lt;'onsiiiiieil. One interesting thing brought CM Ttu- table* also indicate the difference in I &lt; 'onsiiiiieil. One interesting thing brought out itnarkable differ, nc -e in the cash returns from lnarkahle diff.r. m .• in the cash returns froi ■ ■Aorth of feed consumed. For instance, in r'i worth of feel consumed For instance, i No :'.'. l;i\&gt; $4 17 worth of product for • nsumed. while in Herd Xo. II we timl that Kufi returned only .".." cents for evt ry dollar's </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 IMPORTANCE OF A LONG LACTA To Illustrat TAIil.l IOWINi; IMPORTAXCK &lt;&gt;F l.( ral xi n- mak type. \t However, a inii up, winif n KciikI tluw •mpariaon at iliis tin -icr's rtH'urds bcKan in ■ in leng larg. ly because the fact tl </seg>
            <seg id="p038">\ ■3 v 4 L' 4 _' . I :• I t 4 U't I :&lt;'.i 4 I 74." 4 .'4 \BLK l\ Ten l.fisi I'rolttable Cows $13 s I 1 I] COW IX TEST POH KKDS TB8TED. I'M THE TKX MOST I'ROFITAHLE AM AST PROFITABLE COW* </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 From tliis table you will notice thai herd list raws would yield ■ lirofl the meaner profll of only :i result of ;i veal's work witli a eps no record .it k no i in |&gt;ort an • rotitalili Because it was so a| ai ■ crords were rompleted Man; others »civ uteedi lie yearly rei ord t SO OF End that mat mall lots. « ilinK tti .« J. :e ontanizat III. «!ttl \i| hi *-■ This at wholesale pr \ saving on one ro nus. and tln-r Klity ami one li him! r&gt;-&lt;l hk; swim; n&gt; co-opkrativ :,']!! Would ll nad Ioih 'i I paler and \u\ |i;ty ii 1OXKY a To tV«*&lt; &lt; : &lt;|uir&lt; j ti tin FV*d. VI Tiff Ofi Oil* ' n\\ vlnfc on t»n cowt ivinf; on twen This row M ti I :i! rftiiil jiiici A MVillK on T *• r i </seg>
            <seg id="p040">39 ( m &gt;&gt;F XKT ENERGY Theroii (if 1'rii. Xrt Kii.Mi:&gt; ton l *&gt; t; S \ \ I 7 !,'." I t'. I " J 11 ...; :: iCarbohydrati &gt; |.. r c Ti, mm sun 1"_ ii " 11! 111. | l', | 87 Then l'i s ( 1 l tin I i'i; i., VV T() OKCAMZK Ion for nrK.ini/iiiK ;i i u« lestiMf ink ;i lirj rommuBity. If the BHortatloa i&gt; i'h &gt;n is i, itiiil rooting ii is arri'T} to have as man ilif trater ran lest dnrlng the munili. .\ fooling it is nefesaarj to have aa mar in dajrw in Hie month, ii is Kraerallj . Ir- in llui assu.jaliiiii. S|itr al imUMH • a( Ii aw hit to \&lt;uy i ilolhi octal r each my one dollar i^ i&lt;&gt; be tested Aa ciin readily lie s.-en. i Ml, it ih. lesli-rs inn., in i.-st :i sniiill herd IIP lei test ;i ■mall llenl in ii is finite . to have :i in niiiuin ■ TIIK TK8TER ti)inar\ to havp :l ni niiinni 1 1 ' • •■«■ tcsiini; arraMCM to spt-n I dm "liatioii lii.iiihtTs tnttnlly mgr leoting urrmiKe* to spt-n I one da o piin i- though in main aaaortatloM it is ■i aha 1 1 provide himself with a hors.- an&lt; s a ne for the use of th </seg>
            <seg id="p041">40 The work I in- work is so iirranged that t irm ami arrivei in the afternoon so '■ d ( aih i am He ralrtilates ilut of Feed! fed ami makes suites of feeds fed and makes miEirestions f rakle. Hi- keeps a record of tin- pxs id froa this estimates Ike mount He also rarefull] weichi ami te&gt; Ike herd duriiiK tfc&lt; this \ &lt;l 'ICMII ill) Ike amount produced for th.- \ ad* in his hook .ml a rou) ot bhih Kroin infoni ifir poorfst km herd beloBflng to members aa&lt; fifty |K&gt;und« hut i ark of this testing aasoriatii While an attempt made at raille aj «ork id Importa all install' ■ r in (hat . Harding th. til been &gt;". h for his rail an. I It i - The work as lerable MVing &gt; an h.- mad Cow teslini: work repi akinn dairying more profltab ■ it ttiat the remark:! b ■ ml la larRel !»• drri\ cil dland is largely due to tl aid be deri\ ed from » el i During tke last year one ne« nizpd in Douglas . nuntv, nn&lt; n Mcrrirk count The dairy depart in in I that at the present tii llry" industry of the Mat.' thai tjvw in establishinK and din It stands readv Ity desiring work ol ll </seg>
            <seg id="p042">1 was : be i ■ I •i &gt; namely, i ■Ifa, ami r h and </seg>
            <seg id="p043">4 I t\\'e round inn on I liis H icinn as tuucb as t in a 1 ilcm'i believe tli ilnint: ;m&gt; better than w &lt; 11 fed for &gt;■ tmte &lt;&gt;r Nebraska is lira </seg>
            <seg id="p044">t i.v lint I \ lolstein 1)1 Hall., I </seg>
            <seg id="p045">1' La I in \ ii oik Km \il(li&lt;-&gt; ill Will I "i In - ..I l&gt;;iii\ Kiii^iim I S. l»i-|i. \i;rli lllllli i </seg>
            <seg id="p046">win i are si MVellt 1 No : ! A this as ml work wit S i b. oeAelal and 0 startling were the and workings of the &lt; i ) 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ii ties took it;' limed I am rt'iiiin Van !&gt; isiry i </seg>
            <seg id="p047">4 number. V i \ &gt; Ii IVtT they had tliirtv minal ttruwtli. In 1 '•"' • &gt;t association. Denmark had In operation teatlng -'•' </seg>
            <seg id="p048">blank are furnished that (it imt nty-nix nii'iulicr tin tester is to mak member. Since ther vou Id make it hard ai twenty-six herda t (Ilk : lions, in a this v Ing iia nt i&gt; i ■. Mot lairj Kxper nera \ liiral xitioiu o( tru»l i-y &lt; an lie tumid M creamerii </seg>
            <seg id="p049">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S ASS dairies sp&gt; that the men must hi to ttlf fill then 1 iii pU'iit k \ i Mr. Fo A ra i on nvi'l whil. 4 SH and produced rworda irmi r's rword re&lt;ord. Tli ilf|iiirtiui'iit of (irds with tli ■ " i • &gt; 11 puri </seg>
            <seg id="p050">49 I*. 8. Departnu ll Cdll- 91 xt&gt; -pound chatilllon seal \ nmiilier of the sialis loan these outfits ■York i if lnilKfl- i-ci\er lor tile lOO 'radically all ass nations that liav* it on the 91 .50 basis. Few dairymen ting complain of believe th'i covers quite fully t ation of an isociation \ ft to i onsider s' im imu- of the ASSOCIATION. the ill A I'OW TESTING A: A COW TE8TIX0 A iSOt'IATION s ITS TOO MICH T'S TOO \ll( II WORK 11 WORK a bo does not undent no extra work requ l ml isT a ml th»' working of ami the working ol xtra work r quired o! tin- farmer Klis :ill fi t-il anil milk ill fi eil aiiil milk vi) ui red of (he 1 ilred of the farmer nth studying his record th the cowa the day tl A IT ( OSTS TOO MICH r cow for i Laughter &gt;. Of cour A silo i osts moi • ttion. luit a man that will pa nth to know just as a very ke l» position, pure and are milkln - members ■ tirsi MaoeiattoM were organized was s prai tically impossible tu organ* in, ;inil aecHre ■ roinpetent man for tlit- hriiiK in and liesiilcs one dollar U the char*!- of $1 if the association ami the w ■r an u take car- of t </seg>
            <seg id="p051">merchant hasn't liin work, he hires it done. Tlie banker Im follow their example and keep the bool it done. I do no per cow a niontli. Some limit: lor &gt; LONC THEY AUK f!Ol.\(i TO DA1R1 It the test association means more to V MA Your letter at Man received, anil will try to \ did for us regularly and I from Mr. Clark </seg>
            <seg id="p052">to entering the cow testing &gt;« fin a year was about -'"' lbs fat :!1« lbs. fat. -'I'" lbs. fat. IV 16 lbs. fat lurtioa was obtained by dividing :£e i«rit r of butter- it lined by dividing i price of butter- tarted with a local testing association it pro luction per earn (M S#S.I larted with a local testing association ■ per cent of helfen hi I eniere.l the BMOrlatiOB I had found 1 enure | the association I had found :b.' rowi so beiran to feed batter; and an d better; and Hi( n I soon found tlial by Ic.-dint: a itii n 1 soon found tliai by feeding a al. but vari. (1 to suit the net-ds of in- tried to suit the needs of li ifi | rorecdi liad much larger profits were in tine physical condition for liad in larger profits in tine physical ronditioi pflt* -t do not stop here, but Before the lest 1 sold a neighbor teal do not stop her.', hut i.l priced him a certain cow for - n.l priced him a certain cow for what sh. was callable of doins. I sold a pal of doing, I aold u&lt;- man for *L'7:. I am BelliBg other a "t ro portion. iii&gt; to the teat log association : of an 1 hail used a Babcock tester, lint romplete I ir rows for a Joined the asso. iaiiou tliis work ■:ld do it ourselves, and t ows for a h month our books showed us if we « or not. and gave us courage to buy edl of ill.- row. and to care for age to buy as are doing Id get their dairy husii to d "i t Sign&lt; d i \V. H CLAKK ting that last &gt;.n- should get their dairy Inisines: ij to do it." The experi- arly put in the letter just read ia ations </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Ined the work and wu in the cowyard with a farmer loot ■ra and discussing dairying wh&lt;*n he said, "SOME of n WONT PAY FOR THKIK KEEH " And in looking ov« n a number of ligl Toaropk udders am . ontinued. I woii.dnt tkst SELL ONE IF SHE WASN'T PAYING Fo|{ llKH IIHAK THEY ARE MAKING ME A LOT OF li(K)U MAMK because I V Many an should. Its have been I Laaghter). 1 b. There is one me as loim If, I DON'T NEED A \ COWS AUK DOING, I ( \ i nor Hoard. Ih -i place on ear It is a singular tis where lie must A fanner not long than slim per believe that man ha i ompliment this n profit, would mak &lt; \;n ily. A man i will make $15 &gt;&gt;r ■ucf butttrfal For I at licsi Bid s and dairymen ag i an do, until slii' is |&gt; i li.it has 1 1 1 a ' 1 &lt; lUiiinst a «ness it'St » &lt;&gt;U S &lt;MI|&gt; III.- K I Kr where m taaoriatlo «s made just lltMl »•: M ;t \ lif soint' broug Some of the objection offered are rather ludii t approached on the subject said "HE KNEW THA 1 COWS WOULD NOT I'AV TOR THEIR KEEP IK I AMI KNEW JUST WHICH ONKS THEY WERE Hi: \\ BELL THEM BECAU8E III: WANTED To KKF.I' BEVENT AS HIS BARN HELD .11 ST SEVENTEEN." il.aushi.-ri In workiiiE in a community in one of our .astern s </seg>
            <seg id="p054">while Iht Hall-mate was making $13 an average up what a holm und liith have millions i Laughter i . Th.: r t lit- rich man poorer ;issu, iation a ising him mom • • tlinir stall-mates are doing most of the it etiBg where Mr Rabild was once presenting i&gt;c iationi lie said he would gladly answer any work. Presently an old k aliout tlu uni arose up and said, Mr. Speaker 1 man is going to do with those cows that don t hem to your neighbors?" Mr. Kabild h' si No, don't sell them to your neighbor. ju*i low-down, mean rascal, and you have a them to him. if hell promise to keep them 1 'an sit on the fence and look across the igbbor of yours is milking those cows ir an.i paying their hoard hill f n no movement started in the last niry farm* of this country so much known as the co-operative cow testing association ivilege of helping in a small way Neb iska. and I would l&gt; it us activ. d have at least a store of tlu'si associ &lt; ults of work in the Ni li: ih:il |&gt;)i ;isi of work li;is lit'in unsigned In anotl :i ral way. eivint; its history, neral way. giving its histor oni most often met. In i met. In i losing I i r kiml attent Ion. l&lt; I ( III AM. id \ourKliinu l"f«'«ln: : — l(v i:&lt; l.i i i&lt; • ii t&gt; iln- liiiiiy linlusi Itiilx'ii \\. M&lt; (■iinii-.. tc I lie Iliiiiy liKlusiry. Associat ind arranging II t ream manu- ddr. fell </seg>
            <seg id="p055">I 14 and its Relation t" the hairy Indnsii ..I tin- world as "li e Cri ai I moment! and whai I li a , luit I bop* I" make- it avinn in mind iIihi I tilding them until t uniM't till &gt;oiir M \v&gt;&lt; lau^li and kx pond bunch of fell Bincc the orgai Iiivo years ::k« K Factoring :uul handlii tmttarj lav iry ap| </seg>
            <seg id="p056">ii nnil other ingredients "it in the back sin t soon dlacovered lbs. &lt;i i ft • 1 I lie di Keren I x rt-( linty and Nouiishini I'rodurt ." X&lt; shine Product I r emted ■ larger demand for our .ii demand for utir 'amount manufactured in turn i ■d in [urn an for tile lifst grade of sweet i you find an ire cream t t made of sweet nil an ire cream r otherwise nowadays, you will «, you will iicer for good twee! i r— • am and dairy Intl I we.i i rt-am tween tin- in- cream and dairv int&lt; iniiHon interests which ) ts which i ill mi n . we as an OTSBBl in cirKani/, for the eanae m enliKhtemuent tliis proposition fnun 11 i mi tli. standpoint of the as&gt;m i ; w- also recognize association ictnreri an. I we want to I we wan: to mil increase it. Imt we all have ill haw airy Industry and believe that «■ duatrt and believe tliat ■ otion Imili agreeably ami nrotitabl nil agreeably ami iirotitably. 'rested are using their i the old row; tliat hat m.m! a a ; tliat ha ■v ;irr su\ Ing tin- ol. I i i&gt; onrltisively t,&gt; the farmer the old cow and inn. r reding In can make Ins dairy i set better rattle, rut down his down his tt as been their line of edu a similar i .1111 |&gt;ainn only not iiii|iaiun only not id kr,.| irn; hi r on the farm ami o\V and kee|iing In r on the rmrni ro.luct manufnrtnred from raw t manufactured from ra airyuien, and still lucres a in. I still inrreax i- in -en work tm akmg one hue m working along another so linsy that we did not norice na along one l:ne busy that we did not notice til »e happened to meet at a point wher pened to meet at a point when ftinK aii|iiaint&gt; d you will nnd a r s acquainted you will find a r&lt; - our members on pace* IS4 M i list ot our members on pages 12 4 to I repon of the Ni-liraska Dairy- ■ in n:il report of th lad treasurer. Brother B MrotliiT U been the father of your association on. !■• ' nstrurtive ; </seg>
            <seg id="p057">&gt; In n you m- in It might be appropriate ;it this t hf action t;ikc.i by cur apsoriation » i dii a&lt; ccrnt in c for list The follow teit 11 nan i 11 We. your &lt; ii t find' r tl Ttl.T V n l 1 t HAINTY AND XOI'RISH The I'l rnor M Pt t in not nl ;in ii </seg>
            <seg id="p058">w nd in thf t in i ii«l ej had not done tli i t In it; nr since 1 have \ vernor Wli Hid calling her am t his Remit up said. Will man talk:: an talkin ;iy I am her.- hefure &gt;•« lit this time re t t .i lerictiltur I of it. I l&gt; ir to sneak a' at* 1 li.i- licationi for this reminds They B) him I In that much. u!red ilollan i They paid him ■r several if appeared be- Finally aft his audience I not only asrei &lt;l iTU ire paid m The ( I iiok M] s ' l!&gt; me anot hi r ve not lov ltTi :ivi' In ■ . pl:i. ly interest. it tint i 1 ni ing a nil ulad to welcome the peO| I f our state to Lincoln. In thf t aimers of t productive i I am glad to I lie at smile tin thanl- iiidtd b« was with In r to marry him. hut when be was K'-IitlHinan would get in Mtum in- and calling her ill) Mid. "Will ■ when I was not |&gt;re|&gt;areil io&gt; the liieli honors the st but I really h'nil more api D I ever anticipated. And or of :&lt; iurrh in Ark:in.-:^ I am la talking our ■! 1 all vi </seg>
            <seg id="p059">EBKASKA DAIRYMAN'S A Tlie i'p I A I A The (■ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p060"/>
            <seg id="p061">In li and ii l&gt;ri I Ka, I New Y M A () : : rlva \. lv iiti.l thinl ii UMl! NATIONAL ItAIKV Jlln.lM, &lt;&lt;&gt;\ll-,| Itv Kilu. H. l.ovchiml ■ held, the I'niveraity of Neb '■&gt; 1 J. ;ii Cliii ago. • on highea •stake* tor the highest indivii at th«' National LhH in number (it ini'ii r fourteen cdll. i ■ -t imrf i: In II To N. In Judging </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebraska team was &gt;er of points in 1 inn points, beatiM Missouri by 28 points. IK to the man icoring highest in all breeds takes scholarship he was unable ffered by the Holstein F?reeders' Association. n of Iowa, who stood set on I Vhiaenand was beatea for first place by a &gt;\ Nebrask n stood only two-thirds of i iiison of Kansas for first place in judging (!uern- dairynieii of this state for hicli the 1 in preparing for and win- for their state. Scarcely less credit is due iirtinent in ive,l lniversity by th ai Nebraska on the ma states in th THURSDAY'S IMti (CKKIHM Farm. Thursday. January .'■'• ijr, Ja i l't';tlllf|-.VIIt«'M I la) H\l!t^ IMHSTin I replied 1 1 of dair-. ■led t urn just r regret nn before I ha&lt; N urship offered by the Blue n judging Holsteim with a 4imi points with a margin of 17% points the 1 niversity of Nebraska for Nebraska lias K.iod nu !•' OTIocli A. M KOIH \M&gt; l'i:\&lt; Tl( I IS Till-: K. M. l.itll.-. tip invcstigat. Th&lt;&gt; fact was I nt to instruct then away </seg>
            <seg id="p063">KiiTiuui' \\ illKiut a I u .,- i ailed ic i cin unistaui \ i»ts iti, :l! P lemma he proi bouse is sa nit a arabl&lt; la Manage ;i large comiuercia lii ronsidera Btnt'ii ?■ Amociat ifil me In its ti :t ion* King in "ill y our prac </seg>
            <seg id="p064">\ IUU Her ability to yi« n food she tak l.-stal \ il I Th. r ts. w r IM i&lt;li agriculture nt-'rally under- dairying as they ai^ idy in tli.' Agricultural in dairying wl Ige an 1 make liim more |i in ■«■ and |irai! ih are ins«parabt&lt; 1 ili^ir happy rombinmtioa ii!;'.kf ork. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">1 Question In regar rl!i li ss t re in ii Answer A M I i I Tin- 1 Hi . I ;t\ ;&lt; II leav </seg>
            <seg id="p066">I \\ IS,,u-k i .1 ihould permit the 'mid ary, like la Amm ■ iii n they leave, Ill 111 arm t i , ,»■ r 1 win \\n mow r&lt;» r ' i;i i &lt;n: &lt; i:i am s ;i putn s&lt; ill!* 1 natc i in U </seg>
            <seg id="p067">barter rs the curd fr feet, n^ii. in, ml I r in cabl v </seg>
            <seg id="p068">tea and houi T a t r. T i t tliiit will keei A tank or • llfiit. Tl be shaded from th i k t I ;l 1 At ti i \ </seg>
            <seg id="p069">rn California and alit on of tl atH th 1 \ oil I I III Hie ml tht-r &gt;i\ii il in ttum t In- cr*&gt;ai Bjars It i ercolatea throui rmti s thereb) rooliai n all lh&lt; i\&gt;\ it ■ nothing lint it &lt;!&lt;&lt;• ■ i lcr tin' cooling \ ease! </seg>
            <seg id="p070">re . line it :n v xerriMMj i \ 1.1. WATER II I. V IS-23. 1 'i ii I- da \ &gt; itcr Ir will iio the cooling, it er than water. F?&gt;r this ! narrow &lt; aus and should </seg>
            <seg id="p071">i.-i I sell 1. Ill iisiiulitv t ills. II. i </seg>
            <seg id="p072">i it in rna -id; ti hi mixfil ai H al Prof. H. Y A </seg>
            <seg id="p073">■ council of a lie ni ft'ork I </seg>
            <seg id="p074">li (if our time in away from the othe it r cows ami more of then nt-rease production and at the atiun tl at tlii' value of e place fur the inspe. t ion well a through the agenc &gt; s treatment thai th&gt;- patronage may :-e ti of ;i capabl iperator is the iperintendent. in tlie selection of an \f&gt; the standard tiv huh the public rood, clean-cut r immunity in which lie li\ favorable impression, and without ly build a desira'de to permamn n the creamery business in mpelled to ace sirable for any reason ex Illes--. Islial erating stations for some com| vered ts biisine-s i at a hardship be worked upon h as those just lerintendeut would be conferrii atry, and upon his own compai t i.l i a man u ay tn day with e further a&lt;lva earn. It i 11 known far) luring th a hour that the suiierin- ly educated :&lt; !■ &gt; ne er is pr la us that he is mi- nus even v th the present high ml I rather thin rrect in mak- at he has not b&gt; en II tile lac in the feeling and the handling of his luce tile Hill of bis feed and at the lication of the Rabcocl doubt point &gt;ut individuals that bat 1 am voicing the wishes of every me] wnan in the state when I </seg>
            <seg id="p075">74 Each ouldrrx The l'r&lt; sid. in w, «ill all be very nine tad we are always glad tn ha say that 1 hope t use a Habrix k tt &gt;tU KUiisc t lip an Ins far in f the ijiialit ■ i ream &lt;&gt;n band operator We K dairying: ;:nd 01 believe him It-ll us soniethiiiK good, Prol G I. M ■ eta of Oh </seg>
            <seg id="p076">l'l&lt; I. (.. I,. Mi i\l\ »mar as iiiK'rsarin »ve witnessed t eya » Im Bpent not only days 1 »'iiabl&gt; nil thus ni.ik thf intere: I ity-seven ntativ fanners wrr veil represent;! ■ i.i tnral romniitt w inn w ibdivide this text. First. \\"h it? and third irgarine that it ranoo- Prussian war of 1870. As the French pui|ieror. Napoleon III n exper! t ( which wa Ills t &lt;M I &lt;1M \ K(. \l:i\l I.I &lt;.iSI.\TIU\ (»\ XKItKASKX II.4IK1 MKX. I lut (if its v;il fornuilatin MlUI t IlllKll rifiuls practically holil •e of the I'nited Stuu- iitfil lit rimes in W crest of the farmer uir months' I s!m ir hours. k for his text His t xiierimi'iit ttcr. It uas made irni iroduct fr. in the ol.c h:it only the I.. r melting temperatur Htibilil t of iIih i rodu&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Owinti u ■ in t i in ■ imiiiikIs Il'mlci- prew in method for iiicitiiii; f;i t I Mutter melts r is More d era tu re mm I !!•■ rheaiKT than i, tcsiin*: :;&lt;'•, fat at I. 1 pounds of i ii ;i Tin t'liner at wholesale; labor ■ dm « holt' amount </seg>
            <seg id="p078">N \, in, I, lal&gt; nt i at &gt;t ~t Iluu ha r it. ■tuition, it knufactiired lH(imarE;irine industr to their cause. I ai </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 would be used in this i known » hat In 1 vat doii iolhir. Tin- mi 1\ redress tin- bondsmen of th linp to tile dairy i in anufailured from tin- ii oatrol of this product Xotwithstandii hit £r:nlt it' iition of \ iolatii hile tliP man who We find a report cln nt. the bureau of anima in II v notorious procedure TIih report of Mr. il M4 ' • of thf creamer itatpments, 1 «roi </seg>
            <seg id="p080">79 noi think for a moment that :m' ; ' i r&gt; anurii-s in an uns.inita •l i r 1 1 a statement recently ma&lt; reports him correctly i t:&gt; t unsaaitan ntly inailt rrectly i t:&gt; thi .i.- country were putting in their In :n S poun Is cii' salt, thus ma batter than the lit) try « ere i uliiiiR in their In salt, thus mak- *■ the littK . indicates on* of t\\n th'iius eltfl what he knew to be that ct about which he was talking, was talking i. r. as made in our laree or sm mall ■If to one per cent of curd usua in' per cent of curd usually got. Kvery wlK hut termaker kno &gt;-ii r Kvery wise buttermaker ki in would injure the keeping qui in would injure the keeping ciualit i\ In c-ight per cent of salt li butt i\ in eight per cent of salt n l&gt;utt«- Die average per cent ot s;i It plai-eil in b average per cent ol salt placed rec- and one-half Occasionally son and one-half. Occasionally toou r four and one-half per cent Partic r four and one-half per cent 1'arti \ew Knglanil itatea Xew Knglancl Itatei :&gt;icgest market};, prefers from two markets, prefers from two u &gt; that our large central rreami that our large central rream&lt; i i&lt; a 1 ami bacteriological standpoint, .&lt; er that is produced in America t ical and bacteriological standpoint, ■r that is produced in America toda e of four or five of our largest (INI or Hv r Chief Rawl select the make of a steel the make of an we will submit the same to som. the same to Home of e will demons'rate who is correct. t who is correct It- sour, does not in lie ate that it » and bacteriological tests, mad* ttiT from some of our large plants t some of our whole milk plants, there The slandering of any brant ninety interests Hid (iairits at inner neral conditions in the production manufacturing r will drive the dairyman, f man. into some ether line of agricultural &gt;rn belt region are :, the c thai is. a farmer endeavors </seg>
            <seg id="p081">I n to such an extent that it is not profitable t keep a cow for the raising of i li aluahlc for a man In keep a COW ju fore, the fraudulent or im reased M r mi reas 'nly striki- at the butter business, tint it will strikt strike at the butter business, lint it inn and thus decrease our live sto 1 k e the dairy and live stuck Industl &gt;ill place the dairy and I Injuring any branch of agrtcult njuriiiK any in that particular line or not, ;is i' . The argument is pal forth bj the frl is that an Ini their pn erybod) \\ Im I .„ k ■ l t he sal' nan w bo is new ii; lurtloD, which would result in an i&gt;|il&gt; ami demand This oleomai iii that particular The art; i ;ii a try. The fi X 111. I 1 in t Kin T ,,r re I ■• i IH ellleil I am I'll msi .1 to I loyalh I If pi ■ !ie position ol u the Hi ■ ryinan a I man and t ried i. and unsanitary and 1 1 itfliient tl ■ (tatemeni that be bad - - without adding .my fertilizing ■ rtile today as when he started itenient at the preaent a^. with 1.1 - fertile today on and the general kin .mil the general knowli mint &gt;■ tied through th ishid through the |iress. s not a tit i illture. \n dnuht Mr. Burlt son will oleomargarine Interests ol the n untr&gt; live in his hehalf . The National ('.range, which of this country, is about uiianinn and the dairymi n should at least Join If. by any chance. Congressman Bur of agriculture and Commissioner &lt;a •ion. with Dr. Kelvin at nrgarine would i ertainl Be. \o dinilit Mr. lln pomargarlne Inten &gt;t I e in his behalf The National ('.range, which largi ■ion. with Dr. Meh n iiargarine would , .r </seg>
            <seg id="p082">81 and is tile creamery shark, a ersuadi- fanners to take stork and ere mere is not sufficient business a or winery. I have not a wor.l to inaniauai ( ,r co-operative creamery, where they have •fully support such a plant. operation of ■ rrea«ery. like any other hm skill and experience. Qarketing of butter alone is quite a problem at the pi - is I rue when- the quality is not strictly first - neriM that have established their markets l.ave ai « II onet in thai reap iMie la (jiiite ■ problem at the pi 1 their markets have ai r»-&gt;p THURSDAY. K «U THK Mll|{\SK\ I&gt;\IISV COMMISSION. VieK l\ Haiiseii. lirymea'a Atitrlatloi: i for your kind invitation to address you on the su ! nmiaaion ;md its work. I shall attempt in a brief an. I v,,u my oliservations of one year of service in irtment of our state government. 1 have tried t r your kind invitation to address you on the ral ts work. I shall attempt in a brief ;in.| ervationa of one year ol service in this tment of our state government. 1 have tried t touch with this branch of the department of the food, dairy the di ■ artnu'iit of the food, dairy ontmission. ■• meetings should he of great int. Test and value to each •- I i Ited thai mil of the many thousand of dairy - lllj take suffi.-ient interest ti&gt; avail t I work. 1 am inclined to h.lieve that If jome method which would induce ■ desire ar ntereat and value to I that out of the tunny thousand of dairy- ficient in avail t im in&lt; lined to believe that If you ethod whirh would indure a desire among k-s much iirogi-css night the agricultural department of the n of l.arning akng th. M satin- I oral department ruing along these same li rorm you of how necessary it is for you to prop • I. how to feed and how to rare foi ii you to properly are f aj have the opportunity to realise plenty of the product stment. and labor. Now at this point the con and the dairy law in the wisdom of the keg a hand in the regulation of meth. *&gt;jeet. 1 &gt;;■ itan onl on the farm where PJ product originates and follow it until it reaches I realize plenty of the product i n r the commit 1 the dairy law in the wisdom of the ation of method t on the farm wher illow it until it reaches mission, have been scl. n Beli ulating conductor from the cow to the consumer. The .! and regulations to fully matters not how much </seg>
            <seg id="p083">» \ 82 and how pare the product if Be contaminated, due to its great affini The dairy commission has i No milk and (ream and I desire to mak sincerely wish we could gel thii bulletin Into the who milk- The dairy commission eiit t nd larger town These experimen ■ lass prod nated a k ilirt tniiii t germs from disea To, dropping M rained il nary strainer along this 1 IIS btrainer at thi gauze and fas Mraiiier. In t \m required for burned be boob tain Stable should tight 1! i in the stable. Stahl tin- litter should be removed t daily Have the herd exam in promptly remove from the herd health. Often times one cow rontai dairy Never allow the rows to be excited unnecessary disturbance; di not expo abundance easy of access and alway Salt should always be a' days before and 5 days after calvinp tests, found that a lar« Itliy Kcliiciii liberally, using only fresh pahitabl </seg>
            <seg id="p084">rerioua to milking filth to cake upon tringy or un- ■d. Milk with contact with the nly full of milk [lining, but re&gt; ii promptly and cool immediately. \ . which has not been aerated and pro- not been aerated and l itb or mosquito netting. Never mix f B cooled. Do not allow milk to thouid anything be added to milk to ami cold are the only preventatives ting. Never mix frt 1 Dij not allow milk to should anything be added to milk to er the rans, when moving in a wagon, with ■ nt distract. on by heat in the summer nt distract. on by heat in the summer e Of milk is also Inn in the care of cream made of metal and have all joints smoothly k is also true in the care of ule of metal and have all joints smoothly i to become rusty or rough inside. Do not become rust rough inside. Do not 0 the farm in the same cans used for de- ame cans used for de lairy utensils by first thoroughly rinsing first thoroughly rinsing clean inside and out with a brush an ut with a brush an nattrial is dissolved; then rinse and lastly rial is dtasolv 1; then rinse and lastly r steam. Provide the dairy house with a the dairy house with a 1 insure plenty of hot water. After I in pure air, and in as much sunlight :is hand awaiting to be transporfed to market lenty of hot water. After i ure air, and in as much sunlight as be transporfed to market manufactured for that purpose, pr and should be Frequently stirred to issible. thereby preventing unnetes VI the above suggestions would trvation of dairy products upon the farm and lint with ]rss opportunity for contami- i&gt; In Mnit employed by the commission to close in- Wbraska. urging bettiT buildings and more sanitary methods for the production, caring and the farm AMEKY AGENT OR SIT r RIXTKXDKXT rmation collected by the department from time to time shows tendent sometimes instructs his agents to manipulating the test ACM intendents have instructed </seg>
            <seg id="p085">them to raise the tests until ■ci urately. Also the operator cffke of tlie commission «rhi&lt; h ha Th.' luperintendenl is also i operator! and 1 would r hanille in Bentlve for lii on the farm. The following iiiml for properly ( ariim Cool jn k vat« bI ■ lid or in Home way ■hortage ;i&gt; i, si i ti.-.J K! operator pending ication, integrity &lt; be sanitation of t Klahl!-ll]l].|lt onditions in </seg>
            <seg id="p086">&lt; i.WKXTN IN a law lo.-s in patron who produ atron who prodm be bought on a basis of veals results whi.-ta ry. Seven stations in Kansa r arraiiKement- rst month's r ided first and IK Xi'lTlllH first grade cream. le f Donthi later wh-n V d \\ 74'; of first pa le bettor pri&lt; • and the Utdone liy Ms neiKli- incentive of nid bad cream is r &lt;&gt; ns tans so arr (! to 7-r; first K ra If Ttmi in January alien m mi a qualit) assistance in raising ian tkeir ereui busi- </seg>
            <seg id="p087">V Khorousli. firm but intrusted to him it factor in the ■&lt; of your associate ■ It is time that tt Khe dairy insper iology sii ;is i&lt; or alons tke 1 • of dairy prod •hould erase In tonni &gt;f your st;iti- chen </seg>
            <seg id="p088">87 • has held a better qualified 1 department are subjected to iierforni their work, at &gt; more than fully familiar- work and its duties, till a n ;itid other men are placed lies ami we. the |.. I'M -I VI c&lt;i&gt;T &lt;&gt;l' MILK I'INHH &lt;TI&lt;&gt;\ I (.l.iwi. \ •.«■■■ iiil&lt;- Kililm Hoard'*. Ihiir.t man. mils of average testing milk'.' nn he done is I t tile. What are ilk production' ex cost th. tli- 1 at in a year and oth fat up to pounds of fat If re. it is plain ii for the silo from 6 to :;•• is he amount is a large factor in \v stalks and leaves will provide nearh trientl of which £88 pounds will be protein. A t ;ire about 1 1 "0 pounds ilil be made to k&lt;c [) him ndustry of our state 1 of butterfat? How much mini rtble in uiv,- ;&gt; definite answi oncerMd, in thp 1 location ami is opa lhat may b&lt;; grown, variis all tti lire; clover from none of I hi t parts of this (luce corn, a yield of 10 acre will produce 4000 pounds of digest i- uiuls of digestible protein. In ■"&gt;'• bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p089">\ I of digestible nutrients of which 1 7i&gt; pounds arc diges devoted to timothy will yeild a pounds of digestible nutrients of which S4 pounds ' pounds of digestible nutrients i protein and an a&lt; re of clover will protein and an acre of clover will yield 3000 poun nutrients of which 41'X are digeatibli nutrients of which 4l'S are digest difference in the amount of nutrients i difference In the amount of nutrients produced per acre, depend the kind of crop srown. for the jrleli arable ha The man behind the cow is no sn luctioa of milk. Hoards Dairyni; ii order to Ke! hold of facts the kind of crop crown, for the yield rop per acr The man behind th ■ KUCtion of milk. He ises in order to Kit and the methods c milk and the methods employed by d I farms rWted i "titained i $:i::.4:'&gt;: average milk productio i fat Fni , . dollai ■ d * 1.^4 oi I n. I ; -• received J i ollar'i - and thot - in favor Of silai:. W receiv returned .&lt; i . I ; for each dollar in poor stabi. who u. i ra and thi lining 1 8 « i,i pounds i with itll llle CO8I &lt;'t |&gt;ri It i - 5 Biving It is ■:::. «iv it type ferent types of animals '1 ■ iiiiiry in determine nt was nia.li u tl .lit W depredation, taxes, labor, etc. h wa lerdmeu al the Minnesi me a rery good Dpp&lt; thai time I havi had MffiTein i s of ro»'l and I iation, tax erdnieu :&lt;t tin- Mil differeni with all this experience 1 find II 'duce 1 10 pounds of milk or on. following psraj ned for under certain con large degree upon expi To eet at the cos) of producing ■ I all this experience 1 oduce i»" poundi a allowing pnni - iced for under ceri large decree upon » ii </seg>
            <seg id="p090">r the crib and stover? What of alfalfa, oats, timothy and clover uesota experiment stat on undertook the cost of producing; the different ly a certain number of farma tlie amount of labor required to pr&lt;&gt; - inly was the labor of mi n and 1 Interval on the land, interest and ry, in fait, every cost was recorded against tltlished here and many of JO I with the methods employed. It W» at $ I tin per acre silage cost from | in the field and the stalks left to go the field and the stalks left to go ii r aire. Corn cut, shocked and shredde acre. Corn cut, shocked and shredded ml clover liay about $v.1o per acre, niak ■ to $4.ihi. I hav imated that it alfalfa about $14 nti three crops &lt; to $4.nii per ton It was found that grow a oats, (living th* urs and cents br iKs la a variable er if we could Ml It would lie bett \i f labor for men and so many hou i an acre. K\ n to bring conflicting itatementi bi'tter man f labor would I" far akii t producing mH bout 4 it I iwl but this ddlnz N i i the market price ol ! 1 by soim tl • Is as what it told that n the farm and targed to her at that th&gt;: only fair waj on the farm to produce tin My reasons for </seg>
            <seg id="p091">90 ■ the liirm thai would For Inata • i i ;i k«- inti nearly 4"' .it into I lit' wastt .1 F, il Thr In (his circular he 11 ■ ■ row produ consumed of ;i Knd manure worth ; connected with 5. In other words, tin lation on i ow, Inti i t shows ri ad ■ be &lt;l&lt;Ti\- it would com ■ av«-raei' farm will just alimit pa future simply i </seg>
            <seg id="p092">\ 91 t t 1 k.-t I !&gt;; 18 t li.mir tun as a rated it into tin- ration and i furthermore, then . ly any mark« but siiKf tkeM Item do not make an) ilation I thought it well to aaana jg ni production for the etrm - iti| capable of producing 7 pounds fat \ r and (!rali Cowi .\v Farm I" Ing 1 4" His. nf Fat arket I'ri. Y Of Feed inn | y M Fat Milk * the best that ran i \\ the land the are liv no which will make mill ill onnectieut experiment 3. mart it can be Kubatitutc ind fiit I have ! 4m |u. in. st of producing our poii mi of fat that BTermge i t" pouadi ami l'^&gt;&gt; Alfalf In- above talilf by the ('(nine ■ lat milk for market ro </seg>
            <seg id="p093">londit nun the fan i l r r Of (I - In other la of milk The follow Tin- calcutat conditions. Inst&lt;&gt;; from the farm. We hav&lt; tlx a hundred. r&lt;&gt;r th&lt; ■ I Horn tlic farm, the </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Total 1 1 &gt;il ■■&lt;! Where to fo a part &lt; i well ira w... i ry man fan Aid in th n ti </seg>
            <seg id="p095">94 Q. How long does it hike tn I t A. T &gt;n hinery used In filling it. On an a urns of green corn i (.i How mm i ■MM tn plant it I little thii k. r Q Whiit tine do you cut it for t are well dented and the hast d&gt;\ other words, it is cut only a sin shocking purposes Q. About what do rock phosphut A. It costs about $16 ■ ton laid down in For! A Q. What amount of water would vou recommei B the silo" Tin A. Corn should </seg>
            <seg id="p096">N •did than when n the cuttiT is running (« no watar need be n lie put &lt;m ton for at farm ily i onsidered it .1 for her feed :&lt;t more likely to take into ion that affects the yield of nsidered. Putting it in t iws milk production w. 11 yield four tons i t An acre that will yield a 14 in pounds of digestible tin sin Is w ;t a would I t sar k ion an I :ils&lt; diffei nit i rops. How da ry sition r charging t it with what ilt at Colorado and Idaho, whert- Vi Unwed, the prict s of alfalfa hay range mitnunities even in thei wherp ,i New York and even Wisconsin and Illinois r ■ $ir. to $18 per ton. What this difference? The answer is demand. What Kiyes it id? The cow. to a larKe extent If this be true, then should me qualifications at least, that which t( ition of tht •what dry a imall for the feeii ivliat she pro- nsider the amount of milk 1 kiiul of crops tlie aor&lt; ration the kind of cows mcls of dicrstible n i corn will iiroilm g very imiionuur point wlu-th on. As I are higher. East, tn such </seg>
            <seg id="p097">NEBRA8KA DAIKYMANS AS- ASSOl'IATN y. Wliat do you consider the value of maniir ina row worth pet ton? A. It is generally held t he worth from $1 U What aliout permitting rattle to erase on ireen alfa to permit rattle to «r Animals that art- pastured on alfalfa lliled Illd t&gt;lo«t and unless carefully watched many of them an alfalfa. In Wisconsin at any rate, will nut stand past Ids bare been used for pasture the alfalfa BM &lt; i i • i (i. What do you know A Oats cut u Inn in I lir i|U;tl BMncli depends apoi the liarn shoulil he tdl o will ho used more i his will be will depei A It is a dangerous prxti tWhen land is «ri No general :m&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p098">97 t i that when land reaches t conlil be made with the use ;i alfalfa to cur*' in the cook? the weather: ordinarily from th weather; ordinarily from three -e hauling the hay to the barn hauling the hay to the barn the ■ pencil up. permitting the sun a ned up. permitting the sun and AY. DAY Bte Farm, Lincoln. Nebraska. January .'4, Iipcmi O'clock. Nebraska January 24, I o o'clock Ml II l\«. (H liAllty r.VTTLl ■: BREKDKRH 1 .\SSOT1.\TIO\ KIIKKDKKS' ASSOCIATION. airman. John Sneililon. ting reail and treasurers repor ami treasurer's report. ept« 1 and re. -eived. of tk itlon in n ted and n ition w&lt; re re- ola. 1 City. t meeting we hav. ortani/. d th li\ a . id we should hear from anything I roaM add to the nve over half a million dairy ting associations. I ha\ • I iunery lias offered a premium I m the most liutterfat begiiiniiiK ling Jam ary 1st. next year. I think Mr Beatrice Creamery people, and ft\ prize to the cow producing i terfat during the year. Mr xtend a vote of appreciation t r this prize of $.'iO.nn nounred that the association should accomplisn 1 and associated with thi Assoi iation. The members should take great in- est and activity in st inmlat in tr dairy interests throughout Iba her; and which would only be a ii r of a short time until we would be able to stop the purcli </seg>
            <seg id="p099">98 NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S r ■ weal of lowi t in .V we have her in thf country. I n of Arkans - tlir smallest II a I think it is h dairy IniiMiim ouch ■ enough for the eipi have here a plctun equipment, and today that Vi &lt;&gt;s! of building. I s ( Xew Vork p . and they u Gentlemen, you would be dairyman in the tliirtei nrt Increai ■ and we lia\ from earl* four or five . </seg>
            <seg id="p100">99 x 0.090, three stories sin and Minnesota, tin n and Minnesota, their . but 1 think WiKOMta'i k&lt;Mi for ■ $ 1 mi imii 1 think Wisconsin'! ■t this addition, that th-ii ins over $ I : ",n. mm. It j. ui|itnent anil tliat we ar&gt; iiR dairy instruction thai ins to in. nt states. It seems to rablv situated, where « t II in Nebraska. \'c lated. where « ryiiiK as In Nebraska No Dili and a!fal!:; i and favorable i mdlilim mil and favorable rondil ir dairying in the union W iik in the union. \\ ive dairy education that vi&gt; dairy education that t We can (I it and I am sure you « ill t and I am sure jrou will n. ill I ■•&lt; ond to none. and. with -ary for any (I ill not r da instruction. There is ma nst ruction. There is r r cirl should nor receive the ed (1 not lereivp the ■ We can do tli - uir! if you \v:l work to the h incuts nude by tii. &gt;r she mrds. We can do tli- girl if you will worl ■ ( Coupland. t. ami Gentlemen and Memberr tleiiien and HeBbrm •:: thai t his i^ a lubject that li^ il);s i- a subject that lies s coin', ssiiui. that durine (real number of institu- umber of instil ding I hunted up »i ling I hunted up w is the were doinn along that onsulted with tlie coniniitt.,. on indus - im and &lt;xper:nieir r~t nsulted with eat ■niniittee on In tate farm and experiment i V ui have tin strong there is a buildin- rot t s a building hall li e, that shall be rommen- r Nebraska. We t&gt;. &gt;f Nebraska. We I lairy country it is in N&lt; both of soil and elimal in airy country it is in N, - on both of soil and climnt.' t rip your n sen's made in ■ Idei nta made in K over the itate of Wisconsin that we taw more evidences of i i </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NEBRASKA DAIRYMAN'S \SS IA that should slay on tlie farm, milk tt home life so that their children after t that they will continue to stay. You lull of the hoard of regent* in this mat Before cloning I wish to imously recommended t • an h.- Bceomiil iit out. T years that tl .nt. it t i ldl \ tl it, an " Inch don't Br own business and t&lt; ot progress as v Kins, and the regent on must interview the li pet close to him and lell him we B I visited the lonely sc ho of the way city. San Luis (Niispo. Tl put me to shame win n 1 saw it an magnificent building laying right in iiave a fine building at Anns. Iowa, t building in Minnesota. Thev all put us t Why? Hi'iausc the peo f keeping cowi ami tlie Kind tha ::lll la .leal for Ncli KBO tlimlit . iat can be mtdi ;tie. it is our I </seg>
            <seg id="p102">XVEX X 101 as we are by I lit a much ne&lt; II i ar a wdrd from IVnn very great 'n- ■rtance not only to the In t lie dairy in- \arious associ- Iversity farm, and to whether it Nebraska with profit that matter hai been under disi ussion the ■y t hiii u. &gt; t Of th v profit I'riini the io\v anil the Imtt | iIih calf. That wa&gt; OM of ll w \v!n n slic v.t ill into the feed : iv when stu went into the feed : it isgociation which is interested in 'he elation which If Interested in i urn of whether you can p - ahle conditions upon th si.-e the question of whether you can p' er and over asaim, and the oaly n I over Ogata, and the only qm the marsrin of profit depends upo of the nil, ami the effli I think when you begin t e intelligence of the man. and the efficiency en vou begin ; nk w i ulturo here in here in this state JH iiyinc must be fundamental Mot th«» majority but upo'i ted on tliis high priced lam ! i n an acre of land throt.e ■iriency of tlu thai dairying ;n!il m* land beromea hiii'i receded ne liave referreil I risrht her- in these farn ■ damental ajority but upon a located on tliis high priced land ! i acre of land thro ficlency of tin it dairying laml bei-omes hiii'ier ;t I ave referred t her ■arms .. day to i ui^ anfacture on the far . - to Iowa, Illiaoli man- ful fact ure on the farm Iowa, 1 11 in i of thi I Iowa aiul IIUbo ■ of Iowa and Illino x. both. ;tnd you pay the freight o tli. and you pay the freight on uid miles You M t lie expert labor ,1 ml tea. You M t lie expert lal&gt; ture your raw material into concentrated - raw material into coaeeatnti advancement that we have, with the advnnt II that we have, with the advan r to the climate of Nt itin tely superior to the climate of New Me product* shippi'd to New K ark. t on a par with their products. There is </seg>
            <seg id="p103">111 t 1 • fur tin' linn we are in a rmaiieiK y for thin think tluit Kultare in this ■ lout after anot department is eared for. to roblem will not for furthir extei I run I, TIip Rmwth Kw dm from ;ill sid&lt; tly taken owe of, ntg. li will be the 1. D i I arpe of no diEinunt because it is manul IS ired i I iuhf. Wtiy should not this i ml Well, liist. tiic (it'vi'ioiniiciit Irll on this work in a highly efficient ma ■i will not make batter without to get 1 1 I to e nity for tl &gt;u it ir 11 inc. where they &lt;an be most m ISI-Illl &lt; n these laad - i win no nt men i ■ otnc ba&lt; k You • Btt't were born. \ I with 1 1 \*. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">103 N 1 t Of \ ;i be broad en » t ill 1 1 is very impona tilings that a that the home institution will arnen you send your son her then 1 by nil means, li.i 11 hav ink. ilnce I lie last building w shouH liuilil il t F idrt'd tift lrt'il fifty MudeaU take I I I and when the buildinu for four hundred fifty stu.: ill! ned and when the building » r o\v Ions will that meet the I the policy of the faculty of th t is the policy of the faculty nybody else — it is a part of t i.vbody else— it is a part of t Ml le the number of students in t he number of students in \t two years; and if we get our &lt;t two years; and if we g- me back In two years from now and I 1 two years from now and I v. i be twice as manr young men in th e as many youns men in th&gt; That number may not be tr be twice as many young me That number may not be tru ill be true reiianliuK the toUeg ivill be true regarding the collet: I the support of other organizations « ipport of other organization- agriculture. The number I agriculture. The number of f pupils in the secondary a &gt;f pupili in the secondary ■ ry apparent that the secondary school I flit thai the serondary schc In col are two hundred thirty-! 1 . (Tni iir.' in forestry. If we s. th«' agricultural college rn ' regular students an '1 hundred thirty IV Ts i arc in forestry. If we tudenta of college «rade, a ndary schocl there an in the four-year course ai winter coarse. This ma' ■ ade, a econdary school there are four ii the four-year course and This raak' ired in the secondary scl eglstered in t of agriculture and college of agriculture and - ■nty-one (1171). h the support of the people of t [tendance in the next two two ne. which will be efficient and larn it at the present ' </seg>
            <seg id="p105">104 hut ten wars hence. If the dairy department shoul fill that plant on the day it is finished or completed unused portion fur soiiip other department that n pet a place for that other department. A canvas I these building! one year ago showed that every building tory in the institution was used thirty w That is over s:\iy liours a d -indents this year, and next y&lt;ar nt more I agree with t Kin this matt, it that th&lt; r&gt; don't be so at be looked af :i,an an I n Itural th I r.' is Nebraska t thin It in state of Nebrask Illiii' and lentral West, i Mr. WhittiK Bay anyth university. I will say in add &gt;ard of regent nc I take it you arc a Be public improvements, that I on of adopting n solutions (hi r of appropriation by the 1&lt; the agricultural school who are in sympathy with the in Me, and all we ask is that you hrint he men who make appropriations, then Improvement! as fast as we ran. We r- the fact t dairy building is tin- moat w • I lit to a vote in the boar - with ■iippin* h of t We must alwayi reineiul) </seg>
            <seg id="p106">105 1 I t ling built. Thai is the sen g:slatures as member and my compel me to doubt whether s anything like what we need tax layers and representative nd it and make them do it. I tell largely look to their own record. trying to establish a record. Some for Cod's sake, to have the courage hat they know the state net ds, and tii s take care of itself. in New England :!."&gt; years ago to my father and mother had rais&gt; &lt;1 rted them almost exclusively from liry, the first thing I did after ae - •st some money and sonic credit in &gt;f being among t lie first, with Nebraska Dairymen's A r the programme «ill !&gt;•■ carried on it it is not large for the purpose make a dollar and a half ta the purpose of taxation ke that much t of those present ind ng if resolutions were passed e that the members of the assocja all they can to push the matter. n (ommittee will prepare the nee iioniy in state expend) h the presidency of th&lt; rly unfit to hold, but my inti l.v day to this my Interest! ban I of this Male. I shall gladly do Of this associal ion. I not forge) each department ol th&lt;- udge in regard to the n&lt; ■ &lt;ssity ami D ils turn. You can rest auured regent! ol the university arc ddlng a building that will not only hut one that will be adequate for leal longer than that. go the chancellor sent to the board to the building of $i;imi.iiiiii worth riculture. The sooner the leeisU- </seg>
            <seg id="p107">106 ■ at: We will now li naha. !• ! o a 'ECONOMY ol THK Sll.o.' W. Hi liter Wood. There has been s&lt;&gt; much said aboul K&gt;t know where to begin It apin ars to me everybody must know all then li to in about this most economical asaet of the American farm. Y are many farmers out in our state, who turn a deaf ear needed storehouse, for winter and summer's Buppl) . k. Everything that has been created, was n pose. Was the cornstalk destined to stand i ter It had performed a mission of aiding in tu- rn? No' Then- was another callir furnishing "slim-picking" anil shelter for cattle &gt;r to put in our silos. « ! and swine may 1&gt;&lt;- fed a toothsome, economical for good in all seasons of I h watching the onward being filled with t lished with farmers! Arouse jroursel »ith the times! Can you not i numbers — - dotting the lar numbers — dotting the Ian for ;m ornament of lit-anty. but . their worth on liiM"' pi proven iheir wortl proportionated high; tin y will line;, wliero the n Tell nip — what forage ero han corn in the forna of proportionately high: they nine;, where the rei inn tan count on will tx inn can count on will better yield than crass: lint ti" Obc acre of Komi Kebru ! ( orn silapc- Cut it wh better yield than One acre of good \i ern X&lt;'braska that time is abou i ge help with your I ter and summer forage has been Pilacc keeps we 11 if the si! round silo will do the work. Silos have been siu ccssf ull\ u Of late we lind the can worth of ensilage as a portion of the feed foi agricultural college fed as a part of the ration; another without ensilage. Th&lt; se fed t! </seg>
            <seg id="p108">ta feinit 1 1 1 1 C.HTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 1*1 n the clover hay fed steer: ade a profit of J2:',.46 per animal lover hay. or J6.19 per steer armers who have fed steers in i going on in the "small tent armers were erecting more silos an.l iources on their farms The speaker knows that his herd ally, one dry summer, when started on suits from our cows, we must provide possible) for all seasons. The silo is the ago, the speaker went to central Indiana he was taken for a drive in the country, nd tank" that clung to the side of a large e the roof. I asked what it was, and wat tvhat that meant, I asked what it was for. ame: My pood Quaker relative said, "That ■nted Rieon corn, that in time hurne&lt;l out said. "It was against nature to feed cows mi forced feed and did not allow them to it then; but, still my curiosity was aroused &gt; know the reasons why. such a prosperous injurious silo as a part of the farm build- ild, we find the advanced teachers of any ind persecuted. The advance of the silo Las ame antagonism of thought. Today the mbered by the thousands — yet there To give you an idea of how 1 tha silo e find there was only M in IM9; j:.o r lijoo were sold that year alone. late, have "opened the eyes" of many to an absolute ne&lt; e ing a great deal sity . At the speak - on pasture; but on only get about 7» and our cows "fan failure. Wf i!k or butterfat to sell at ially during the time, wh.-n of the market alto- anting corn for ensilage: If heck it. because you can keep rii li and dean, the corn will do well </seg>
            <seg id="p109">NEBRASKA liAIIIY \\ The silo lit- nr farm: It will il Fa ■ \\ n it 1 My i..|| our community in genera Imination of drt joy forever if w. I In rlosine. I u r. s. c I drilled. It ccsls about then it is worth l Ii anil every plai silo, is ready to ' &lt;l ii in moderai I one iti i hell i to better farm Improvi We on m;iki eol.er judgment. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">109 N \M) COMPLETE :iir Ciibbo t. stretch this wonderful vallt f corn and of wheat e homes of its pioplt il river; ■ dream-land complete. love ;ind adore I! w ;iih1 ailore th innlcrs our lot lias been cast; .!&gt;ors iid trials and plBMUl thy bosom at Im crs our lot lias been cas rs iid trials and pU las HTERXOON SE8S1ON NOON SESSION IIU.I IV Till: HAIKV ; i\ Tin: dairy nation. l*:i ll I Hunter. ii a! In to twelve dollars .1 |M i:\tk»\ 1*11 II I Hunter. t id alfalfa hay at live tci six dollars a ton it was not -11 vi rv hard to compound a r ot -ii vi rv hard to compound a ratio In' would do fairly well on and, at the - 1 tin' gradual increase in the market ralui i Tims' in the market val ars tin 1 prii.' of grain lias heen nearly doubled ten &gt;ear&gt; ago, aai raosed the 6 has caused the da :i ■after ration for their cows. I ration how many of them have w: ed that would contain the quailiti We have two tYeds that an- ny of them have » I that would contain the quailitl We have two feeds that an- ■ pastille and produce BSUck more feed to tlM roots But as th.' cost of tending and harv - . ■!&gt;• double the cost of tending a crop of ■ and iKii i nsilaKe. when properly put in her- - nut hurt by freezing as are the niore feed to th&gt;- t of tending and harv- t of tending a crop of t hurt by freezing as are the nsiderations. cheap production and keeping tiuali- ationa, cheap production and keeping quali- fact that experiments show ensilage to be a &gt; makes ensilage the best substitute for ;it experiments show ensilage to be a etter ft ed than beeta makes ensilage the best substitute for re. that we have. If we substitute one feed we will compare the analysis of If we substitute one feed </seg>
            <seg id="p111">\ Watt Pasture Grass Corn Ensilagt :i The analysis show that the two are nearly I \\ protein content, but In Nebr K Queen, that is easily reined Corn ensilage and alt a make a perfectly balanced Jin ing cow could not ha feed some concentrates. At the Nebraska »\jm rment st \ falfa and ensilage have been fed It is easy to gel a feeding ration but sometimes these ratio • d results ••d results, as shown Iments. Two ratk same nutritive ration will | f nutritive ration this is, but up ration is ■ why this is, but experiment &gt; in a ration is A ration could be IkiI A ration could as with corn (mUmc and alfalf as with corn en silage would give ■nek better n silage would giv proof of the palatibillt] proof of the pal ing of ensilage to a herd of ing of ensilag hay or their grain Now that we liav. hay or their grain I Now that ensilage we must find tl ensilage we n t of production and the price of production ami th the profit in dairying. Henry's ■ 'F- a ll and I many pounds of digestible nutrii Prof. Haecker, while at the many pounds of t X&lt; braska •SperlBteot station, wo Nebraska experiment statior producing a ton of ensllag producing a ton of Wl llage, Bgi of seed, planting and cultivating, of seed, planting and cultiv ton. The cost of tilling the silo. ton. The cost of tilling the silo teams, he found to be seventy-four i c n&gt; teams, he found to be seventy! rhinery and storage, incliicliiin i: taxes and insurant e, lie fo M three items give I total i .-hinery and storage, ir taxes and Insurant e, 1 These three items give a total of $l.!i4 slightly different methods of figii slightly different methods of figt result. So we can see that lit: result. So we can see that and succulent part of the ration. and succulent part of the ration \Y why silage should form a part why silage should form a part &lt; ) The year around be&lt; au.-e I hi The year around because tl will not relii </seg>
            <seg id="p112">&lt;N I A I . (ON V ENTION 11 re so hard, so in July ; during these months the lik e that the dry. dusty grass often fails nths wl a there is no pasture it should form a part of &lt; in, no matter how well balanced. litis a variety rm a nplete dairy ration II dairy rations, especially winter rations. e below zero with two feet of snow on the irm barn and ensilage in your ration your luring any winter month. v have a paper, "The Silo." written by Mr. is not here and I will ask Mr. \V. C. An- THK SI I o — \ FARM BQT1PMKXT. K. \V. liacliicr. of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association additional improvement upon the farm ng of a pure bred sire with which to grade :inn machinery, or the building of n&gt; w w building, for a home or for the shelter Brain or hay; we are as a rule nt too much from the point of, "wh.it ars and cents, and can I afford it?" Now 1 at lirst hand consider it from this view ;i&gt; other things into consideration also, that to do for us; how much of a lal in added profit is it going Is that new fence going to keep our it going to keep our neighbor's stock Is it going to keep us from a possibli lg to give an added that boy and girl better uning to lighten the work of the average farmer is considering onks at it from this point only, "can can I afforr if farming, have a great deal tc mimercial man of today. The successfu d hundreds of dollars, to effect a small saving iiibles natures ration, | it is my observation </seg>
            <seg id="p113">in his operating expenses. The M hundreds of thousands of dollar* to effect ot &lt;ieiii •&gt;• in operation. Khe farmer of today should ipeU tlie word eft tcrs, and spell it every day. row the silo is a farm e&lt;iuipni directly with the efficiency I am convinced tha ion of "can I affor ' I can not afford to he tl N. KN what o that for every i illK Hi akes t t it lhiiiit Tl. Itl 1 The sih t on a then nimiher ssity to the man ra Eil«* siln will cur red for your M When you stn| ;i The silo on your dair B amount of milk, at th ar when hutterfat is tl i this you are us nc MM arketing of the coininc :i The silo on your dairy arm ■&gt;r cent cheaper than y( makes the sil" I I ution is sought i can \ Tin' si I ! big lirn iliiv </seg>
            <seg id="p114">I t H 113 \ ariu means a profit every year; your wheat rn may make only ten bushels per acre. \vi t strike a year that you a silo full of sin culent feed, in spite milk at a profit. That fact alone mak ice milk at a profit. That fact alone makes r dairy farm, as insurance against failure. lairy farm, as insurance against failur 1 the* the fi ■filing of ensilag ug of ensilage Irak from going stale, or in other words, it From going stale, or in other words. healthful condition. ng and healthful condition ilo as a farm equipment, means — a farm equipment, mean le storage of feed. HVfa of feed e amount of feed cheaply. nt of feed cheaply i he feeding value of your own ran tn feeding operations he feeding value of your own ran i ri| (ling operations landle more livestock, iractiie winter dairying e more livestock, e winter dairying. ock in a healthy condition your liusiness. ik in a healthy condition. our business. nst failure to make a profit. the f«ee of these facts, say. "1 can n f these facts, say. "| can nut lk 1'rof. Frandsen tn lead the dis. Id rather defer my talk until 1 ha\ Id rather defer my talk until 1 hav i there is any difference in feeding vali llage with corn'.' iv difference in Feeding vain th corn ff Y and. that corn ensilage with t of nourishment. Th. sts I am simply giving you amoiii it It Mill grow best in your part an )rn for your sil are tl r the pit the one liel.&gt;w er 1 tl stave silo, and a brick been mostly by proxy. after he returned from tl \ hen he came back. I told him I had nt where 1 had concluded to build one. 1 told ii in build a ] it silo i he material, but I said irni nyihing in a stave silo. He said. "All right." so *- him dictate the dimensions. We concluded to build a silo. That ented with ordinary Portland cement, on the plan that you tern. He sent off and tot a new silage cutter and we </seg>
            <seg id="p115">hired a steam engine and a binder and went t KI had never sren any sil farm. I had i Hid 1 concluded that th.- pn &gt;rn was just about i We tilled that silo as I mM extra good feed. We wen •his fall something I cm tkc ed«e of tin- hill anil on the edge of tin- hill and we t that way: we tunnel rtghi lUt into tin' f&lt; that way: we t would frnti ibove t! right (nit inr Tli»" rement i, inn lakl Tl rather taki ' ii t'.i M and k&lt; •re ball) our lil Tli' .mm- dram, der tin' trui k ol that way '&lt;&gt; &gt;li' t • ■• • t lot ii Stat \ No, we i COMBti V. il we have in A N( dig iluu ii as d&lt; ' in that country li'-s all the I) feel "ii the I he tirsi I !n- i rn'k bottom to 1 mtry li&lt; t&lt; the first VI feet to first Will I first water. Now. \ bat land will not holt t EOtag down tc: fust water you have that kind iiiiiry because of the Tlie President : If th going down tn first water should pal in a silo or 1 ot I would ■hoald inn in a silo or no all the information I &lt;an M all the Information I can ge&lt; t last twelve years, that we have never ha last twelve years, that we uiie in perhaps a litt! une in perhaps I little too green a i 'Uiditinns. We had an i </seg>
            <seg id="p116">HTI t t ■iiry &lt;-i :i r v \ ( ». 1 would like to ask if there being used for twelve years. nty-six years ag Ubion twenty-six years old Exeter nineteen years old. getting a silo too bi tand it you should build a silo of Is. At any rate you may have to ii ml the top and edges when &gt;etter to build two small silos than ;it within the past two years I have t-r had a silo that regretted he had one. In fact, he calls himself a been brought to our attention :s or deaths happening in underground It was stated that this matter should farmers and they should be warned pal ers I could set addresses of and ml it and that was Hoard's Dairy attention to that fact every winter from silos from carbon dioxide cident happened near Cincinnati the fact! in regard to that. ui will find this the fact in regard to Im re they till a silo partly fall and thea lid then go back again to it. In tha ltiring into the silo. Carbon tat ion. It is heavier than air, an I iur days, before filtering it to continue tarted to blow out the pctoOMMM those above ground eeka, so far as I can gather Last summer I saw a silo in which i\v around. When an animal ran As long as an animal like that can exist ioxiile pis to human b&gt; e opportunity to visit all the silos in the state have vis ted the one at Exe built. It was built ■ ruling in the silos Wis., :it the state farm for the insane. It \v:is • u round and had doors. As I understand, it t they were three, four or five days filling t!i" t after partly RHins the silo </seg>
            <seg id="p117">116 nut Blie (round and plastei with ivmeiii In re 1 Lin rcgaril to pelting our minda not to build a I Yon havH to carry the all lv he should be ;it&gt;]«' to reach for tl MM, and built in tliat ua\ lit- i It would not be a difficult mat et-d forty &lt;o«s in twenty-live mil feed it. but with a pit silo this i aye some elevatiiiR deyice handy !e and do the other chores too. A Voice: Centlemen. I am sixty ■ rare to mm it (let ing ihi eaallage &lt;&gt;ni o </seg>
            <seg id="p118">N Tl is itli t Mie of us hero in ttii tnd bor 3f it. and 1 throw in the Dose? I wonder (led the broom 11 over our head. Hi. r k and the day after we n $i:.o acre land n atterw tlirow away one-third of half of it i. l shall stick i ry professor in us that 60 per rent of the value We hustle around and get that ear it into the crib and then ther 4&lt;i per rent that is worse than re has been enough waste in this y farm in Nebraska K io myself and the surrounding! on my ipression on you if I ran. I have a mt get 1 00 tons of hay in tting it at the highest figure Including &gt; which I can put 1 58 tons tl T limit that silo the coldest morning we and I can feed forty head of cattle in do it every day in the year 1 can ie wife can get the break- t.i the field and draw in plenty of fodder from cattle' You can't do it. Besides if around it but what you e house hungry and you will eat hot pancakes wi'h never do at any other time. 1 am only here (or II a single silo, that is not my busi- an agricultural state where we can raise best advantage of any state in the union. I r forty years and 1 am going to die here if sin interested in every man. and everything that uild the state of Nebraska because I expect my children ke thijr home here. And Mr President and gentlemen. ill- </seg>
            <seg id="p119">118 A Well. I expect «re will my iifiKli ttown with Ii i nt to n etued tn till mi- :iln I mid, "You don 'I h 1 I the agricultural pap y Gentleman." it tell ! 11 I ■i net understand why in particular, ■ A certain gentleman nli • . bul I t I bad t" ■ ' in time !&lt;&gt;i' ! yet. Tl H I told !ii that In- eould pi - in the r«ace The I day and push I be other fel I bustled art I ami put t len 'I t not make any difference lo iiiis cutter eame doi with those two men. I fed It. pin up silos anil t he\ pat ling piirp' •4 he ntd, "My silo is ■ rent ir too, \\ In !•■•(! his cattle froi lie told "if the saint- thin.: silos ami anxious to Kit tl loatl of stit-is mil of tin- s:l cut of tlif silo anil f&gt; il them in the tall whin we head of tattle welched thirl o </seg>
            <seg id="p120">119 r puts up a silo an.l 1 an. The Cod of Hi nsllage. l tell don't tiiink He ever will. (Apptas bia sild . 'iithiisiasiii will stay with yo it ism will stay with you tr may never rub off • may never rub o •I'M'd in is that you should ha\ .1 that you should have ili! have rom ami alfalfa ensilage to till the: i in \'e\\ York I took occasion to notii ed from the train window. in a m»Y« prominent faraeri in regard to rhe valu lid M thai they would just as len\ to do without ■ silo Those of you wl HI ■ lfa ensilage to till tlie:n York I iision to notii the train window. in a conve '•in tanners in regard to the value thai they would just as leart lo Those of you • ■ climate of New York know that they won am Your tmtterfat will lie produced aboi New York know that they would butterfat will he produced about er when you are feeding ensilage as utu i feeding it; and the land also liecoin, linK ensilage as nark as he Kind also beeomea I Of W I&gt;ITI\&lt;. » OMMITTKK. to audit the hooks an I nnnun ■ -tl'iiMy report that we have pe I tirul tlie re, nrds pro | ani ■..-.I , to audit the booka and arrounti rtfully report that we have per- Is pro t and ii c young, YOl'NU V. 8. CULVaW. \ TI.VKH K \V FROST. Commit I K VV FROST. . 'in in it t •■#• waa adopted. Mil T (l\ V&lt;OII\\T|(&gt;\ (il OKKMKKS. •otated to place in nomination officers o vi a i- respectfully recommend a&gt; foi nt. nt. MMITTKK o\ \&lt;»ll\ \TII&gt;\ (IK DHKIIKIts nomination off lary-ti adaen, K. L. Uedf.-rn. I s. CUKK, I R. KOHKKTS W. F BOISKA Coininittet of tile committee Has adopted and the per- Manied </seg>
            <seg id="p121">\ The President: We will BOW lii-N tee on resolutions Prof. Haerker Vc.ur cniiiiiiii • following report REtOLl'TIONS WHEREAS, The hoard of r ■si t &gt; have recommended I of all the aiti\iiits of the unlvi ■Mzinp tin- vast Import I agricultural development i-i the Mate, growth aiid upbuilding of the ag KeM&gt;!\ed. Thai we tnOBl .;i r ri |j&gt; the board and I ellnr. and aiiKiiriiir the i»i]i(&gt; recommend) Reaolved, That in \ poorly r ■ill a sul - his ■ or k to I ■Delation ii. it Ik, exhibit. Reaolved 'i Kiiire for his i hill thereto upholi «titin - •olved. That iinl aesaton fron leomarKartne Inti ■ Kesiilvcd. Tlmt _i'iit&gt; in their ■ the universil nd urn 1 mi- ici cupply Bufflcii nt : ::np. (&gt;ti mot ion remlutiona »•&lt; Mr. l'.assi ti . I h inild re«-&lt; perititendi'iit &lt;M' the dair) depart "iniiic-iid Mr. W. C. A ! stal' lioniil (if igriculturp I.. I Irjr department ;u the Nebt The iiKitimi was ran A resolution, rriticleing Ihe ii The motion wai A resolution, criti (ie|i;irtnietit of Ifrricultui department of tgrlculti by the department i </seg>
            <seg id="p122">121 ri'aru used by such was offered by the com- lderable debate was. on motion. th power to act: the matter fu nl the following preamble and resolu- mously adopted and a copy of lha nit lire t of A. 1&gt; Melvin, Chief of th rge is broadly made respectins lit ry iei in good sanitary condition r and turning out :i tmeries are unsanitary to a prca ream used is dirty or decon lias been allowed ,i ellar, or in the woodshed until it reamery » * * and made into buttt r nainuated that this butter ( arri h then is danger of Infection. Stated, "Consumers should not lie hi danger of infection tated. "Consumers should not n unsanitary place and made from insanitary place and made from impoaed." lli nt work whirl has ben done in the depart meiit of iisricultin ■ wlii 1 is been done in x !l leuartment of agriculture its present veneralde. efficient and by the dairy schools of the cm i nt venerable, efficient ai:i by the dairy sell oil of the ions organizations of dairymen, is lairvmen r«aniza body of men over our entire .o'in- r entire . om v ■;, mi lies, and the well know I il labon the standard! and product - have been and are betaf in comparison with the Id the civilized world, we m- n n wit li t the civilized world, we m- eport referred to is without founda- t without foiiinld- t to the departiiieiit of agrictiltur . departiiieiit of aarii ult n r . ry orRanizutions. an I, the dairy organizations, at: sent and which is amone the in st be to injure the mart : I those who are engaged in bile inferior and fraudu- </seg>
            <seg id="p123">We therefore resolve and li ■hould bring upon Its ami demand that pi Mure an. I those In ■ In fa ven 1, I H IHK row .11 -|m;i\«. &lt; (»M I - I The row jlldn nf tlir annual Fed si-cire. that 1 ml point! and ill 01 ■ Klture an. I those in auttai I tin- &lt; r.aintry industry ■Ible make right the «rr ■ if the universil the champion tiani at </seg>
            <seg id="p124">H 1 123 tribution of the !:"" in premium aro such points. The cc as follows (a letter pastel on the \ F No c No. in K c, and ',', 1 of the number scored i ;; i of stai:&lt; and exchange in remitting the prem- exebani md inc 1 1 including the minimum (7"i ai it will be noted less than 15 per will b nil 7.'. or more points. In the seven pre- more i ive been held the per cent of those who scor. the per mi iidin points is as follows: 1 !&gt;i 58 , it . i :• l -i r rent: 1»«S ( nt . 1 :•! 1. 7.'. per cent is! of the names of the contestants and -ii" H in Ci Nanir \ani«-&gt; ol ( oiili-iaiil^ anil Score* in Com .luiluiiii: &lt; 'oiitfst ( hriitensen, M. l&gt; Cochran, Myron hran. Byro </seg>
            <seg id="p125">Iran, ai A K I Middleton Yus ob. !•: EV. rnon Bcii ■eholder, Ki ,.-. V .1 Rael Muri.ln. Th( i, Me&lt; . elms Ithv. I T k. II C unit. He l.loy.l M. V V M. M. Olinj:.-!-. Oliver i, Henry -I Phlllipi, Urn. B ., r. k. </seg>
            <seg id="p126">N 125 M riiiiil \iimiiil Mwiiim . i ii- \-k \ \ (|\ti&lt;&gt;\ (»i hi (T.i am m \\i i \« 1 1 i:i:i;s liMH) Mill Mini -Jlsi. I'd;!. Mu Nebraska Ah ittoa of i Til A liy (he president, R. W. \l i hotel. Liiicol Co. ON. ill. N.b O'Neill, Nebr m Co. lor, N'-l, Xebr limit Creamer? Co. Omaha, Neb Omaha. Nflir klin I,. Cream «',, Lincoln. Neb l&lt; •■ Cremm Co. Lteeeta. N.-l. Cream Co i i&lt;ii«i r«-u&lt; , Neb Co. O'Neill. \el&gt; in Creaa ■ Franklin, \'eh ■ In. N.-I.r ncoln. Neb O'Neill. \* Delljr Wtaaer, Geaoa, N.-li &gt;. N« C CO I'.CIHVJ Crj i .sup Co. Omaha. Nt*i .V Omaha. Net On:alKl. \el Omaha, Nebi ritriiMisliure. Wl re. N't • I' A V 8 Co. Beatrice, Nel i • Bob Aiiliiim. y.l Xelir I"" ' : Co. OiiKilia. Sel Omaha, S'ebr Krt'inont. Xebr llM Co Krftiiont. Nai pheason ("-■ Seward, Xcl i':m I C. Co. Liiiiolii. Cn;ini.T.v Co. RaVHtilia. \..| arJ. Xebr C Wvmori'. .Wl) '.v-Turnquiai Co. Chiracs, I Chlraso. Ill iperage Co . Martin.svillH. In MartlnsvilU, Ind COB« CO. l.illiiiln Lincoln. .Nfii r.v State Dairy Ass'n Lincoln. Neb Dairy D. t State Para Uaeota. Nab Dairy A Llni oln, Wl&gt;r Far in l-iiuoln. NVhr Lincoln. N'ebr. Llacotm, Nflir Lincoln. Nebr. ('KMiiiiissiniK'r IJnooln, \eb cii'inist Uacota, Neb list leoretary to Governor retarjr to Governor l.in&lt;oln. Neb eGlnnia o|&gt;ened the meeting with a few appropriate mis opened the meeting with ■ few appropriat i|&gt;oM F O. Caldwell of I. in. oln. for an opening a. Mr. Caldwell'i addreca Included an invitation t ociation in visit tli^ Dew bnililings of the Comniprcial and Klks .1. M. Harilinp responded in an able manner. The meeting was then addressed by President MoClinnis. He pre- nt. rest cnverine many points vital tn the m </seg>
            <seg id="p127">\ in manufacturers. He stated, tliat Mr. S. (' l!a treasurer of the Nebraska Dairymen atlon. hail treasurer of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association. rtat the proceHdinirs of the last meetta* of the t&lt;. print tin- proceeding! of -t meet tmii of lee Cream Manufacturers in tlie aillHlil) n j( tion of let- Cream Maniifart Dairymen's meeting without cost to the association. Dtirymen'a meeting without coal to I itlon. and he a some action l,e taken ill FKOgBitiOfi 0* Ml He also ail\ oca ted ro-operatloa. with Illf l);iir.V actloa be Uiken ill recognition Of Mr. Bassetta kin, In, I lie also a&lt;! that some action lie taken by (be assoctatioa to sh toward the dairymen IBd offer any assistance I iation to belli in aecarina a new dairy I ■ miental farm PrwMcRt McGinn ■ .lllients to i ur I'l' -''111 I:. . ; J|j(] Ml tiOn lie tllketl .it tin to look a • to defra i A notioi nmendal iona 'I lie i &gt;m m I ('. li l&gt;. Harding The i mi I F. Q. Ca Id well. .1 IJ Krwin that some action he tal iward the dairy xpcnn n IO I \ nmei I M. H 'I an F Q ( S. C. P. wag here introdu, . i .■ U |, Ui \, • h. comparlnf Nebraska's position ai '"■ "'•• ""■ that he lias been at the h&lt; v |nd Mr. BUWtt ailvoiateil no chaage in lnitt.- : anil • raCttOO it! tbl tpiCHld hi allied themselves vita the Dairymen Profawor .1. H Ki;i in! isity. w.is next Introduced bj Hy relation exiatlng between t ■• a Industry and said that th themselves « it h tin- D, Professor .1. H Ki dairy school Included ice cream making and i • ■"n. iiis remarks wen. briel but to ti. H Dodds next described his trip to Iliillas. ' !airy ichool included i. Cm. H. Dodils him .! Ol Ike hist national ran vent ion of i&gt;tion of the &lt;iii&lt;s viaited u II i ill llle hist national convention of Ice cream naaafi ution ot the cities visited and Ills r*pOf1 0 tor- received at the rarioaa places , nroute was proof ■y«rt«atty ot ttktig the irlp must i The report of the secretary was ne\[ rKiil ami •&lt; opportunity ot taking the tr The report ot the secretary WS8 Ilt'X IHitnber of &lt; onimunii at: </seg>
            <seg id="p128">ii tai 1 i (1 I red n to read u bill which bail been of empty cans from leaned before beinjt iing the return :iipp d. A motion w»« am Cabinets the bill and that bill and offering in ing in favor of trie nt the secretary hav it ion of the law referring inK hat e;uh manufacturer buy tags ami conditions war- IBtil such time a ppointed con ym]iathy to \\ R. rite a letter of ber )niin ri uns shall li la on advisibility of making a rhare^ •oin the factory. It seemed to be the ■rhoil would be lumbfrsomi' and no and | id ;i ti ) in in iY. IAMARV L'l i in A re ori wai &lt; ailed appointed t i consider the advlsabilil ran into Hi.- lesile Illillllll;i( till' n the recommend] e by-U bach duly s«-coml&lt;'ti ami larricil tilt- t membershipa to the Nelirask.i I &gt;:iir \ i iii- icecream ■■aortetioa ami to roll* t .issililf. the object titMiiK to i in iibmI— ami .ort to the dalrrnm'i UK&gt;ctattoa, lommtttec be appotatad to invcstiEatc Um tion cit' tl ■ r &gt;i * ■ rt'tuin of empty lilt if three, composed of Corliss, chair- appoiated in ("Meet dat.i from manufac- Tr:iiu shiiiiif'd diiriiiK a cmtli period and (1 if possible. ■sii!« nt M.Cinnis. Professor Houska ive paper on Ike topic of pastuerization. ainl explaining very carefully the </seg>
            <seg id="p129">128 ■am iiit-ani very little indeed unless it « its well us quantitative, h uas prMmt t'r&lt; that what Mr. Bouaka saul was appreciated by iiioin was left fur irKumrat Mr. Bouska lias be&lt; nt' 1 in iir Mi-Cinnis I lark :mil Bteiihensoi Election of officers re« til : (, It. I &gt;&lt;mI i p i 'aid* ell. in ttun r !"■■ Mr. C'orlira m III inn go nil ri ii tar) i&gt;f agririiltur </seg>
            <seg id="p130">129 nnient provided during the meeting. at which President McGln- he evening wire Andrew i Mr. Han.seii and Mr. Kedfern it ion by unanimous vo iss eeting the aasoclatloa has ever had. ,ui- I i-i hi I. if cii-eil &lt; i .-; 1 1.~ in \ilna-ka Oma'i Arehc Vreadia Mason fit i. Allian I. in. mi. Linooli Crab ()ri-li ('i)ll ( o w Franklin Pontanellc Cr .1 Islai,! Oinki Freiiimit rinaiitdw ii llarliiiBion Iliildri llPlllinsfiird i I ii in ))• &gt;• t Omaha 1 .1. K. Krwin were given a Senator &lt;'if&lt;&gt;. U'olz: Prof. .1. li liinission.r: K. U KertVrn. atatt and Drujj ('ommiMioii for jmtg Haatinc Cortl Carle </seg>
            <seg id="p131">130 I N -one Creamery ■Valley Co-op. Creamery ;ton Co-op. Creamery rille Creamery \ Bister County Milk Produc In I'ure Batter Co. rs Ass iatiou Enis Creamery ka Cream Co. Cold Btormc« C s Creamery Omaha Creamery Creamery Knt Dale Creamery na Creamery . na ('realm r&gt; Kiverton Creamery S&lt; liuyler Creamery St I.ibory Creami ry Stai'leton Co-op. Cn T he Kearney The Hygenic Dairy Vcnlipree Creani&lt;r&gt; I A. F *.• S( loo Creaniei loo Creame •• Itnttt-r Co I'oini Butter ■shed :it West Poll shed in Nebraska t Jo K \ silo was also I. probab l.i-t of \\ In. I. ille l&lt;e ( I an llenleix N Bs furnisheil I *1 2-1 91 1. Pood, I B-ee Hutter Ch. &lt; i- Dairy ( ■lin lee Cream &lt; lin Creamery ( Buckhalter I ' D Keese A Wood C( A Fremont Candy Kitchen K w tarn Fr« v i Note — A crean </seg>
            <seg id="p132">VXNCA INVENTION 131 Orleans Crawford Omaha Chadron Columbus i'lattsmouth Grand Island Hebron Alliance Talmase Holdrege Seward Ord York Ord Mitchell Sargent Superior Albioa O'Neill West Point Oakland Parlor Geneva Gordon North Platte Geneva Nelish Tecums^h Lexington David City ry Factory Beatrice Central City Fremont Tetunis^h Wisner Nebraska City Randolph Fa Albioa Oniahr* Deshler Valentine ,v- Holdrege Crear Auburn \- McCook \- 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">\ *.■ Knus li e Cream &lt; n Warner Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p134">133 UtIJSHIM; MM II. IMiKI'KMini \Mi » O-OI'KIMTIX K riti: imkkiks. lebrauika'*) IimmIv— i\ Veara K\|K-riein e in Thi* IMio -tiun. t&gt;. « . iMMtt. agitation In Nebraska at preasst In regard to build I co-operative ereamerte* and i r— saury pr&lt; are more ihiin usually active In this work with the result thu ire being established in various toealtttra in Ik* stat&gt; brief history of t lit* establishment of mm li ere* merit &gt;r twenty-six years may he of Interest if not Nebraska at preamt in regard to built Iterative creamerlei and creamery pro this work with the result that active in rv of tlif establishment of mm h creamer) 1885 there hut- bsea published in tli aaa been published in th« ilie Nebraska Dairymen's Association ■ list of cre:in In the year 1885 there were thirty-eighl creameri" re were thirty-eight rreamerii II were In operation. It is believed that not one of til • ration today. Includinn the thirty-ei^ht Bent tone . 1885 the report! of the Dairymen's A— Oftattoa U and Including the year 1 !• 1 1' there have lieen bin ihree hundred sixteen (31CI local Independent an reameries, not Including 'n the number i or iniluditi itement I the rentraliser rreamerie* having the Omaha or Lincoln. In the year I !• 1 -' there were fon ion It is believed that not one of tke Including the thirty-ei^ht neationed there have been built ;n een 13161 local ind*i&gt;endent an lulling 11 the number I or IncludinK tralizer creamerifs having the coin. In the year 1912 there were ton dependent ;m&lt;l ro-operative creaineriea thonuh nut all wei tiat after being to the expense of baildtni :;it'. creamei i\ yeari we hare two more such i hints tl;;i ■ t» i ost from |".,0»&lt;l to lio.ooii each and it Hive rreamerJea thouiih not all m* building '■'• 1 ti rreamerj e have two inure such i hints than 1' ( h ami it 5-tate that the average cost of these plan rears 1900-1902 there were established in the sta x :i the stat. skimming stations at an average e mine stations at an averaf not of these sk ■■!■! station* is in oper Hnanctal experience in the pa«1 twenty-e u t t twent.v-s \ men! of local independent and co-operative creai us can be briefly stated as folia tive cream \\ plants at 12.212,61 1 iiram "" ♦•4,9&lt; 4H4.no otal |t.t7«.»( t;;t; m,l, |S12. forty local independent and ro-operative Ml e year I! Nebraska had M2,".44 dairy cows beinp an aver inare mile. In the year !!• I " there nil ■ ■I S dairr cows to tiie square mile. A: </seg>
            <seg id="p135">increase of 100,000 dairy cow in Nebraska is less than a I crease of one dairy cow to the farm or of one and one-third B. so that while there has ber of dairy cows in the pa been an increase of Bt ten years (1900-1 SUM at of 100 per cent in the pounds of butter made in creameri but little change in local dairy conditions in the pa twenty years, the ratio of dairy cows to rural population and miles being practically t Outside of Douglas county with an average of thirt to the square mile. Washington county with an averag and Lancaster with an averace of twenty (these thrf nisbing whole milk to the litiis of Omaha and Lincoln) r a county in Nebraska having an average of twenty dairy w square mile and sixty-six of the ninety-two counties in an average of less than fifteen dairy cows to the squar As comparing local conditions, Wisconsin, which a dairy state, has an average of twenty-six dairy cow mile; there are seventy-one counties in Wisconsin; fifty of t tie* have an average of more than twenty dairy cow mile; thirty-six counties have ir a seven counties have more than fort ten have more than sixty a dairy cows per squar creameries prove financially dairy cow population Because of thin and scattered dairy ing a side issue in farming opera pendent and co-operative — witt been financially successful in Nebraska The records of the Dairymen's A to disclose that only twelve I established in Nebraska hav words, eighty-eight per cent have f From the best information availa tour financially successful co-operat creameries making approximately Of the local creameries (not financially do not depend upon local cond most of their cream by rail wherevt advantage, the transportation expense, ab( paid by the creamery; under such conditions and mana such creameries paid in December last 34 f making the cost delivered i cents; the highest price quc • </seg>
            <seg id="p136">135 li ameries. under most favorable conditions ta, being 37 cents, and those being (it i ameries iell and ship his rream to a creamery such t produce sufficient cream to fill a can once mst produce first-class cream amery where cream is shipped in from out- re ixpensive plant and much larger capital i lepends entirely upon local support as does a A ASKA DA1HY &lt; OXIMT1OXS. XKltt bowing area, number of dairy cowb, average ntit square mile and average population to square iry cows tc i n S Pom us returns for 1910 n Av Number Average Number of dairy cows dairy cows to sq. mile population to square mile Area 7.639 13 19 10,465 12 16 742 1,027 1 2 711 1.690 2 I S92 9.803 14 II (176 2.552 2 6 2.T..-.2 2 6 53S T.243 13 II 4.T.H4 4 I 145 .. 11,976 II ■!■'■ 47:. «,7M 14 27 583 MM 14 If 1,594 II 37 8.484.. 14 If II II, 1M IS 20 11,189 IS 1,911 3 4 929 .......... I 4 7.4SI l - , 1 94 t.MI i' 4 S53 1' 4 571 - 7,:?:!3 ... IS. II 7,:?:s3 ... IS.. II 40a 7.631 1- 19 is II 577.. ln,4«4 is 24 ln.464 II 24 19,146 1" I.SS] 14 II 1H.14" 1" &gt;82 14 II 4".' I.SSI I I I us;, '.. II I .11 4::&gt; 1,911 47'.' I,t77 in -'4 531 9.131 IT 4" 1,13] 17 4ii 331 19,141 3" 591 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">136 NEBRASKA DAIRY COXDIT1OX8 A v . X vi in I Number of dairy &lt;■&lt;&gt;» An a dairy cow* to s&lt;i n ', 7 1; 7.»» 1 14 Killmore Franklin SET. \ 64 S ley •lamilto Parian I Hit. hcoch nk,r hnscm ■I 1 aha hall Kiel .-mi son M&lt; rrirk us NVmaha N.Kkolls t'l * l'awnt-e I'i rkins Ih.ips s s •; 7, ; ; s : i </seg>
            <seg id="p138">137 AIRY CONDITIONS — Continued At. Number Average Number of dairy cows population to dairy cows to sq. mile square mile :36 i:&gt; 15 T.'MT 14 4. ".24 4 3 H.937 18 31 4.T.4N 19 39 13.550 is -^ 2,34* :: 11 74 '.&gt;.:•! s 17 i-s 4.S44 2 A 8,203 14 14 ii.tl"^ 1 I •;.HK2 16 ii V.iHii |I 2H »&gt;« 1 3,683 9 •&gt; ~ t!.177 1 1 17 9.224 4 8,172 is II 7. Mir, 14 2 1 Clio .4 4 s.:i!O 14 Hi', «13,»:,2 v .11 ing average number of dairy cows per square mile also average population per square mile in groups ties in Nebraska. (1910 I'. S. Census) r 613.95 Increase in dairy cows — 1900 to 1910 SO ber of dairy cows to square mile 8 i having less than T&gt; dairy cows to square mile 28 r having ■"■ and less than 10 dairy cows to square mile 8 ing in and less than 15 dairy cows to square mile 2» lav Number having 15 and less than 20 dairy cows to square mile 23 Number having 20 (Lancaster) dairy cows to square mile 1 Number having 24 (Washington) dairy cows to square mile 1 Number having 30 ( Douglas i dairy cows to square mile 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCI 138 ATION 1 4 4 i Population. Population in 1910 Per cent of increase 1900 to 1910 Average population to square mile Rural population in 1910 Per cent of increase in rural population, lymi to 1 II Average rural population to square mile in 1910 Number of counties having less than S population Number having 5 and less than 10 to square mile Number having 10 and less than li to square mile Number having li and less than 20 to square milt Number having 20 and less than 2."&gt; to square milt Number having IS and less than 14) to square milt to square mi Number having '.U&gt; and less than SS to square mile Number having 3. r &gt; and 1&lt; ss than 4ii to square mile Number having 4&lt;i &lt; Dodge I Number having 84 i Lancaster t Number having N4 i Lan Number having 591 ( Douglas) Number having 5C9 (I)ouglasi THK DAIRY IMHSTKV IN \\ KSTKKN RBMI Dividing Nebraska into two equal parts the • THK DAIRY IMHSTKV IN WKSTKKN N'KBKAKK.% Dividing Nebraska into two equal parts t a would be a line drawn through the center of Custer county would be a line drawn through the renter of C cm border of said western part would !&gt;.• the MM) t rn border of said western part would Brown, Maine. Dawson, (iosptr and Furnas; this Brown, Blaine. Dawson, Q paper and Furt ft' contain 37,718 of the 76,8118 square miles comprising the contain 37,718 of the 76,808 squar mi braska. The folowing table gives the names of counties in the brack*. The folowing table gives the n; of Nebraska, the area, population in 1910 and in i of Nebraska, the area, population in 1910 md ir COW population in 19141 and I9«fl as r icw population in i»lt&gt; and I'.kmi as reported in tl- 1 \r. 191" l»«« I'npuhi! ion l'anner 742 1.444 1.114 I.* sr 742 1.444 711 l,«71 Hlaine 711 l,«71 l.H Box Butte I.n7&gt;; 6,l:il Tl' 8,5 Box Butte Chtrry Chtrry S,»7I lii.414 ti.:,41 7.4 Cheyenne 1,1*4 4,551 5.57i 2,8 -Custer ! . l* ;t 4 IS.O4 M79 »,5 Dawes 1,4*1 I.2S4 ti.21". 1,5 Dawson Dawson MS I5.M1 12.214 V4 Ileuel 439 1.7Sti 2.fi3o l.« 439 1.7Sti 2.fi30 1.01 Dundy 927 4,O»8 2.434 3.1 927 «.£»98 2.434 3.1 Frontier '.&lt;-:, I.57J 8,781 &gt;* -Only one-half of county tak«?n into ronsld* pal 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p140">WE&gt; Y-EIGHTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 139 Area 1910 1900 1910 Population Cows Cows Dairy Dairy 12.083 12,373 7,648 x.xss 1,(51 3,538 2,212 4H4 4,933 5,301 4.237 4.484 7SI 1.M7 736 745 442 72:! 3,011 2,708 2,821 3.14S 724 Mil 4,409 4,474 4.488 BW 722 981 432 671 112 1,068 3.692 1,951 2,686 2,308 all 958 1.942 758 1,013 407 Paha Paha 755 3.452 3,076 3,053 2,711 2.536 15,684 11,416 8,989 8,057 ,:z 573 1,521 960 1,304 642 1.674 2,470 517 1,938 432 1,417 4 3,329 886 2. .",70 1.702 1.910 3.847 How 7L'il , 11.056 9,604 5,230 5.590 ;&gt; Bluff 723 8,3 5.". 2,552 2,349 1,231 nr 2.469 7,328 6,033 4,844 7.020 2,055 5,599 2,055 3.609 1,333 716 1.191 628 926 294 7,718 179,lf&gt;4 128,764 112,813 112.060 lat n, 1 )M to 1910 50.390 rent *T ow population ,i r in 1900 1 Total number of cattle in 1910 ber of cattle ►■n Dm«l county in IHt. Cheyenne county in !••• </seg>
            <seg id="p141">140 NKHKASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION w 1 i DAIRY COMUTIOXS IX WISCONSIN. Table giving name of county, area, number of dairy number of dairy cows to square mile, together with a si together with a sun conditions mentioned based on the V.&lt; 1 S. Cen us retur Xumb da Area (84 cows Ashland Barren Bayfleld Brown 1,503 L'..".4 Calumet Chippewa Clark Columbia Crawford ::::■■ Kan Clair Florence Fon du La« :;:;: Lake Jefferson -t 1-aFayette ar... 4 4 4&gt; 64:: V7 9 4,846 Manitowac Marathon «S7 I0.S8 = Ml 724 SI 1.554 31.. 2« 1.4 IT, tSi I </seg>
            <seg id="p142">141 NDITION8 IN WISCONSIN. — Continued Number dairy Average cows to sq. miles Area cows 253 11.131 44 937 39.323 II 1,111 15.709 H Ml 1.479 tun IMM •! 233 16,094 N 236 6,593 563 18.579 33 935 23,811 2:i K12 18,783 M 1,279 4,359 3 324 20,277 62 590 28.529 48 716 35.712 925 3.227 3 735 25,213 34 842 36,167 43 1.320 *i 1.158 24,932 21 521 39,507 76 '.•91 8.001 8 748 -111 34 S21 31.618 »« 833 347 4 560 39.147 835 3.621 4 431 24.256 56 rt sh 549 31.938 58 759 31.152 40 at a 646 17,493 27 nra 459 26.256 bago 809 18,465 23 55.256 1.473.5H5 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">142 4 I 4 Summary. Counties having less than 10 rows to square mile.. Counties having 10 and less than 20 to square mile Counties having 20 and less than 30 to square mile Counties having 30 and less than 40 to square mile Counties having 4 0 and less than 50 to square mile Counties having M and less than 60 to square mile Counties having 60 and less than 70 to square mile . Counties having 70 and less than 80 to square mile Counties having 88 (Vernoni Bber of counties 1 population Ege rural population to square mil. ge dairy cow population to square mile ge number of acres in farm Nebraska Dairy Conditions Summary Eties having lees than 10 cows to square mile ties having in and less than 20 to square mile ties having N and less than 30 to square mile ties having 30 (Douglas I Number of dairy cows Average number dairy cows to square mil Rural population Average rural population to square mil Average number of acre* in farm Number of counties </seg>
            <seg id="p144">WENTY-EIUHTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 143 L181 OF CREAMERIES KSTAHMSHKI) IX NEBK\&gt;k\ Krt.ni the Year 1885 to and Including the Year 1912. S. C. Bassett ameries in Nebraska from 1885 to and including the ot including centralizer creameries located in the cities )maha or having their headquarters in those cities. posite the name or location of the creamery is given the year stablished as shown by the yearly list of creameries as pub- m the annual reports of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association hen the name or location of such creamery ceased to appear in ilished list. In many instances the names of creameries have uded in the yearly lists when possibly the creamery was not in ion it being impossible to ascertain by correspondence-letters not answered. In some locations given more than one creamery has ablished: In some cases where it appears that a creamery has operation many years it is known that the creamery was not &gt;usly in operation but it is not possible to ascertain the date* any instances creameries were operated only in the summer the remainder of the year 1886 Beatrice 1895-1897 1897-1899 1885-1889 1885 Bennett 1885-1894 Brownville 1885 Burwell Blair 1897-1899 1885-1886 1896-1901 1893-1898 1886-1912 1887-1900 1892-1897 1892 lt»l Bradshaw 1 * '.' S-l I '.' I Bee 1895-1909 Bancroft 1895-1897 Beaver City Battle Creek 1892-1897 Bloomington 1887-1889 1892-1894 1893-1899 1893-1912 1898-1899 1898-1899 1898-1912 lMT-ltll 1904-1912 1892 Broken Bow .1889-1894 1890-1901 Blue Hill .1894-1899 Boone Burchard 1892-1897 1892-1897 Belden 1893-1895 Boheek Beaver Crossing Bismark 1896-1900 Aowa Vallev .1908-1912 Burton Blue Valley 1887-1895 t Valley Point ice .... Black Bird ~ 1895-1901 1911 Benkleman 1897 1898-1899 1885-1886 Bruning 1895 </seg>
            <seg id="p145">l Deweese 1905-1912 Guide Hock 144 1910-1911 Goehner ( *-ntral ( i!&gt; 1885-189] I&gt;&lt;&gt;&lt;]Kt Central City l»*t-1912 Dactt Central City 1909-1912 Decat Chambers 1S8S-1899 Danbi Chambers IMS-1899 Danbi ("larks IS8S-1891 (Marks 1SSS-1SS ColriUge Bxete Colridge I Kxt ColridRe 1896-1899 Ed 1896-1S91 Edgar Columbus ISS«-189« Ewini Columbus 1886-1890 h Columbus 1191 Emen mIhis 1 :mi.-.-i ;. i j Bib* n4 1890-1899 Emeri • llaiii.ls 188; Klkbo Colunibus 1 Columbus 1905-1912 Cortland 1890-] (Vdar Uaiiiils 1 1 • i^ y ' It Edam 1887-1894 - liton i'ton r Frank Falls Cordova Cordon 181 I - Falli I 1896-11 Km i rln Crab On-hard 1896-1912 Frank • r Is:.". I g97 Pairm Crab Orchl Campbell Cainpliell lift 1 BhiVl Fuller Bluffs Chadron Chadron 1898 ■ tOB Kirth Mock - 1910 Farm- stork Cain i Calloway Calloway Chapman chapman BM Colfax 1887-189S ,;,,,„,, Springs rs« P ri. Cohax ! Ciilbertson is Dakota City 188 5 1 v 9 - 1892-189 liester 1892-1894 G nport 1885-18'.! ( Doniphan 1892-1897 1887-18J &lt;: 1889 Ciollicnb David City 1892-1899 Coldcn U&lt; 1895-1899 Greeley 1895-1 8 '.if, Dannebrog 1896-19U' Geneva ( </seg>
            <seg id="p146">|vv Lyons 1890-lHnr. -1897 Lender 1893-1894 Is Locust Grove 1897 INS I.oup Valley 1 s:i^-1897 ls:U Milfortl 191 4 Molim ISIS lull Madison 1886-1897 McCook ls»7-lw.. 191 1887-lmH 1897 Minden 1892-1897 Maniuette Millard 189K 1900-1901 Martinsburg 189C-1903 1 Vhi-1894 Malcolm 19O« 1905-1909 Mason City 11*11 1901 Mead Midland 1903-1904 1892 McCool 1 -v 9 9 XeliRh Nebraska City 1894 l»-«:.-1886 Norfolk 1885-188!* Norfolk l!n.7-l!tl 1897 North Platte 1887 1884-1897 North Hend 1892 linn Niu Port 1890-1901 New Castle 1901 [gtg-lltl Newman's Grove Whr. CrPani Co. I9im-i:ui 1« Nelson 1890 North I.oup 1908-1*12 1895 1 VI7-1899 O'Neil 1885-1886 1907-1*12 O'Neil 1908-1912 1 :• 1 n- 1 !♦ 1 1 Oakland 1885 Oak'und 1895-1898 1897 Ord 1895-1912 1909-1912 ( taceola 18911-1891 1898-1899 Ohiowa 1893-1896 1895-1897 Orleans 1909-1H1L' 1895-19"! 1 !t 1 -1 Opportunity 1896-1V.17 idd 1897-1898 Peiuler 1897-1899 1899-IHimi I'onca ixs.', 1885 1898-1901 Ponca </seg>
            <seg id="p147">146 lyni 1897 Svraous Papillion 18S7 Shelto Pawnee City l'.t(MI-l'.tlll Stockham 1897-1899 Savag* 1898-18! SliptTil -nit Valley 189 Shi(kle\ Pleasant Dale 1895-1897 St. Lib) 1896-18 Pan Panama renter 1897 Staplehi nit Valley 1896-1897 Springfield Stratto gii.-. „ City Hoyal Oair H,.,i cioad i Table lu«k Ked Cloud llinsil Raves na \\&gt; \: aK( ){a&gt; niond Ti-k 1895-18 k- City Trent Handolph RlTCTtOII Glen • nson lsv .Spring l.ak. lxs.-.-ls Spraitne bs;-^v •St Edward Spring Creek 1908-191 SpauldiiiK 1897 Silver Creek 1897-1898 Valpar pa Stromsburg Sherman 1897-1901 1 s '.' s ird Co-op Schuylnr 1897 Wa 886 Wa Schuyler Stanton Stanton 1898-1912 Wa 1885-mrt We«t Pon 1899 Waketi 1885-1886 Wausa 19*9 Waterbi 1885-1886 Wins 1893-1X'.&lt;7 W.-stoi 1885-l!«nP. 1I9A.1I92 18SC-1993 Wood Kiver Willsonville W.-Il:'- zz </seg>
            <seg id="p148">147 Winer 1897 York 1891-1898 &gt;l MM AKY .luhlislii-il in the state since already established in the year 1885,» izer creameries located in Omaha and Lin- Itiarters in those cities, such centralizer jarate list ameries in 1885 niber established 1885-1'.* 12 :'. 1 H ran not to exceed 1 year nt ran not to exceed l' years nt ran not to exceed 3 years not to exceed 4 years 111 years 11 years 12 years 13 years 14 years 15 years 16 years 17 years 18 years 19 years 2?. years 24 years L'5 years r 26 years :iti years ( 'KVTKAMXKK ( KKAMKKIKS S. C. Ifctsx'tt plan of operating the creamery business in Nebras- said to have begun in the year 18!*o in the organization of I'latte Creameries with \V. A. Carpenter as manager, this pany having that year a line of creameries at Aurora. York, Osceola npany being later merged with the Fairmont reainery Company. In the year 1X!*2 The Fairmont Creamery I'om- any. with .1. H. Kiishton u pn sidtnt. had a line of creameries at Fair- ■t, Friend. Milford, Dewitt. Dorchester and Crete. In the year 1893 Harding Creamery, with Charles Harding as manager, had a line Creameries at Wlaner, Norfolk and Humphrey, and the Sutton Cream- </seg>
            <seg id="p149">14^ NEBRASKA DAIRTMEN'8 ASSOCIATION I ry Association, with .1 ('. Merrill as - nton. Davenport, PairfteM, Rusi mm liad enuMrtM at Cohinib nager lit Button, Davenport, Fail-field, Ruskln, Nelson, and K Dson had creameries at Columbus and Boheek. Ii the Beatrice Creamery Co., located the Beatrice Creamery Co., local manager, had i n aim ries at Beatrte 1'ntil the jrear ls:w; a ]l ereana Baaaser, had rreameries at Beatrice. F";i 1 Is City, Unmix gathered cream plan with gathered frwi plan with one or n ■ the skiinniinu station plan un I'l built, thf whole milk being delivered ami shipped to a central ereamei M'ar there were twenty i im sk built, the whole milk mil shipp ■ ear there were twenty i lm skimming statioi W'ahoo Creamery with .1 . K Culling Walioi) I'n such stations. In the year 18S7 ft'U idinpaiiy at Lincoln with George K 1 skiinininc it at ions In the year 1899 ;■• ration in thi pted at ai The records of the dairymen'! aai of the hand ■eparator in connet Khe records the hand in the yar 1897 W m Button being tin Ni'ligh lining the fl I In the ) ■ the skim i In tl the hand separator plan was becoi - located in Lincoln and Omaha, the hand sep ocated rompany. Qeorge K Haakell, P mery. Charles Harding, Ha -iiery operated on the direct sh Creamery, Charles Hani reamer) 1 oper tka and Iowa (' The Fairmont Cream&lt; at this date tliere wer Nebraska and Iowa Creamery Co in pi The Fairmont Creamery Company v at this date there were 22 creamerie Id the year 1M4 tlie dairymen' III the year 1904 tin Nebraska showing the location ol of such separators being -Si'.-:!? From tile records of tin ih' pioneers in the cream bus since 1 S8 J at Archer; Chart Hard F Howe, continuously since 1km|; J. H. Ru 1888 and F. N". Stevenson, continuou Among the other piom rs w l.iveringhouse in 1885, \V A Carp .1 Dixon Avery in 1885. Ueorge A Hrooks in : 1885. A. F. Hartwell in 1887 , J. C. M rrill in 1^7 The growth and development braska is b&lt; st illustrated by the fol such creameries: </seg>
            <seg id="p150">\.\.\ 149 (NVEXTIOX ISiimr M I ill &lt; it-iinifi-ic- in \ehr;i-kj«. 65.7TL' pound l,97t.7lf pound 11.7XC.1SI pound tS.»7S,l«] pound UllK'lllK'll 85.772 pou mis i'7H.78f&gt; pounds U,72«.1M pounds 1«] pounds lion ti.S9C.7SI pound on tt.9M.9tJ pound 09C.9S2 pounds iton S1.1S4.1 15 pound :&lt;14. per cen 1.114. Ill pounds Ml 4. per cent !&lt;:'.. pit pit emt 1 &lt;&gt; 4. par n-i I. per Ml 14. per let B. pt -r cei 1 •• 4 . pi 8. per cent 14 par cent in tin- creameries disclose that !*t&gt; per cent of iit-rii-s disclose that :•« per &lt;■■ ies in Nebraska in the year 191 imeri Nebraska in the year 1912 ameriea operated on the niitralizer plan iperated on the utitralizer phi eamery From outside points i m outside points i n Nebraska with lieadipiart. Kebrmaka witli headiiuarters m date when organized and ytar when ■ l»12. when organized and year whe ■ 1HHT-1H 1 1S»7-1»12 l •♦«•••- 1 :..,:, I9M-1M2 l'.tnl-ll'n:: l»O2-l&gt;12 1999-19* iipply Co. 199K-191 pply &lt; 1991-1 1992-191 1 :•'&gt;:, IS) 1905-191 190S-191 199C-191 19«7-1&gt;] 1907-191 1907-191 1910-11 1 1912 199C-191 I90S-191 1999-191 1997-191 1997-191 1997-191 1919-11 1 n 1!&gt;1J \ i»\ii:\ n»\V ( KVSl S l\ \KI&lt;|{\Sk\ IS l\ NKKItASKA S. ( . Ita^setl l-M-tl I s&lt;iuare miles and bad 61 1910 1' S. Cenan ih t&lt;' South through the center of Custer Kejra Paha and Royd. Brown and iwaofl and Buffalo. Gosper and Phelps. Furnas tate into approximately two equal parts, the I Harlan pan having eb area ot ::7.T1&gt;&gt; siiuare miles and the Eastern </seg>
            <seg id="p151">150 I rask part 39, 119(1 square miles: according to the 1910 1 rn Nebraska had 112,111 dairy cows or an aver to the square mile and Eastern Nebraska had 501,1 or au average of thirteen (13) to the square mil of $10,000 In the 1910 V. S. Census returns tl reported as having "i . »■ 4 7 dairy cows or an aver dairy erwi to the enure mile; it: April 1913 the Nebraska I Association had taken ■ dairy cow census in .1 six ( &gt;i i milis in each direction from th promoted creamery is located. A creamery had 1 point in lKKT, and later abandoned. The cenaa ate 111 rut in thai department In taking tin- census a on the bai report in detail. In the report is given the nann distance from Nuinl)er of farms having i Jii per cent of the farms li 4J per cent of the farms had not to e*ce« til' per cent of the farms had not to exce&lt; K&lt; r ci nt of the farms hi rms had 1" dairy cow Brin had 1J dairy cows rms had 14 dairy cow 1 farm had 19 dairy cows 1 farm had a herd of dairy bred 1 farm had a dairy bred bull. 4 silos had been built on imrposi Total expensts of taking this dair mately 12 square miles. J4T farms and mak thing name of farmer, distance from town vai t:\ lirrr **■ promoted In a county in EastiTii N MperrMoo of the dairy departmei ivs beiac niilki Herewith is p ■Minimal \ ui Itair) ( &lt;&gt;u &lt; ••ii-ii- EnatiMl an her of ft I number •ge tmni Average number of «l </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>