<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Nebraska Indstrial Home</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Fifteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Industrial Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">466 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION Le.na E. Wakd Superintendent Wh. Sandisky Physician Si t de B. Ward Matron and Head Nurse M. Evelyn Meyer Secretary, Bookkeeper and Steward DEPARTMENT HEADS Lydia Hays Domestic Science Teacher Trecia Win jams Art and Sewing Teacher </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 467 NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA To his Excellency, Honorable Keith Neville, (jovcrnor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Com- I. Holcomb, and Eugene 0. M 01/ field. Gentlemen : I, hereby, submit to you the fifteenth biennial report of Nebraska Industrial Home covering the period from Decem - ber 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918. So much of the same ground is covered by each re - port, that I fear, to many of you, the summary will sound familiar, but when we realize that this report will fall into the hands of many who know nothing of the "Home," or what the state is endeavoring to accomplish through it, I feel that it is imperative to repeat what has been said in previous reports in order to give a full account of the work. The main object of the "Home" continues to be the restoration of the unmarried mother to society, by shelter - ing, protecting and encouraging her at a time when she feels that almost the gates of heaven have closed against her, and by teaching her by precept and practice what God wants her to be, that she may go out and take her place in the world and prove herself an asset and not a liability to society. Statistics gathered from all countries show that the death rate among illegitimate children is far higher than among legitimate children. This excess death rate is not due to any inherited weakness, but almost entirely to the bad environment into which their illegitimacy naturally throws them. Through this "Home" the state gives the illegitimate child a chance to be born where it can have the best of medical care and proper nourishment and thereby often saving its life and giving to society a strong healthy citizen in place of a dead baby or a blind, crippled or diseased child, which must always be a burden to itself and the community in which it lives. missionera of Stoti Institutions, Henry Chrdea, si lux </seg>
            <seg id="p004">468 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP The "Home" not only gives this physical care to the child but it also makes it possible for the child to be placed into environments, where it can grow up to manhood or womanhood without being constantly reminded of its un - fortunate birth. The state can well be proud of a number of these chil - dren who through this "Home" were enabled to grow up into useful, respected citizens; many of them graduates of our best schools and filling positions of honor and trust, and many more are on the road to success, who, according to reliable statistics, would, in all probability, have become state charges in some way, had not the state provided so kindly and wisely for them, thereby giving them an equal chance with the child of more fortunate birth. We feel that the work of the biennium has, as a whole, been a success. The health of the institution has been ex - ceptionally good; we have been able to find good homes for nearly all of our babies, who were for adoption; have been very fortunate in finding desirable employment for our girls, and most of the girls are proving themselves worthy of the confidence, which was placed in them and are giving general satisfaction to their employers. We have had a very good class of girls to work with and, with but few exceptions, each has put forth her best efforts to learn all she could while in the "Home" and to do what she could to make it happy and beneficial for all. This we greatly appreciate in the girls. There has been but little change in the general work, except that special emphasis has been placed upon the vo - cational training. Realizing, as we did, the absolute neces - sity of most of the girls being able to go out and support themselves upon leaving, we felt that the vocational train - ing would be of more benefit to them and have, therefore, spent more time upon it. Some of our more fortunate girls have had fairly good school advantages before coming here. These we have been able to send out as teachers, stenog - raphers, clerks and practical nurses, and some have, upon leaving, gone back into school. But a large number of our girls do not have the education to take up these lines of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 469 work and in the short time they are here it is impossible to do much for them along scholastic lines. But we are able to accomplish much along the line of general housework, cooking, cleaning, mending, sewing, laundry work, care of children, nursing, fine needlework and so on. So that many of them go out as good housekeepers with an entirely differ - ent idea as to what constitutes a well regulated home and wholesome, well prepared and properly served meals. Aside from the regular work done in the institution we have tried to do what we could for the Red Cross. Every girl In the institution joined the Red Cross, so that we had a 100 per cent membership. Some did not have the $1.00 membership fee, so work had to be provided for them, that they might earn it. A number of articles were made by the girls and sold and the money given to the Red Cross; a deal of time was spent under a certified instructor in the making of surgical dressings. MORAL AND RELIGIOUS TRAINING Every evening a short chapel exercise is conducted by one of the teachers. On Sunday the regular International lesson is studied, and splendid interest has been manifested. We also have a well organized and thoroughly alive Chris - tian Endeavor society. Not only at these meetings, but each day and in all departments, whenever and wherever opportunity affords, we try to impress the girls with the absolute necessity of right living, what we teach in the chapel, we try to have them practice on their details and at their play. LIBRARY A number of new books has been added to our library through the State Library Commission, as well as a nice lot of magazines provided. Once a week books are checked off to the girls to be taken to their rooms, but the library is open all of the time and a girl may go in and spend any spare time, that she has, reading, and every day as soon as detail work closes, a number can be found reading in the library. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">470 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF SEWING ROOM We feel that we must make special mention of the work done in this department the past two years. The fol- lowing table will give an idea of the amount of work done, and when we realize that many of the girls had never run a sewing machine, or worn a thimble, to say nothing about cutting or fitting, or doing any kind of fancy needlework before they entered, we feel that they have accomplished a great deal in this department. Each girl, in the past two years, has taken with her a nice little wardrobe, consisting of one good dress, three bungalow aprons, two corset covers, two night gowns and underskirts, all of which were made and nicely trimmed with hand-made lace or embroidered by her. With but very few exceptions they have taken a great interest in doing this work, each trying to have her outfit look the best. A number after being gone a few months, have written back and told how much pleasure they have gotten out of their clothes, also how thankful they were for what they had learned in sewing, that they had been able to do all of their plain sewing and in many instances had sewed for others. LIST OF ARTICLES MADE AND MENDED Aprons, bungalow 540 Aprons, dining-room 12 Aprons, hospital 11 Aprons, kitchen 15 Aprons, nursery 27 i Aprons, nurses' 25 Aprons, pastry 18 Bags, broom 36 Bags, laundry 63 Bands, infants' 206 Belts, sanitary 144 Blankets 32 Boys' suits 21 Binders, abdominal 12 Caps, kitchen 69 Carpet rags lbs. 321 Coats, infants' (trimmed with crocheting or embroidery) ... 42 Combination suits 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 471 Comforters, large, tied romrnrl^M -. _. ... . *&gt; Comforters, nursery, quilted Cnrant **— 69 Corset covers Curtains, pairs 235 Dish rags 52 M Dresses, adults' 4:: Dresses, infants' 1,328 Dresses, child s ' ■ :,.»-&gt;... .. j..i.-. ! 38 Gowns, adults' linn. A . . 212 Gowns, doctors' n«..,«» ._»-_._■ 4 Gowns, infants' Gowns, hospital 21 Hoods, infants' Napkins, infants' . 2,936 Napkins, sanitary 578 Pads, bed 31 Pads, nursery 137 Pads, table **' Doi«« 9 Pajamas . . r, in _ , 19 Pillow cases, large 174 Pillow cases, nursery r.2: 1 . Pillows 1 Pot holders l:::; Quilts, nursery Quilts, large J " ' "" BC o Sheets, bed Sheets, draw 2 Sheets, ironing , "'"6 «„ Sheets, nursery cv, • ""• "C J r (lt* Sleepers, infants' ... 55 Skirts, child's fi Skirts, infants' ° 01.,.. 536 Skirts, serge " Skirts, poplin Skirts, under ..... ,f° Sunbonnets Table cloths ,V~ • — ~ &gt;-.v. lUD . Towels, hand „„. * 184 Towels, tea ... Waists " 6 1*4 Wash rags ,„ Crocheted lace, yards u 36 Tatting, yards « o Dresser scarfs, fancy Towels, with crocheted lace and embroidery ..........."." jg Pillow slips, crocheted edge and monogramed ............ 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OK 472 Articles mended 36,082 THE FARM Last year our farm produced an abundance of garden vegetables for summer use and a good quantity to put away for the winter; some feed for our stock; plenty of apples as well as some other fruit. But this year, we raised very little and almost nothing for winter. Our alfalfa has died out and will have to be resown next year. REPAIRS A number of much needed improvements have been made this biennium. The first, of which, was the building of a modern dairy barn, this was something that had been needed for years; two large high-pressure boilers were in - stalled, in place of the one low-pressure and one small high - pressure; a well with an electric pump has been put in, which now supplies us with an abundance of good water; a new storeroom and coal house were built; new roofs and ceilings were put on the porches of the main buildings, and some other outside work was done on these buildings and the laundry. Very little inside work has been done the past two years, therefore some will have to be done next year, also some more outside work will be needed. NEEDED EQUIPMENTS, REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS Our most urgent needs in the way of equipments are an automatic anaesthetizer for our hospital and an electric tumbler and washer for our laundry. During the winter months it is impossible for us to get our laundry work done as it should be with the machinery that we have, and this necessitates the running of the laundry every day in the I'illow slips, embroidered 7S Fancy baby dresses 16 Embroidered baby coats L'orset covers, with crocheted yoke or embroidered no 3owns with crocheted yokes or embroidered 220 : T nder skirts embroidered or crocheted edge 110 Waists, trimmed 11(1 la&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS week, whereas, if we had the needed machinery the work could be done in much less time, and with less help. An - other needed equipment is a feed grinder with motor. This would enable us to lay in our grain in the fall, when it is cheaper and to have the freshly ground feed for our stock. As it is now, we must buy the ground feed, which is often of a poor quality, much more expensive and impossible to care for in great quantities without a great deal of waste. During the last two years, a great many of our fruit trees have died, and unless a new orchard is set out soon, it will only be a short time until there will be no fruit at the institution. This would certainly work a great hard - ship, as the fruit means so much. We also need some small shrubbery. The walks and drives are badly in need of attention. The cottage, which is occupied by the farmer's family, is located near the main buildings. This should be moved further away as it makes it bad for the institution and also for the family living in it. I, therefore, ask for an appro - priation to be made to cover this expense. We must have the following new buildings: horse barn, hay barn, feeding barn for cattle, implement house, silo and piggery. The old horse barn, which is located entirely too near the main buildings, has been in use ever since the institu - tion was established and is past repairing. There is no room in it, in which to store feed for winter use, and it is also impossible to make it comfortable for the horses. The hay barn, if it can be called such, and feed shed for cattle, is just ready to fall down, and it is impossible to make it stand another year. We have no silo and with the number of cows, which we must keep, we feel that this is a much needed im - provement. There is no house or shed in which to care for the implements. We have practically no place in which to care for our hogs, and therefore ask that a building for this purpose be provided. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 474 LAND There is only a very small tract of land in connection with this institution, so it is impossible to raise the garden and feed, which we could easily do, if we only had the land. In an institution where there are so many small children, it is absolutely necessary that we have plenty of good, pure milk. The state now has a good little dairy herd, all that we can care for with no more land, but it is only about one-half as large as it should be. So we most urgently re - quest, that more land be provided. There is an eighty-acre tract adjoining the institution, which is for sale, and which would be just what the institution needs, and could be handled nicely. APPROPRIATION'S NEEDED FOR THE COMING BIENNHM Appropriation for general maintenance and salaries J65.500.00 Equipment and furniture 3,000.00 In conclusion, I wish to thank you for your wise coun - sel and advice, and for the many kindnesses shown us. Whatever degree of success may have been attained is largely due to your hearty co-operation. Respectfully yours. Lena E. War t &gt;. Superintendent. Milford, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. Land and new buildings 26,000.00 II General repairs 2,000.00 I mprovement to buildings and grounds 3,500.00 Miscellaneous 1,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 475 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE INMATES' FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 Notk -Thfse are the personal funds of the inmate* held in trust by the Institution tor these nmatee and received and expended tor their sole individual benefits. Approximate average number of accounts December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918, was 56. PERIOD Debits I Credits Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1916, $108.86 December, 1916 January, 1917 February, 1917 March. 1917... April, 1917. May, 1917 June. 1917 July. 1917 August, 1917 September, 1917 October, 1917 November, 1917 Total for year Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 •. tu»M Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917, $283.26 December. 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March, 1918. April, 1918 May, 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918 August, 1918 September. 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 Total for year Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, 1166.47 Grand total for two years 61.53 17.62 29.64 36.31 41.06 37.47 134.04 ttJI 107.82 77 M 70.S9 174 .OS 830 J6 i 61.80 90.04 84.65 97.09 94.11 38.23 74.07 8531 90.63 67.01 95.57 126.25 i 1004.76 143.01 f 110.40 173.1:1 82.84 128.61 143.91 53.03 89.83 94.25 111.69 li'l.oS 34.83 84.54 47.50 til 1 1 134.39 127.67 102.38 136.65 71.64 65.96 86.26 39.17 44.08 1176.54 * 1059.75 2006.90 S 2176.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 476 RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 1916, December 1, 1918 t AMOUNTS RECEIVED GENERAL SOURCES Total Dee. 1. 1916 Dec. 1, 1917 I Dee. 1. 1916 to to to Dee. 1, 1»17 j Dec. 1. 1918 Dec. 1, 1918 Hogs Co«l t 787.38 j $ 523.00 , $ 1310.38 1190.07 1190.07 196.88 I 196.88 Cattle and poultry Refrigerator 178.49 | 132.12 310.61 65.00 65.00 Refund freight Saeks S4.71 I 34.71 32.70 32.70 Kraut Wood 30.94 30.94 24.00 24.00 Clothing and furnishings Refund on warrant 16.70 1.00 17.70 16.67 16.67 Junk 16.07 16.07 (iroreri.- Labor 6.83 ; .50 I 7.33 (i.30 .90 7.20 Stamps 1.68 1.68 Refund express Vouchers .92 .92 .38 2.18 ' 2.56 Correction on cash sheet .01 ; .01 Totals $ 1287.02 $ 1978.41 i * 3265.43 INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE- MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE November 30. 1918 Acres Acres Cultivated Uncultivated Total Esti- Acre- | mated Garden I Farm Orchard : Campus Waste age Value Land owned by institution 9 15 II 40 ! $ 13000.00 8.75 I 2250.00 Land rented by institution leash) Land rented by institution sha res ) Total 9 24.2 12 :t 48.75 S 15250.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Barn, horse Boiler room $ 500.00 S 230.00 f 730.00 1000.00 182.30 t 6477.20 I 7659.50 Chicken houses (3 1 Coal house 175.00 ! j 12.00 : 187.00 621.00 I 621.00 Cottage 500.00 ! 148.00 . 648.00 Dairy barn Hog house Ice house . Laundry 2500.00 195.00 I 2695.00 M.00 25.00 100.00 j j 100.00 5000.00 53.75 2154.25 . 7208.00 Main buildings (2) Store room 40000.00 4125.30 6439.50 i . . 50564.80 100.00 100.00 Ground improvements 3534.63 | S 465.77 4000.40 Total $ 50521.00 j I 4591.35 I 18960.58 ] * 465.77 t 74538.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 477 L&gt; 3ii a* 9 ? 3 ■i i = 111 X J x 5 ii? si is in i. e -5 * « 8 2 ( I IPS ! I § i J 1 J s g - ■* « 2 I *ia »3 ! * 5 5 : S 5 i-- *a i I I i H ! § 0 2 £ I I , si" 1 tl ■■ s - s i '; riiii g £ 1 1 &gt; SS || = •J _ 3 ? 2 s" I g a a * ? z x &lt; &lt; ii &gt; 1 ■ mmii a i P "5 h &lt; § II M </seg>
            <seg id="p014">478 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF M J X p b s 3 iAONiA W ." =: 0 ■ -coe«jCCt- S §2 £&amp; S'£*S i SlseaS i -a :5 I! :J i t- ? ? E 2 5 ! S !5on555SKoSS55SS « N N * 5 5 H.s,a a - s Tl 5 ■a S TiaMt--«c:-«io X •] 8 * I 's I -Si- ~i — *is a - a •- «| s H 1" = S- &gt; S • rsr ;i 3 3 3 3 =i 3 3 Sjg » - § Ij *u iiiiiiiAii » iiiyiiiiiiiyN \ I !if*illjii 8 iiiltr I *£ ,_ i | g^i jo-*e5cjO-c-SoN»- I — i! K 31 i a - r </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 479 II iJ 3 i -'» i 3 i £- S « as oi ei -v » ?i -- 1- d x ?1 5isJ 5 Jii 3 3 £Si ;« •♦ X 2 555 « » r^ © k 85"° ; s: i i" H 5 1 3 3 S E S^^ : *3 X E 2 I" I ! d ?? r:" ■ 55* tH I C X a a a &lt; 5 » tt .- 3 ! s i £ mi- ■ .55 ■ ; |T V ■ ■ a ; I X _ ||| S8S . 8 2§S SS5 K~ a as"° ess Is ! Hi C * 9 i I ii£ i 2 Hi a ii* ■ i4\ ■ I s o 8 °° t:» X a i ! 1 1- S ?Sg |S I :222 X •» S I -5 5 — "3 J5| NUS9&gt;O &lt;=ji-» ■C.O.C JS.O *S' : : « : 1 _Jii*l --288 i iii'lgii;;; i | </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 480 33 I i i * 5 "3 -£ I- s I z m I Hii^ll! ,-LJ U_! « I E I si -S I ' •a I i I 1-oS :2 ! * jlj^- i: i | vl\f*\\i i lli|Pi[i i g ■ i ; «" ■ i ■ I , I . S»S8S is I 1 wi'P'il i »'!l|' a 'l ,f ■a I S I ???9 i T ? !j||J!:!| 1 i iiii i i D : : : : : fc I j j I I I 111 g 5 if ? !Pr Ml- a* El PC - u I I I 2 in 1?1 i i -a III |= X2 &gt; i i o 5 i - H s i Uttl I : 15 ! Jll. ■ ! :*M|i ! i ;iSSj : \_z_ !:iSSj; Sift ■* SSi ' S ill I ■ 1 ;»r I : : : : I : I : : : : I i : : : : : m i:M:i s </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS 481 t IJ % i 55 i 5 I ss ' 5 J m •i a ilr 2 !: J ? jjljl i . glil l|s I 3 i i *r-h- 1 !•§ !_L_L_ i nil i Prph j » 3 ? mi 1 iii'Hii i 3 1 1 S3 a »- is * 1 - 5;« : a * .« r — , — — a - r- S I ' I ail 3 g 1 - I 1 SI = 1 5 5 0 *t 0 ? a k- « 1 3 1 « i i 9 •- ■ ? *•* I Jilt I i |! SiH I i -5 a i ! i ; : i i ■ 1 a * &lt; S f S a 9 S « 1 ? X 8 k ~ 1 s : 1 — L .. . I a: o 1 a -- 1 I, j I ■5 s ; » i M s ; 4 * SIM J t _i I Ml 1 i s ? g 3 5l H S^ iiii .. 1 z ; nnriT" si mil § </seg>
            <seg id="p018">482 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ■ is ■ I Pi s : P IKS'! : ' liSS|!I H t i IS !-S= : - 1st*. «. «*. = = ■ -r. -a ■ « — «5 * — — *? — ?~ — — 11 &gt; 1" i 5 JJ E - § I I f 2 2 «! [El* 7 ! 21 lijh: \ e i- I! i 2 * I j i &amp; J I I 3 *| I H** ■ -1* l z3 i i £ il -ill? I ji jir »1 1 Jl 4 3c* g J IP! »*M i l^i-i! i iff i j i jgs§ s i i s |s 3*« I 1 ■= t B-a i__L__J | il^ljl "SS : f z" z £ : § ~T^ - ;sss s "2 8 i\m i i i -i ■ I ] , i: il M J 2 o - £ ?■ a _■ i 3 - nif-;;i I! Ill * u z i ■ n i iissiis i» ! L!T L* 11 jjl S *"&gt;\ ?.- sSs . S I" !■! ; ■! i - + ■ ' ' x % s g&gt; ' &gt; : + ; s -i &lt;* i .'8 i § Fill:" ■s. ; »|ii§s s g. I ilr"|l ■■■■■' " i ■ " : • ! S| lit S l| \U\\l </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS 4TS3 0 x m — • I |j 0 - 5 | E I ■■ |x \ i 8SSI3 . ism is" II li||ss— « •»! : «I ' ! s n § ' 5 i — n 5^ — b- 5-5. i 5 I :«Wd : .x 5 .i " i "IS ! i_g il*!. 1 **"-:!: -- ' ' s _ ! • ' • • .2 . . 12 £| j|i I = s i I -i a :f ijMJl -■■I I i» 5 i • i ! z i • • • -I • -_ I-Sj i | : si j| ' &gt; \ ■ ■ - ■ i 8 i-- f I :?«TP| J s fl i i| ! : § ■ : : : I : tI I : : 5£l9 ?: — 5 ' 2 i : : : : : I : §J Si r : &lt; i *1 : 2is t --5? s ■IjiiLllil P'li^- ! «* [I 1 ! a I £* -ijs :2ss Ms I g III 8 ! [I p |ji|«;*": ; </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OK 484 TABLE I MOVEMENT OF POPULATION TABLE II -ACE AND COLOR OF ADULTS ADMITTED MOVEMENT For Year Nov.'*, 1»17 For Year ending Nov. 30, 191* Total for Biennium Present at beginning ot period Admitted: Adults For firs! time Readmitted Returned from parole Transferred from other institution!* Infants: Born at institution Admitted for first time. . Returned from trial homes M. F. T. 13 81 74 65 «5 33 28 61 . ... 1 1 1 .. .. 1 M. F. T. 27 85 112 . ... 41 41 14 22 36 2 1 .1 I 1 M. F. T. IS &lt;1 74 . 106 106 47 50 97 2 2 4 2 &gt; Total under care 47 15S 202' j 44 149 193 61 219 283 Discharged : In due course Transferred to other institutions Died Departed without leave Infants placed in permanent homes Married . Infants placed in trial homes and not returned during period Still born 8 44 52 3 3 2 4 6 2 6 X 4 4 2 6 8' 1 1 2| 14 69 83 :l 1 4 3 2 5 2 1 3 10 12 22 22 113 135 3 4 7 5 6 11 8 9 17 4 4 12 18 30 1 1 2 Total removals Total remaining at end of period . . Absent in trial homes at commencement of or during period and later discharged without returning to institution I '. 20 70 90 27 85 112 3 1 4 32 85 117 12 «i :&gt;; 3 3 6 52 155 207 12 64 76 6 4 10 AGE For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total tor Biennum j W. C. T. W. C. T. '. W. C. T. Under 14 yean 14 and under 15 years . 15 and under 16 years. . 1 6 and under 1 7 years . IT and under 18 years. . 18 and under 20 years 20 and under 25 years . 25 and over 1 1 3 3, 2 t 6 6, 11 11 22 22 18 18 2 2 ,s 7. . . It 1 1 1 . ... 1 *.... 4 5 7 ... 7 3 8 ... » 3 24 24 7 29 .. 29 11 29 . ... 29 1 3 3 Totals i h. ... 65; 41.... 4 41 106 ... 106 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 485 TABLE 111 -SEX AND COLOR OF BORN AND ADMITTED TABLE 1V-EDUCATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED TABLE V NATIVITY OF ADULTS ADMITTED COLOR For Yemr i Nov. 30, 1917 M. F. T. For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 '. Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. Born at institution: White Colored Admitted: White Colored 33 28 61 1 1 14 22 36 47 50 97 2 13 t t 4 Totalu I 33 29 62 16 23 39 4* 52 101 EDUCATION For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 F. For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 F. Total for Bienniura T. None 3d (rule and below 4th grade 5th grade 6th grade 7th grade Hth grade High aehonl College Unknown Totals 1 3 1 8 6 13 15 15 2 1 65 1 5 2 3 6 6 8 7 3 41 2 8 3 11 12 IS 23 22 &amp; 1 106 NATIVITY Nebraska 0. S. other than Nebraska 1 : For Ye»r ending Nov. 30, 1917 F. :)9 24 fi:l 1 2 65 r 1 : For Yemr ending Nov. 30. 1918 F. 27 13 40 1 0 1 41 ■ Total for Biennium r. 66 37 103 2 1 3 106 Total native born Bohemia Holland Total foreign born Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p022">486 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI PARENTAL CONDITION OF ADULTS ADMITTED TABLE VII AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF ADULTS ADMITTED PARENTAL CONDITION Both parents dead Father dead Mother dead Parents living Parents separated Has step father Has step mother I'nknown I 1 For Year Nov"*l. 1917 F. 2 10 13 40 4 6 1 ] ! For Year en dine Nor. 30, 1918 F. 3 I 23 4 1 2 Total for Biennium F. 6 16 22 M 8 7 3 76 48 124 AGE For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 ¥. 1 ] For Year ending Nov. 30. mix F. Total for Biennium F. .R at death of father: Under 10 years 10 yean and under 15 15 years and over .... Lge at death of mother: Under 10 years 10 years and under 15 1 5 years and over .... 2 8 2 I -I I S 12 4 7 5 3 27 4 2 21 13 9 5 48 Totals i </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 487 TABLE VIII— ADMISSION OF ADLLTS FROM DELINQUENT ANO DIFZITIVE HOMES TABLE !X PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF ADULTS ADMITTED i i feeble-minded: Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister [nsane: Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister intemperate: Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister Delinquent- Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister Unknown Totals CT«ASS For Year | For Year eidinn endinc Total Nov. M, Nov. 30, i for 191? 1918 Bienmum ~~T~ ..... . , , i .... i i .... i 5 1 C 2 4 « 5 2 1 ..... " i '.'.'.'. i « .... « 9 ( IS SO 15 45 OCCUPATION Clerk Cook Dommtie Faiiory H.MUF-keeptr Hotel 1 li school Laundry M usirimn Nunm Office worker Restaurant Teacher TiHephoue office Tvput Worked at home Total*. .'. ■ * • i • For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. SO, for 1917 1918 Biennium p. f. r. 112 1 1 15 • 14 1 t S * 3 • I If 4 M IS 7 M 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 t .... t "t 3 S 2 2 4 1 1 8 2 10 66 41 1M [ \ I I </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 488 REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM C Antelope Boone Box Butte gL:::::::: mSF'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Ca Ctany Clay Ma Dodfe Filhnore Furna« Gn^ty'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Hall.. Hamilton Hayes Hitchcock Holt , Howard Jefferson T«am»aiitw Lincoln Merrick .'..'.'. Morrill NuckolU Pawnee Phelp. PUtte Polk Richardson . . . Red Willow Saline S«rpy Saunders SeotU Bluff Seward Sherman Thayer Thuraton Valley ST".:::::: Total. COUNTY 31' [TNTY For Year For Year All ending ending Total Remaining Nov. 30, Not. SO, for Nov. 30, 1*17 1918 Biennium 1918 r. ¥. ¥. r. i i s s 1 1 1 1 1 i * i :;: « "i s "t 2 .... 2 '.'.'. 2 "i ■■» ... 1 2 3 S 9 4 IS 5 ... 1 S 4 S ...4 S 7 4 &amp; 5 1 1 .... 1 1 2 S Z ... 1 1 2 1 1 1 ... ..„ ..„ ...^ j 1 1 ... 1 1 t 1 2 6 5 I! i :::i j :::i '.'.'. i "i 2 '.'.'.'. l l i ...4 1 B 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ...2 1 S 2 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1 ... 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 * 1 1 1 :::. i_ ::: » 1_ ::: i 65 41 10« 47 41 106 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 489 TABLE XI— PROCEDURE FOR ADMISSION OF ADULTS For Year For Year ending ending Total PROCEDURE NotVM, Not.30, for 1917 1918 Biennium f! f. f. loluntary application « 37 9g 3eeree of court : {Delinquency 4 4 8 Dependency .... .... .... Totals «S 41 10« TABLE XII— CAUSES OF DEATH CAUSE Acute streptoeoeeia infection . . Hydro-syphilia spina B-fidm . . Malnutrition . . Pneumonia .... Premature Puerperal eclampsia For Year For Year ending ending Total CAUSE Nov. 30, Nov. 80, tor 1*17 1918 Biennium II. F. T. M. F. T. M. T. T. Acute streptoeoecia infection IIS 111 Hydro-syphilia spina B-nda 1 1 1 1 Malnutrition 2 t t .... 1 1 2 3 5 Pneumonia 1 . . . . 1 t . - . . 1 Premature 1 1 1... 1 Puerperal eclampsia 1 1 1 1 Total. t4« 3 2 5 5 « 11 Totala I I I TABLE XIII— ACE AT DEATH i i i TABLE XIII— ACE AT DEATH For Year For Year ending ending Total AGE Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium II. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. Inder 1 month Ill 213 126 One to three months 1 1 t 1 1 2 Three to six months Six to twelve months 1 . . . . 1 1 . . . . One to two yean 1 1 1 1 t I Twenty to twenty-five yean 1 1 1 1 Totals 2 4 « 3 2 5 ft • 11 </seg>
	           <seg id="p026"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>