<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Sixteen Years' Grain Production at the North Platte Substation</title>
               <date value="1923-07">1923-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 193 July, 1923 Sixteen Years' Grain Production at the North U ZOOK AND W. W. BURR W. P. Snyder. Superintendent Background: Oats on Summer Tillage. Foreground: Oats following Alfalfa. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. BURNETT. Director Platte Substation Bulletin No. 24 of the North Platle Experiment Substation </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS PAGE Summary 3 Soil and location of Farm • Corn — Varieties « Listing compared with surface planting g Rate of planting and distance between rows 9 Effects of early fall plowing 11 Effect of the previous crop 1J Winter Wheat 15 Turkey Red 15 Nebraska No. t ~ IS Nebraska No. 28 _ 1C Kanred _ , 17 Blackhull _ 17 Seedbed preparation _ 18 Time of plowing.. 18 Depth of plowing _ 19 Effect of packing _ 20 Rates and manner of seeding 23 Spring Wheat- Comparison of spring and winter wheat 26 Varieties _ _ 27 Rates and manner of seeding.... 30 Dats« of seeding _ 31 Variety tests 33 Rates and manner of seeding _ 35 Dates of seeding _ 37 Varieties _ 38 Rates and manner of seeding _ 40 Time of seeding _ 41 Emmer _ 43 Ry« - - — 43 Climatic data 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SIMMARY Locally adapted seed corn has given higher yields than seed brought in from a distance. Listing has given 4 bushels per acre more than surface planting during 12 years' comparisons. Planting in rows ZVt feet apart with one stalk every 24 inches has given higher yield than any other spacing tried. Where corn follows small grain, early fall plowing has given approximately 4 bushels an acre more than spring plowing for corn. Corn following corn has given 3** bushels more per acre than com following spring grain. Summer tillage gave approximately 2 % bushels per acre more than corn following corn. Plowiag deeper than 10 inches for wheat showed no increase in yield, but did increase the labor over 7 inch plowing. Plowing as shallow as 3 inches also gave less yield than the 7-inch plowing. lncreared yields of winter wheat have resulted from early plowing and packing of the seedbed. Winter wheat following winter wheat or other small grain has given the lowest average yields per acre. Summer tillage has given the highest average yields per acre. Winter wheat seeded on corn land has given consistently good yields and with the low cost of the seedbed preparation has proved the most profitable method. Seeding winter wheat at 5 pecks per acre has given the highest average yield. On summer tilled land the difference in yield between I pecks and 2 pecks was not material. On disked corn land the dif - ference was approximately 3 bushels. In an 11-year test spring wheat has given only 61 per cent much yield as winter wheat. Macaroni or durum wheat has given consistently higher yields than the common spring wheat. Unless grown in carlots there may be difficulty in marketing it. Seeding at 4 pecks per acre has proved the best rate for spring wheat. Averaging several of the best early strains of oats and taking their yield as 100 per cent, the best late oats have given only 58 per cent of the early oat yield. Six pecks per acre has proved the best rate for seeding oats. The earliest seeding for spring wheat, oats, and barley has given the highest average yield. Barley of the common 6-row type has proved the most satisfactory. &lt;7-'»-51l). </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at the 5 Platte Substation I. ZOOK ANT) VV. W. BURR This bulletin gives some of the more important results obtained in the study of crop production at the North Platte Substation during the past 16 years. It does not attempt to give all of the experimental evidence obtained in this line, but rather to set forth the results obtained on the more practical phases of production, which may serve as a guide to the farmer and answer the questions that frequently arise as to crops or methods. Many of the results obtained, such as the advantage of early over late varieties of spring grains and the importance of early seeding for spring grains, are of wide application. On the other hand, the data on such problems as rates of seed - ing are of more local application, since they are determined largely by the amount of rainfall, the proper seeding rate decreasing or increasing with the rainfall. We feel, therefore, that most of the results, with slight modifications to meet local conditions, are applicable to much of the hard table-land in west-central and western Nebraska. The bulletin also gives a summary of the rainfall during the time that these investigations were under way. The cli - matic conditions during that period should be taken into consideration with the study of the results obtained. Climatic factors are, within certain limits, the most potent factors in determining results. A clearer understanding of the climatic conditions that may be expected will enable one to adjust more completely his farm operations to meet these conditions. The results obtained show years of relatively low and years of relatively high yields. While there is some evidence that these run in cycles, still they are on the whole irregular. In only one year in the 16 has there been a total failure of grain and on the whole profitable yields have been obtained from several of the crops considered. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 SOIL AND LOCATION OK FARM The North Platte Substation is located 3 miles south of the city of North Platte. It lies partially on the bench land, extending back thru rough canyon pasture to level land on the table. The farm contains 1920 acres, of which approximately 280 acres are on the level bench or second bottom land, where it is 30 to 40 feet to sheet water. About 120 acres are level table-land approximately 250 feet to sheet water. The remainder of the farm is pasture land — much of it quite broken. Eie soil on the farm is mainly derived from the loess for - n. In the pasture land the Ogallala formation (so-called esia or Mortar Beds) outcrops in- several places, but does not occur on the level farming land either on the bench or table. The soil is classified as fine sandy loam. It contains about equal parts of fine sand and silt with relatively small amounts of clay and is consequently easily tilled. The upper soil contains more organic matter and is consequently some - what darker colored than the lower soil, but aside from this the soil is quite uniform to considerable depths. In a few places decomposed Ogallala may be found in the fifth or sixth foot, but on the whole the soil is deep and capable of rather large water storage and the full development of plant roots. CORN VAKIETIKM Tests of varieties and strains of corn have been conducted each year since 1906. The number grown in different years has ranged from 6 to 35. Many local strains and varieties have been included in the tests ; also varieties from a number of more distant sources. No effort has been made to compare a large number of the same varieties thru a number of years. Two varieties, known as Substation White and Calico, have been grown each year. These are well adapted to local condi - tions and have been used as a basis of comparison for other varieties grown. Varieties which were much inferior to these standard varieties were discarded after 1 to 2 years' tests. Those which seemed more promising were continued for longer periods. The detailed results of these tests are not of sufficient interest or value to justify their publication. No varieties have been grown which have proved them - selves superior for general farm use to the 2 Station varieties </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 7 named. Most of the local varieties grown have produced yields about equal to those of the Station varieties, while those brought from a greater distance have as a rule been inferior. The varieties which have most frequently outyielded the standard Station dent varieties have been of the flour and flint types. Blue Flour or "Squaw" and Australian White Flint have been grown for 8 years. During this time Blue Flour has outyielded the dent varieties 6 times, in amounts varying from 2.4 to 9.5 bushels per acre. Its average yield has been 4.4 bushels more per acre than that of Substation White. Aus - tralian White Flint has outyielded the dent varieties 3 out of 8 times, but its average yield has been 2.1 bushels per acre less than that of Substation White. The flour and flint types of corn have objectionable characters, such as the habit of pro - fuse suckering, low-growing ears, and heavy thick ear shanks which make them very unpopular where the crop is husked by hand. It seems unlikely, therefore, that even with higher vielding qualities, they will ever replace a very large part &gt;f the dent corn acreage. For certain special purposes, how - ever, where the crop can be harvested with livestock, or cut and husked with a shredder, they have an undoubted value, and should be given consideration by a larger number of farmers. It is possible also that some of their objectionable qualities may be reduced or eliminated by careful selection, or that they may have value for crossing with other types of com in the production of strains better adapted to dry land conditions. Variety names are frequently misleading. Differences between strains of corn originating from the same parent variety but grown under different conditions of soil and cli - mate or selected along divergent lines are often much greater than differences between unrelated varieties which have been subjected to the same conditions of soil, climate, and selection. In eastern Nebraska, where conditions for corn are favor - able, a large type of corn with comparatively large ears and deep kernels is grown. Westward in the state conditions become less favorable and the type of corn becomes smaller, until in western Nebraska small early varieties, with small ears and shallow, smooth, flinty kernels, are found. For exam - ple, the type of dent corn with striped or variegated kernels, known as Calico, in eastern Nebraska produces large stalks and large ears, many of which have deep kernels and rough </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 8 surfaces. In extreme western Nebraska, Calico corn has a short stalk and small, smooth ears with flinty kernels. At North Platte a medium type has given better yields than either the large or the very small types from the eastern or western parts of the state. I.IHTIX. I'lmrtHKII WITH SIHKACK I'I.A\TIN&lt;. The yields secured by surface planting and by listing corn for 12 years are shown in parallel columns in Table 1. Higher yields have resulted from listing in all except 3 years. The Table 1. — Listing versus surface planting of corn. Yield in bushels. average gain has been 4.1 bushels per acre. The low yield from listing in 1909 was due to a very poor stand. Under conditions of heavy precipitation and low temperature, such as those of 1915, surface planting is an advantage. There are several factors which make listing superior to surface planting for a large part of western Nebraska. The most important of these is probably the checking of early 'In 1907 and 1914 no corn was surface planted. These years are omitted from the averages. j n Ull and 1913 the crop* were failures on account of drought. These years are counted in the averages. Surface planting ncrease from listing kear 1 Listing Buthi U Bushrlt Bush&gt; Is I** ' lMt 1909 1910 1912 1915 191« 1917 _ 1918 1919 1921 1922 15.5 20.7 38.2 1C.3 19.2 35.7 00 1.7 26.9 33.0 1«4 24.C 25.8 26.7 29.1 24.8 22.6 33.7 14.1 3.1 25.6 39.5 27.6 25.0 in.3 6.0 -9.1 8.5 3.4 -2.0 14.1 1.4 -1.3 6.5 11.2 .4 14-year average... 17.7 21.3 3.6 i_ , </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 9 growth, which results from planting in the colder ground at the bottom of the lister furrows, and the lower setting of roots caused by cultivating soil into the furrows. Surface planted corn which is not subjected to any retarding influence is fre - quently several inches taller than listed corn by July 1. The surface planted corn, on account of its larger growth, requires a larger supply of moisture than is often available during July itnd August and is frequently unable to reach its full develop - ment. On the other hand, the smaller, sturdier growth of the listed corn, on account of low water requirements and bet - ter root protection, is able to stand thru longer periods of drought with less serious injury. Covering the lower nodes of the corn plant in cultivating listed corn lessens the amount of suckering and thus reduces vegetative growth and conse - quently the water requirement. With the specialized machin - ery now available for cultivating listed corn, one man can handle a larger acreage or the same acreage at less expense than is possible when surface planting is practiced. The advantage of listing over surface planting for corn applies in most of the corn growing area of western Nebraska. As the western line is approached, however, it becomes less distinct. In the extreme western and northwestern part of the state, where the growing season is short even for early types of corn, the retarding influence of listing delays maturity to fcuch an extent that the practice becomes less profitable than surface planting. KATK OK IM.AVri.\&lt;; AMD DISTANT*: IKTWKKK ROWS Tests' conducted in western Kansas from 1910 to 1913 indicated that under severe conditions of drought advantages might result from growing corn in rows 7 feet apart rather than in rows spaced at the ordinary distance of 3.5 feet. The chief reason for expecting more favorable results from this method were: (1) That competition between the plants planted thickly in the row would help to prevent excessive vegetative growth. (2) That the wide spaces between rows would serve as an area for storing reserve moisture which would be reached and used by the roots as the plants became larger and their needs became greater. To determine whether similar results might be expected under central and western Nebraska conditions, experiments •"A New Method of Growing: Corn," Journal of American Society of Agronomy. Vol. 6. No. 2, 84-88. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 were begun at North Platte in 1915. Comparisons between wide and ordinary-spaced rows were made at each of 2 rates of planting. In order to maintain the same stands per acre, plantings in rows of twice the ordinary width would have to be made at twice the ordinary rate in the row. For experi - mental work with corn at the station the standard distance between rows is about 3.5 feet and the average distance between stalks in the row is 24 inches, thus making a stand of 6,600 stalks per acre. This is obtained by planting thickly, and thinning the plants when small to an exact count, so that the desired stand will be secured. For these experiments the ground was listed in the ordinary manner and the plantings made in these furrows with a corn planter. For the wide - spaced plantings at the ordinary stand, every other row was double planted and the plants later thinned to an average dis - tance of 12 inches in the row. For the wide-spaced plantings of one-half stand every other row was planted in the ordinary manner and the plants thinned to an average distance of 24 inches in the row. For comparison with these plantings, plantings were made in every row and thinned in one case to 24 and the other case to 48 inches apart in the row. Six years' results from the 4 methods of planting are shown in Table 2. The results for 1918 and 1919 are omitted, as a shortage of labor in those years prevented the thinning from being properly done. In 3 of the 6 years the highest yield TABLE 2. — Yields of corn from full stands and half stands rows S.5 and 7 feet apart. Distance between plants in row. inches 24 48 12 24 •istance between rows, feet M 3.5 7 7 'lants per acre, number 6600 3300 6600 33iMi ield per acre, bushrlt 1915 1916 _ 1917 1920 1921 1922 18.3 19.5 3.1 343 27.6 25.0 12.0 14.1 13.2 25.0 26.2 27.1 16.9 12.2 2.9 32.3 27.6 28.3 9.3 11.8 8.8 21.4 22.4 23.3 ■year average 21.3 19.4 I 20.0 16.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 11 was made by the standard planting of rows 3.5 feet apart and an average distance of 24 inches between plants in the row. The average yield from this method is 1.3 bushels more per acre than that from the same number of stalks per acre planted in rows 7 feet apart, 1.9 greater than that of a half stand in rows 3.5 feet apart, and 5.1 bushels greater than that of a half stand in rows 7 feet apart. In 1917, which was a dry year with generally low yields, the half-stand plantings produced more per acre than the full stands in either the wide or the ordinary-spaced rows. The highest yield was produced from the half stand in rows of ordinary width. In 1921, equal yields were produced by full stands in both the wide and the ordinary spaced rows. The only case in which the higher yield was produced by the wide-spaced rows was in 1922. In this year the July rain - fall was above normal and conditions were favorable for moisture storage. On August 1 corn was in an unusually good condition; dry weather followed and by August 15 consider - able firing had taken place in corn that was planted in the ordinary manner. The plants of both the half and full stands in wide-spaced rows remained green for several weeks later Since wide spacing of rows has produced an increase in yield in but 1 trial out of 6, and the average yield from this method is somewhat lower than the average from ordinary plantings, it cannot be recommended as a substitute for plant - ing in the ordinary way for west-central Nebraska conditions. RKKRCTS OK KAHLY FALL PLOWING In western Nebraska the common practice is to disk the land once or twice in the spring previous to listing, but a con - siderable amount of corn is planted by listing without previous preparation of the ground. Only a small percentage of land is plowed where planting is done with the lister. Fall disking is not very frequently done. In the experiments at the North Platte Substation, land has been prepared for corn by early fall, late fall, and spring plowing. Of 16 plats following spring grain in Field 41, 7 are early fall plowed and 9 are spring plowed. Of 13 plats follow - ing oats or winter wheat in Field 49, 6 are early fall plowed and 7 are late fall plowed. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 Table 3 shows the results obtained from these plats for the 11-year period from 1912 to 1922, inclusive. In Field 41 the yield, after early fall plowing, has been above that after spring plowing in 8 of the 10 years in which a crop was produced. In Field 49 the yields after early fall plowing have been greater than those after late fall plowing in 9 of the 10 years a crop was produced. The average yields from Field 49 are somewhat larger than those from Field 41 and the difference TABLE 3. — Comparison of corn yields on early fall plowing and spring plowing in Field 41 , and on early fall plowing and late fall plowing in Field 49. in methods is greater. In Field 41 the plats in the 2 groups are distributed in equally favorable locations and the differ - ences in yield secured in favor of early fall plowing are with - out doubt due to the superiority of this method. In Field 49 some of the early fall plowed plats are located on slightly lower ground and occasionally during heavy rains receive run-off water from other parts of the field. This advantage may ac - count for part of the gain made by the early fall plowed group. Field 41 Field 49 Spring plowed' tirmin from early fall plowing Grain from Early fall Late fall early fall plowed 1 plowed 4 plowing , I HuthrU Fiushi I* Buihiln Uuihilx Buthclx 1912 913 914 915 1916 l»17 1918 1919 1920 1H21 1922 26.0 0 4.4 28.0 S.1 7.5 25.3 35.7 36.8 20.4 32.6 26.0 .0 0 0 3.2 1.2 29.5 -1.5 5.2 2.9 5.2 2.3 18.1 7.2 33.0 2.7 34.4 2.4 10.1 10.3 25.9 «.7 26.2 22.9 3.3 0 0 0 5.9 2.5 3.4 16.2 20.7 -4.5 14.1 11.7 2.4 18.8 7.6 11.-' 25.0 22.3 2.7 40.4 31.1 9.3 46.9 42.3 4.6 34.1 23.2 10.9 46.4 31.8 14.6 11-yr. av. 2(1.4 17.S 3.1 24.6 19.6 M 'Avertge of 7 plats. 'Average of 9 plats. •Average of 8 plats. 'Average of 7 plats. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 13 If the 2 groups of plats occupied equally favorable locations, it is probable that the average gain from early fall plowing would approach more nearly the average gain of early fall plowing over spring plowing in Field 41. The chief advantage of early fall plowing seems to be the saving of moisture thru the destruction of weeds under this practice. Winter grains and early varieties of spring grains mature early in July. The normal rainfall for July, August, and September, at North Platte, is 6.66 inches. This is 33 per cent of the total annual normal. Where weeds are allowed to grow in the stubble fields after harvest, very little of this moisture is stored for the use of the succeeding crop. Weeds are generally prevalent in stubble fields except in those very dry years when lack of moisture prevents their growth. Under such dry conditions there is probably no advantage in disking or early fall plowing. Disking after harvest may be as bene - ficial as plowing if the weeds are effectively destroyed. On light soils diskings may be better than plowing, as the trash left on the surface lessens the chances of soil blowing during the winter and spring. If plowed in the fall, soils should be left rough and not worked down to a smooth surface. There is little advantage in either late fall plowing or spring plowing for corn where planting is done with a lister. If much trash is plowed under at these times the plowing may be a detri - ment as it leaves the soil too loose and it is difficult to operate under such conditions. The results secured in these tests indicate that when corn follows small grain, yields may be increased several bushels per acre by keeping the stubble fields free of weeds after har- vest. RKFBCT Or I'RKUOIS &lt;ROP Sixteen years' data have been obtained from growing corn continuously on the same ground, growing corn in rotation with small grain, and in alternation with summer tillage. Results for each year of the entire period and the averages are shown in Table 4. These results are from Rotation Field 41 on the table-land. Of the 2 plats used for corn continuously one is spring plowed and the other fall plowed. The yields of corn after small grain are the averages from 2 adjoining 3-year rotations in which the corn ground is spring plowed in one case and early fall plowed in the other. The other crops of the 3-year rotations are barley and wheat in one case and oats </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 and wheat in the other, so that corn is grown on the same land but once in 3 years. But one plat of corn is grown in alterna - tion with summer tillage. The yields of corn after corn have been rather consistently higher than those after small grain. The yields after small grain were greater than those after corn only 3 times in the 14 years a crop was produced. The increases in none of the cases were large. In 7 of the 11 cases in which the larger yield was produced after corn, the increase has been 5 or more bushels per acre. In 1914 and 1917 the yields after corn were more than double those after small grain. As in the case of early fall plowing, the chief cause of the better yields of corn after corn seems to be more favorable moisture conditions. TABLE 4. — Annual yields of corn following corn, corn following small grain, and corn alternating with summer tillage, from 1907 to 1922, inclusive. Corn alternating Corn following Corn following with corn 1 spring grain 1 summer tillage Buthcli Btukelt Huxhi I, 1907 28.2 21.1 17.9 19M J1.6 32.7 38.1 1M» 30.3 22.3 l»10 ; 7.« 6.4 21.9 1911 0 0 1912 _ 37.0 32.0 1911 _ 10 0 4 Itl4 12.0 4.6 1915 28.8 29.6 19.7 191C 11.9 9.2 17.8 1917 l«.l 5.4 26.6 1918 27.0 20.2 28.7 1919 40.0 37.7 37.7 1920 32.6 35.0 32.0 1921 24.0 18.0 36.0 1922 MJ 27.« 35.0 l&lt;-year average 22.4 18.8 25.0 ■Average of 2 plats. : Averaee &lt;&gt;T 2 plats. ■One plat only. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 15 Numerous soil moisture determinations made during the pro - gress of this work show that corn seldom exhausts the soil moisture supply as thoroly as do the small grain crops. The additional moisture left in the soil after growing a crop of corn not only may be of direct benefit to the succeeding crop, but also may be of considerable benefit indirectly by enabling moisture which is received later to penetrate more rapidly into the soil. A greater proportion is thus stored in the subsoil for the use of the following crop. 1 The average yield of corn grown in alternation with sum - mer tillage is somewhat greater than that of corn after corn. The gain is only 2.6 bushels per acre, however, or 11.6 per cent of the yield of corn after corn. The yield of corn after sum - mer tillage has doubled the yield of corn after corn in only 2 cases during the 16-year period. The corn yield after corn has been greater than that of corn alternating with summer tillage 6 times in 16 years. The results of these tests indicate that summer tillage as a preparation for corn can only rarely be expected to return a profit and under average conditions the yields secured by this method will exceed those from land which is cropped every year by only a few bushels per acre. WINTKlt WHEAT A limited number of winter wheat varieties have been grown in comparative tests on the Station bench land since 1906. From 1906 to 1917 these tests were all on land that had been summer tilled the previous year. Since 1918 the tests have been conducted both on summer tilled and on corn stubble ground. The detailed results of these tests up to and includ - ing 1921 have been reported in previous publications. 2 The 1922 results which have since become available do not ma - terially affect the standing of varieties. A brief description of some of the more important varieties grown and the results secured are given in the following paragraphs : Turkey Red. — This variety has been grown at the Station from the same stock since 1905. No attempt has been made at selection or improvement except roguing to remove rye or other obvious mixtures. It has been used for seeding the check plats in the variety tests and as a standard with which 'Bulletin No. 140. "The Storage and Use of Soil Moistures." pages S-». 'Bulletin 135. "lirowlns; Crops in Western Nebraska," page 12. Bulletin 179. "Growing Winter Wheat in Western Nebraska," paces 33-37. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 to compare the yields of other varieties. It is a hardy, high - yielding: wheat of good milling quality. These qualities have kept it near the head of the list of all the varieties with which it has been compared. In 17 years it was but once entirely killed out during the winter. This was in 1917. Its 17-year average yield following summer tillage on the Station bench land was 31.1 bushels per acre. Following corn on table land, its 11-year average yield was 18.9 bushels per acre. Kharkov and Turkey Red are practically identical varie - ties. Two lots of Kharkov seed were secured thru the United States Department of Agriculture, No. 9125 in 1904 and No. 1440 in 1916. Sixteen crops of one or the other of these num - bers have been grown in comparison with Turkey Red. Khar - kov has produced the higher yield 8 times and Turkey Red has produced the higher yield 8 times. Both winterkilled in 1917. On summer-tilled land the 17-year average yield of Kharkov is 31.3 bushels per acre, while that of Turkey Red is 31.1 bushels per acre. Ghirka. — Seed of this variety was secured from the Kansas Experiment Station in the fall of 1909. It is a beardless variety. It was included in the tests for 9 years and yielded as much as Turkey Red only once in that time. Its 9-year average yield was 21.3 bushels per acre in comparison with an average of 23.9 for Turkey Red for the same years. Nebraska No. 287. — This is a pure strain of Turkey Red produced at the Nebraska Experiment Station. It was car - ried in the North Platte tests for 11 years. During that time it outyielded the Substation Turkey Red twice. In 1908 on a one-half acre plat it yielded at the rate of 63.3 bushels per acre, which is the record individual yield of these tests. Its 11-year average yield was 27.8 bushels per acre, which is 1.1 bushels per acre less than the average of Turkey Red for the same years. Nebraska No. 28. — This is a small early wheat selected at the Nebraska Experiment Station from a cross between Tur - key Red and Big Frame. It matures fully a week earlier than Turkey Red, has a short stiff straw, and on this account rarely lodges. The grain is somewhat soft and its milling quality inferior to that of Turkey Red. It has been included in the tests on summer-tilled land for 8 years. In 1915, 1919, and 1922 it outyielded Turkey Red 4.8. 14.4, and 5.1 bushels per acre, respectively. In the first 2 of these years the yields of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Sixteen Yeaks' Grain Production at North Platte 17 Turkey Red were reduced by lodging, while the No. 28 was not so affected. In 1922 the early maturity of No. 28 allowed it to escape the severe June drought with less injury than that suffered by Turkey Red. Under special conditions of this kind it can be expected to outyield Turkey Red. Its 8-year average yield on summer-tilled ground is 26.1 bushels per acre, which is 1.7 bushels per acre more than the yield of Turkey Red. During 5 years its average yield following corn was 16.7 bushels per acre, which is 1.7 bushels per acre less than the yield of Turkey Red under the same conditions. Kanred wheat is a pure strain selected at the Kansas Sta - tion. It has received much publicity and has been received with popular favor among growers. It has without doubt replaced a larger acreage of Turkey Red than any other strain or variety yet introduced into the hard winter wheat belt. The first seed for the tests at North Platte Station was obtained from the Kansas Station for seeding in the fall of 1917. Five crops have been grown on both summer-tilled and corn-stubble ground. The average yields are 28 bushels per acre from the former and 19.9 bushels per acre from the latter, in com - parison with Turkey Red yields under similar conditions of 25.5 and 18.4 bushels per acre, respectively. It has given higher yields than Turkey Red 3 of the 5 years tested. Kanred is more resistant to attacks of rust than Turkey Red and per - haps also somewhat more winter hardy. When the yields of Turkey Red are depressed by rust injury, as in 1920, Kanred may be expected to outyield it by substantial amounts. Nebraska No. 6 is &amp; pure strain of Turkey Red produced at the Nebraska Experiment Station. It was included in the tests at North Platte for 4 years on summer tillage and for 3 on stalk ground. Its average yields were 29.6 on the former and 17.1 on the latter, in comparison with yields of 28.7 and 17.3, respectively, for the North Platte Turkey Red. Nebraska No. 60, another of the pure strains produced at the Nebraska Experiment Station, has been grown at North Platte for two years only. In 1921 it produced poorer and in 1922 better than the North Platte Turkey Red. Blackhull is a strain with dark awns and chaff, selected by a Kansas grower from Turkey Red. It has been grown at North Platte for one year only. In 1922 it outyielded Turkey Red 3.1 bushels per acre on summer tillage and 1.8 bushels per acre on corn ground. It appears to be somewhat less winter </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 hardy than Turkey Red and the thinner stands with which it came thru the winter enabled it better to withstand the June drought. MKKD BKIJ PKKPAHATION Various methods of preparing the seedbed for winter wheat have been studied during the past 11 years. These studies include the effect of the time and depth of plowing, of packing, and of crop sequence. Time of Plowing. — In Table 5 are shown the yields from early and late fall plowing on adjacent plats for a period of 11 years. The average date of plowing for the early fall plowed plats was August 15, and for late plowing September 15. It is quite probable that if the so-called early plowing could have been done a month earlier the advantage would have been greater. It will be noted that in some years the dif- Table 5. — Yields of winter wheat on early and late fall plow - ing and increase from early fall plowing over late fall plowing for the 11 -year period from 1912 to 1922 inclu - sive. Early Late IMMM for Year fall plowed fall plowed early plowing ■More detailed results and fuller explanations of experiments in seedbed preparation and the effects of crop sequence on winter wheat yields are K&lt;ven in Bulletins 178 and 179. which may be secured on application to the THrector of the Agricultural Experiment Station. Lincoln, Nebraska. Butkrlt Buthelt Buthrlt .912 ..._ 913 1914 916 191J L&gt;17 1918 „ _ 1919 1920 „ 1921 1922 7.7 S.8 4.7 MJ 28.3 4.1 8.2 18.3 81.2 19.8 11.2 7.2 3.2 3.3 39.7 23.5 5.0 4.0 19.8 21.2 18.5 4.8 .5 .6 1.4 .1 4.8 -1.5 10.0 a 1-year average... 16.2 13.7 2.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 19 ference in yield was quite material, while in other years small differences occurred. In 2 of the 11 years, late fall plowing showed a slight increase over the earlier plowed plats. This variation is doubtless due to differences in climatic conditions. The accumulation of moisture and nitrates in the soil is an im - portant factor in determining the yield of winter wheat. When the soil and climatic conditions are favorable to the storage of moisture, the earlier the plowing can be done the more advan - tageous it is. The accumulation of nitrates in the soil is closely correlated with the accumulation of moisture. In seasons when the soil is dry and there is no moisture to be lost thru weed growth and no moisture comes that could be accumu - lated, the difference in the effect of the time of plowing would probably be relatively small. Table 6. — Effect of depth of plowing in a comparison of the effect of plowing and disking in preparation for winter wheat. Yield per acre. Depth of Plowing. — The data shown in Table 6 are the average yields from 4 plats for each depth of plowing and 2 plats on disking. The results obtained show the highest aver - age yields for plowing at depths of 7 to 10 inches. Of the plowing depths the 3-inch plowing has given the lowest aver - age yield. It is quite evident that this depth is not sufficient to prepare a satisfactory seedbed. On the other hand, plow - ing 14 inches deep has not only failed to increase yields, but also failed to show any advantage in moisture storage. In the absence of other depths for comparison it is safe to assume Depth plowed 1912 1913 1914 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 At. Imhrt Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bit. Bu. Bu. Bu. 3 7 10 14 isked only 5.7 8.5 8.6 5.6 1.5 7.4 7.1 5.5 5.9 4.2 4.1 40.1 25.4 5.7 4S.S 28.8 5.5 41.6 32.2 5.1 44.7 29.6 S.0 17.* 26.3 4.2 3.0 159 13.2 5.0 5.8 17.4 15.2 5.1 5.8 17.6 15.3 4.1 3.9 16.8 14.5 5.6 i 2.6 14.6 12.0 verage 6.5 6.2 4.9 41.9 28.7 4.7 4.4 16.7 ! 14.S </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 20 that plowing at from 6 to 8 inches in depth is probably fully as satisfactory in yield as any other depth. It is more easily accomplished than plowing at a greater depth. In the plats that were disked the attempt was made to keep down weed growth and prevent the weeds using moisture, and generally more than one disking was necessary. From these data it would seem that under average conditions a sat - isfactory seedbed cannot be obtained by disking alone. In this study it was found that in favorable seasons one disking would not entirely destroy the weeds. Had only one disking been given under such conditions, the difference in yields shown would doubtless have been greater. TABLE 7. — Effect of packing as compared with non-packing. Yield per acre. No. of Treatment plat* 1*12 1»1J 1*14 1»1S 1916 1*17 1*18 ltl* Av B«. flu B* At. Bu. Bu. Bu.Bu.Bm. Pacfcai I »J «.4 s.t Not smtkai.-. » i.t (.4 4.* M.t 4.1 If.* 1S.S Gain from parking 4.» .0 1.6 M •• Effect of Packing. — In Table 7 are shown the average yields obtained from 8 plats which were packed following plowing, in comparison with 8 plats not packed. The average gain from packing is 1.8 bushels per acre. In 2 years out of the 8 under trial the effect of packing was considerably higher than this. In 1 year no increase in yield was obtained from packing. Of the 8 plats in each case, 4 were plowed early and 4 were plowed late. The effect of packing was some - what more pronounced on the early plowing than on the later plowing. The necessity of packing and the advantages to be expected from it will depend much upon the condition of the ground at plowing and at seeding time. On clean ground containing sufficient moisture to plow well, harrowing and drilling may be sufficient to firm the ground and make a good seedbed. If on the other hand there is a heavy growth of stubble or trash </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 21 on the ground, or if the soil is somewhat dry and breaks up cloddy, packing may be of much benefit in securing a good con - tact between the furrow slice and the soil below, in pressing out air cavities and in securing a firm seedbed. In Table 8 are shown yields of winter wheat obtained after small grain, corn, and summer tillage. Results are shown following small grain on an average of 8 plats, after corn on 9 plats, and after summer tillage on 4 plats. The lowest aver - age yields have been obtained from winter wheat following small grain. This is probably due to the fact that the small Fio. 1 — Winter Wheat, 1917. On left: Wheat following Corn. On right: Wheat on Summer Tilled Land. grain more thoroly dries out the soil than does corn, and emphasizes the advantage of rotating with corn rather than having the land continuously in small grain. Land used con - tinuously for small grain is more apt to become foul with weeds than where a cultivated crop is grown. Yields of winter wheat following corn are about intermedi - ate between those following small grain and those following summer tillage. While summer tillage has given the highest average yield, it must be borne in mind that this practice </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 22 necessitates the use of the land for 2 years for the one crop of wheat. Furthermore, the labor in growing the corn is prob - ably little if any more than the labor in summer tilling, the difference probably not being greater than the seeding and harvesting of the corn. The increased yield from summer till - age was therefore obtained at the sacrifice of the major por - tion of the corn yield. TABLE No. 8. — Yields of winter wheat after small grain, corn, and summer tillage on table land, from 1912 to 1922 inclu - sive. Winter wheat After After small grain After summer tillage corn Bushel* HhmHiIk llutht /* In Table 9 is shown a comparison of yields of winter wheat following both summer tillage and corn on bench land. This work was conducted on fields of either 7 or 10 acres, so that the yields represented are from either 3 l /-&gt; or 3 acres of each preparation. During the year of preparation one-half of the land was in corn and one-half summer tilled. During a 5-year period summer-tilled land has given an annual average yield of 7.3 bushels more wheat per acre than corn land. The average yield of corn is 21.1 bushels per acre. In this test, therefore, each bushel of wheat gained on sum - mer tillage represents almost 3 bushels of corn which might £" 1918 , «» J20 \tXl LMS a S.S 7.1 1M MJ 18* &gt;.( 1V.V 16.9 8.1 37.3 38.2 20.9 23.6 10.9 29.6 29.7 15.5 29.5 21.5 verage ... 15.2 18.9 HJ </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 23 have been produced had the land been used for corn instead of being summer tilled. In only 1 year during the test was there a wide increase in yield from summer tillage and in 1 year the 2 methods approached closely the same yield. Considering the value of the corn crop and the lost cost of seedbed preparation of this method the most profitable yields of winter wheat were those following corn. Table 9. — Winter wheat yields following summer tillage and following corn, the increase in yields following summer tillage over those following corn, and the corn yields of the previous year, on bench land. Yields of winter wheat After After Increase from Corn yield of summer tillage corn summer tillage previous year HATKM AND MANNKH OF -I llll\(. Rates of seeding tests with winter wheat have been in pro - gress at this Station since 1906. For the first 5 years 4 rates were in use. The highest of these was 5 pecks and the lowest 2 pecks per acre. Since 1911, seedings of 1 peck per acre have also been made. In 1913 a broadcast seeding at 4 pecks per acre was added. The annual and average yields from each rate of seeding are shown in Table 10. In 1917 the crop was a failure on account of winterkilling. This year is counted in the averages. In 1918 the threshing machine became clogged and carried over grain from one plat to another. On this liuthrlx Buihel* HiihIii ix HuthtlH 918 919 »M 921 922 19.1 24.1 32.5 33.3 ... | 20.9 M lf.7 32.0 24.7 14.3 13.5 8.6 M 5.0 10.0 42.0 32.8 15.8 H ' i H h i-year av. 26.0 18.7 7.3 21.1 S-year av. 26.0 18.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 account the weights could not be used and this year is omitted from the averages. While variations between rates have occurred from year to year, there is remarkably little difference in yields between the 5, 4, 3, and 2-peck rates of seeding. Stooling is heavier on the thinner rates. The straw is usually stiffer and the heads larger. These factors compensate to a considerable extent for the less amount of seed planted at the thinner rates. There is considerable dropping off in yield from the 1-peck rate of seeding, but this is less than might have been expected. In 1911 and 1912, when yields were reduced by drought, the high - est yields were made by the 1-peck rate of seeding. It should TABLE 10. — Annual and average yields of winter wheat drilled at 5 different rates, and broadcast at one rate, on summer tilled bench land. Driller! B-nlcH, KmU of MWd'ng- prckm prr mrri Yw 4 S M.7 1»1»» 12.3 21.t 2t.l 19.9 21.» »4.1 S2.S SO.O 21.6 B0..1 tt.4 tO.S 2S.1 21.4 :i(l.!i tt.t 26.0 1».« ll.» 21.4 UN U.8 1M1 3«.8 M.7 IMt «.» 23.0 lfi year avermse I 32. 7 32.0 tl.« 32.3 t-jp«ur averacc tt.l i8j ta.4 tt.t m* ma »In 1»17 the crop wu a failure. Thl« year is counted in the an-rat In 1118 the threshing weights were inaccurate. Thin year (■■Hinted in the averages. 'Average of 2 plat*. •Yield entimated. 22.0= JO.O IMC \WI 15*10 ' ■' 1*11 Itlt l»l* 1*14 ItlS i*i« 41.1 5*.4 U.T 42.« «T.l U.» 10.2 4*.« 24.$ S2.0 41.4 ;;« 40." M.7 58.0 44J.2 Sl.l 14.C lt.l 47.8 tt.S *1.0 41.* Dm. 4Z.IC S9.4 57.1 42.0 M.5 14.7 10.7 St.l a.4 S8.0 4S.0 /*■&gt;. MJ «lJ 5C.0 S8.2 S2.7 15.4 14.8 47.8 26.9 89.0 SCO Ha. U.I 1H..-. »«.5 B.1 3S.5 U.t II.,. MM 2S.5 S2.5 S3 .3 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 25 be borne in mind that these results were secured on summer - tilled land, where conditions for germination and stooling are unusually good. It is probable, however, that under average conditions in western Nebraska as good results could be se - cured on summer-tilled land from seeding winter wheat at the rate of 3 pecks per acre as from seeding 4 or 5 pecks. Broadcasting is rarely done in general farm practice, and the method is carried in these experiments only as a demon - stration of the superiority of the press drill. The broadcast seedings were made with the drill, with the disks out of the ground. The seed was then covered with a disk. This method Table 11. — Annual and average yields of winter wheat drilled at 5 different rates and broadcast at 1 rate on disked corn bench land. LVverajfe of 2 plats. of seeding has consistently produced lower yields than drilling at the same rate. The 9-year average yield is lower than the yield from the thinnest rate of the drilled plantings. For the past 4 years, rates and methods of seeding have been made on corn stubble ground as well as on summer till - aee. The yields are given in Table 11. The results differ from those on summer tillage in that the yields are lower and there is a greater difference between the average yields made by the 5 and 4-peck rates. These tests have been carried for too short a time to make the results conclusive. Drilled B'rdeut Rmtt* of fading — peek* per mere I 4 Annual tar i !ll( !KS» •121 .._ 922 14.1 S8.« M.1 lt.4 Bm. tl.J tu 1S.7 Jin. 18.1 ».6 M.t 1».O 17.7 1O.» tt.7 17.* B«. 1S.7 27.0 UJ$ 1«.X I Bm. 19.5 25.0 18.0 ll.» Bu. 16.9 S0.8 24.4 17.0 -year averam .. 2.1.3 2».l 21.8 2U 2O.» 18.4 22.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 SPRING WHEAT COMPAKIMON Of » M. AND W1KTKB WHKAT In comparison with winter wheat, relatively small amounts tering wheat are grown in central and southwestern Ne - &amp;. The crop has some economic importance, however, chiefly for reseeding areas of winter wheat when winterkilling takes place and as a substitute for winter wheat when the acreage of the latter is reduced by unfavorable seeding condi - tions in the fall. In the northwestern part of the state, where winter wheat more frequently winterkills, spring wheat is more largely grown. A comparison between spring and win - ter wheat yields at the North Platte Station is afforded by the crops grown in the 2 rotation fields on the table land. In Fig. 2. — Spring Wheat Varieties. Field 41 there are 19 plats of spring wheat. In Field 49 there are 25 plats of winter wheat. In each field the crops are grown under various methods of seedbed preparation, the average of which is about the same for the 2 fields. The an - nual and average yields of spring and winter wheat from these 2 fields and the annual and average increases of winter wheat over spring wheat from 1912 to 1922, inclusive, are given in Table 12. The spring wheat used was Kubanka durum and the winter wheat was Turkey Red, except in 1921 and 1922 when Kanred was used. Every year except in 1917, when win- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 27 ter wheat all winterkilled, its yields were more than the spring wheat yields. For the 11-year period the spring wheat yield was but 61 per cent of the winter wheat yield. \ WtlKTIK* A few common and durum varieties of spring wheat have been grown each year since 1906. Tests from 1906 to 1912 were reported in a previous bulletin. 1 Since 1916 every fourth plat of the spring wheat variety test has been seeded with Kubanka durum as a check plat. In different years the plats have varied from one-tenth to one-half acre in size. In a few instances plats of the same variety have been grown in dupli - cate, but for the most part only 1 plat of each variety, except Kubanka durum, was grown. Yields of each variety for the years grown are given in Table 13. This table also shows the number and average yield of the Kubanka check plat each year and the annual and average yields of the durum and common variety groups. Table 14 shows the average yield of each variety for the years grown, in comparison with fhe aver - age yield of the Kubanka check plats grown nearest to it, the Table 12. — Yields of 19 plats of spring and 25 plats of winter wheat and annual and average increase of winter over spring wheat yields on table-land. ,-o.r Spring wheat Winter wheat Increase of winter wheat over sprintc wheat yields 1912 191J _ 1914 _ 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 1920 1921 1922 Bvshrlt Bu$hrlt Buxhrlt 6.4 11.4 5.0 3.2 14.4 12.2 5.9 7.6 1.7 27.1 35.6 8.5 18.2 30.7 12.5 «7 0 -8.7 5.2 8.2 3.0 15.1 21.9 6.8 17.3 28.3 11.3 9.8 22.9 13.1 4.3 13.1 8.8 I , 11-year average 10.8 17.7 «.9 'l-.ulletin No. 115. "Growing Crops in Western Nebraska." page 15. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 28 Table 13. — . ■Annual yields of Kubanka, other durum and rom- mon spring inclusive. varieties on table-land, from 1916 to 1916 1*17 1*18 1»1» IMO 1*21 1!' No. plau • T » •&gt; B« B«. /»•« Mil. ««. B*. 10.7 8.1 Ml 21.2 1S.4 /;« Kabanka a». yMd i 2».« II. i, Durum. Arnautka 17.2 Ml4 8.4 14.0 15.9 11.8 •.4 Gharnovka 20.0 M SarogaHa 18.7 11. ti 9.4 Kahla 18.4 U.I Acme 14.4 JH... ll.o 1 Pdia«icr 20.4 11.9 Monad 12.1 Av. durum. 1 18.S 10.8 9.0 I 14.2 MM 11^ 1 CuMiiii varietim Marquis lt.2 8.8 lO.i ll.ii 10.0 14.1 1 Ghirka 1C.S ».6 *&amp; 10.4 S.8 U.C Prcatoa U.8 $.7 10.5 7 1 6.7 10.0 1 1 PnM* 10J 21.8 ».l 10.« 11.7 :,.; 5.4 10.S U ».7 ■• 1 PioBcer 1».7 Hajaaa 104 8.1 GhradoB ]|j 1:1 Power 10.8 numphack KKcfcetwr Laramir «J ».l 17.« ».l II «. I.C Kate Norka -. I Red Bob* Ruby __ M II At. oommon nrictiM 15.4 8.S 8.2 in 8.7 1 'Kubanka not included. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 29 Table 14. — Summary of spring wheat variety test, showing number of years from 1916 to 1922 inclusive that each variety was grown, its average yield for the period, the (nerage yield of Kubanka durum in adjacent checks for the same years, per cent of each variety to Kubanka durum yield, averages of durum and common groups, and their percentages of the Kubanka durum yields. Av. yield of adjacent Yaan Av. yield Kubaaka Kubanka ■rown of variety check. check. Ho. Bushels Bushels Percent *UM CROP Kubanka Arnautka (•harnovka .. SaniKalla Kahla Acme Peliiwier Monad 7 I 3 3 4 i 15.0 13.0 13.1 13.2 12.8 16.3 17.2 10.9 15.1 13.6 14.1 13.6 16.7 16.7 14.4 M 96 M M M 103 76 Average durums 1 ... 2i 13.9 15.0 93 COMMON GROUP Marquis 7 Cliirka C Preston 7 Prelude 7 Pioneer C Haynes 2 Glyndon 2 Power 2 llinnpl&gt;ac'k 5 Kitchener 3 I.:ir;imie 3 Kola 2 Norka 2 Red Bobs 2 Ruby _... 1 13.0 10.5 10.6 13.6 10.3 6.0 6.9 7.1 11.4 6.1 M 6.3 5.6 11.1 14.0 14.9 87 14.8 71 14.» 71 15.0 HI 13.7 75 15.6 38 13.9 50 13.4 53 13.7 S3 1«.5 37 16.8 4n 115 56 115 4* 15.1 74 14.8 95 H — I i Av. common varieties 57 10.3 15.0 «9 •Knbanka not included. k:i </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 per cent of each variety yield to the yield of the check plats, the average yield of each group in comparison with the average yield of Kubanka, and the per cent of the yield of each group to that of Kubanka. The average yield of the durum group is greater than that of the common group each year in amounts varying from 0.8 to 12.2 bushels per acre. One of the chief reasons for the greater yields of the durum wheats is their greater resistance to rust attacks. In years when rust injury was unimportant the yields of the 2 groups were not much different. In years like 1919 and 1920, when rust injury was severe on the com - mon varieties, their yields were much below those of the durum varieties. The durum wheats cannot be milled by ordinary milling machinery. On this account they are frequently discriminated against in local markets and difficult to sell in less than car lots. They are objectionable in mixtures of winter wheat and are therefore unsuitable for use in thickening the stands of winter wheat that have partially winterkilled. For these rea - sons they should not be grown in small areas in isolated locali - ties, and care should be used in keeping the seed free from mixture with other wheats. The most promising of the common spring wheat varieties in these tests have been Marquis and Prelude, both of Can - adian origin. Marquis is a beardless wheat of high milling quality. In western Nebraska it usually does not produce a plump grain. Prelude is a very early variety and on this account is espe - cially adapted for reseeding partially killed out stands of win - ter wheat. Unfortunately it is not widely known, and the seed is not easily secured. Good yields also have been made by Humpback, but this wheat is soft in texture and of poor milling quality. It is not, however, as objectionable as are the durum wheats in mix - tures of winter wheat. II » I ■!■&gt; AND IHWr.ll OK -KCIIIM. Kubanka durum spring wheat was seeded at the rate of 5 pecks, 4 pecks, and 2 pecks per acre, for 10 years from 1907 to 1916 inclusive, and broadcast at the rate of 4 pecks per acre for 8 years. Annual and average yields are given in Table 15. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 31 The yields from drilling at the 5 and 4-peck rates are practi - cally the same, with a drop of about 25 per cent for the 2-peck rate. Broadcast seeding at 4 pecks per acre made practically the same yield as drilling at 2 pecks per acre. On account of later starting in the spring and consequently greater competi - tion with weeds, thin seedings of spring wheat have less chance of making up the thin stands by stooling, than is the case with thin seedings of winter wheat. DATKS OF M.KDIM. A test of dates of seeding spring wheat has been in pro - gress since 1909. The plan of this test is to make the first seeding as early as it is possible to get into the field in the spring and to follow this with 3 more seedings, spaced at inter- Table 15. — Annual and average yields of Kubanka durum spring wheat drilled at 3 rates for 10 years and broadcast at 1 rate for 8 years, on table-land. Drilled Broadcast 1'nte of trrriiny, p.&lt; kt prr acrr fer 5 4 2 2 4 m MM Mt 9ie .Ml .912 911 814 816 ;91« Buthrlt 28.6 32.5 22.8 2.4 0 7.4 11.6 2.5 20.9 18.2 lluthrlt 26.4 31.5 MJ 2.9 0 6.3 9.8 2.4 21.5 21.2 lUtnhiU 17.9 23.3 1 19.3 u o 4.5 4.3 .9 15.5 20.4 llimhrlM 17.0 0 0 5.0 7.0 1.8 21.2 14.9 O-yr. av 14.7 14.7 10.9 8-yr. av 10.7 11.1 8.6 8.4 'Viflll HMl . c </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 vals so as to have the last seeding done by April 30. There has been considerable variation between dates of the first seeding in different years, and in length of intervals between the different seedings. The average date of first seeding has been March 25, second seeding April 6, third seeding April 18, and last seeding April 30. The annual and average yields from each date of seeding are given in Table 12. The yield differences between the first and second seedings are not great, indicating that seedings of spring wheat made on the average by April 6 are sufficiently early to give good results. Table 16. — Annual and average yields of spring wheat seeded at U different dates each year for 14 years, from 1909 to 1922 inclusive, on bench land. Seeding dates First Second Third Fourth average average average average Average Year Mar. 25 Apr. 6 Apr. 18 Apr. 30 Hitthclt Buthilx Huthtlx Huthi In Hu*h&gt;l» 27.9 21.7 26.6 24.1 25.1 ■St-edinK* made on only two cImIik in 1912. YieldH of flmt date entered under nrnt and swund. and yield of Mecontl date entered under third and fourth date*. 909 910 1911 912 1 191S 1914 1915 1916 1917 1918 1919 1920 1921 27.9 14.6 0 6.1 4.2 4.2 12.1 20.8 15.3 12.6 14.3 22.1 10.7 4.5 21.7 12.0 0 6.1 3.2 2.8 12.2 17.8 13.4 9.5 18.4 19.8 11.0 4.1 26.6 2.4 0 4.3 1.1 6.7 10.2 9.8 7.8 7.0 10.7 13.9 8.0 2.3 24.1 M o 43 0 4.3 8.4 8.0 5.5 2.1 7.0 8.9 4.8 J.2 25.1 7.8 4.9 2.1 4.2 10.7 14.1 10.5 7.8 12.C 112 8.6 8.6 4-yr. 12.0 10.9 7« «n </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 33 There is a rapid decline in yields of the third and fourth seedings from those of the first and second seedings. The aver - age yield of the fourth seeding is only half that of the first seeding, and the average of the last 2 seedings is but 59 per cent of the average of the first and second seedings. OATS VARIETY TK8TS From 3 to 12 varieties of oats have been seeded each year under similar conditions since 1904. For the first 6 or 7 years the fields used for the tests were on the table. Since that time bench land fields have been used. The previous crop has usually been corn and the land has been prepared in the spring by disking. ' Kherson has been used for the entire period for seeding check plats, and the yields of these plats has been used as a standard by which to compare the yields of other varieties. In most cases the plats were one-half acre in size. With the exception of Kherson, one plat of each variety was usually grown. When more than one plat of a variety was grown, the yield given in the table is the average of the number grown. Table 17 shows a comparison of the annual and average yields of Kherson with 6 other early and 2 late varieties of oats. A number of varieties not shown in the table were grown for one or a few years. These were discarded because of failure to show any particular promise and their yields are not of sufficient importance to justify their publication. The yields of Kherson and the other early varieties shown in the table are very similar. Most of the differences shown are within the limits of experimental error. In the 55 com - parisons between Kherson and the 6 other early varieties, the average yield of Kherson has been 32.2 and the average yield of the other varieties 32.3 bushels per acre. Kherson and Sixty-Day mature at about the same time and are very similar in appearance except that the Sixty-Day grown in these tests has a whiter kernel. Perm is also very similar to Kherson. The Burt and June stocks used were very similar. They head and mature several days earlier than Kherson, which is sometimes an advantage in escaping droughts. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 r*E 17. — Annual yields of Kherson oats compared with yields of 6 other varieties of early and 2 varieties of late oats; average yield of each variety for the years it was grown, and average yield of Kherson for the same ■period; and per cent of each variety and group yield to that of Kherson. Early varieties Late varietin U i\ h I h I ! \u It ill Y««i« Bu. Hu. Bu. Hu. Hu. Bu. 8k. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. 1M4 1 48.0 48.0 lt«4 , 1 48.0 48.0 IMS 1 20.0 20.0 IMC 1 20.0 20.0 ».O ma ■J MM 1 47.* 47.8 1M« 1 47.0 47.8 43.3 MM 1 M.7 54.7 50.7 IMS 1 M.7 S4.7 50.7 40.7 M.1 40.7 M.I 23* 18.2 2».4 li.t t.S i.7 1" " 0 • • IMS 3 15.1 M.0 S8.2 IMS 3 js.l M.0 18.2 ■J 1*1* 2 11.1 15.» 1J.5 ltlt 2 12.1 15.» 1».5 J f.7 1" 1*11 • 0 i»n • o o Kit 4 S.5 8.8 IS. 8 Kit 4 S.5 8.8 1S.8 2.» '.I lflt 1 8.0 8.1 8.5 1»U _ i 8.0 8.1 8.S Z.« 18.4 I 19.S 2S.S 20.1 8.8 Z.« 18.4 I !».« 1(14 _ % 19.4 2S.4 28.1 1*14 J 1».4 25.4 28.1 2W.1 8.8 IMS - I 71.7 54.0 S9.2 Itlt S W.7 54.0 7S.0 To. 1 1 11.0 81.0 »1« 8 tt.5 55.1 tt.0 »1« * at.6 M.I a.0 «1.« :»8.« J7.4 IT.l «!.* 58.* J7.4 17.1 1»17 4 8.S 10.4 1»17 4 8.0 10.4 1*7 2.5 »..". 10.7 2.5 ».5 IMS 4 1X.8 , 15.5 18.0 Itll 1 4 12.8 1S.5 18.0 «.4 17.« 25.8 1.5 6.4 17.« 25.8 1.5 ltlt 1 41.0 82.4 S3.0 Itlt I 1 41.0 82.4 S3.0 40.7 41.1 15.1 20.8 40.7 41.1 l.i.l 26.8 IMt 4 4».8 51.0 4«.3 Ittt 4 4t.8 51.0 4«.3 5».7 44.3 51.11 27. S 48.3 58.7 44.3 51.11 27. 5 48.8 Ittl 8 Xt.5 28.8 88.5 lttl 8 ».S 28.8 SS..1 M.7 10.5 15.7 19.7 M.7 80.5 15.7 19. 18 12.4 11.0 14 2t.4 .'!&gt;.". ii 10 M.8 S6.3 8 :u :&lt; H. 4 42.1 I.V'J * S9.» n.i 11 S0.7 17.2 1* i 2S.7 i:..:i Variety per cent of Kheraon ■ M 100 t8 107 100 14* ! 54 : M Group per eent of Kheraon l'MI -.8 The variety tent i&gt;f l»07 waa de«tr«&gt;yed by (n-&lt;-zinu. Uicht yield* were made in the te»t of 1»22 but a xtorm mixed the varieties when in the shock and the yields could nut be u»ed. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 35 Nebraska 21 is a strain of Kherson, selected at the Ne - braska Experiment Station. In comparison with the original Kherson it is a few days later in maturity, produces slightly longer straw, and the grain has a white instead of a yellow hull. In the 3-year comparison shown in the table its yield is 5 per cent above that of the unselected Kherson. Yields of but 2 late or midseason varieties are reported. Swedish Select is about 15 days later and Silver Skin 10 days later than Kherson. The yields of these later varieties have been reduced nearly every year by heat and drought before they have had time to mature. In 23 comparisons these later varieties produced as much as Kherson only once. Swedish Select in 1913 produced more than any other variety. In 1915 when the weather was cool and moist, the average yield of the 2 late varieties was less than half of the Kherson yield. This was the result of severe rust injury and lodging, which the earlier maturing varieties largely escaped. KATK.K AND M \\\l:lc OF MIKIIIM. Kherson oats have been drilled at 4 rates, 8, 6, 4, and 2 pecks per acre, each year since 1907, and broadcast at 6 pecks per acre, beginning with 1913. These seedings have been made in the same field with the variety test. The previous crop has usually been corn, and the ground has been spring disked. Annual and average yields are given in Table 18. The results show rather conclusively that the best rate of seeding for oats is 6 pecks per acre. While the average differences in yields from the 8, 6, and 4 peck rates are not great, the con - sistency in results from year to year point to the accuracy of this conclusion. In the 14 years in which a crop was produced, the 6-peck rate outyielded the 4-peck rate 13 times and the 8-peck rate 9 times. The yield from the 6-peck rate was exceeded by that of the 2-peck rate once and equalled by it once. Thin seeding has frequently been recommended as a prac - tice under very dry conditions, the theory being that with fewer plants on the ground competition would be less severe and the chances of survival would be greater. Under the con - ditions of these tests the theory has not proved to be well founded. As a rule the higher yields have been made by the </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 thicker seeding in dry as well as in more favorable years. In 1914 the 4-peck rate yielded more than the 6-peck rate, but the yield of the 2-peck rate was very low. In 1917 the yield from the 2-peck rate was above that of either the 4 or the 6-peck rate, but all yields were very low and the difference is probably accidental rather than real. On new ground, thin seeding might prove to be an advantage in dry years, but on ground that has been farmed for a number of years weeds are apt to come up in the thinner seedings and the plants will be sub- jected to competition as severe as in the thicker seedings. Good yields were produced by broadcast seeding in 1915 and 1920. The difference in the average yields between drilling and broadcasting, however, shows the superiority of the former method. TABLE 18. — Annual and average yields of Kherson oats drilled at 4 rates for 15 years, and broadcast at 1 rate for 9 years. Drilled Brdcast Av Rate of m'nliny, peckt per acre I 6 4 6 Jin. Hii. Hit. Bu. l:u Bm l»O7 45.1 48.3 46.6 HJ 40.8 1908.— 50.9 48.8 42.6 45.8 47.0 190S „ 73.0 71.0 69.6 41.6 63.8 1910 17.0 23.0 16.9 15.2 18.0 1911 0 0 0 0 0 1911 19.0 18.3 14.4 14.0 1C.4 191J «.l 4.7 2.J 0 4.5 3.!&gt; 1914 1«2 16.7 17.2 5.6 7.6 12.7 1915 76.0 77.0 71.0 55.0 75.2 70.8 191«._ h «1.« 65.3 59.4 61.2 29.9 55.5 1917 I 8.2 5.5 4.5 7.0 7.8 C.f 1918 2.5 4.5 1.5 1.2 1.1 2.« 1919 I 26.8 34.9 28.5 32.5 23.8 29.3 ltM _ _ 52.0 52.4 44.2 37.6 53.2 47.9 1921 24.5 S0.7 26.1 30.7 27.7 27.» 15-year av 31.9 33.5 29.6 24.6 29.5 9-year av I 30.4 32.4 28.3 25.6 25.9 28.&amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 37 DATES OF »KKHIM. Yields of oats seeded on 4 different dates each year for the 14-year period from 1909 to 1922, inclusive, are given in Table 19. These seedings were made on the same dates and in the same field as the dates of seeding tests of spring wheat. The effects of seasonal variations on seedings made at differ - ent dates are apparent. The highest average yields were made by the first 2 seedings. These seedings also produced the high - est yields most frequently. In both 1909 and 1914, however, the highest yields were made by the last seeding. In the latter case the 2 earliest seedings were entire failures. Cold, dry weather retarded growth until weeds gained such a start that the weakened oat plants were unable to compete with them. As a rule, however, competition with weeds is more severe in the late than in the early seedings. Table 19. — Annual and average yields of oats seeded at 4 dif - ferent dates each year for H years, from 1909 to 1922 inclusive, on bench land. Seeding dates First Second Third Fourth average average average average Average Ye»r Mar. 25 Apr. 6 Apr. 18 Apr. 30 Buxhrln Buthrlt Buthrl* Bu*helt BuskrU 42.3 38.2 59.3 66.0 51.4 38.2 59.3 66.0 51.4 15.4 11.9 9.:; 7.7 11.0 mi 0 II II II • 22.0 22.0 21.8 15.0 20.0 10.8 .V4 1 fi .9 4.7 16.0 19.3 K.X 50.(1 50.0 40.6 35.7 44.1 1916 57.2 54.2 27.4 22.2 40.2 35.1 21.4 21.2 u 21.5 26.4 36.0 28.0 14.0 26.1 49.5 48.2 39.0 39.0 43.9 46.6 68.6 45.7 44.0 51.2 20.5 21.1 18.0 12.0 17.9 1922 10.1 12.3 120 S7 10.8 14-yr 27.6 27.8 24.3 ■M 25.1 •v. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 Not only have the early seedings produced the higher yields the greatest number of times but the quality of grain has in most cases been superior to that produced by the later seed - ings. That from the later seedings has frequently been light, with a high percentage of hulls. The results of these tests indicate that for this part of the state the chances of producing successful crops of oats may be considerably increased by seeding not much later than April 10. IJXItl.KV \ miii: in » A number of varieties of barley have been seeded in com - parative tests each year since 1909. From 2 to 6 plats of Com - mon Six-Row have been seeded each year. The average yield of these plats is used as a standard with which to compare the yields of other varieties. The plats in use were usually 2 by 40 rods, or one-half acre in area. Except in 1920 and 1921, only one plat of the varieties, other than Common Six- Row, was grown. In 1920 and 1921 two plats of each variety were grown and the yields given for those years are the aver - ages of 2 plats. The annual yields of each variety for the time it was grown are shown in Table 20. The average yield of each variety for the years it was grown, the average yield of Common Six-Row for the same years, and the per cent of each variety average yield to that of Common Six- Row are shown in Table 21. None of the varieties grown has consistently outyielded Common Six-Row. Coast, which is similar in type to Com - mon Six-Row, has a slightly higher 8-year yield average but has produced the higher yield in only 4 of the 8 years. White Smyrna, which is a 2-row type, compared very favorably with Common Six-Row for the first 2 of the 6 years it has been grown. For the past 4 years it has produced the poorer yield of the 2 varieties. Smyrna produces a plump grain free from beards. The chief objection to it is that in dry years the straw is short and very difficult to harvest. Trebi, McClymont, and Minnesota 184 are all barleys of high quality, but they have not been grown a sufficient length of time to show their yielding power in comparison with that of Common Six-Row. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 39 ?: I 1 K -° ~ II rl * a IV o J 5. rl » I a s .2 i] ii, . 1 53 is o °&gt; ° — i i a m 00 *4 Oi «-^ ■ US — I 9&gt; N I — | ■ I I «4 ; ; I^MMriW | ft H M N N C ?i : : ioooeice : doinc *4fH HfHH *|H HH :• i 5 : i i T °. n . *T °^ °J 'i *? ! SB M «nMmNN««« ' .t- : : : : : m h t- h * : : : : OQe* NNNMNH ' ' ' ' .qd : : : : : m o io h ei : : : : : ■ m j : : i ci d \a o c4 i M j* I I ! ! j i1«T«! • i • i ■ M rio : : ; : : : a&gt; &lt;■ oo : : : : C t j pje^«»&lt; _ i • • i ! t T e i lf » &lt; »:' &lt; &gt; MM! fij us •utunc ' ' ' ' ' I.o : : :o :«oo«n j I I I I I •d i i :o ioit^oci i i : Bin ■ ■ « 'nnmn Cqr-I'' rill „ oe .»;^ e i ; .:!!i!:i b^" 11 "•••mIiIIII M i^ 14 14 I ! I I 1 I I I I ! aa^'rt I \ i . tc ■»■ to i«a i i I I I i I I I I -owieooNN :::;;: : ; j j h 1 i| ULjll ill i 1 !iil!iiH22isl|| I ■ ft I I c i i i ■ I I 8 &gt; — vt o I s ~ - 1 £ . M £ -II I ° 3 - 1: - §1 it a &gt; -5 it &gt;&gt; - *&lt; II ■ V rl </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin lyy KATKM AND MANNKK OK SKI3DINU Karley has been drilled at the rate of 8, 6, and 4 pecks per for 13 years, from 1907 to 1920, with 1919 omitted, and e rate of 2 pecks per acre for the 11-year period from 1907 to 1917 inclusive. Broadcast seeding^ were made in 1908, from 1910 to 1917, inclusive, and in 1920. Annual and average yields from each rate of seeding are given in Table 22. There is very little difference between the average yields from the 6 and 8-peck rates. The yields from the 4-peck rate are close to those from the 6-peck rate, while there is a decline of about 20 per cent in the yield from the 2-peck rate. Barley, in common with the other spring grains, is unable, when seeded at less than half the optimum rate, to make up for the less number of plants by stooling. Competition with weeds TABLE 21. — Summary of barley variety test, showing the number of years from 1909 to 1922 that each variety wax grown, its average yield for the period, the average yield of Common Six-Row for the same years, and the per rent of each variety yield to that of Common Six-Row. Averaio Numb*-' Average of years yield of Variety grown variety Six-Row Buthrlt llush'lx Huxhrttt lSuthrlg Common Six-Row 12 Manchurian 2 11.8 13.8 2 11.8 13.8 8 Black 3 12.4 14.1 »s Hanna 3 6.7 12.6 Beardless fi 11.4 Hulless 2 6.7 13.8 4K Coast 8 24.9 23.8 Stavropol 9 24.6 24.0 Wls. Feed 8 22.8 ■ '« ss White Hooded 7- 23.1 26 1 &gt;&lt;&gt;» White Smyrna. _. 6 27.6 28.0 Gatami _ 2 21.6 31.1 W&gt; Trebi 2 28.0 24.8 113 Hannchen 2 26.5 24.8 107 McClymont 2 26.2 24.8 106 Minn. 184 _ 1 10.2 12.1 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 41 is more severe in the very thin seedings, and while the heads are frequently larger, the resulting yields are smaller, than those from the heavier rates of seeding. The results of the tests indicate clearly the superiority of drilling over broadcasting. TIMK OF SKKD1HG Barley has been seeded on 4 dates each year from 1909 to 1 922 inclusive, except in 1912 when but 2 seedings were made and in 1915 when 3 seedings were made. In each of these cases the yield from the first date is recorded under both the first and second dates' of seeding in Table 23. Table 22. — Annual and average yields of barley drilled at 3 rates for IS years, at U rates for 11 years, and broadcast at 1 rate for 10 years. Drilled Broadcast Rate* of teeding, peck* per acre .1.1 — T~| — « 4 2 &lt; mi :M« Mt .91* 911 .912 913 914 .915 916 917 [91« 1920 Bushrlt 40.8 25.2 17.2 7.4 0 15.8 8.0 9.9 37.4 «1.2 , 29.7 11.2 43.0 Buthrlt 40.1 27.0 19« 6.6 0 18.7 7.0 10.2 31.8 57.2 28.5 10.2 46.3 Hnxhrl-s 38.1 23.5 ICO 8.1 0 12.3 8.2 18.9 30.8 56.8 28.6 12.1 39.8 lluthilt 34.9 17.7 16.6 5.5 0 11.0 6.3 16.3 12.8 51.8 26.6 Hushclt 17.7 3.3 0 (.8 4.7 11.6 26.6 43.3 27.4 20.2 3-year average.. 1-year average.. (»-year average. 9-year average.. 23.6 22.9 23.8 21.7 23.3 22.4 23.3 20.8 22.5 21.9 22.7 20.8 18.1 16.2 16.2 15.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 The dates of seeding of barley were the same as the dates of seeding of spring wheat and oats. Omitting 1912 and 1915 when the first and second seedings were made on the same date, and 1911 when the crop was a failure, 11 comparisons remain in yields of first and second seedings. The higher yield has been made by the first seeding 8 times and by the second seeding 3 times. The 14-year aver - age gain of the first over the second seeding is 1.5 bushels per acre. The 14-year average gain of the second over the third seeding is 2.3 bushels per acre, and the 13-year average gains of the first and second seedings over the fourth seeding are 8.9 and 6.2 bushels per acre respectively. As with oats, the Table 23. — Annual and average yields of barley seeded at -4 dates each year, for 14 years, from 1909 to 1922 inclu - sive. Dates of seeding First S»tond Third Fourtl average average average average Averagi Year Mar. 25 Apr. 6 Apr. 18 Apr. 30 Buthflu I; a. sin lx IIhkIi- Is Mutlnl* Bvth 41.0 32.3 44.1' 37.4 3« 1!HI» 32.3 44.1' 374 x 1910 18.5 16.0 X !&lt; x | 13.1 1911 0 II 1912 19.6 19.6 19.8 1 1913 XT 11.8 x :; 2.4 ; x 1914 11.2 x x 11 10.1 1 1915 30.0 30.3 26.2 M 28.2 1916 32.3 31.3 21.9 163 25.4 1917 35.7 32.8 21.1 15.2 26.2 19.7 1918 14.4 19.3 15.2 17.1 1919 53.0 44.8 32.1 27.ll UH 1920 MJ 27.3 27.9 17.1 26 1921 15.3 17.8 14.8 12.8 If. 11.1 10.0 14.1 M 11 14-yr. av 23.1 21.6 19.3 lS-yr. av 2S.4 21.7 19.3 14.5 19.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 43 greatest difference between any two consecutive seedings is between the third and fourth. The time-of -seeding tests with spring grain all indicate that the chances of producing profitable crops are greatly les - sened if the seeding is delayed for more than 2 or 3 weeks after it is possible to begin field work in the spring. KMMKR Emmer was grown in comparison with barley, oats, and spring wheat for the 10-year period from 1909 to 1918 inclu - sive, and the results published in a previous bulletin. 1 Seed - ings were made at 4 dates each spring. Emmer made a poor showing in comparison with the other crops. In the 10 years its average yield of all seedings in pounds of grain was greater than that of barley once, greater than that of oats twice, and greater than that of wheat 3 times. Its average yield, based on production in pounds per acre, for the entire period was 88 per cent of the wheat yield, 63 per cent of the oats yield, and 52 per cent of the barley yield. As emmer has no special qualities which make it superior to the other grains for feed - ing or market purposes, and as the yields to be expected from it are less than those of the other grains, there seems to be no good reason for growing it. RYE Rye may be classed as a special purpose crop. Its market and feeding values are lower than those of winter wheat. On the hard lands of western Nebraska rye usually does not pro - duce as heavily as winter wheat. It is, however, much more winter hardy than winter wheat and stands pasturing better. On light or sandy soils where a heavy fall cover is necessary to prevent soil blowing, rye may be seeded with better chances of success than winter wheat. The experimental work with rye on the North Platte Sub - station has been limited. It has been grown every year as a pasture or green manure crop, but only a few crops have been harvested. A recently introduced variety known as Rosen gives promise. It seems to be somewhat less winter hardy than common rye, but it has larger heads and larger kernels ■Mebrxxka Experiment Station Bulletin 172. Spring: Grains in Western Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 and under average conditions will probably produce higher yields. In a 2-year test at this Station the average yield of Rosen Rye was 19.5 and that of Common 17.4 bushels per acre, a gain of 2.1 bushels per acre in favor of the former. As rye is an open pollinated crop it is necessary to grow any variety which is intended for seed at some distance from other varieties to prevent crossing. In Table 24 are shown the average annual yields of various crops grown on the table-land at North Platte during the pro - gress of this work. The yields shown are the average for all methods. The table offers some interesting data as to the possibilities of grain production under the conditions obtain - ing during this study. They indicate somewhat the relative TABLE 24. — The average annual yields of various crops on the table-land. Spring Wintr Corn wheat Oats Barley wheat Bu. Hit. Bu. Bu. Bu. Ton* 1910 _ 5.3 8.2 13.1 15.2 1911 6 0 1912 25.7 6.4 12.3 17.5 11.4 1913 0 3.2 0 7.9 14.4 1914 _ 4.7 5.9 8.4 V.2 1915 24.0 27.1 61.9 37.2 35.6 4.S 1916 9.7 18.2 42.1 30.9 30.7 1917 9.0 6.7 9.6 16.8 1918 22.0 5.2 8.7 10.2 8.1' 1919 34.1 15.1 39.5 34.1 L'l .&lt;» 4.4 1920 38.2 17.3 39.9 24.1 28 3 4.7 1921 _ 20.1 9.7 23.2 18.7 U I kJ 1922 33.3 4.3 16.9 12.3 13.1 3.5 Av. 16 years 18.7 12.2 24.6 20.4 12 Av. 11 yearm ■ 20.1 10.8 MM 19.9 18.5 3a 1907 20.2 24.7 31.4 37.7 5.1 1908 26.1 26.6 61.1 35.5 4.&lt; 1909 26.4 17.2 26.0 19.1 5 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 45 possibilities for various crops. Of the several crops tried, winter wheat is undoubtedly the most profitable cash crop. During the eleven years for which the record is shown, the yield has been below 10 bushels but 3 times, from 10 to 20 bushels 3 times, and above 20 bushels 5 times. Next to winter wheat, corn was the most profitable crop grown. For the 16-year period, the average yield of grain was 18.7 bushels. For the 11-year period in comparison with winter wheat the grain yield was 20.1 bushels. During the 16 years the yield was above 20 bushels 10 times and below 10 bushels 6 times. It happened that there were no inter - mediate yields between 10 and 20 bushels. From the 16-year period the average difference between the yields of corn and barley was not great. Barley outyielded corn 8 times and was outyielded by corn the same number of times. Its average yield was 93 per cent of the corn yield in pounds per acre. The preference of corn over barley for most feeding operations, the greater forage value of corn fodder over barley straw, and the additional benefits of corn on the succeeding crop place corn well above barley as a general farm crop. On the other hand, the favorable results secured with barley in some years when corn yields are low suggest its value as a supplemental feed crop. From the standpoint of cash grain value, spring wheat jffers the most opportunity of the spring grains. The yield of sorghum as feed averaged 3.2 tons per acre r the entire period. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 CLIMATIC DATA The climatic condition is an important feature in crop yields. Western Nebraska is usually spoken of as having a semiarid climate. It is probably more nearly correct to say that the climate is changeable, varying from almost humid to almost arid conditions. The rainfall and relative humidity are lower than in eastern Nebraska and consequently the rate of evaporation is higher. The lower rainfall, together with its tendency to more rapid loss, requires methods of farming that will tend to conserve the moisture. Fn order to acquaint the reader with the climatic conditions ng the process of the investigations reported in this bulle - several tables and charts are presented. Space will not permit of detailed discussion, but the rainfall and rate of evaporation of water are shown for each year under considera - tion. The rate of evaporation of water is measured from a free water surface and the same factors that tend to increase the water loss from a free water surface would also tend to increase the loss of water from the soil and the transpiration thru plants. The seasonal evaporation in comparison with the rainfall is shown in Fig. 4. It shows clearly that when the seasonal precipitation is low, as in 1910 and 1911, the rate of evapora - tion is high. There is consequently the added effect of both of these factors adverse to production. On the other hand, when the rainfall is comparatively high the rate of evapora - tion is low and conditions for production are favorable. The table showing the crop yields shows a rather close correlation between the years of low production and the years of high water dissipation. The tables giving the monthly rainfall and evaporation show clearly the wide variation from month to month in these factors. In addition to these, there is quite commonly a con - siderable variation in the local rainfall of adjacent communi - ties. For example, the rainfall records kept at the Experi - ment Station frequently show considerable variation from those in the city of North Platte. This variation is sometimes rather wide and may be either above or below, but during a period of years tends to agree quite well. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 48 ; i i I o*&gt;M*x?s.';x -nsx«»-r - x ~ x : i t. -r t. r-. -r •^ i • s — i ' M wl _ , — _ I i » •*• ~~ 1 i I -r r. l* n :i ; ; x :i r« u; us h ae u; n « * x is u: m ?i - | * &lt; 9i %o oo t™ t"" sj is j; ci oc ui ji po ci oc (© o a t» j ?i t-« ri pj ac ri « ?i •-« ?i « 'nM« "w«»-iNHi-i-ii^ci« I! 1! ! J l If 7 . - i ! Max. i:-MMT«X7. «3»£«x:«T£SN*^:i.- » ♦ » X I M - 1 - X : » M iN&gt;»i-&lt;irt23.. &gt;. r; ■» B »H '^iiiip9M»-*t^ — m « ri - ?i h^ '^•M^ri^ri^p-rc aNNSN»sis»»»x»^*»t-MnM»»-L:rjt HHfiON«l»TMTr. I"»C»X5»*5!»J, :iM»K NtonH»NXA3Hu:9«99te«ii;»p&lt;«»«tovxnu: (B " "^« ' m — ri « ri ;i » ri » — pi^i^ mn 9AA3Hxte«t-ttt*p3?i«Mt^?. :i?. .otevrsten ««H«HriNS«xn«N««N&gt;&lt;»»^:x»«x:i&gt;.-. ■; m i» x s n •■: :; x n o m m t- x j. i- m r. * » s ?. » i f MH»rt»S[-«nHf&lt;H»»O»»eltflXS»«Bh;» — i j j I j j i j 1 1 1 j 1 1 1 j 1 1 [77777771 1 1 1 1 1 j I j ! I i 1 1 j j 1 1 1 ! j 1 1 i i ! 1 1 tO(et-aOA9HMcO«U)«t««AOHNt&lt;9VO(eNXAQ^ (•t-t-t-t-XXXXXXOOXXKTlAAAAA 9: AAXdO Qeao«aoxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxT.?. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Pi lTTE 3 , i * n I pt a I ( 3 1 « &gt; 9 I h &gt; r- » « h « » « n MHNNNHHMHHitrtplCQHrifHMrHHH I i 1___ / - r. t- * : c t- :u: x y. t» ? i m n h m o ri I r - &lt; ___ «• •• MM I s L I I 5 » m i.: c » r. ; « » m » ti h « m « » » :i » 1— t _ . &lt; t 1 I S»s«ieri«t-t-N«er-Me«a«noo --3 - - c 1 r &gt; l I! i " « M rt US N H H N M ri '««C4i-ii-i ' W M M vnoQC«3ii-HOHHt-oot0anBO»Me&gt;-&lt; ■AftACHNHMianqnifleifiHoonvgooi »N»Cq«»(!lO MVM '« ' i-&lt; &lt;-i W &lt;-4 « T *. T * * • = . T =". "*. ■*? 1 * n . s . "? " 1 n , n . x . «»■♦'- '«usiflf»H •i«MMMM«MM »&gt;euiX«9;»u)h-auiHiO9i«nnnxu: 1 . ___ i M«Nxan«Mxxni-xsNuiHri»3ri fi ti ' M M M «« •• 'rtNNKrici MNNIO«S3X*SXXkm;kn«XN« — — l: f- n -■ ti y. f- m o » t « M * « * M v r-i M M M M M M l29)ISA5HXHn«H«tDHHU}XONVIfi HNqvxttNvqnxaxHKnN^ne • •• - i-i' 'i-i''' et-N3H»»a«ao«e»rtu:««t9t-go« i j I | I I I ! ! I I j I I I I I I i i ! I ! I 1 ! I I I I i I I I I I I I I a ft 3-. ff 3; J j. 3; j. a 3: X ?- j; 31 y. a 3i 3! 5i a f^ (*M I B — i i s s — 1 - E s"! hfi a g !o 8 S e hrl L_l s » rr! &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 = zae/ e/e/ 3 z 9/e/ a "3 = &amp; $&gt;/«•/ tr/€/ &amp;/6/ 2/6/ I II Is //6X R ■ t. d?/^/ t 606/ I l! I U 1 1 a a § S^*/DA// 5 o 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Sixteen Years' Grain Production at North Platte 51 Table 26. — Rate of evaporation from a free water surface, for the months of April to September April May June July Aua. Sept. Seasonal. Apr.-Sept. .907 ... 908 .... M .910 .... 911 .... 912 913 914 915 .... 91« .... 917 .... 918 .... 1919 [920 .... 1921 .... 1922 .... 6.45 6.00 4.62 7.49 5.70 4.83 6.62 5.64 6.11 4.51 4.63 4.30 4.02 3.32 4.57 4.64 6.23 6.99 7.35 5.98 7.21 7.54 6.63 6.32 5.87 6.83 5.03 7.36 6.07 4.56 6.64 6.68 7.78 6.27 6.12 9.90 12.48 7.59 9.22 8.98 6.04 6.69 7.75 8.39 6.98 6.48 7.18 8.24 7.56 7.51 7.85 9.74 9.86 8.96 10.39 10.15 6.61 10.59 10.63 8.88 9.95 8.63 10.87 7.03 7.70 6.93 8.34 7.60 7.09 7.45 11.59 9.58 5.98 7.52 7.31 8.04 7.38 7.51 8.01 8.06 7.59 8.24 6.1S 5.84 6.35 5.29 7.00 6.7C 4.87 5.94 4.90 4.86 5.7S 5.88 5.50 6.31 43.31 41.94 40.41 46.55 49.69 41.68 51.45 47.43 35.48 42.08 40.25 41.83 40.13 36.38 42.77 40.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 193 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>