<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Turkey Production</title>
               <date value="1926-07">1926-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 34 July, 1926 Revised April, 1929 Turkey Production F. E. HUSSEHL Department op Poultry Husbandry M—' H 1 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Bubb. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">'HUtS0O\ *IU_ONS t ■ I I ■ too . — «=^^^^ " ALL PbuLlfP^^' K* ~s_j*___: I «0 r—^^^^ P&lt; 1PUUNT .OM~ "j "sw .HE ~ , _. so izzZZL -~---^.§^^ — I _«■» *~'**-yj.-j— """* BEEFCATTu£~ io j —^IIZS l I I I I '000 l0»O 1900 IJio 1920 Fig. 1. — Turkey production has declined consistently since 1890 but this decline is not due to a lessened demand for turkey meat. This graph (from U. S. Dept. of Agr. Yearbook, 1924) also shows comparative, growth of other lines of animal production and increase in human population. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Turkey Production F. e. MUSSEHL 1 Like every other business turkey production has its ad - vantages and its special problems. One of the special ad - vantages of turkey production is that roast turkey enjoys an especially good popularity. For the past few years turkey meat has been reserved for holidays and special events, but with a slight reduction in price to the consumers the use of roast turkey can be increased very appreciably thruout the year. The natural popularity of this native American fowl is indicated by the fact that for the past three or four years dressed turkeys have brought from 10 to 12 cents per pound more than have high quality dressed chickens. The first essential for success in any business — a demand for its products — is therefore available for turkey growers. For a number of years, nevertheless, turkey production the country over actually declined (see Fig. 1) and only recently has the industry recovered, so that production is now increas - ing very slightly. The chief cause of the decline in turkey production during the period from 1890 to 1920 is summed up in the one word, "blackhead." Recent experimental work shows that this disease can be controlled, and if certain prin - ciples of sanitation are observed, one can expect to raise 85 per cent of the poults hatched to a profitable maturity. The costs of turkey production can furthermore be reduced by using incubators and brooders. The use of such equipment is part of the sanitation program, and also helps lower the production costs by increasing the number of poults which can be reared from each bird in the breeding flock. The experience of many successful turkey growers now clearly justifies this program for profitable production: 1. Artificial hatching. 2. Artificial brooding in clean houses with sand, gravel, concrete, or board-covered yards until poults are at least 8 weeks of age. 3. Move poults to wire-enclosed roosting sheds on clean range after they are 8 or 10 weeks old, 4. Feed complete rations with special emphasis on green feed. 5. Use every practical method of providing clean feed, clean water, and clean range conditions. If these principles are observed turkey growers can grow 85 per cent of the poults hatched, and this should be taken as the goal of achievement. 1 The cooperation of Mr. S. J. Marsden, Mr. J. Wray Taylor, and Mr. Chas. P. Jordan in carrying out parts of the observations herein reported is gratefully acknowledged. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 a~ — j»\ . i__i±±\. '\^ZP\ r^y: .Y£j=&gt; {• :\ • .*. . .. • • • Rfe Tb^^^^v^ T«" # \r P^ r77 *r r *77Z^T s&gt;^ z^\^y •*•••• " •)^Si\\ FIG. 2. — Map showing distribution of turkey production in the United States in 1920. Each dot represents 10,000 birds or major fraction thereof. Lest there be some fear that turkey production will be rapidly increased, and thus lose its economic attractiveness, let us call attention to the fact that in 1928 we produced only a few more than 4,000,000 birds in the United States. During the same year American automobile manufacturers produced 4,600,000 motor cars, most of which were absorbed by the American market. The automobile industry is still expanding on the basis of better products produced at lower prices to the consumer. Labor employed in automobile production is well rewarded, tho the number of units of labor per unit of finished product is being reduced. The same principle should, we believe, be studied and applied by turkey growers. If they are properly applied, no one need fear for the future of turkey production. HOW SHALL WE START? We have a choice in starting our turkey raising operations of either hatching eggs or buying mature stock. If good hatching eggs can be obtained from good vigorous stock this will generally be most economical. Turkey eggs sell at from 20 cents to $1.00 each and the problem will be to get them early in the season so that the poults will develop into good breeding stock for the next year's use. In Nebraska, turkeys </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Turkey Production do not generally start laying until about March 15, but if the breeders are well fed they will lay all summer and even into October. If special attention is paid to cleanliness and para - site control the poults hatched during the late summer and early fall months can be raised to marketable age, but only early-hatched poults should be used for breeders the following season. If a start is made with matured breeding stock, selection should be based mainly on health and vigor. The names of breeders having stock and eggs for sale can usually best be obtained from farm and poultry papers. Long distance ship - ment of eggs, especially, is not desirable if a good supply can be obtained nearby. For best results hatching eggs should not be over ten days old at time of setting. INCUBATION OF TURKEY EGGS Turkey eggs can be hatched with turkey hens, chicken hens, or with incubators. Artificial incubation has several ad - vantages, one being that by avoiding contact between poults and older turkeys we are less likely to have trouble with black - head. Furthermore, the time of a turkey hen is valuable from the egg-production standpoint and we can lower our egg - production costs by breaking up the turkey hens when they go broody. During the laying season of 1925 we obtained nearly 100 eggs per hen from a young turkey breeding flock at the Agricultural College. Many of these eggs were of course laid late in the season but some of the eggs laid in September were incubated and hatched poults which were sold the following February at a profit. Table 1. — Hatching record of turkey eggs — first four hatches, 1928 . - ■' (Artificial hatching) Date eggs No. eggs No. infer- No. poults Percentage hatch set set . tile hatched of all eggs set March 27 118 2 83 70.3 April 6 290 8 203 70.0 April 1G 290 11 145 50.0 April 24 434 24 .217 50.0 Total 1132 45 648 Average 57.24 Turkey eggs can be hatched in any incubator that will successfully hatch chicken eggs. Incubation requirements with respect to temperature, humidity, ventilation, and turn - ing of the eggs during incubation are the same for turkey as </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 for hen eggs. The incubation period is 28 days. Turkey eggs average slightly over 3 ounces in size so that about 125 eggs can be placed on a standard tray which will hold 180 hen eggs. Cabinet incubators are being used successfully for hatching turkey eggs, and some hatchery operators are ac - cepting eggs for hatching on a custom basis at prices ranging from 5 to 8 cents per egg. The hot weather chick boxes, which are made somewhat higher than standard chick boxes, are very satisfactory for shipping baby poults. feeding and brooding Quick, economical growth and freedom from blackhead infections will be the main consideration in feeding the poults. Chicks and poults, have much the same feed and temperature requirements. If any difference exists it is that the young poult, being even more of a high-speed organism than the chick, responds more readily when well fed and brooded and fails more promptly when certain principles are violated. The feed and brooding requirements of young chicks are discussed in Nebraska Extension Circular 1401, and exactly the same principles apply to growing poults. One item in which we have been interested especially is the re- Fig. 3. — Sour skim milk given in crock feeders which can be cleaned easily. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Turkey Production sponsiveness of young poults to direct sunshine. We have several times experimentally produced severe cases of leg weakness or "rickets" in poults by giving them rations com - plete in all respects except the anti-rachitic factor. When the rachitic poults have been exposed to direct unfiltered sun - shine for a few hours on two successive days an immediate improvement was noted and complete recovery was obtained in about five days. Egg yolk and cod liver oil furnish the vitamin " D," 'which takes the place of direct sunshine, and these feeds therefore have great value during a cloudy, rainy period when direct sunshine is not available. Fortunately Nebraska turkey raisers are blessed with an abundance of this turkey-raising essential and it should by all means be liberally used. The following feeding program has proved successful for feeding poults: J First 48 hours. — No feed. Skim milk supplid in crocks when poults are put in the brooder or placed with the hen. Second to ninth day. — One boiled infertile egg for 25 poults crumbled fine and fed on clean board or egg case top. Sprinkle a little dry mash on the crumbled egg. Feed three times daily. Give all the finely cut green alfalfa or similar 'fft* '_i7&gt;, ,-* ., .-lijj ,_^^_w^s\\r'^i j *__?$*._- 1 *j | fyJj*'iirf«'»V\* -^? , jfH \Q. .«&amp; Vy *^&gt;S^^v*y^____i^S^^&amp;&gt;^ ,^^____________-'*»JL'i*^v Fig. 4. — Young poults should have free access to a well balanced dry mash. This .simple feeder- with a lath reel helps to keep the feed clean. • i . </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 green stuff that poults will eat after third day. Feed dry mash in box or trough feeder after third day. Dry mash mixture when plenty of skim milk is available — 3 parts corn - meal, 2 parts shorts, 1 part bran, 5 pounds raw bone meal, per 95 pounds other mash ingredients. Tenth to 42nd day. — Continue hopper feeding of above mash mixture and skim milk. If milk is not available, add 15 per cent of good high grade meat scraps. Feed all the green alfalfa the poults will eat three times daily. Confine poults to sand-covered yard if possible to lessen possibility of blackhead infection. Seventh to the 20th week. — Continue hopper feeding of dry mash mixture, cutting down meat scraps to 10 per cent of total mixture. No meat scraps needed if skim milk is available. Clean range over an alfalfa field is quite ideal and will be effective in controlling grasshoppers. A clean water supply is very essential. Look upon every pond or puddle in the turkey range with great suspicion. Keeping the turkeys away from these will be better than ipecac, catechu, or other drugs given later. Twentieth week to marketing time. — Fatten turkeys on corn With an occasional feed of mash moistened with milk. Provide free access to grit and oyster shell. TOTAL FEED REQUIREMENTS A record of the feed consumption of one lot of poults raised at the Agricultural College Poultry Farm proved of consider - able interest. This lot was hatched May 13 and weights were taken and feed records kept until October 28, just a few days before November 4, when most of them were sold. At that time the lot of 93 surviving birds averaged 12.3 pounds per bird, or a total of 1,143 pounds. They had consumed 3,712 pounds of grain and mash feeds and 2,762 pounds of milk up to that time. The range during the greater share of the growing period consisted of an alfalfa field and they con - sumed large amounts of this excellent feed. Nearly all of the feed was given in hoppers, so that the labor cost of feeding was not high. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Table 2. — Turkey feed consumption record (not including green feed) Lot GX — 98 poults ', Infertile . Chick Dry Skim \ Period hen eggs scratch mash milk Green feed : — r — ■ : — - •-€ ■'.:■. Pounds Pounds Pounds __\ : : — — : : : — M WG-^ept 2 inclusive' 706.0 328 ad lib.— not we ghed O Sent 3-30 inclusive J 1040.O. 1334 ad lib— not we ghed * 401.0* B64.0 56 ad Kfc-not we.ghed Trtal 3294.2 2762 Total weight of 93 surviving turkeys on October 28 was 1143.2 pounds. • Whole yellow corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 The chick scratch referred to in Table 2 consisted of equal parts of cracked yellow corn and cracked wheat. The dry mash consisted of the following ingredients (parts by weight) : 300 pounds yellow corn 200 pounds shorts 100 pounds bran 100 pounds meat and bone meal 7 pounds granulated salt An observation of the growth rate of one lot of young poults raised at the Experiment Station also proved interest - ing. At hatching time the little fellows averaged only 1.7 ounces each, but four weeks later they averaged 12 ounces, an increase of 706 per cent. At eight weeks they weighed 34.4 ounces, which represents a gain of 287 per cent over the weight four weeks before. We must conclude from these observations that the young growing poult is a high speed animal and responds readily to good feed and care. TABLE 3. — Showing growth rate of turkeys — Lot GX Age in Average weight of 1 turkey calculated from the weights of weeks 5") Females 43 Males Average (both sexes) At hatch May 13 1.7 ounces May 13 1.8 ounces 1.7 ounces 1 May 20 3.1 ounces May 20 3.4 ounces 3.3 ounces 2 May 27 5.1 ounces j May 27 5.8 ounces 5.4 ounces 3 June 3 7.9 ounces ', June :i 0.3 ounces 8.6 ounces 4 June 10 11.0 ounces j June 10 13.0 ounces 12.0 ounces 5 June 17 15.1 ounces j June 17 16.0 ounces 15.5 ounces fi , June 24 19.2 ounces June 24 24.0 ounces 21.6 ounces 7 : July 1 25.6 ounces j July 1 32.0 ounces 28.8 ounces 8 July 8 30.4 ounces July 8 38.4 ounces 34.4 ounces 10 July 22 48.0 ounces July 22 59.2 ounces 53.0 ounces 12 Aug. 5 64.0 ounces ] Aug. 5 81.6 ounces ■ 72.8 ounces 14 , Aug. 19 86.4 ounces | Aur.19 110.4 ounces 98.4 ounces 16 Sept. 2 96.0 ounces Sept. 2 137.6 ounces 116.8 ounces 20 , Sept. 30 124.8 ounces Sep. 30 192.0 ounces 158.4 ounces 24 I Oct. 29 153.6 ounces Oct. 29 248.0 ounces 200.8 ounces i i ARTIFICIAL BROODING IS PRACTICAL We have all observed the increasing use of artificial methods of brooding chicks. Economy of labor and better control of the feed and of the environmental conditions which affect the growth and well-being of the chicks are the reasons for the growing use of artificial equipment, and for the same reasons </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Turkey Production /m^Em*^?*:.' •'•'•■ — -■ --- &gt;.r..„.LL_' __' ' -■"' ' ii"M-' "' '" \ ■■ I __W_W\w, * \l '_ '• " ■ — _■ .. ■».—.-»■,_■ . 1 1 , , - ■ , . .^j . . Fig. 5. — A double unit brooder house with graveled yards which can be used to brood poults until they are 8 weeks old. we believe that artificial brooding of poults will grow in popularity. We would not advise brooding more than a hundred poults in each unit but this number can very well be cared for in an 8 x 12 or 10 x 12 portable colony brooder house. Either oil burning or coal burning brooder stoves can be used. These brooding devices should be regulated for several days before the poults are put. in the brooder, so that a temperature of 100° F. is available at the outer edge of the hover. A strip of roofing paper or hardware cloth encircling the hover about 2 feet away from its outer edge will help to properly acquaint the poults with the environment of the brooder house during the first few days. Open the windows of the brooder house as soon as possible so the poults will obtain the benefits of direct sunshine. A small yard covered with several inches of sand or gravel will be much more practical than free range for the first 6 or ; 8 weeks. After that the range of a good alfalfa field will be quite the ideal environment.. Since chickens are known to be host to the blackhead organisms, the growing turkey flock - j should be kept entirely separate from the hens. Neither is it wise to permit poults to use range which has recently been jj used by hens, since the soil is likely to. be infected with the : | blackhead parasite. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 Fig. 6. — Half grown turkeys on alfalfa range. Nothing surpasses an alfalfa field as a range for turkeys. roosting sheds After the poults are well feathered out they can roost out - side in cheap sheds or in the trees, provided the risk from predatory animals is not too great. The saving of one or two turkeys, however, will justify a cheap roosting shed which can be closed for protection against marauders. Hq£_BB_KL1 T^_-J__W)__^_____________________iMi_i_l iff. "•V*** Z* 1 '"" **i ii ii MMM_fc^__tf_M__3M__Ej__H_tfffj_Hfi-_FBff?^^-- 'IGg?*^^^'^ 4&gt;^«x^?a&gt;ffit_!__S • i fcfe^ : II _\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\_\f__^/Im_^^ I Bftr^-_tr!?jJ'»j'it 1: '.". ■ . —.- *- . :i ' Fig. 7. — An inexpensive roosting shed 20 x 20 ft. in size arranged to ac - commodate 100 mature birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Turkey Production marketing The greatest demand for turkeys obtains at the time of the Thanksgiving and Christmas holidays. The turkey is tradi - tionally the central figure about which Thanksgiving hospi - tality is organized and if the producer has early hatched, well finished birds, ready to market at least a week before that ' time, they may well be sold at that time. Unfinished stock that will, not grade No. 1 quality should, however, not be sold at that time but should be held for the Christmas market. No standard description of No. 1 quality stock is yet avail - able, but in brief the qualities which make a dressed turkey attractive are as follows: 1. Straight keelbone and absence of other skeletal deformities., • 2. Plump carcass, well fleshed in all sections. 3. No-scabs or bruises on the carcass. 4. Well bled and dry picked. 5. Picked clean, all pinfeathers removed.. &gt; Whether to sell turkeys alive or dress them will depend on the local marketing service, distance from the final consuming market, and the availability of labor for doing the dressing on the farm. As a rule, turkey producers are not well equipped for dressing turkeys properly, nor are they always skilled in the operation. Torn skins and poor bleeding lessen the attractiveness and the market value, and consequently one should not attempt the dressing operation without a demonstration by someone who is skilled in this work. Turkeys are considered dressed for market when they have been killed and the feathers removed. They are sold to the consumer without removal of the entrails from the body. Investigational work by the U. S. Department of Agriculture shows that undrawn poultry keeps much better than does drawn poultry. • "• | .^_ ... ~t\ Fig. 8. — There is little danger of overproduction of prime well-finished . i turkeys of this type. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 Fig. 9. — A truck load of 4:12 turkeys being marketed by a Nebraska turkey grower. For dry picking, the turkeys are usually hung by their legs at a convenient height for killing. The jugular vein is cut by the single stroke of a sharp knife and the point of the knife is then pushed up thru the roof of the mouth into the brain. This last operation is known as "sticking" and when properly done paralyzes the bird and loosens the feathers so that they come out easily. Turkey feathers can be removed more easily than can chicken feathers, the proper bleeding and sticking being the most difficult part of the operation. After the feathers have been removed, the body heat should be removed. At the time most turkeys are marketed in Ne - braska, outside air temperatures at night will range from 30° to 45° F. Twenty-four hours' exposure to these tempera - tures will remove the animal heat, and this is very important. Care must be taken that the carcass does not freeze before the body heat is removed, but after the body heat is removed temperatures below freezing will do no harm. Clean barrels or boxes lined with clean paper are suitable for packing. Dressed turkeys must of course sell at a higher price per pound than live turkeys to compensate for labor and shrink - age. Shrinkage will vary somewhat, depending on the condi - tion of the birds, but will range from 12 to 14 per cent on well fattened stock. Ninety birds in one lot grown at the Agricultural College Poultry Farm totaled a live weight of 1,312 pounds, a dressed weight of 1,159 pounds, representing a dressing percentage of 88.3 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Turkey Production In some sections of Nebraska splendid marketing service has been rendered by cooperative organizations for market - ing. Assembling the turkeys of one community at a central point, grading, and then offering the graded stock to the highest bidders has proved satisfactory for producers as well as dealers. BREEDS AND BREEDING PROBLEMS . The difficulty of obtaining good hatching eggs at reason - able price" at the time they are wanted makes it imperative that nearly every turkey producer maintain his own turkey breeding flock. There is always a good demand for any sur - plus eggs which one may have, so that it will generally be better to have a breeding flock somewhat larger than neces - sary for one's own needs. The choice of a particular variety is not of so much im - portance as is the selection of good vigorous individuals within the variety. There are six standard varieties of turkeys, all of which are descended from the wild stocks which ranged over the eastern part of the United States from Maine to Florida. The standard shape and color descriptions of these are given in the "Standard of Perfection" which is pub - lished by the American Poultry Association. The standard weights of the respective varieties are given in the following table. Table 4 Is" 30 tfltll S%* wg° *§&amp; Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Bronze 36 33 25 20 16 Bourbon Red.. 30 25 20 18 14 Narragansett 30 ~ 25 20 18 14 White Holland 28 24 20 18 14 Black 27 22 18 18 12 Slate 27 22 18 18 12 For our experimental work at the Agricultural College Poultry Farm we have used the Bronze variety. This variety is probably the most popular and, as the standard weights indicate, is the largest of the standard varieties. Since </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 f J f **' g^- ii _flk_ i r^ KB f-at- ■ - '.&gt; --^St -v * . ■ :^M|ip_wggg5i^ — *■ . ■ — *^ r itB!IBy''f I -* r— ■ •■&gt;-:- -'i'- -— -^m^^-' ' ■ , \ — r t *" i "" ) f J » : i«BI^»_J_MM' ■' J I £: K--— L____ •*- — MBa _ — mZH^----^ —^4=dK^§fl ■ FlG. 10. — A house for the turkey breeding flock. A shed 16 x 16 feet in size is recommended for 36 hens and 3 males. turkeys are sold by weight, their large size is an asset. The first essentials to be looked for in selecting breeders are con - stitutional vigor and freedom from all physical defects. One of the factors affecting the cost of turkey production is the number of eggs laid by each female bird. Observations of a flock of turkey breeding birds that have been trapnested at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station indicate as great variations in egg laying ability among turkey hens as among chicken hens. Selection for productive capacity be - cause of the value of the eggs for hatching purposes is likely to be just as practical. In this respect our observation at this time has been that pullets lay much better than yearling hens. The apparent vigor of the poults hatched from pullets has been at least equal to that from the yearling hens and we do not believe there is any special disadvantage when the early hatched, rapid maturing birds of the previous year's hatch are used for breeding stock. In 1925 our breeding flock of 35 pullets averaged nearly a hundred eggs per bird thru the entire season. The egg pro - duction per month until October 1 was as follows: March, 21; April, 735; May, 507; June, 620; July, 634; August, 544; September, 263. Not all these eggs were used for hatching because many were laid after the practical hatching date had passed ; but the interesting point is that turkey females will </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Turkey Production lay more than the allotted two clutches, or 30 eggs, if en - couraged to do so. Another interesting item about this breeding flock was that a flock mating of 35 pullets with 4 toms proved very successful. The males used in the mating were raised to - gether and were placed with the flock at the same time. Sometimes the males in such flock matings fight a little, but this method of handling saves the labor which would be necessary if the males were alternated regularly. Three males for 35 hens or pullets are sufficient to insure good fer - tility. The common belief that one mating fertilizes all the eggs laid by one hen in one season is probably entirely mythical and should not be relied upon. DISEASES AND PARASITES It is not the plan in this circular to discuss turkey diseases and parasites from a detailed technical standpoint but only to mention briefly those which especially affect the manage - ment and production problems. For a more detailed discus - sion of blackhead, roup, and other troubles which affect turkeys we would refer our readers to Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 195. As was stated at the beginning of this circular, the usual reason given for the decline of turkey raising is the black - head disease. This disease is caused by a small protozoan parasite which enters the digestive system thru contaminated feed and water. Many different chemicals and drugs have been suggested, but to date no treatment has proved positively helpful in controlling this trouble. There is evi - dence, however, that a clean feed supply, a clean water sup - ply, and clean yards will vmake turkey raising quite safe, and our turkey program should be built on these essentials rather than on ipecac, catechu, or epsom salts. A few dollars spent in providing covered feed troughs and water pans will be more wisely invested than if spent for so-called blackhead "cures." We show herewith several types of feeders and watering devices, not that these are perfect but that they bring us a little nearer the goal of practical sanitation. Just how to arrive at the clean ground ideal is probably the most difficult item in our turkey program. There is consider - able evidence that the blackhead-producing parasites can live for long periods in the soil and just what policies aid in puri - fication have not yet been definitely established. Cultivation is probably helpful, especially for the heavier soils. Soil sanitation is not so difficult in those sections where the soils are light and permeable and where each rain quite definitely washes the body wastes deep down into the soil. For this </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Circular 34 reason those sections of Nebraska having light soils are splendidly adapted to turkey production. Free range over an entire township is not in itself a solu - tion of the blackhead problem, as is attested by many tm-key raisers who have glorious distances for their birds to ramble over. If all the range were equally used, the infectious ma - terial would be diluted over a great area and the risk would be reduced, but this is practically never the case and the dis - ease is picked up when the turkeys range over the soil which has been contaminated by previous contacts. The answer to this problem may vary from place to place, from farm to farm, and individual producers can best work out the most practical method of obtaining the 3 Cs of turkey success. However simple the suggestions may be, we want to stress them once again — clean feeding methods, a clean water sup - ply, and a clean range. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Turkey Production bibliography (1) Curtice, Cooper, Bulletin 123, Rhode Island Agricultural Experi - ment station, — The Rearing and Management of Turkeys. (2) Cole, L. J., and Hadley, P. B., Bulletin 141, Rhode Island Agri - cultural Experiment Station, — Blackhead in Turkeys: A Study &lt;• in Avion Coccidiosis. (3) Graybill, H. W., Bulletin 347, New Jersey Agricultural Experi - ment Station,— The Artificial Incubation and Brooding of Turkeys. (4) Fortier, Victor, Circular 30, Dominion Experimental Farms (Canada), — The Management of Turkeys. (5) Jull, M. A., and Lee, A. R., Bulletin 1409, U. S. Department of Agriculture,— Turkey Raising. (6) Van Es, L. ( and Martin, H. M., Bulletin 195, Nebraska Agricul - tural Experiment Station, — The More Important Poultry Dis - eases. (7-)" Reliable Poultry Journal, — Turkeys, Their Care and Management. (8) Lamon, H. M., and Slocum, R. R., Turkey Raising, Orange Judd Publishing Company, New York. ■ tlOM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>