<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00012">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00012</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>FORTY YEARS OF NEBRASKA AT HOME AND IN CONGRESS</title>
		             <date value="1902">1902</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-08</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">CHAPTER I. 

THE TERRITORIAL GOVERNORS. 

GOVERNOR FRANCIS BIKT. 

Aug. 2 to Oct. 1&gt;. iv',4 

Thf sad history of Governor Hurt 1 of South Carolina, tinfirst 
jrovernor of Nebraska, is soon written. He was appointed 
by President Pierce and reached the Territory at the Mission 
House at Bellevue. now of Sarpy county, on the 7th day of October. 
1S54. just four months and seven days subsequent to the 
passage of the act organizing the Territory. Coming there 
much indisposed, lie died on the 18th of the same month of his 
arrival, having taken the oath of office on the lfith of October, 
1864, and riteiag a two days" term of official life. He has been 
spoken of as "a man of stern integrity and unblemished character, 
greatly beloved by these who knew him." and in the peculiar 
terms of that day. as "an accomplished southern gentle- 

man. 

Governor Francis Burtt Ni-I.r. State Mist. Soc. l'uh.. sec. Mfiaa, I.. 35-38: first series. 

I.. «8 (hiog. fri.in .V. J'. Time. Nov. ». 1854): II.. ID. Savage anil Bell, llht. of &lt;&gt;mak». 

50. The follnwiiiK genealogy of tlir Kurt family is furnished by Mis.- Katharine Bun. 

drachter of Got. Francis Burt 

Matthew Bvrt [l&gt;. fcHan ITS-.'. MecMiahns, Ya.: in., Harwixid: after Re\ 

ulntion, moved to EdceAeld. B. C.j d., ] had 14 children: Harwood. Matthew. 
Philip, F.dward, .lohn. Francis. William, linlicrt. (iarland. Moody. Susiin. Martha, Mary. 

Ann. FbaXCH Bt'BT [b. alHiut 1774: m. Katharine Miles (dau. of Aqoibl Miles, and 

Harriit liiroud who nas dau. of .loiirdan. dan. of French Huguenot, and who 

had x children: Susan. Rebeccm, Katharine, t'amilia. Amelia, .lack. Lois. Ai|iiila): il .. 
] had ll&gt;&lt; hildren: Louis. Matthew, Oswald. Armistead. Francis. Knismus. Harriet 

F.liza. Katharine. I'amilia. FBA2ICU Bt'RT [h Jan. 13. Utf; m.. 1h:U. (ieorgiana Hall. 
JH. Qrtmt AblK&gt;tt Hall of Charleston vm of &lt;ieo A Hall and I.ois Matthews, sister 

of Mrs. Thomas Haywanl whose hu-hand was signer of Heclamtion of Independence 

and Anne lhiwson (V. Oct. B. 1774: dau. John Dnwaoa iind Joanna Mmick : descendant 
Dr. Henry Wixxlward; in., IHOti )] had six children: Frank (4. 1H30). Georgiana lln. 

William H. Dawsuii. 1»54; d. 1882 1. HaVriet Ini. I). M. Young. lWWi. AmiMead i m. 
Ijiura Rippeton. 1M7). Joanna (in. (ieorRe Roh«'rt, now decraiwd. 1879). Katharine I li. 

|H4a. lirea Macon. (!a. ). Mary (in. William A Johnston. 1871: &lt;l. 1M7»), (ieorge Al&gt;bnlt 
(•Frank": m. Minnie Nutting. 1SH1 1. 

•&gt; 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
2 

Illilin 

,„,„,,, 
ationa! 


XKKUASKA STATE II ISTi &gt;Itl&lt; AI. SOCIETY. 

tBecretty &lt;&gt;f the TerrHary, T. K. ruining, of I&lt;»wa. 
y iiKKuiiicd tin- duties of acting-governor, and bis 
ii. announcing the sorrowful death, draping tlie n 
and a])]MMiiting an ewrt, was the tirst executive </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
3 


ACTING GOVERNOR THOMAS I?. CIMINO. 
Oct. 18, 1854 to Feb. 20, 1855, and Oct. '-&gt;.-&gt;, 1857 to Jan. 12, 1858. 

kTlie first Territorial Legislature of Nebraska convened Janrj 
Hi. lS.Vi. Acting-Governor Thomas K. Cumin^ delivering 
e message. In that document he said: 

The first official act within our Territory lias been indeed 
a mournful one, the transmission to a bereaved wife and 
orphaned children in South Carolina of all that was mortal 
of your late lamented pnvernor, Francis Hurt. In his death 
you have suffered a severe loss — the loss of a man peculiarly 
qualified by his public experience and capacity, his private 
virtues, and his energy and firmness, for the satisfactory 
ami courageous discharge of his official duties. He s|»ent 
but a few weeks of suffering una| us. and his j^rave in 
a fur off State is only another tie of union between com- 

munities widely severed, who 
with fraternal pride, and to 
sympathetic sorrow. 

will revert to his memory 
his untimely decease with 

There were no unpleasant discriminations to subtract 
from the universal esteem in which his manly and amiable 
traits were held by an enlightened people; and the fact that 
South Carolina has yi\en us one of her distinguished sons, 
is accompanied upon your record by the expression of your 
undivided reaped and affection.' 

The Territory beiiifj without a system of civil or criminal law. 
ir corporations, financial institutions, or public works, as railoads, 
bridges or highways, the foundations were to be laid, 
iiul nperotraetarefl erected. In the absence of financial resources, 
appeals were Male for congressional aid. in behalf of 
he Pacific railroad, telegraph and mail facilities, a chain of 
nilitary peats for eoaiCTUt protection, and land donations for 
ill conceivable purposes 

Having hoped for the arrival of Governor Hurt's successor 
up to the meeting of the lenixlature, and not wishing to pledge 

Ci until Journal. 1st sewiou. pp. ¦*-«. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
4 


him to any sj&gt;ecitic ftUej, the Bctiag -ffwmr ieaM in brief 
a ad geaerml allusions and closed as follows: 

1 could not forbear, gentlemen, in transferring to another 
the trust reposed in me. from expressing- a pride that, our 
Territory being- thus speedily built up as another arch in 
the national fabric, your public acts and counsels will 
contribute to defend and perpetuate the I'nion and the 
((institution of the Inited States as the only sure foundation 
of our civil liberties. 1 trust that \our deliberations, 
by the blessing- of Divine Providence, may be conducted 
with efficiency and prudence, and that the most 
ardent ho]&gt;es of each one of you who have confronted the 
hardships and trials of pioneer life, may l&gt;e realized in the 
promotion of the lasting pood of our vast and promising 
young- Territory.' 

I When the 4lli Legislative Assembly convened December Stli. 
s.17. Se&lt; reiary Cuininy;. briag ajrain acting fjovernor. delivered 
message congratulatory and instructive: 

We arc assembled today under the most favorable auspiet*. 
The Territory of Nebraska has. thus far. achieved 
all that her friends could ask. Her early org-ani/at ion and 
rapid progress have signally illustrated the safety and c\- 

panshe force of the principles of the Federal compact 
from which naturally sprang- her org-anic act. 

« »n account of Nebraska's close proximity to the Ami Slavery 
strife in Kansas, where the slave jmiwci- was determined to 
¦utlironc tin* ••jM-culiar institution." and the resident citizens 
vei&gt;- ei|iially devoted to the free soil and free men. the j;overinr 
made ilie following allusions: 

Although lamentable dissensions have given to our sister 
territory a wiiler notoriety, we may well congratulate each 
other upon the verification of the political truth. "Happy 
is that |&gt;eople whose annals are tranquil." Safe, thus far. 
from the interference of reckless agitators and the mad 
Hforta of intolerant fanatics, we can furnish to the world 
an enviable proof of the legitimate effect of the genius and 
spirit of our republican institutions. 

Among his recommendations he mentioned the fact that the 

&lt; '(Hincil Journal. 1st scfttion. 12. </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

I mis of Omulia had contributed f 50,(100 to aid in completing 
'apitol building for which Congress should reimburse- them: 
that tin- government should give the territory ¦ Mrvcjrw 
ral; distribute troops along the emigrant line of travt'l; 
nak&lt;- appropriations fjop railroad construction and for Migteg 
lie river* and streams on the United States mail routes. Be 
lrew a very true picture of the evils of unrestricted and MgH 
f banking and demanded all the safeguards that pradeMC 
¦imld dictate. 

The few (lavs allowed for a MMtM of the U'jiislal lire hail 
demonstrated the fact that legal enactments were limited. MS 
fused and contradictory, and needed constant amendments and 
comparisons with the legislation of older communities. 

The thoughtful reader will understand that the laws, regulations 
and customs of a new and formative society will tie con 
stantly sujK'rseded by the progress of intellectual and physical 
development. 

This final message of (iovernor Ouming closed as follows: 

1 have thus presented to you. gentlemen, plainly ami 
hurriedlv. such consideration! as have occurred to me. un- 

certain, until the eve of your assembling, whether in my incidental 
position, such a communication would 1m- rei|iiired. 
Once l)efore we have met under similar circumstances. Since 
that initial period, the bitterness of sectional strife has l&gt;eeu 
measurably allayed. Strange faces and new interests hawtaken 
their places upon the stage and many of the actors in 
our early history have passed away, or been lost in thethrong 
of events. Men. out of repair politically and morally, 
will continue to be prostrated, one by one. and their names 
expire with the forgotten influences of the past: but our 
jKVwerful young 1 Territory will move on with augmented 
mid prevailing- force and realize, in its future fortunes, all 
that human hope or ambition can anticipate or wish. Acting 
for that Territory in a coordinate capacity, and in \iew of 
the mutations of public affairs, and in the vicissitudes of life, 
permit me to assure you. each and. all. 'hat I cherish a 
sincere desire for your success, individually, as well as in 
your endeavors to promote the public good. May no personal 
resentment or local alienations hereafter mar the 
harmony which should inspire the intercourse of the representatives 
of the government and of our people. May no </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 


boundary natural or artificial prevent the union of all our 
energies, in building np an eminent, honored and thriving 
State. Maj you Ite prospered in all your laudable aims, and 
after performing tlie hijjh (hit v of legislating for a patriotie 
and eoafldhag people, return in health to the eoniforts anil 
friendships of vour res|x&gt;ot ive homes. 

Within three months from the date of this official document 

ils author had passed from &lt; 
next Irgiriatwr. &lt;ioveriior Ki&lt;lust 
one at her brightest inte 
tainments h;xl inspired his m 
marked 0111 for him a brilliant 

¦arlh. and at I In- neetiag of tin* 
hardson said: "The Territory hM 
Heels, one whose genius and at 
any friends with hi^h hopes and 
and useful future. T. B. Cuminj;. 

Kccretiy &lt;&gt;f the Territory, has been called away forever." 1 

The legislature having referred this message to a eamUttee, 
the follow in}; report 1 was made by its &lt; hairman. Hon. K. W. 
Fiirnas. subsequently governor: 

Thomas It. ( umiii'r was appointed secretary of the Territory 
of Nebraska by Kranklin I'ierre. President of the I'niteil 
States, upon the oifr.mi/.at ion of the Territory, and entering 
at once ii|m&gt;ii the discharge of the duties of his office, he 
arrived here in the month of September. ls.*&gt;4. l!v the 
untimely decease of Governor Hurt, he Boeceeded to the 
supreme executive and became e\-ofticio Governor of Nebraska. 
How ably he tilled that office, those living can 
testify. In the organization of the first lei_nslat lire, surroundeil 
as he was In conflict inf.' elements, threatened by 
fieree contending factions, standinjr in Imminent danp-er of 
personal violence, he wavered not once in his fealty to the 
general frovermnent. nor in his fidelity to the trust reposed 
in him. Throughout the whole duration of those troublesome 
times he pursued a policy, the sagacity of which was 
proxed by its success, and the wisdom of which is evidenced 
by the present prosperous position of the Territory which 
he governed. 1'pon the resignation of OoTCTBOV 1/ard, he 
ayain assumed the executive office anil from that time till 
near his death maintained it. He has l&gt;een identified with 
the Territory ever since its organization, as one of its 
highest officers. He died with the mantle of authority still 
alM&gt;ut him. in the land which he had chosen for his own; 
in the country which he had ruled so well. He was buried 
with his honors fresh upon him; from the halls where he was 

' ( iniiK il Journal. 5th newinn. 19. 
- CuniH .lonriial. 5th m-xsiim. 30-31 </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

tt 'HIT TO T ?*t*H Cl I11IIOI1 J; i\ JWf )|lif^ TriilT M " 1 1 i^ 1 1 (("Ml Ifl 1 1O fliltl 
reverence. He WM followed to his grave by those who were 
his friends, and the soil for which he had lived and labored 
received his remains. His requiem was tolled by the silence 
of those who knew what they had lost, and 'if you seek his 
monument look around you." llesides Iwinjf for a long time 
the first executive officer of the Territory, he was in many 
respects the first man of Nebraska. And hereafter when 
th.e roll of the jrreat men of the Territory is called, and 
the name of Thomas 1!. Cnming is pronounced the first upon 
the list, let the answer 1m- as it was with the surviving comrades 
of l.a Tour. DWinerne. first grenadier of the army 
of France. "Died on the field of honor." 'The closing moments 

of an existence, checkered as his has lieen by worldly contests, 
cannot lint attract attention. His life was no holiday; 
but almost every moment of it had l&gt;een passed in the busy 
thoroughfares of the world, and when finally prostrated by 
disease, the closing acts of his public life were characterized 
with the same energy and decision which made his character 
what it was. Your committee have in this hurried manner 
discharged the duty im|&gt;osed upon them. They are conscious 
of their inability to present a report for your consideration 
commensurate with their estimation of the man. 
and their appreciation of 'Thomas I!. Curing as an executive 
officer. Your committee would close their report by expressing 
their earnest hope that here in the shadow of the 
Capitol. alMiut whose arches the spirit of the deceased may 
linper: that here the memory of those sectional disputes 
amoiifr which the latter part of his life was unavoidably 
passed, will cause this legislature to avoid them, and unite 
for the furtherance of such measures as shall be for the 

I of the whole country 

i-vcr was the pathway of a voting politician beset with 
tti j&gt;erplexities and temptations than those surioundiiifi 
list temporary executive of the Territory of Nebraska. To 
nexj&gt;ecte&lt;llv called upon to assume the duties of another, 
t-xperted to evolve a &lt;roverninent from a state of elementary 
ih. in the absence of precedents, would have required all 
aye. experience and human sagacity could have furnished, 
le it became his duty to designate the place for the assem 

legislature, the tinal i|iiestion 
representatives of the |&gt;eople: 
first meeting would have the 

Mh*g of the first session of the 
of I'apitol location was left to tht 
but inasmuch as the place &lt;&gt;f tht </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 


prestige &lt;&gt;f an incipient Capitol, his iecMon was sought in the 
spirit of desolation. What there was of sett lenient, was di 
\ ided by the l'latte River into North and South, while in the two 
antagonistic sertions. three rival towns in each were ready to 
destroy their local r— iprtilw to gain a permanent advantage. 
These were Mellevue. Omaha and Florence to the norlli. and 
riattsnioiitli. Nebraska City and Hrownville to 1 1 1«* sonth. 

Ilevtie. baring been the pine* where tin- first govern &gt;r 
d and died, and whence his acting successor issued the 
official proclamation, and possessing the most beautiful 
on. had main reasons to anticipate becoming the perma 
seat of government. 

When, therefore. Mr. Owning, baring ordered the taking of 
I census, in 1N."&gt;4. and the election of members of a legislature 
and of a delegate to Congress, appointed the assembling of the 
tiisi session for Omaha, the dans were mustered for war. In 
the absence of courts to issue the i/iid irnrnuitn or ¦wiwil, 
appeal was occasionally made to the knife and revolver, and 
under mental conditions affected by the use of money or whis 
key. Accordingly, in L858, when the location qneation was again 
revived, and Secretary Coming was once more acting-governor, 
after Governor I/.ard's resignation, a majority of the legislature 
removed to Florence. ei}rht miles Bp the river, and called apon 
him for the records in possession of the minority at Omaha. 

Before a solution of this complication was secured Gov. Kich 
ardson of Illinois arrived and. assuming control, released tin 
voang official on&lt;-(&gt; more to his original duty of secretary of tin 
Territory, which place he tilled until early in the sprin&lt;i of lv"i^ </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
TERRITORIAL GOVERNORS. 

9 

UOVKKXOK MARK \Y. IZAKl). 

Feb. 2i). ISM to Oct. M. 1 

In the illustrated history of Nebraska, a writer quoting from 
tin- Omaha Hcniltl. pro&lt; ceds as follows: "Mark W. Izard. who 
HUM into the Territory as Catted States marshal, was appointed 
successor to Governor Bint, and the ball was -riven 
in honor of his excellency." It might be liere parenthetically 
¦tated that when the governor was to read his inaugural mes 
sage he arranged it so that a negro was to announce his ;tp 
inoaih to the legislative chaml&gt;ei\ by saying, "Mr. Speaker, the 
OlWfm is now approaching"; but forgetting his text he el.-.-trifled 
the assembled wisdom with. "Mr. Speaker, de (riib'ner 
hab done come." The following is from the Herald: 

l/anl was I stately character physically: mentally, rather 
weak, and felt a lively sense of the dignity with which the 
appointment clothed him. He had never known such an 
honor before, and it bore upon him heavily. To the few persons 
who then constituted the population of the city, the 
governor was careful to intimate I desire to have his 
gubernatorial advent suitably celebrated. The factious and 
WUJ C inning suggested the idea of fltlag Izard an executive 
liall. The larger of the two rooms, which then constituted 
the building, was the theatre of a scene perhaps the most 
ludicrous that was ever witnessed in the history of public 
receptions. The room had a single coat of what was called 
plastering, composed of a frozen mixture of mud and ice, 
and a very thin coating .it that. The floor was rough and 
unplaned, and not altogether safe for those who preferred 
the upright position. It had been energetically scrubbed for 
the occasion. The nig'ht being dreadfully cold and the 
heating apparatus failing to warm the room, the water froze 
upon the floor and could not l&gt;e melted by any then known 
process. Hough cottonwood boards on either side of the 
room were substituted for chairs. The hour of seven having 
arrived, the grand company begun to assemble. Long before 
the appointed hour his Arkansas excellency appeared in 
the dancing M ;i 1 1 . He and Jim Orton and The band" of </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


Tin- vton i-riior was \er\ |xdite to .lim.and .Mm ma just "ti)fht" 
enough to l&gt;e toi icspondingly polite to the governor, while 
l/anl was the fullest of nine ladies, who were all that coulii 
Ik- mustered, even for a state occasion in Omalia. They were 
Mrs. (I. I.. Miller. Mrs. T. I!. C'uininjr. Mrs. Kenner fVrjr\isnn. 

Mrs. .I. Sterling Morton. Mrs. 
l&gt;;n iilsun. Mrs. A. .1. Hanscoin. 
S. K. lingers. Two of the ladie 
places were supplied by the &gt; 

('. li. Smith. Mrs. Fleming 
Mrs. A. I), .tones, and Mrs. 

I could not dance, and their 
nine nnmbrr of gentlemen. 

Tlie norprwir had a son by the name of .lames. He was his 
excellency's private secretary, and wishing to present a hi^rh 
example of style, he came in at a late hoar escorting Mrs. 
Davidson. His bearing was fearfully stately ami dignified. 
He wore a white vest and white kids, as any pentleman 
would do, l&gt;nt these were in rather discordant contrast 
with the surroundings, l'addock. l'oppleton. (uininfr. Smith, 
Morton. Ferguson. Goodwill, Clancy. Kolsoin. and Dr. Miller, 
liesides a larye assembly of legislators, attended. .lini Orton 
was the solitary fiddler, occupying a corner of the room. 
The dance was opened and it was a fray and festive occasion. 
During the dance several accidents happened. One lady, 
now well known in Omaha, fell flat; others ilid likewise. 
The supper came off almut midnight, ami ((insisted of coffee 
with brown suffar. lint no milk, sandwiches of a peculiar 
si/e. \erv thick, anil made up of a singular mixture of bread 
of radical complexion, and bacon. The menu was supplemented 
with dried apple pie. and there being no tables in 
those days, was passed around. The got wot having lonjf 
lived in a hot climate, stood around shivering with the cold, 
but bore himself with amiable fortitude, buoyed up with 
the honors thus showered upon him. and at the proper time., 
under a deep sense of his own consequence, made a s|&gt;eech 
returning thanks for the hijrh honor done him. 

• in the •_'((! li day of February, 1866, the successor of Governor 

Bar! lummy arrived, Secretary 

SUaiag introduced him to the 
try npeeck, which was replied 
•honors were easy." and eulo 

&lt; 

Eture in a most compliment 
a manner indicating that ' 
at par. 

M». Ci 'mim.: We eongrai ulate 
the bit— Ing of prosperity and 

you and ourselves. Sir. that 
harmony, and the frlory of 

great hopes for the future are lijrht infr up your path, which 

the vigorous arm of popular sovereignty has carxed out 

and upon which we ha\e entered. * • * We feel assured. 

Sir. that a glorious destiny will result from that manifesta- </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
11 


T 

I 


ti, 

! 

• 



ward ••in;irrli of empire": anil we rejoice in the assurance 
that you will hereafter occupy ¦ prominent place amon^r the 

Ix'nefactors of commerce, the promoters of patriotism and 
the friends of mankind.' 

&lt;&gt; which the governor replied: 

I return mv sincere thanks to you for the kind and complimentary 
manner in which you have received me. In the 
difficulties throuirh which you have passed, and the embarrassments 
which you have unavoidably encountered in the 
oriiani/ation of this now pros|ierous ;m&lt;l yrowiiijr Territory, 
I am conscious you had at heart the welfare of the 
whole Territory. I return to you my sincere thanks for the 
cordial welcome and friendly feelinir with which you have 

I feel that there is wisdom and in- 

received me 

tegrity enough here to lay the foundation for a jr&lt;n eminent. 
the blessings of which are soon to be enjoyed by a population 
unparalleled in the settlement of any country, a population 
which will rie in |M&gt;int of morals and intelliirenoe 
with any country, new or old.- 

ti*sc few iniiipliiiii'iitaiv extracts may suffice as intn 
to an official acquaintance an&lt;l a (u-elude ti&gt; tin- trover 
messap- &lt;&gt;f February -'7. 1855. which ran as follows 

The circumstances under which I make this, my first 
official communication to your honorable body, are somewhat 
|H*culiar. my arrival in the Territory Bar lag l&gt;een 
delaved by causes entirely lieyoml my control, until a late 
dav of the session. I cannot Halter myself that I am 
officially fainiliar with the progress already made, to indi- 

cate a &lt; roc of policy for the frovernment of your future 
actions, with as much clearness and precision as I could 
desire, but finding the session fast drawing to a close, and 
the more important matters of legislation which are of 
vital interest to the |&gt;eople of the Territory, yet in their 
incipient state, or wholly untouched. I feel it my duty to 
cull your attention to the subject, and recommend to 
your favorable consiilerat ion such measures as I deem Important 
for the speedv organization of the Territory, and 
future |&gt;eace and harmony of our voiiiifr and givwtag community. 


¦niiiil Journal, M srwion 

.uncil Joaraal, l*t wjoa, 7-&gt;. 7H. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 



I 111 It 11 1^ 111 t M lilt S^t ( i II IH 111 1^ llTlllltll Iti I'M 1 i il*l*?* % t \ llM 
ergaaie act, he recommended iliat the rode of Iowa for rivil and 
criminal practice he adopted, and that a general election law he 
framed, and a system of territorial revenue he established, and 
rules and regulations prescribed for defining the rights of set 
tiers under the act of Coagif . There was a most preaslag 
m-r.-ssity for the admonition against special legislation, instead 
of general laws, for all manner of peraaaa wen- \mder a frenzy 
of excitement ill order to acipiire charters for lianks. ferries and 
endless corporations, the erection of counties and location .it 
hiwns. and for the ]termanent establishment of the capital. 
whereby a tiditious value sliould at once he attached to real 
estate, and vast fortunes amassed. The legislature then in 
sion was not responsible to any settled and well defined earnsiitueiicies: 
and manv members were citi/.ens of other rt*te*. 

mere adventurers, who. being on Bttwpeetiag tours, found time 
to take part in the h'rsl organization. On the eighth day of the 
"ii. charges were made against six members of the council 
for want of citizenship, and one for being a minor, leaving six 

I MUM valid citizenship: and 
was expected before another 
us were introduced in the 
nation of the members and 

inasmuch as a large inimigra 
elect ioTi. a preamble and v&lt;--&lt;&lt; 
council suggesting a general 
a new election. 

Closing his message, the governor said 

Having tin- fullest i mUrniii in jroar wisdom, brtegritj 
;md patriotism. I invoke the Measfog of the Divine UeiiiL' 
upon youv &lt;lelil&gt;er:it ions and look forward with lively iintieipations 
for tlie result of this, the first legislative usetnlily 
of the Territory of Nebraska, to bring honor anil 
prosperity upon her people, :i"d invite our friends from 
•broad to come in and share witli us the Uaaatagl of a 

mmrnimi founded upon Hie et&lt;-rniil principles of popular 
sovereiirnty. and 1 trust that you will always find in me a 
faithful co-worker in seeking to effect these desiralile 
objects. 

1 Miring this firnt wession a report was made on the subje. 
|. inhibiting the sale of intoxicating Honors, of which two pan </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
13 

TK.lt KITOKIAI. OOVBRNOM. 

Tlmt in their opinion, where the people are pre|&gt;ared 
and public sentiment sufficiently in favor of a prohibitory 
law to fully sustain and enforce it. such a law would l&gt;e productive 
of the best results to the eommuuity. • • * As 
much, however, as we may be in favor of a prohibitory law. 
until the community by petition or otherwise, may fully 
manifest their determination to sustain such a law, it would 
be idle to enact it. 

The house of representatives having passed a dill excluding 
flee negroes from obtaining ¦ settlement in the territory, it 
\\;is finally indefinitely postponed in the council by a vote of 
7 against 4. On the l'.tth day of December. L88S, GaitlBOT I/.ard 
&lt;lelivered his second message 1 to the legislature, and as the t 
of history were few. and the realms of fiction unbounded, he 
dealt in the imaginary creations of the present and the gorgeou* 
realizations of the future. The infant territory was prosperous, 
the early organization was of bold and energetic measures, the 
principles of "popular sovereignty" vindicate&lt;l. the people 
happy in a decree heretofore unexampled, while towns and 
cities were springing up as if by magic. The capitol. for which 
lie had projected the plans, and which were worked out in detail 
by the accomplished architect of St. Louis. William Kumbold. 
would be the most imposing of buildings, and would be copied 
b\ Kansas, and admired by all master builders visiting the T.-i 
ritory. The territorial road westward to Kearney would be the 
forerunner of the l'acitic railway; and the completion of the 
surveys of government lands would supercede the term "squat 
tei ¦" and we become sovereigns of the soil. Special attention 
being given to the ordinary wants of the new community, and 
a highly colored portrait drawn of our enterprising and intelli 
gent and patriotic neighbors of the Pacific slope, he promised 
hearty co operation with the new legislature, and invoked uim.ii 
them the guidance of Divine Providence. 

On.- of the most notable acts of the body was the adoption of 
the report of the committee on codification of laws, and an effort 
to arrest the ocean tide of divorce applicants and to refer them </seg>


            <seg id="p014">
14 

NEBRASKA statk HISTORICAL BOCIBTY. 

•Xrlusivelv Id tile colitis, became a prpMing necessity. Tllr end 
if the second legislative year found a network i»f eocaotm tkfS. 
ml llif town site plats in universal existence. On the fit ti of 
aniiarv. 1857, &lt;iovernor Isard came to tlie front with his lasr 
uessap'. 1 Inn lie came ti|&gt; smiling, and his voice attuned to 
trains of congratulations. While Kansas had been desolated 
&gt;y pillage and her people murdered. Nebraska had been at 

|H-a&lt;« 

When we refect that l)ut two short years have passed 
inee Nebraska was si vast uncultivated and unsettled region. 

with scarcely a mark t&lt;i indicate that civilization had reaehed 
its harden, its present condition almost startles us with a 
conviction that the hand of niayic. rather than enterprise of 
the pioneer, has wrought the change. We can boast of a 
population of more than l.i.lMMI intelligent, orderly and 
energetic citizens, who may challenge comparison with those 
of ;inv State or Territory in the I'nion. of flourishing towns 
and prosperous cities, with their broad and beautiful 
prairies, briny thickly dotted with comfortable farm houses 

and well cultivated fields, yielding their rich treasures to 
the hand of peaceful industry, and with handsome church 
edifices, well regulated schools anil busy streets. The appreciation 
of property has far esceeded the expectations of 
the most sanguine. llusiness lots upon streets where the 
wild jrrass still flourishes are 'readily commanding from 
$."&gt;(K| to $:;.immi each, and land adjacent to our most prosperous 
towns eommanding from $M to *4nn per acre. 

El he election of ¦lames Itiichaiian to the presidency iw 
¦ded the jireat internal wan. lie saw aa evidence that 
tv agitation was settled forever, and exclaimed: 



Preparatory to the reception of the immense tide of 
immigration and wealth that is destined to flow into our Territory 
at the opening of Baring, from all sections of the 
country, it is our duty that you will adopt, at an early day. 

a wise and judicious system of legislation for the security 
of persons and property. 

The value of education, common and collegiate. rec( 


marked and extended attention, and the duty of memorializing </seg>

            <seg id="p015">

15 



GoaglCH for RTMta iif land for those pur|M&gt;ses was \ ijrunmslv 

Hciteraliiif; inaiiv foiwf recommendations, lit- closed his of 
ticial i-oiiiniuiiii-ation : 

In conclusion 1 cannot too earnestly exhort you to cultivate 
a spirit of harmony anil conciliation in your councils, 
ami I trust that uniler the wise direction of an overruling 
l'roviilence. the result of your delil&gt;eratioii may be such as 

will l&gt;est promote the future growth anil prosperity of our 
young and rising community. • 

Following the DMSMge in hot haste came a resolution for ¦ 
committee on removal of the capitol. which in two days there 
after, reported in favor of the measure, which passed the !• 
lature and in due time was vetoed bjr the governor. The insinu 
ations of undue iiiHnences in the original location at Omaha 
mre offset hy the following lanjjuap- of the veto measure: 1 

It is not pretended that a single house, or even sod shanty 
has lieen erected on the site of the proposed capital, or in 
the vicinity. It appears to Ik* a floating town, not only 

without a location, lint without inhabitant 

In regard to hanks and hanking a committee used the follow- 


We have now six hanks: add six more and we ha\e twelve, 
a hank for every thousand inhabitants. Who are the men 
who are asking for these charters'.' Are they sovereign 

sijtiatters of NrhraskaV Not at all. Most, if not alt of 
the leading men are from other states, who would Ik- very 
much obliged to us now to legislate to them the opportunity 
of filling our pocketa with their bills, hut who would laugh 
us to scorn when they had our gold and our property in 
their possession. 

The bill to incorporate the extra six met with the executive 
veto and failed to become a law. The committee to whom was 

B-ed so much of the &lt;:oveni&lt;ir's message as related to the 
on of President Muchanan. re]»orted: 

That while we have no objection to the election of .lames 
Buchanan, yet they cannot see that the rights of the South </seg>


            <seg id="p016">
16 


all 



B 


arc more secure than if John C. Fremont had been the 
fortunate candidate, neither do we think that it will be for 
the interests of the South that her peculiar institution 
should be secured to her. Seeing that with them, and all 
her superior natural :ul van tapes, a blight hangs over and 
eventually cripples and enervates all her energies. 

His last veto 1 arrested a Mil entitled. An art to repeal 
&lt; liminal laws pawed at the first session of the legislative 
semlilv." which was finally passed over the veto, and before 
rWTniag of the legislature. December !Mh. lsr&gt;7. Thomas 
&lt; 'inning was agate acting governor, due notice of which 
already lieen taken in the section concerning him. 2 

&lt; •¦iiu.il .l.nmiiil. 3rd wtmkmk, IM-IW. </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

TERRITORIAL GOVERNORS. 

Jan. 10 to Dec. 3, 1858. 

In the Directory of Congress the following appears 

William A. Richardson was born in Fayette County, Kentucky; 
graduated at the Translyvania University; studied 
law and came to the bar before attaining his twentieth 
year. He soon settled in Illinois, and in 1S35, he was elected 
state attorney; in 1836 he was elected a member of the 
legislature; in 1838 he was elected to the state senate, and 
again in 1S44 he was elected to the legislature and made 
speaker of the House. He was chosen a presidential elector 
in 1*44. In Is-m. he served as captain in the Mexican war, 
and on the battlefield of Buena Vista was promoted by the 
unanimous vota of his regiment; in 1*47 was elected a representative 
to Congress from Illinois where he continued to 

servo by re-election until ISM, when he resigned. In 1857 
he wns appointed by President Buchanan, governor of Nebraska, 
which position he resigned in 1S3S; in I860, he was, 
against his consent, re-elected to the house of representatives, 
but before the expiration of his term in 1861, was 

liosin ¦ senator in Congress from Illinois, for the un 

spiled term of his friend. S. A. Douglas, serving on the 

minittee on territories and the committee on District of 

Columbia. 

appears that Gov. W. A. Richoffice 
on or about the 12th day 
he was called upon to recogthe 
legislature then in session 
had seceded from Omaha. On 

From the- legislative recorda it 

.ml son assumed the duties of his 
of January, 1858, at which time 
nize the action of the majority of 
at Florence, to which place they 

the ground that Omaha was tin- seat of government for the territory, 
their request was promptly refused. 1 while the minority 
adjourned the legislature, on January 1(5. 1858, four days after 
his accession to power. Inasmuch as all criminal laws had been 
repealed, and a great legal confusion existed, an extra session 
cim-neel on the -2:1(1 of September. 1866, and a regular one or 

('•.unril .limrnul. till ~."i.m. llli-ll* 

&lt;;&amp;amp;lt;&gt;VKKNOK WILLIAM A. RICHARDSON. </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

NEIlRASlvA STA7 K HISTi'Itl'".\I. IMVftiTT, 

dered by law to follow it beginning October 4th, 1858. One 
brief message 1 sufficed for both sessions and also annoum e&lt;l 
the fact of the governor's resignation of his office. As a justification 
for a special session he said: 

The only law under which crime can be punished in this 
Territory is the common law of Enpland. All other criminal 
laws have been abolished by a previous legislature. The 
«ommon law of England is so uncertain and doubtful in 
reference to every proceeding- and offense and its punishment, 
that every point will have to be adjudicated before 
the courts can tell what the law is. 

As reported the territorial indebtedness was $l."i.774. and it 
was said that only five counties had paid a part of their tun, 
also that banks had failed to redeem their notes and should be 
dealt with accordingly, and that CoagreM should be memorial 
ized in aid of roads and bridges and general improvements. In 
a burst of enthusiasm never vet justified, he fancied a new El 
dorado of gold at Cherry Creek and Laramie Peak, that "should 
ghe an impetus to every branch of industry, and eventually 
make the great valley of the Missouri not only the garden Imt 
the central money power of the Union." In imagination his 
«'ars caught the thundering Union Pacific trains, and his eyai 
were gladdened by the world's commerce gliding from ocean to 
hi. But he is entitled to utter in glowing rhetoric impressions 
of the future: 

Nebraska occupies a position in the very heart of this 
jrreat republic, and as she is now the geographical center 
of the Union, so shall she soon become the commercial. 
Standinp as we do midway between the Atlantic and Pacific, 
where the wealth and commerce of both oceans shall pay 
tribute to our people, their wealth, their advancement, anil 
their power is inevitable. With a soil unsurpassed in fertility, 
and a climate whose healthful influence! are admitted 
by all, settled by a class of people whose industry, enterprise, 
and intelligence is fast converting the wilderness into 
a garden, who shall dare portray the fullness and prosperity 
of that splendid destiny which is reserved for the future 
of Nebraska. • * * </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
19 


T 


&lt; 

Mining resigned the place 1 now occupy, my official connection 
with you will soon cease; I can therefore have no 
interest, no wish and no inclination to enter into any local 
agitation. But upon the other hand, I wish in some degree 
to contribute to the advancement and improvement of the 
Territory. I shall recur with pleasure to the many kindnesses 
of the people of the Territory towards me, and 
&lt;-arry with me the recollection that I have endeavored faithfully 
to promote the public welfare. In conclusion permit 
me, to urge you, gentlemen, to discard all local feelings, all 
jealousies, and unite where interests are the same and where 
opinions cannot be divided, in passing laws so necessary 
for the interests of those you represent. I hope peace, 
concord, and harmony may characterize your deliberations: 

nd that you may so discharge your duties as to merit and 

eceive the approval of your constituents after your labors 
hall have been completed. 

In- following report 1 is a flattering testimonial of ajiprecia 
i and esteem: 

Your committee to whom was referred so much of the 
governor's messafre as relates to the resignation of his office, 
beg leave to respectfully report: (lovernor Richardson 
arrived in Nebraska on the 10th day of January last, in the 
midst of the most violent contest this Territory ever witnessed. 
He came here under an appointment of the general 
government, most fit to be made. He had stood up in 
the Congress of the United States, one of the foremost 
champions of that principle which asserts and vindicates 
the ability of the American citizen, whether a resident of 
the older or newer settlement of the country, to govern 
himself. The champion, the eloquent, powerful champion 
of natural rights of the people of Nebraska, most 
tit was it that lie should l&gt;e set over them as their governor. 
He came welcomed by the wannest enthusiasm of 
the people of the Territory. They felt, as they had 
abundant reason to feel, most grateful that a man of his 
reputation, which was national; of his abilities, which, in 
the then present exigencies of public affairs, were needed 
for the public good; of his connection, so intimate and so 
honorable, with their first history, should be sent among 
them. Open arms, warm hearts, welcomed him to this Territory. 
He has served us for nearly a year: all his wisdom, 
all his best efforts, have been ours: no personal feeling, 
ambition or pride, have e\er swayed him. Tatriotism. a </seg>


            <seg id="p020">
20 


generous regard for the highest public pood, have 
characterized his administration. The Territory of Nebraska 
stands today on a moral and legal position far 
higher, more honorable, than ever before. We have now 
a complete, wise, and well regulated system of lawe; individual 
and public rights can, and henceforth will be vindicated 
and wrong-s punished. For all this, how largely are 
we indebted to Governor Richardson, to his wholesome 
and timely advice and direction. He goes from our midst 
carrying the sincere regrets of every class of our citizens, 
that the pleasant and useful public and private relations 
which he has in so short a time so firmly established, are 
to be severed amid all the shifting scenes of life. He will 
carry with him the gratitude of this whole people for the 
great pood lie has done us and our posterity, and our 
hearty wishes for his prosperity and welfare, will attend 
him in all time to COie. 

The governor' ¦ expose &lt;&gt;f the territorial banks was ainplv 


tained by a minority report of a committee, lenimmending the 
repeal of four of their charters, while the Majority suggested the 
i«|i.al of all. unless their cases were to receive the attention of </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
21 

TKRRITOKIAL GOVERNORS. 

ACTING-GOVERNOR HON. J. STERLING MORTON 

H&lt;m. J. Sterling Morton 1 came to Bellevue, Nebraska Territory, 
November 10, 1854, and on April 12, 1853, removed to 
Nebraska City, where he established his permanent home. 

P.y the appointment of President Buchanan he became secretary 
of the Territory July 12. 1858; which office he held until 
mi. .ceded by A. S. Paddock, under the administration of Abraham 
Lincoln. At the date of his arrival, he was onlv twentytwo 
years of age, having been born in 1832. No young man 
ever cum to the territory better prepared for a useful and honoral&gt;l&lt; 
earcer. Having enjoyed the advantages of Michigan 
University, and having received his final diploma from Union 
College, New York, and being endowed with a fine command 
of language, with the fancy of a picturesque writer, and the 
aggressive style of the ready debater and orator, journalism 
and polities offered indaeeawata in the line of his capabilities 
and taste. 

Bat these acquisitions' and natural endowments were fortified, 
directed, and restrained by sound morals, high sense of 
honor and that chivalric aeaifag that charms society and makes 
home happy. As a writer on the Detroit Free I'rcxx and Chi 
Times, his contributions were highly prized, while before his appointment 
as Secretary, he was editor of the Nebraska City 
A'eir*, and in ls.V&gt; elected to the legislature. 1 hiring the Bession 
he attempted to stem the tide of wild-cat banking, which 
resulted in his defeat in the election of 1856. This was a source 

K;ret on the part of many new made friends; but the Board 
gents, members of the faculty, and many students of the 
gan University, could have said, "I told you so"; for I re- 

!i. r Morton iniiL-niti .1 fn«m St. Album, Vt . to Jefferson County. N. V.. about 
MM His son. Jaaaph I&gt; M«It— , aarinated fr.nn N Y. in Mi.hiir.in in !¦&lt;.•«. .lidiu. 

Dec. 5, 1858 to May '_&gt;. 1IM, an&lt;l Feb. 24 to May 1" </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


mi«-iiiIm-i- how the bo; si I t&gt;\ ;in excommunicated professor in 
the College, denounced all in authority, and chose expulsion 
rather than sacriajce a single com iction. In is."7 he was again 
elected to the legislature and saw at once in exploded banks 
;ind a defrauded iM-ople. evidence of the wisdom of his unrelenting 
opposition to the issue of an inflated. IrrcinVrisasli paper 
• -urielicy of JS.Vi. 

In 1S('»(I he was democratic candidate for delegate to rwgrrw 
against Samuel &lt;;. Daily, repaMieaa, and inasmuch as Hie I'.u 
&lt; hanan administration with which lie was connected, si 1 
charted with betag the hot lx*d of treasoa, and his party the 
home of traitors, in the hour of national peril no explanation 
or protestation could prevail. Kven Douglas democrats who 
approved Mr. Lincoln* war policy, could not receive absolution, 
unless the name of democrat was discarded for that of republi 
&lt;-an. Hut after the storm passed over. Mr. Itlaine, a republican 
historian, declared no man would have lamented over a dm 
trojed I'nion more than President liuchanan. In this cam 
paifni, joint discussions were held by the rival Candida i is. 
thousands of miles traveled, a few voters addressed and cabins 

and dugouts transformed into opera houses and hotels, with 
the opes prairies as an annex. No railroads or turnpikes or 
canals aided in travel, but private vehicles struggled through 
the grass, marshes and quicksands, furnishing opportunities for 
walking, wading and swimming. Patriotism was retailed at 
a premium, eloquence lavished in profusion. Yet only .Vioo 
votes were returned, of which a majority of fourteen were 
awarded Mr. Morton, but afterwards lost by a contest in &lt; "on 

I years thereafter, in 18ft, we find him a candidate for first 
rnor of the new state, against David Butler, republican. 
&lt;¦ arguments, for speedy admission as a state, were used by 
dicans, to the effect that the best government lands were 
: taken by settlement, and in a few years a new state would 
to receive an inferior grade as her donation for education 
internal improvement purposes; that the Territory could </seg>



            <seg id="p023">
23 

not draw capital to it as readily as a stato could: and that the 
¦ 
salaries named in tin- constitution to be voted upon, were so 
small the people could meet them without oppressive taxation, 
mi account of t lie enhanced value of property. 

To which it was replied that the national domain was inexhaustible, 
the salaries delusively low. and increased prosperity 
would demand ebmapoadtag expense. Republicans were intl'i 
Meed privately by the consideration that they were now in a 
majority, and state ami national patronage would be dispensed 
in their behalf. Hut democrats hoped that enough conservative 
republicans, sustaining the polk? of Andrew .lohnson. could by 

I with them capture the 
ears" delay. Accordingly 
also rated against state 
Butler a majority of 14: 

state and national offices, with a 

when they voted for Mr. Morton, 
idmission. but the returns finally 

and state admission a majority 

At the tirst election of I'nited States senators. Mr. Morton 
was a democratic candidate, receiving the full party vote, as 
against T. \V. Tipton. republican. Sixteen years thereafter, in 
1^l\ when the vote had increased from S.041 in lMt, to S7.:'.4."&gt; 
in 1880, Mr. Morton was again put forward by his party a* a 
candidate tor governor against .lames YV. Dawes. In this contest 
a majority of the votes were given to Mr. Morton and Mr. 
Ingeisol: but Mr. Itawes. having more than either of the others, 
was elected. Again in 1SS4. Mr. Morton and Mr. Dawes were op 
posing candidates, while Mr. Morton increased his vote over, that 
of two years previous from 28£f2 to 57,04, and Mr. Dawes raise. I 
his from 4:&gt;.4!t"&gt; to TtjBU and was again elected. In 1802, he once 
more carried the minoi-ity party's banner, in a contest for governor, 
and retaniBg it unsullied, re-entered the democratic 

Often called upon to act in the capacity of governor, during 
the absence of that official, and at one time for six months con 
tinuously, following the resignation of Richardson, he met the 
emergencies with promptness and efficiency. In ISo'.t. on account 
of the attack of the l'awnee Indians upon the persons and 
property of citizens of Dodge and ruining counties, he called </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 



in the shape of cavalry. 1 As a result of this appeal Lieutenant 
Robertson, V. H. Army. C«a4'g 2nd Dragoons, joined the mm 
mand under deal Thayer. which was arrow fialtfJ by 'low 
Black and staff, and overtaking the Indians in camp, received 
tWir surrender, tlie delivery up of seven of their young men. 
and pledges of future good conduct. 

In September of the same year. 1889, Secretary Morion iethr 
ered the address al the Agricultural Fair. Nebraska City, whicli 
was incorporated with the first annual report of the state society 
and entered upon the legislative records. No other citizen 
could have given such a sketch of the first five years of territorial 
life; and at no other place and time could the intellectual 
photograph have been pictured. Without agricultural data on 
which to draw, the task of "brick without straw" was re-en 
in led; and the address comes forth today, from the tomb of 
otlicial documents as history embalmed in sparkling garniture. 
We claim it as a Nebraska classic, ami have only one fear of our 
proprietary right being disputed. This arises from the fact thai 
the young orator emigrated from the state of Michigan, whose 
J'rofi-ssor. Moses Coit Tyler, in his history of ••American Lit 
erature." declared that England had a claim to our early HIgrim 
literature, inasmuch as "an Englishman undergoes no 
literary evolution by sitting down to write in America inof 
England." We set forth in our demurrer, that the Pilgrim 
eloquence was couched in ancient forms, while ours revelled in 
the fri-&lt;'dom and independence of impulses unchained, thoughts 
exuberant, and fancies born of a future of incomprehensible 

splendor. 

In introducing him, Robert W. Furnas, president of the ter 
ritorial board of agriculture, said 

Ladies and Gentlemen: I congratulate the Nebraska Territorial 
Board of Agriculture, and others who honor us with 
their presence and aid on this first effort made to hold an 

ht. State Hist. Sue. l'ub., first series. II., IM-tN, 1*1 -Mi; III.. PHM At II 
IH4 198. may be found runic* of a petition t.i Secretary Morton, tin letter af Serntary 
Morton toCol. May, a reply by l.icut. William (J. Hill, anil a list of tlie rfhara in the </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
25 


may be said of those who have ventured into this "west era 
wild," we are a feeble folk in most respects; we are, 
evertheless, enthused with "western pluck" and have "delared 
intentions" to carve out of this "New West" homes 
or ourselves as well as for those who are to come after 
s. This first effort to present "products and resources" 
s a striking evidence of this. That there is a promised 
uture for agriculture in Nebraska, and that not in the 
far distance" we have abiding faith. 

It affords me pleasure to introduce as an orator of the 
day one of the earliest of pioneers; a young man who has 
given much thought to the future possibilities of a region 
known until a recent date only as the Great American 

Desert. He will address y 
platform, a farm wagw 
native oak tree. I ask for 
attention. 

~&gt;u from the improvised rostrum- 

, placed in the shade of this 
him vour careful and considerate 

The address of Mr. Morton 

\v;ts as follows 

Mr. President and Gentlemen: Called upon to address 
"ou, the farmers of Nebraska, you, whose calling I so much 
honor and love, I was flattered, and in a moment of selfreliant 
enthusiasm. I accepted the call and have undertaken 
the duty which it impo- 

It had been my intention at first thought to gather 
ogether accurate and reliable statistics concerning the 
agricultural interests and capacities of the Territory: but 
laving made a trial at collecting data of that description, 
have given it up as impracticable from the fact that 
no regular accounts or correct statements relative to the 
jroducts and exports have been kept in any county in the 
Territory. Kven the returns of the assessors of taxes in 
the various counties as sent up to the auditor of the Territory 
are very inaccurate and convey no well defined idea 
of the amount of land in cultivation, nor any information 
upon which a reliable estimate of the capital employed in 
agriculture can bo based. I have, then, only ni.v own 
observation, dating from SowWf, lv - ,-t, together with a 
somewhat limited experience, to draw upon and can assure 
vou that such information is far less satisfactory to me 
(and probably will be to you) than statistical facts and 
figures. But such knowledge as I have concerniii4r the 
beginning and the success of farming in this territory. I 

give to you with pleasure. </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
26 


The Indian title to the Omaha ami Otoe lands, which 
comprised respectively the land lying along the Ml— null 
Kiver. north of the Great Platte, and that similarly situated 
south of the last mentioned stream, was not extinguished 
until late in the spring of 1854, and the Kansas-Nebraska 
bill did not pass the House of Representatives until the 24th 
of May of the same year, so that the season was too far 
advanced for the emigrants of that summer to put in crops, 
except in a very few instances, and T think it safe 
to say that not more than a single section of land was 
tilled in the whole Territory of Xebraska in 15.14; in fact. 
the only considerable patches of corn that I remember 
seeing that fall were riised by the Mission of liellevue. and 
by the town proprietors of Nebraska City on the town 
site. I remember that we commenced the winter of MM-'U, 
a little colony of hopeful boarders, purchasing everything 
that we ate, and even feed for our horses and cattle in the 

neighboring states of Iowa anil Missouri, and they. r\ 
liail very little to spare. 

The winter was exceedingly mild ami with the early 
spring-time came the farmers with their breaking team 
and the big plows, and the sturdy hand of industry w a 
for the first time browsing in the sunlight that gladdenei 
the beautiful prairies of our new found homes. Yet wha 
did they know of the rich soil of this untried land? It 
productiveness was to them an unsealed book. No huma 
test had ever demonstrated their worth, and yet the farme 
till Bed the heavy sod and planted his corn for the firs 
time, with an abiding faith that his labors would be ri 
warded, that li is all that he had invested in the experimen 
would be returned to him ten fold, and that his wife and 
little ones whose very lives were staked upon the soil and 
its rapacities, would be fed, dollied and cared for by the 
generous returns of the earth. The man who builds the 
first house, gathers his family around the first home fireside, 
and plants the first seed, and risks his all upon the 
first crop, in a country whose lands have been forever 
untried, and u|x&gt;n which the sluinWrs of barrenness have 
rested down unnumbered centuries, must needs be and is 
braver and grander in his heart than he who leads an army 
into a battle, and moves unawed amid the emissaries of 
death himself. 

The spring and summer of ISM were seasons of intense 
anxiety to the first tillers of the soil, but the harvishone 
propit iously and the benignant rains and the growthgiving 
dews were plenteous, and when the autumn came </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
27 


HT.-ssfiil; and to the &lt;| &lt; Nebraska ever 
be settled up? Can she ever sustain any considerable 
population?" the joyous fields of golden grain nodded an 
indisputable affirmative, and gracefully beckoned the weary 
emigrant to a home of healthfulness and abundance. The 
f.'l:i&lt;l tidings of our success in agriculture were heralded 
far and near through the medium of our pioneer press, 
ami a new impetus was thus given the emigration of that 
full mid the following spring. 1'ut beTC came also a spirit 
of evil among us. a spirit of reckless speculation, and a 
seeking for some new method to acquire wealth, some 
method which required neither mental nor manual labor. 

The legislative assembly in January. ISM, deeming it 
i ry to have more money in the country, had, very 
unwisely, concluded that the creation of banks of 
bjr special charter, would accomplish that much desired 
object. And so six banks were created, or one bank for 
Erv '&gt;&lt;IO men in the Territory, and each bank had power 
issue as many dollars of indebtedness as the circumnees 
of its individual stock-holders demanded for their 

own |&gt;ee\miarv necessities or ambitions. And what were 
the consequences? Haj; money was plenty, everybody had 
credit, and it was no heavy undertaking to secure discounts. 
Town property, though very plenty, as many, very many 
thousands of acres of land had l&gt;een planted with small oak 
stakes, were not so amazingly abundant as Fontenelle, Nemaha 
Valley &lt;.V- Western Exchange bank bills, anil, as is 
always the case in commercial matters, the scarcer article 
went up in price, and the plentier went down; that is to 
saw money was plentier than town lots, and consequently 
cheaper. And now indeed did the unsophisticated and enthusiastic 
lK-lie\c that the method of making without either 
mental or manual labor had most certainly l&gt;een invented 
and patented in and for the Territory of Nebraska. So far 
did this idea diffuse itself throughout the community, that 
it reached and took entire possession of the executive 
head of the Territory, insomuch, that in a message to the 
Legislative Assembly of the Territory, Covernor Izard mentinned, 
as an evidence of our flush prosperity, the fact that 
town lots had advanced in price, in a few months, from 
$300 to $3,000, apiece. 

t'nfortunately for the wise constructors of those patent 
Us for money making, there was no reality or soundness 
in the prosperity of that day. It did not arise, as all 
wealth and true capital must arise, from that great substratum 
of prosperity which underlies and supports the </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
28 


Yet the popular mind was apparently satisfied, and lulled 
itself into the belief that the honest art of industry and 
economy belonged to a former generation, and that here 
indeed they were certainly useless and obsolete. Who would 
bend the back, nerve the arm to labor, and sweat the brow 

in cultivating- the soil, when by the aid of a lithographer 
and the flatulent adulation of some ephemeral newspaper. 
a half section of land could be made to yield three thousand 
town lots, at an average value, prospectively, of one hundred 
dollars each? Whom could we expect to desert the elegant 
and accomplished avocation of city founder and dealer in 
real estate, for the arduous and homely duties of the 
farmer? AVe acquired great velocity and speed, in fac 
became a surpassingly "fast" people. W T e aspired at one 
to all the luxuries and refinements of older and bette 
regulated communities in the East. We emerged suddenly 
from a few rough hewn squatters, arrayed in buck-skin an&lt; 
red flannel, to a young nation of exquisite land sharks anc 
fancy speculators dressed in broad cloths. 

The greater portion of the summer of IBM was consumed 
in talking and meditating upon the prospective value of 
city property. 

Young Chicagos, increscent Xew Yorks, precocious Phila 
delphias, and infant Londons, were duly staked out, litho 
graphed, divided into shares and puffed with becomin 
unction and complaisance. The mere mention of using sue 
valuable lands for the purpose of agriculture, was con 
sidered an evidence of verdancy wholly unpardonable, am 
entirely sufficient to convict a person of old fogyism in th 
first degree. 

Farms were sadly neglected in the summer of 1856, and 
there were not as many acres planted that season, in proportion 
to the population, as there were the year before 
but the crop of town plats, town shares, town lots, am 
Nebraska bank notes, was most astonishingly abundan 
We were then very gay people; we carried a great numbe 
of very large gold watches and ponderous fob chains 
sported more fancy turn-outs, in the way of elegant car 
riages and buggies; could point to more lucky and shrew&lt; 
fellow citizens who had made a hundred thousand dollar 
in a very short time; could afford to drink more chan 
pagne, and talk and feel larger, more of consequence, ant 
by all odds richer than any yearling settlement that eve 
flourished in this vast and fast country of ours. We a 
felt as they used to print in large letters on every new town 
plat, that we were "located adjacent to the very finest 
proves of timber, surrounded by a very rich agricultural </seg>


            <seg id="p029">
29 

country, in prospective, abundantly supplied with building 
rock of the finest description, beautifully watered, and 
-sing very fine indications of lead, iron, coal, and salt 
in great abundance." In my opinion we felt richer, better, 
more niillionairish than any poor deluded mortals ever did 
before, on the same amount of moonshine and pluck. 

But the seasons were prompt in their returns, and the 
autumn winds came then as they are coming now, and 
the ripening sunbeams descended upon the earth as they do 
today; but the fields of gTain that they wandered and 
glistened among were neither as many nor as well tilled 
as they should have been. 

The fall of 1856 came and passed, and not enough had 
been raised to half supply our home wants. Town lots we 
could neither eat nor export; they were at once too expensive 
for food and too delicate for a foreign market. 
All that we had in the world to forward to the Eastern 

marts was a general assortment of town shares, ferry 
charters, and propositions for receiving money and land 
warrants to invest or locate on time. The balance of trade 
was largely against us. 

We were now, more than ever, a nation of boarders, 
eating everything eatable, buying ewiything consumable, 
but producing al&gt;solntely nothing. 

The winter of iv&gt;c; and '57 came, and the first and seiond 
days of December were most admonitory and fearful harbingers 
of suffering: they came like messengers of wrath to 
rebuke the jx-ople for the folly, the thriftlessness, and extravagance 
of the summer that had passed unheeded and 
unimproved. The storm that lashed those two days through 
and ushered in the terrible life-taking winter of that 
will never l&gt;e forgotten by those of us who were here and 

xperienced it 

Ee legislathe assembly commenced in January, 
again were the wisdom and sagacity of Solon and 
rgus called into active service. A grand rally 
had for the purpose of raising more means and more money 
by legislative legerdemain. New towns were incorporated 

and new shares issued: insuranee companies were chartered 
with nothing to insure and nothing to insure with: and, 
finally, another nest of wild eat banks was set for hatching, 
t having been deliberately deeided that the easiest way 
make money was through the agency of paper mills, en- 

gravers, and the autographs of fancy financiers. Not less 
than fifteen new banks were eonteinplated and projected. 
Preparations wen thus coolly and deliberately made for 
I sy I I I tl IT t * I" ! 1 &gt; Tfc t\ t 1 I* * 4 I* </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 


to millions of dollars, and a confiding and generous public 
were expected to receive them as money. Fortunately for 
you. for the Territory, for your reputation for sanity, the 
gTeat infliction was escaped, and out of the entire number, 
]&gt;e Soto. and the never to be forgotten Tekama, were all 
that ever saw the light; thus this second attempt to legislate 
prosperity into the country by the manufacture of an irre 
sponsitile ;md worthless currency failed most signally. It 
only fruits have lx-en seen in the thousands of worthies 
pictures which have the impress of the Tekama bank, am 
have finally exploded in the pockets of the merchant. 
mechanics, ami farmers of this territory, and thereby de 
fnuided them of some hundred thousands of dollars wort 
of capital and labor. 

In the mid-summer of 1S37, while credulous men wer 
buying town lots at enormous prices, and sapient specu 
lators were anxiously looking 1 up enough unoccupied prairi 
land to uphold a few more unnamed cities, while the ver 
shrewd and crafty operators in real estate were count in 
themselves worth as many thousand dollars as they owne&lt; 
town lots — while enthusiastic seers observed with propheti 
eye city upon city arise, and peopled with teeming- thousands 
while the public pulse was at fever heat — when the ole 
fogies themselves were l&gt;eginning to believe in the new 
way of making- money without labor, the financial horizon 
began to darken. Al once hope whispered that it was onl. 
a passing cloud, but judgment predicted a full grown storm 
And one pleasant day. when lots were high and town share 
numerous and marketable, the news came that one Thompson, 
John Thompson, had failed, and also that the hithert 
invulnerable Ohio Life &amp; Trust Company had departed it 
pecunious and opulent existence. 

The streets in cities thereabout were occupied by knots 
and groups of wise and anxious men; the matter was fully 
and thoroughly discussed and it was g-enerally conceded 
that, though it did sprinkle some, it probably would rain 
very little, if any. Bat again and again came the thunderbolts, 
and the crash of banks, and the wreck of merchants, 
and the fall of insurance companies, the decline of railroad 
stocks, the depreciation of even state stocks, and finally the 
depletion of the National Treasury. The quaking of the 
credit of all the monied institutions, in fact, of the governments 
themselves, of both the old and the new world, 
demonstrated beyond a doubt, that the storm had indeed 
t'un. and furt hermore. that it was a searching and testing 
rm. 

.lust ;i^ in roar own farm vard*. when a sudden storm of </seg>


            <seg id="p031">
31 

rain, lightning and tempest has broken out from a «ky 
almost all sunshine, von have seen the denizens of the 
piir-sty. the stables and the poultry eoops. run. jump, squeal, 
eai-kle, neigh, and bellow in their stampede for shelter; 
so vamosed the pity builders, speculators, bank direetors 
ami patent eash makers of Nebraska, while the terrible 
financial tornado of 1857 swept over the world of commerce. 

The last day of the summer of 1&lt;:&gt;7 had died out and was 
niiinlierecl upon the dial plate of the irrevocable past. The 
September sun had (Mime, glittered, warmed and ripened and 
the time of harvest had gone by. November, cold, cheerless 
an«l stormy, came on apace and wMapaiW in chilling 
accents of the approach of winter. 

It became the duty of every man to look to his pecuniarv 
ndition and to prepare well for the season of cold: and 
I examinations then made by you and all of us, proved 
is: they proved that the season of planting in 1S57. like 
it of the year previous, had slipped by almost unnoticed, 
d unimproved by a great many of the people of Nebraska. 
• had not raised enough even to eat: ami as for clothing, 
looked as though nakedness itself would stalk abroad in 
f land. 

If the great, states of Illinois and Wisconsin found themselves, 
that fall, in an almost, hopeless bankruptcy, what 
then must have been our condition? 

The irrepealable law of commerce which declares that, 
"whenever the supply of any article is greater than the 
demand, that article must decline in market value,"' was 
must clearly proven in Nebraska. The supply of town lots, 
after the monstrous monetary panic of K')7. was as large 
a- ever. There was at least one million of town lots, in 
lowns along the Missouri River, between the Kansas line 
and the J/Kau-qui-Court : but where was the demand? It had 
ceased! It had blown away in the great storm, or been 
crushed out in the great pressure. We had nothing else to 
offer for sale, except real estate, and even that of very 
doubtful character. We were yet a colony of consumers; 
we were worse off than ever: we were a nation of boarders, 
and had nothing to pay hoard with, and very little 
valuable baggage to pawn for the same. The greater number 
of our banks had exploded, and the individual liability of 
stockholders, as marked on each bill, proved to mean that 
the bill holders themselves were individually responsible 
for whatever amount they might find on hand after the 

I think we were the poorest community the sun ever 
looked down upon: that the history of new countries can </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 

Mir.liASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

fnrnisfa no parallel for utter and al)ject poverty. 1 Ix-litve 
on the first clay of January, 1858, there was not, upon an 
average, two dollars and fifty cents in c;isli tu each inhabitant 
of the Territory. Hard times were the theme 
of each and every class of society, and all depart ments of 
industry. Merchants, mechanics, speculators and bankers 
were continually lamenting their departed fortunes, and 
their many failures and losses. 

There was one class of individuals who, although thev ma 
have been sadly pinched by the pressure of times, noted n 
failures in their ranks, and who, when winter set in, wer 
comparatively well off, in fact, relatively opulent an 
luxurious in their circumstances. They were the very fe\ 
farmers who had passed through the era of speculatio 
untemptcd by the allurements thereof, they who had fa 
lowed the plow steadily, and planted their .pops caiefu.ll} 
They, and they alone, of all the people of Nebraska could 
board themselves. There is no doubt but that poverty intlinught. 
It may paraly/e the physical energies for a 
time, but it will induce reason and- reflection in the thoughtand 
judgment and discretion in the reckless, 
after all other arguments have failed. I lx-lieve that 
owing to our extreme poverty, we were led to more thinking 
and reasoning during the winter of 1857 and 1858, than up 
to that time hail ever been accomplished in the Territory. 
As you have mi your grandfather*, ll II I lag the long winter 
ewning's. &gt;it &lt;lo\wi by the large tire place wlien the huge back 
lop and biir blaze burned so brightly, away back east, somewhere, 
at your old homesteads, as when the old man, after 
reading his aewspaper, would wipe his spectacles, put them 
up by the clock on the manile piece, and seating Unwell 
there in the genial fire light, place his head between his 
hands, and his elbows on his knees, and have a good ""long 
think": just so with us all in Nebraska that winter. We had 
a "think." a long, solemn, gloomy think, and IMM| us all. 
we thought nut these facts:, that the new way of making 
money by chartering wild eat banks, had proved a BKM 
profitable delusion and an unmitigated humbug. We 
thought that building large cities without any inhabitants 
therefor, was a singularly crack-brained specimen of enterprise: 
and furthermore, that everybody could not live 
in town who lived in the Territory unless the townlaid 
off in so acre or quarter section lots. We thought, to 
sum up all hurriedh. that it was useless to attempt to legislate 
prosperity into that country: that it was i in |n is-i li!«- to 
ili into oar laps by lags! enactment : that we 
• n ¦ very fast, very reeUeaa, very bopefal, </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
33 

TEKKITOKIAI. &lt;;&amp;amp;lt;&gt;VKRXORS. 

enthusiastic Bad self-deceived people: that while we hail 
assumed to ]&gt;ln_v the |&gt;;irt of Dives, we were really letter 
fitted for the )M'rforinance of the character of I.a/arus. The 
seheine for obtaining wealth without labor, prosperity without 
industry, and gruwlag into a community of opulence 
anil ease without effort had be«a a complete failure. 

The spring of l-;,«. dawned u|M&gt;n us. and the icy hand /&gt;f 
winter relaxed its hold upon the earth, anil the prairies 
were once more clothed in sunshine and emerald. The 
result of our thinking during the long dreary winter, was 
now alHiut to Ih- eiulxMlied in active efforts to enhance our 
real pros|&gt;erity and substantial wealth. It had been fully 
and justly determined that the true grandeur and pros]&gt;erity 
of the people was concealed in their capacity for 
industry, honesty and patient endurance. If there were 
fortunes to Ik- made in Nebraska, they were to l&gt;e acquired 
by frugality and penereriag exertion alone. The soil was 
to he tilled and taxed for the support of the dwellers 
thereon; and out of it and it alone was all true and substantial 
independence to l&gt;e derived. For the first time 
during our political existence, we realized our true condition, 
and comprehended the pro|&gt;er method of ameliorating 
and improving it. The numerous signs marked "banker, 
broker, real estate dealer." etc.. bagM one by one to disfiear. 
and the shrewd and ho|iefiil gent lemen who had 
&gt;pted them were seen either departing for their old homes 
the east, or buckling on the panoply of industry, and following 
quietly the more honorable and certainly paying 
pursuit of prairie-breaking and corn-planting. The gloom 
of the long night of poverty was almut passing away forever. 
The clouds were breaking, the effulgence of a l&gt;etter 
and brighter day sent its first triad l&gt;eauis to reanimate 
and rejoice the dispirited and encourage the strong and 
ho|&gt;eful. Labor at once l&gt;egan and its hundred voices made 
Eair resonant with its homely music. All al&gt;out us. on 
rv side, the prairie plow was at work, turning over, as 
ere. the first page in the great volumes of our prosperity, 
rvwhere were brawny arms lifted up to strike the 
th. that a stream of plenty and contentment might flow 
Ih and bless the country, even as the rock itself sent up 

•red waters to quench the thirst of Israel's children when 

smote by the strength of Aaron. Kwrvwhere these rich 
and roiling' prairies which had lain for unnuml&gt;ered cen- 
Bas blank leaves in the history of the world's progress 
l&gt;einjj written upon by the hand of toil, snatched from 
Itscurity of uselessness. and forever dedicated to the 
rt of the Anglo-Saxon race. The sunshine seemed 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 

NKItKASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

brighter, and the rain and the dews more plentiful and 
refreshing, because they descended upon the earth and found 
it not all a wild and desolate waste Seed had been sown, 
farms opened and every energy had been taxed to make the 
Territory of Nebraska self —fining [1 was the first 
genuine effort in the right direction. The people were 
aroused to the fact, that agriculture, and that alone, was 
to be for many years the sole support, the sheet anchor and 
tlic salvation of the Territory. Kniulation was excited; 
each endeavored to outwork the other in the good cause. 
In many of the counties, fairs were held last fall, and agriculture 
had at last, after three years of neglect, assumed 
its true position in Nebraska. As you well remember the 
season was favorable, the crops were heavy. We ha&lt; 
enough, aye. more than enough, and the last spring- wit 
nessed the first shipment of our surplus production of grai 
to the foreign market. The first steamers that came u 
Um Missouri in T-,17. brought us corn to keep us and ou 
stock from perishing by hunger and starvation. We paid fo 
it at the rate of two dollars a bushel, lint now by tli 
energy of our farmers, Nebraska in less than two years ha&lt; 
Ix'en transformed from a consumer to a producer. And th 
steamboats of the old Missouri bore away from our shore 
in the spring of 1*39, hundreds of thousands of bushels of 
corn to the southern and eastern markets, which we did 
not need for our home use. and for which, at the rate of 4n 
cents per bushel, \\ e have taken more money than for town 
lots in the last eighteen months, or will in the next twentyfour. 
Thus Imperfectly and hurriedly I have narrated the 
history of agriculture in Nebraska, down to the planting of 
last spring's crop; what that was and how much greater the 
breadth of land cultivated than ever before, the new farms 
that met the eye on every side, and the vast fields of ripening 
grain that magically unsurpassed the place of the rank 
prairie grass, eloquently proclaimed. 

If our brief and only half-improved past has been thus encouraging 
and thus indicative of prosperity: if notwithstanding 
the mereilessness of the panic and scarcity of money, the 
present time, today, finds Nebraska richer in the true elements 
of prosperity, stronger in the golden capital of 
skillful industry and contented labor than she ever was 
before, who shall predict her future? Who shall attempt to 
portray the fulness and glory of her destiny? 

The Anglo-Saxon race are being driven by the hand of God 
across the continent of America, and are to inhabit and 
have dominion over it all. These prairies which have been </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
35 

TKUUITOKIAL (iOVKIl 

himself, are intended for the abiding' place of the pioneers 
in the progress of the world. The American Indian, in 
fin there are none of the elements of thrift, held a 
ncv upon these fertile plains for centuries; but there 
neither lalmr in his arm nor progression in his spirit. 
was an unworthy occupant of so goodly a land and he 
been supplanted. He has |MW, and his race is fast 
becoming extinct; the world is too old for its aborigines. 

Their destiny is completed; they 
fate; they must die. and a few ye 
through their history, as it was 

are journeying to their 
ars hence only be known 
recorded by the Anglo- 

eson. while he pushed them r 
¦ad. 

lefore him in his onward 

We stand today upon the very verge of civilization, riding 
up hi the head wave of American enterprise, but our descendants, 
living here a century hence, will be in the center 
of American commerce — the mid-ocean of our national greatiic-s 
and prosperity. Upon this very soil, the depth and 
richness of which is unsurpassed in the whole world, in a 
country whose mineral resources — as yet wholly undevelope 
— are certainly magnificent and exhaustless; whose 
coal beds are as extensive as its prairies; whose rivers and 
springs are as healthful as they are numerous, in such a 
country agriculture must and will carve out, for an industrious 
people, a wealth and happiness, the like of which 
the world has never dreamed of before. Manufacture and 

skill in the various arts may. and will undoubtedly aid us in 
our pursuit of a glorious and independent opulence, but our 

real trust and strong hope is still hidden in the fertility 

of our soil and its adaptation to general cultivation. The 
agriculturist may l&gt;e proud of his calling for in it he i» 
independent: in it there is no possibility of guile or fraud, 
and for his partners in lal&gt;or God has sent him the genial 

sunshine, gentle rains and the softly descending dews. The 
very elements are made his assistants and co-workers; the 
thunderbolt that purities the atmosphere and furnishes 
electric life to the growing crops, is his friend and his 
helper. It may be urged, and often is, that the calling 
of the farmer is an arduous and homely one, — that i 
is arduous no one can deny, but it is honorable 
The idea that a man cannot be a true gentleman am 
labor with his hands, is an obsolete, a dead and dis 
honored dogma. All labor is honorable. The schola 
in his study, the chemist in his laboratory, the artist i 
iilio. the lawyer at his brief, and the preacher at hi 
sermon, are all of them nothing more, nothing less, tha 
, I , r|iri . ¦ ., thp world's workshop workers with til </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 



head. Ami the smith at his forge, the earsieater at liis 
ImmhIi. mechanics anil artisans of every grade ami kind, and 
tin- fanner, are Ihe same laborers workers with the hand. 

The two classes represent the two divisions of lalmr. and 
they are mutually de|&gt;endent n|&gt;on each otlier. lint if 
amim&lt;_ r them all there is one art more health-jfiviiiL 
art more tilled with quiet and honest eoutentinent. than 
another it is that of agriculture. i And yet agriculture, 
although it is the art support ive of all arts, although it is 
the hasis ami foundation ujion which the supers! ructure 
tall the commerce of the world is reared, is less studied. 
I thought of. and more remote from its perfeetion than 
others. 

During ihe last tell years it has. however, lx'fjun to attrart 
a greater decree of attention and has taken a few 
steps towards that high place in the world's business which 
await- it. The enmity, state, and national fairs, which 
sire now proven so useful, are the protrarteil meetings of 
husbandmen, where agricultural revivals are initiated and 
thousands annually converted to the faith of the 
church of human industry. And this is the first revival of 
the kind ever inst it uted in a territory. To Nebraska 1m&gt;toagfl 
the honor and the good name of having placed a 
bright and worthy example In-fore the sisterhood of children 
States which iMMind her on the south and west. Let 
u- continue in the (food work: let every heart's aspiration, 
•¦wry thought and effort Ih* to make each succeeilinjj; fair 
&gt;.'ive better and »t longer teatl— oaj in favor of the resources 
and wealth of our vast and beautiful domain. 

And while in the east the youth are being prepared for 
the so-called learned professions, law. divinity, and niedi- 
E\ let us 1m- content to rear up a nation of enlighi 
iculturists. Men sturdy in mind and thought e\en as 
y are robust in body and active in all that |x-rtains 
to the lull development and perfection of the pi 

system of mankind, let it lx&gt; our high aim. l).v our enlightened 
and well-directed training of both the body anil 
the mind, to elevate and improve our race and make the 
western man the model, both physical and intellectual, 
from which all the world may be happy to make COB 

With such an ambition in the minds of the people, and 
an energy to gratify it. the future of this commonwealth 
is such a one as thrills the patriot's heart with gimtefsd 
pride, and makes one sad to think that death may close 
Eeve before it shall have rested u|m&gt;ii the beauties "f 
(iarden State that will have been builded up on these </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
37 


I 






two Neinahas. shall be -.horn of their native wildness ;¦ rid 
Ik- resonant with the snnjr of the husbandman. 1 he rumble 
of mills, the splash of the paddle wheel and the puff of 
the steam engine: when away out upon those undulating 
plains, whose primeval stillness is now unbroken. sa\e by 
the how I of the wolf, or the wind sighing through the 
rank prairie pw, the Ameriean citizen shall lime huilded 
¦ 1 1 &gt; homes, hamlets and villages: when the steam plow, 
with its lun^s of tire and breath of vapor, shall have sailed 

over the irreat land-ocean that stretches its luxuriant waves 
of soil from the western bank of the Missouri to the base 

of the Itoeky Mountains, leaving in its wake thrifty settlements 
and thriving villages, as naturally as a ship riding 

upon a sea leaves the eddy and the foam sparkling in the 
¦untight thai irilils its path through the waste of waters. 

When, only fifty miles westward from the Missouri Kiver, 
the stronff saline waters of Nebraska shall have arrested 
the attention of thi' capitalist, and attracted the skill of the 
manufacturer anil shall have l&gt;ecotne. as it must anil will. 
tin' salt producer of the whole northwest; when the rockribbed 
mountain* that form our western boundary shall 
have been compelled to up to mankind their loniy- 

when afar off up the winding 
the antelo|K&gt;. the buffalo and 
¦tart led by the scream of the 
mil rumbles over the prairies 

hidden and golden treasure? 
channel o.f the irreat I'latH 
the Indian shall have I n 
locomotive car. as it roars 

and the mountains, hastening to unite the states of the 
Atlantic and Pacific into a unity and fraternity of interests, 
a future greater and brighter than words can pictnre is to 

achieved, and you. the farmers of Nebraska, are its 

prime architects and its master workmen 

Be inspired then to hasten the earring out of that destiny 
of indisputable superiority which Cod has assigned the 
American people: anil, so inspired and so laboring in the 

greal Held of the world's advancement, when death, that 
harvester whom no seasons control and no laws restrain. 

gathers you to his dark and noiseless gamer, may you ffo. 
like the grain that has thrived and ripened in the brightest 

sunshine, pure and untainted by the mildews of the world, 
back to Him who planted mortality on the earth, that Im- 

iii&lt;1 aaintrtd and loved ii» 

mortality might be reaped 

flis M^iiiii 1 1 iit;i I address \v;is no sporadic effort, but the 
rcincnt of a devotion to the tillage of tlie soil, to tin 
. f * f H -1 i- ill w &gt;nwl t I- • • ¦ *l ilevot ion W'llii-ll I* </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 


Eated in the rural decoration of Arbor Lodge, the presentation 
f a beautiful park 1&lt;&gt; Nebraska City, and to the association of 
is name with Arbor Day triumphs and its beneficent results. 

ARBOR DAY 

In the preface to a book entitled "Arbor Day," which &lt;!ov. R. 
"NY. Furnas dedicated to the Horn. -7. Sterling Morton, we have 

&lt;he followin 

and a farm library of twenty-live dollars" worth of books to 

to be known as Arbor Day 
vision was incorporated in tl 
ons legal enactments. 

In aid of the object a Jin 

state ( 

Within two months of the public observance of the tiist Arbor 
Day the lion. P. W. Hitchcock was instrumental in passing 
through the United States senate a bill "To encourage the 
growth of timber on the western prairies," the beneficent operation 
of which continued for twenty two years. Within the 
space of sixteen yean Arbor Day was observed in twenty- 

Perhaps no observani rer sprang so suddenly and al- 

most universally into usi' in the higher ranka of life 

ns thai of Arbor Dny. The name itself attracts, and at 

iinc-r secures fast hold on refined, intelligent people. The 
thought originated with one who worships ;it the shrine of 

home and its endearing relations. A resolution providing 

Hint "Wednesday, the Kith of April, 1872, be and the same 

is hereby set apart and consecrated for tree planting in 
the state of Nebraska, and the State Board of Agriculture 

hereby name it Arbor Day. and to urge upon the people 
of the State the vital importance of tree planting, hereby 
offer a special premium of one hundred dollars to the agri- 

cultural society of that county of Nebraska which shall. 

upon that day. plant properly the largest Bomber of trees: 

11 

thai peraon wfco, on i hat day. shall plan! property in Ne- 

braska the greatest number of trees," was unanimously 

tdoptfd In tin' State Hoard of Agriculture on motion of 

Hon. .1. Sterling Morion. January 4. 1872. 

On tin' day specified in tlie resolution, the people re- 
sponded by planting 1,000,000 trees and. repeated the same 

in 1873. Supplementing the State Board, &lt;¦&lt;&gt;'¦. Furnas issued 

ii proclamation March 31, W4. and in I88S the legislature 

made the -.'rind of April, Mr. Morton's birthday, a holiday. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
TERRITORIAL GOVERNOR 

39 

¦era &lt; &gt;f the States and three of the Territories. Editor H. 
L \\ odd. of the Nebraska city Daily I'nxs, having cone 
the happy idea of issuing an Arbor I »a y edition of his paper, 
received congratulatory responses from inan.v distinguished 
citizens. From .lames Kussell Lowell, poet and diplomatisi 
: "I am glad to join in tliis tribute of friendly gratitude 
to the inveiiLor of Arbor Kay." From George II. Hioker, of 
Philadelphia: "I beg to join with you all in the eoagratslai 
that may l&gt;e offered to this friend- of humanity on his birthday, 
which was a happy day for the world into which he was born." 
From the brilliant author. I. .1. Headly: "All honor to the 
founder of Arbor Kay." From George William Curtis, editor: 

Pi very glad to join in grateful congratulations to the author 
i' surest ion which has resulted in so beautiful and service;ui 
observance as Arbor May." From Got. Martin of Kan 

838: "Mr. Morton's tboaght has brought forth good fruit, and 
has Ix-en of vast pecuniary value to Kansas and Nebraska, and to 
all the slates of the West." From ex Senator T. F. Itayard: "I 
count it my good fortune to have long known .1. Sterling Morton, 
and appreciate his many delightful qualities of head and heart." 
From .John C." Fremont, the explorer and pathfinder of em- 

pire: "I am glad to have the opportunity to enroll myself ai 
the friends and well-wishers of Mr. Morton, and to congratulate 

him upon the success of his unselfish and broadly useful work." 

In the House, the irrepressible and genial Hon. Church Howe 
introduced the following resolution, which was passed: 

Win mis. The President eled of the t'nited States lia 
¦en fit in aclect one of the most distinguished citizen 
f this state fin- Secretary of Agriculture; and 

In mi* 

liraska Bad the creator of Arlxir Day. is particularly well 
equipped fur the position, which wt tiriulv belterc lie will 

till with credit to Nebraska and honor to the Nation: t&gt;e it 
Kim.i vm&gt;. That the house, Irrespective of party politics. 

tender its thanks to the Ifon. (Jrover Cleveland for the 
honor conferred upon the State of Nebraska. 

The fact that the measure was introduced bv a republican and 

rling Morton, one of the pioneers of Ki </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
40 



was pamed without ¦ (lissriii inj; rote wiis especially gratifying 
in ilif fri&lt;'iids of Mr. Morton. 

Within two months Mr. .Morton became Secretary of Agricnl 

kW'hcn the people of New 
ill's proclamation, met to 
¦pread before then an &lt; 
1 essay, by tlie Secretary. 
is. 

.Iersev. in compliance with the 
celebrate Arbor I&gt;av. their prolaborate. 
philosophic, and sta 
¦poo the Forestry of Civilised 

of the "relentless, never-ending war between the animal 
vegetable kingdom," he said: 


Like irreat wheels the cycles revolve and reappear, now 
in the animal anil then in the vegetable world, us mere 
niites in the stupendous machinery of the universe. The 
¦ ¦¦low of beauty on the cheek of youth to-day, inav tomorrow 
tint a rose growing upon that youth's jrrave. 

We die. we. are buried, and down into our very graves the 
kingdom of the forest and field sends its fibrous root-spies, 
its pioneers, and sappers and miners. The grand oak. 
the ma jest ie elm. throw out their arms and foliage to 
wave and shimmer in the sunlight, and deploy their roots 
and rootlets to invade •rraves. and liriii}* then food and 
strength from the tired forms that sleep therein. 

The almost infinite possibilities of a tree irerm came to 
inj mind, one summer when traveling in ¦ railway carriage 
amid beautiful cultivated fields in Belgium. A cot ton wood 

s I on its winga of down drifted into my compartment. 
It came like a materialized whisper from home. Catching 
it in my hand I forgot the present and wandered into the 
past, to a mote like that which had, years and years 
before, lieen planted by the winds and currents on the 
banks of the Missouri. That mote had taken life and 
root, growing to splendid proportions, until in 1V&gt;4 the ax of 
the pioneer had vani|iiished it. and the saw seizing it with 
relentless, whirling teeth reduced it to liunlier. From its 
treehood evolved a human habitation, a home my home — 
wherein a mother's love had blossomed and fruited with 
a sweetness surpassing the loveliness of the rose and the 
honeysuckle. Thus from the former feathery floater in 
mid-air grew a home, and all the endearing contentment 
and infinite sat isfa"t ion which that blessed Ang&lt;O BaXOn 
word conveys, that one word which means all that is worth 
living for, and for which alone all good men and women </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
41 


Never did the Secretary of Agriealtare area ;i mk titling 
part of his rarr— ¦illaga than when on Arbor Day, ls&lt;&gt;4' h»- stood 
IHIKKll under the towering trees and Utl| the aspiring 
slirulis. u )mmi the lower-clad lawn of his greal departnient : and 
there, with firm hand, steadied in plate the Morton Oak of the 

¦ e&lt;|uallv true to nature and the occasion did inspired in 
entwine the moral and epitaph: 

tit sinus to me tli;it I tret' :in&lt;l I truth arc Mm two 
lifest lived things of which m:i nkiiwl baa any knowledge. 
lerefore it behoo\es all men in rural life beaMei planting? 

truths to plant trees: it lieh 
plant economic and political 
from a small twig to a gfl 
Eiallest economic truth, as 
ales, even in the last year, 
e fTovernment of the jrreat 

tom nil men in public life to 
truths, ami as the tree yrows 

lid overspreading oak. so the 
we lia\e seen in the I'nited 
•an so rro* as to revolutionise 

Republic. I siiy. then, that we 

should all plant trees ;md phint truths, anil let e\erv man 

;t niggle so that when we shall all ha\e passed aw;iv w« 
hall have earned a yreat I'pitaph which «e tind in St 

Paul's Cathedral in London. Von reineml&gt;er Sir Christopher 

Wren was the architect of that wondrous consummation 

of beaut; in building, ami there among the heroic dead of 

England*! irreatest heroes upon land or sea repose his 
remains. On other tombs are marked words of eulojry. 
fulsome sometimes, always intense, but ttfMM the sarco- 

phagus where Sir Christopher Wrtjn's remains repose is 

inscribed only these simple words: "IU &lt;/i/ti/x iiihiiiiiiii nliim 
liniiinsiiir" If you seek my monument look around you. 

y man. woman and child who plants trees shall lx' 

able to siiv. on coming as I have come, toward Ike evening 

of life, in all sincerity and truth: "If you seek my nionii 

uient. look around Y( 

Eis occasion was a surprise 
rtnient: but one year aftc 
I on Congress Heights. I ». 

arranged by the otticials of his 
rward it was more than dupli 
»'.. April 11. 18M, beteg Arbor 

Sand his sixty Ihird birthday, when sixty three trees \w-re 
ed in his honor and named for distinguished persons. »&gt;n.-¦se 
he plaated and named "Sound Money." 

Mr. Morton's ability as a platform apeahet made him a favor- </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 



t«tl*lIH l« IMM i 1 1 1 I \ (HI lIK 111 II I i Mill II I 1 1 f fc MM'lillt 1 1 1 1 I I JIS Wf^ 11* 
and wlici her his efforts were repotted from cosmopolitan Cliieagn 
or primitive Boston, prairie garlands twined gracefully 
with conservative chaplets. 

Had liis fortune Keen cast in a democratic stale, lie would, in 
national politics, have at once wielded the rudder as well as the 
oar. In 1880, Prof. Perry of Williams College, being ready 1" 
dedicate the ervwaiag effort of his life. "Principles of Political 
Economy," inscribed that supreme analysis: 

To MY PERSONAL FRIEND OF LONG r-TANDIN 

J. STERLING MORTON 

OF NEBRASKA 

A FRIEND OF THE PEOPLE. At 

FOUNDER OF ARBOR DAY. 

I For forty yean Mr. Morton has illustrated the "survival of 
[* tit test." and the Uoman motto. u Bempar pmrmti*" — always 
rpared. 

tlfr. Morton unintentionally and unexpectedly evoked a storm 
denunciation as the result of clear concept ions, bold utteram .d 
intellectual aggressiveness, from a speech delivered in the 

Congress of Agriculture," at Chicago, 111.. Oct. Hi. ls'.t 

The American farmer has foes to contend with. They are 

not merely the natural foes — not the weevil in wheat, nor 
the murrain in cattle, nor the cholera in swine, nor the 

drouth, nor the chinch-bog. The most insidious and de 

¦tractive foe to the farmer is the "professional" farmer 

who. as a "promoter" of grnngea and alliances, for political 

purpose*, farms the farmer 

He thought "individual investigation of economic questions" 
of more value to farmers than granges or alliances attempting 
"to run railroads and banks, and even to establish new systems 
of coinage." He affirmed that "no man should give a jmwer of 
attorney to any society or organization or person, to think for 
him." Immediately upon the delivery of the address, he was 
denounced as an enemy of agriculture, and the president was 
im]Kirtuned bv granges and editors for his summary removal as </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
43 



Ill IX \ *"" 111* &lt;l*"lllll &lt;!'" II' 4l I I " ' II i ¦ I I » ¦'!• 'I I ' 'II J lit ii«ii i 
tin- address without mote or com ml and Lacorporated with it 
tin- most violent criticism! &lt;&gt;f his traducers. in order tliat the 
public nii^lil discover I lie grounds on which they planted their 
enginery. A copy of this most valuable address, falling under 
the attention of a distinguished economist, received the compli- 

a nut. and lively as a play." 
was before Congress, offering a 
the destruction of the \l&lt; 

nient. "clear as a bell, sound a 

When the I lanshoroii-'h hi) 

Etiient appropriation for i 
. and an appHcani was ¦ 
linalois. tlie Secretary 
e-bnri and fan tail grass," 

seeking a|&gt;]&gt;ointnient as chief of 
ironicalh anggeated including 

ind further said 

Bcrer be perfeci until patornal- 
Ikim' tin' not onlv 
ami ptfiw all oro|&gt;s for the 
'riii- lirciilation of pint, qaaii 
Kentucky antidote for snake 
iverimient franks thronirh the 
m as the serpents open up for 
no erop so ilaiiirerous to nianin 
the Gardes of Edea shows) 

The Hansboroueh liill will n 

nilfil it ;is tf 

but plow. 

people of the United Stati 

id y:ill&lt;m package* of th 
tea, n-ataltonsly, under ¦„ 

niL'ht to l)etrin ns 

There i 

incl (ns Adam'i experieM 

!'hen Mr. Morion took charge (&gt; f (llt ' Kepartnient of Agrieal. 
March 4th. L883, he found U.4!I7 employees ..n its pay rolls. 
honi ::•»."&gt; were discharged within nine months. He was aMe 
ulnnit an estimate for tlie tiscal year, to end .lime ::o. 
;::ti!i.ii.-,s less than was appropriated for the previous J 
found the Itepartmint in its fifth year taking on all the ex«na1 
vices of the older ones, as indicated by a few items 

from an interview. 

K- conversation here turned to the Department of Agrkatand 
1 asked the Secretary whether he was making any 
mm in tlie methods of rauiag it. He replied: 

in making a trreat main, anil I am trying to brtaf the 

.l.'partnient down to a ]&gt;ractieal bii-iness basis. I believe 
in spemlinir money where it should Ik- siH-nt. b&gt;it I don't 
be.He*e in wasting it. I kmm already found a number of 
U« leaks which I am stopping, line is in these experimental </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
44 


W 



tiiticms which have ii.'iii established by the di part aw I 

onr thf country. Simie of them are no good whatever. 

Win. 1 have founil one nt Garden Cltv, Kiin.. the busines 

of which was to evolve ¦ pin which would grow on the 

:iri&lt;l |&gt;l;iitis of the west. Twenty-two thousand dollars have 

been spent on it in five years, and a Professor Veasv is 

trying there to produce a sort of grass that will jrrow 
without rain, water or soil, a sort of orchid. 1 presume. 

From what Inquiries ' made I found that this Professor 

Ycasy had a home address at Denver. Colo., and he seemed 

to be only heard from at times when his salary was due. 

1 have stopped the appropriation and I suppose he will now 

1 got a rei|iiest the other day for *."&gt;&lt;&gt; for a United States 

tia^r. which was to 1m- put up over the smith r l&gt;eet farm at 
Schuvler. Neb. I couldn't see the reason for the appropria- 

tion and I investigated the station. I found that it wa 

costing us over 15,000 a year and that all we eould fret out 

of it was some beet seed, which the retrular sugar l»eet 

factories woidd send to us if we would only pay the freight. 

We pay on these experimental stations about .&lt;:;c&gt;0.(HH1 a 

rear, and I think the most of them should be abolished. 

My idea is that experimenting; should 1m- done through 

the agricultural experiment stations of the states. There 

are forty-four of these scattered all over the liiion. They 
tret an appropriation from Congress of $750,000 a year. 

This iroes direetlv to them, and over it we have no control. 

I think that the seeds could lie distributed through these 

by the congressmen. It costs 
&lt;eeds from here. I am going 

experiment stations and not 
$135,&lt;KM a year to send out 
to recommend Congress to 
ness. As the seeds are now 
parties they should nor do 
to the proper localities. 

¦bolish this part of our busi&lt;ent 
out they do not reach the 
the proper kind of seeds 

Hun iirc vim jjniii"; to do as to the meat inspection., Mr 
•v?" I asked, lit' replied: 

I am going to aboUah a good part of it. Our meat exports 
to (ierinany last year amounted to only $2,000,000 and 
I And that the (lermans reinspected all the meat that came 
in. We sent |3&lt; .800,090 worth to England, where there 
was no inspection. The inspection costs a vast deal more 
than it comes to. and in eleven months it has footed up a 
total of about $200,000. Why. during that time we paid out 
$4,000 to inspect the meat at the Indianapolis abattoirs, and 

materialise in sonic sIi;i|k- or other. </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
45 


Just $3 "i !..'»&lt; i. For every dollar's worth of pork sent to 
(ierniiiny from Indianapolis we paid more than $11) for inspection. 
It isn't pood bush)' 

"How about American Corn in 

Europe? bCornml Murphy 

oini; to revolutionize t lit- continent ?' 

I think not. thoiiph he is still in Europe More of our 

i-nni should In 1 used in Europe, but I believe we can create a 

gfCStcr market for it by getttag the fill— M to use it 
in the makinp of l&gt;eer rather than the making of bread. 

Most of the Wer in the I'niteil States is made largely of 
&lt;-orn. The Milwaukee brewers will tell you thev don't use 

it. lint they use plucose. which is the same thinp. and th 

greatest |mt cent of our beer conies from corn. Milwaukee 

turns out a hundred car loads of l&gt;eer every day the year 

round, and our breweries have a great deal to do with the 

price of corn. The (iermans use vast quantities of l&gt;eer. 

Havana alone turns out '.i.imhi.ooo barrels a year, and the 
other (iernian provinces have vast brewing establishments 

in all of their large cities. Corn makes a very gsod beer, 
iind I think we can gradually pet them to usinp it. I have 
selected a bright, well educated brewer to po to (¦ermanv 

look into the matte 

While the above shows in wliat spirit of intelligent discrimination 
he beg— placing his department upon an honest basis, 
the general oiitcoine lias become his splendid vindication. I Mir 
inj.' the absence of Secretary Morton in KurojM'. in the fall of 
l&gt;!»4. studying their agricultural systems, and economic ineth 
oils. I). MaeCaaig, Esq., Chief Clerk of the Department, in MM 
1 1 1 1 \ vindicating him against political campaign cfaargi 
a republican committee, incidently touched upon the subject 
of the fotcgateg interview. If there is one tiling which S 
tar\ Morton detests BKHTC than paternalism it is nepotism. 

Kid the subsidence of premature clamor, the words of the 
E. .1. Hairier of Nebraska, in the House of Representatives, 
arv 4. 18K. add to the official vindication : 

I know that there is no better friend of the real genuine 
agriculturist, not the fraudulent kind, not those who 
masquerade as agriculturists, — there is no l&gt;etter friend of 
the genuine farmer than the present Secretary of Agriculture 
I Sterlmir Morton thoiiirh he lx» a Democrat </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 


Iii ili«- Fefcraary amber of the Xurth Awilcw Mmrime, 1895, 
there appeared an article from the pen of the Secretary, in 
which lie illustrated the proposition, that "today analyzed. N 
¦ inly a portrait in miniature of an aggregate yesterday." From 
tlio history of early exchanges of proper! j, and the opinions of 
ancient authors upon a circulating medium, he passed to the 
object lesson &lt;if Nebraska in her infancy, with an inflated paper 
currency, before her possession of exchangeable t-onunodit i&lt;-s. 
and the crash two years later, when the inferior currency had 
expelled the superior. In a subsequent interview the salient 
points of the article were condensed: 

1 (In nut believe that an international congress can H 
;iblisli permanently ¦ commercial ratio between gold an 

establish a jwrmanent comand 
wheat. But if an 

silver any more than it can esta 
mercial ratio between rye am 
international conference can fix i 
silver, it can also fix the price of 
commodity, and thereby avoid all 
in values which tend to cause panic 

fix the price of gold or of 
•e of wheat or of any other 

all the possible shrinkages 

1 think the word "intrinsic" ought not to be used. The 
value of gold is always relative. To illustrate: If I sell 
you a thousand bushels of wheat today for $5711. the transaction 
has established, for the time being, the wheat value 
of gold and the gold value of wheat. Tomorrow's cables 
of titter failure of wheat crop in Argentina. Kussia. and 
Europe entirely change 1 lie relation of gold to wheat. 
and the thousand bushels of wheat purchased at 57 cents 
yesterday, is worth *1.U a bushel today. Hut in the meantime, 
there has been no '•intrinsic" value of gold, notwithstanding 
there has been a change in the relation of wheat 
to gold. 

My own judgment is that we must sooner or later declare 
that the United Slates of America recognizes gold as the 

lxst and least factuating measure of value and medium of 
exchange which the commerce of civilization has thus far 
utilized. 

The time for straddlers has passed. Those who are for 
iound currency on a gold basis ought to have the courage 

to say so. and abide by the results of their declaration. 
It makes no difference to me whether a declaration of 
truth, either upon the tariff or the money question, temporarily 
di from or allures them to us. </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
47 


It is barely possible that the financial fallacies of the 
populists and other vagaries may temporarily secure a 
majority of the voters of the United States. Should such 
I catastrophe overtake the country, the people must learn 
r experience what they should have learned by diligent 
udy and reason. 

fhave no hesitation in declaring myself utterly opposed 
all free coinage fallacies, all the 16 to 1 lunacies, and all 
tin' cheap money illusions and delusions which populists 
and other vagarists advocate. 

t[y judgment is that silver cannot be restored to its 
netary place in the commerce of the world, because the 
supply of silver has outgi-own the demand for silver in the 
exrhanges of civilization. The relation of supply to demand 
is the sole regulator of value. This maxim applies alike to 
salt, silver, sugar, and soap. All tin' legislation of all the 
law-making bodies on the face of the globe can neither 
mitigate nor annul the operation of the inexorable law that 
ihe relation of supply to demand is the sole regulator 
value." 

Ehe President's critics ask. What is sound money? Any 
inary man of business may answer that question. Sound 
money is that sort of currency which has the most universal 
and least fluctuating purchasing power in the markets of 
all countries. That money 'mildest for which, 
throughout the commerce of the civilized world, there is 
the most universal demand. And that universal demand is 
always based upon the universal and unfluctuating purchas- 

ing power of that money, 
silver fever will in due time 
Um 16 to 1 patients decline 

The present epidemic of the 
abate. As the temperature of 

mental aberrations will dis- 

appear and reason once more resume its sway. </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 


GOVERNOR WAMUEL W. BLACK 

The appointment of Samuel W. Black, 1 as associate justice of 
lie territory of Sebraaka, in ls."&gt;7. was the date of his iatrodaeion 
to the "Far Wcsi." Horn in the city of Pittabwg, l'a.. in 
818, then on the routines of western civilization, and educated 
inder the severe moral constraints of covenanter influence, lie 
eaclied mans estate better furnished for the battle of life than 
majority of American youths. At twenty two years ol 
liousands were diarim-d l»v his brilliant oratorical effort! in 
hat incomiirehensilile campaign of 1S4II. when sjmm»«-1i iind song. 
iurle&lt;l in passion, drove democracy from the White Mouse and 
nthi-oned "TipperMoe ;ind Tyler too." 

Sanguine friends were predicting for him the garland* of aacess 
at the bar. when the .Mexican war gave an outlet for yonthul 
val&lt;»r. iind a colonelcy commission tilled the demands of an 
¦niliusiiists ambition. When introduced to Jadgc Hall, of He• 
raska. a .Mexican remembiiince incited his wit. when lie . \ 
¦laimed. "Jadge Hall, are you related to The Halls of the Mon 
ezinnas?" " iind received the retort. "Goyeraor Hlack. are you 
i rehitive of the Rlacks of South Carolina?" 

After the resijiiiat ion of (Jovernor Richardson in the fall of 
1858, the Hon. .1. Sterling Morton, territorial secretary, became 
act in}: governor until the arrival of Governor Samuel lllack on 
the Sad of May, 18». 

On the tth day of December. L8S§, (lovernor Hlack delivered 
his first official message to the legislature. Beiag ii m.in of 
scholarly attainments iind well posted in political historv, ho 
devoied half of the space of a long message to dispel the cloud 
cast over the Territory by the ignorance iind hasty decisions 
of early explorers, iis to its being a desert region, and further, 
to establish its right to s]&gt;eed;v admission as a state. 

1 Bi&gt;&gt;Krai»lty ol' ( Juv. Klark. Netir. st;tt. Hist. S&lt;h\ l'uh.. 1st M-rii-s, I., ft4, ft 

May 8, 1859 to Kel&gt;. .'4. lsiu </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
49 


Esminli as practical agriculture has completely dissiillusion, 
and the question of an admission to the 
?n a fixed fact for twenty-four years, both theories 
ssed over in silence. At the threshold of discussion we 
following: 

Nebraska has heretofore suffered from inconsiderate and 
nasty legislation, as well as from sudden and untimely 
repeal of a large portion of her laws. We have, however, 
just cause of congratulation that the code, both civil and 
criminal, adopted by the legislature of last year, is in 
full force and successful operation. 

The recommendations relative to lands bearing the greater 
share of taxation, homestead exemption from sale for debt, 
prudent usury laws, the intelligent limitation of official fees, the 
« •nai-tment of laws to protect debtors and secure creditors in the 
sale of real estate under execution, were worthy of a sound law\&lt;t 
and impartial judge. The brief allusion to the mistakes and 
calamities of the past was pungent and graphic: 

It is a matter of bitter experience that the people of this 
Territory have been made to pass through the delusive 
days of high times and paper prices, and the consequent 
dark and gloomy night of low times and no prices. 

¦ far the most notable message ever delivered, up to that 
in Nebraska closed, pure in morals and beautiful in style: 

We may here turn to our past history as a territory, and 
find material for pleasant meditation. Individual faults and 
occasional infractions of the law are of course upon the 
record, but not a single page is darkened by the registry 
of a single outbreak among the people. Our growth in 
population and prosperity has been equal to the most sanguine 
expectation. Of agricultural supplies we already produce 
far more than we consume, and we may reasonably 
hope that but a few years will roll around before Nebraska 
will be as well known in the markets of the world as the 
oldest and largest grain growing states in the Republic. 

A railroad to the Pacific Ocean is no longer a problem 
without a solution, and its construction and completion 
are but a question of time. These prairies will all be 
peopled from the great rivers to the mountains. The farm 

5 </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
50 



iii&lt;l tin- school house will decorate tin 1 plain- ami 
temples reared to the living God will resound with praise 
from living anil •rrateful hearts. This is the nii^htv and 
majestic future to which we look almost with t lie assurance 
of divine faith. Our fathers saw this an. I were jrlnil. And 
when tins "goodly frame."' without a parallel, this Union, 
was first conceived, they trusted in .Ichovah and were not 

lisappointed. They knew as we know that there is ¦ 


sperial providence In the fall of a sparrow, ami in tht 
rise ;ind fall of nations. That their fate, who have fallen 

may not 1m- ours, mill that our 
and increase in just power, 
should l&gt;e .iihI will Ik', in all 
to riiiiic. as in the times |»a? 
of the patriot. 

country may continue to rise 
in excellence and ill virtue, 
parts of it and in all limes 
t. the invocation and prayer 

(&gt;n die occasion of vetoing an act &lt;&gt;f incorporation, the gorer 
MO siid: "It is time that tlic spirit of incoi|M&gt;iatiin si ould U' Mil - 
iliif«l and checked. All ¦pedal privilege! and chartered rights 
. (infilled on a few. art' so much tak&lt;'ii away front the gf neral 
privilege* and ¦¦chartered! rights of the mam." As illaatrative 
of tin- bugling way in which laws had been farted, a -om 
mittee reported: "Tliat there was no law in existence in l-Ov 
which authorized the lew and collection of territorial tax. The 
IfgialatTe of 1857, in attempting to adopt a revenue law. only 
Mooted ilif enacitneiit clause." As only four counties paid 
anything into the treasury in 1868, said amounts were reconv 
iiiended to he returned. There seeming to lie no doulit that 
there were six slaves in Nebraska and had been formerly M 
many as iliiiieen. a bill was iniroduced and passed for the 
abolition of slavery in the territory, which was vetoed on the 
grand thai slavery existed in the Louisiana purchase when we 
acquired it by the treaty, and could not be disposed of until the 

I ion of a sialt- constitution. 
the governor delivered his 
to the legislature, and procc 
in which the people were i 
B previous session, lie said. 

(&gt;n i he 4tli day of .December 
second and final annual meu 

leded at once to the vital cpies 
ipeciallv interested. Referring 

I urL r *'d then, us I iirsre now. the necessity of the law 
niinfti usurious rates of Interest. Better have no ntoney 
</seg>


            <seg id="p051">
51 

than bin it with the life blood of the needy and hard 
-• d of the people. 

fn response to this otteraace the rate of interest was placed 
10 per cent in rase there was no agreement for another rate 
imt exceeding IB per cent. Of salaries lie said: 

It is perfectly well known that the income of several of 
the officers in the Territory is far greater than it should 
be, and that the territorial debt would be an easy burden 
if it were not for the issue of the warrants to satisfy the 
claims of public officers, whose fees in many cases are 
four times as much as their services are worth. 

E&gt; remed.v this evil, a most searching ami comprehensive law 
passed covering the whole raage of fees and salaries. The 
itorial debt was staled at foiVJfili, with collectible resources 
amounting to 930,259. &lt; 'onteniplating the manner in which the 
public debt had increased from a small amount in five years to 
150,000 his indignant tannage was: 

Let tlie dmyi Of extrsvagaaee ami eaormow fees be numbered 
and cut short, and let a system of rigid and severe 

cononiv. raited to the times and our condition, l&gt;e intra 
need and adopted, ami that without di lav. 

rlis plea for an indirect bounty bv which the growth of timber 
the ireeless prairies might be encouraged was promptly met 
the passage of an act allowing a reduction of f50 on the val 
nation of real estate for every acre of cultivated fruit, forest or 
ornamental trees. On the supposition that "the relation of a 
Territory to the general &lt;;o\ eminent is peculiar, and one in many 
respects of entire dependence," he urged that Congress be called 
upon for aid for bridge! and roads on the lines of western travel, 
and for emigrant hospitals, and an arsenal of repairs and suptea, 
No important interest of the home seeker seemed to e» 
pe his attention. His confident e in the future of the Terri 
rv was reiterated: 

climate for the most part 
,|| .,.;i-ii|]&lt; -o full of health. 

A -»il 

rao i 

-*l lornAtfl C fwi hl« </seg>

            <seg id="p052">

52 


written His decrees for her prosperity deep in the earth, 
and developed His designs in the rejoicing harvests which 
return in smiling abundance to them who. betimes, have 
sown in tears. 

Bh his eye upon the storm cloud in the sky of the Union, 
is ear sensitive to the strains of discord, he came to his 

final appeal: 

The suggestions of self interest and the loftiest patriotism 
should combine to make the people of the Territories 
faithful to the constitution and firm to their attachment 
to the Union. When one is the subject of open and frequent 
violation, and the other trembles on ¦ sea of trouble, 
every pood and conscientious citizen will ask himself the 
question, what can I do that my country may be saved? 
You cannot shut your eves, nor can I close mine, to the 
fearful fact that this confederacy is shaken to the center 
and vibrates with intense feeling 1 to its farthest borders. 
If it is not in our power to do something to bring; back the 
days of other years when peace prevailed, let us at least 
do nothing towards making the present more gloomy and 
the future, at best, but hopeless. Bather with one accord 
let us invoke the God of all peace, for "even the wind and 
the sea obey Him." that He will sulxlue the storm and quiet 
everv angrv element of alienation and discord. 

T"j&gt; to the ¦wtnbling of the legislature in lstil), the government 
officials had been members of the Democratic party, and 
those of them from slave states uniformly brought with them 
one or more slaves, claiming that slavery was national. During 
the first four or five years of territorial existence the antislavei.v 
sentiment of the people had been in restraint by the 
theory that it was better for the material interests of the new 
« oninuiiiity that they should not antagonize the policy of the 
party la power. And as the repeal of the Missouri Compromise 
and the struggle to force slavery upon Kansas had threatened 
the life of the Union, it seemed nothing short of the Republican 
cyclone of 1800. which brought Mr. Lincoln into the White 
House, could consolidate the emigrants and check the domineering 
assumption of official dictators. Rut the make-up of this 
1 pit i si 'it uro i&gt;r&lt; m*1 ;i i n n*&lt;l 1 1 1 • * &lt;*iu&lt;tii&lt;'ip&lt;itioii of scut 1 1111*11 1 find the </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
53 


dawn of a new political era. Of cmhm there were at all times 
u lew bold spirits, illustrating the fart that a true reformer must 
be in advance of his times. 

¦ the 834 dav of tli&lt;' session, in reply to the governor's niesof 
censure, a committee of whom T. \Y. Tipton of Nemaha 
y was chairman, made the following report: 

The select committee to which was referred the special 
messaire from the governor, dated December the lfith. 1860, 
calling the attention of this body to the fact that only seventeen 
working days of the session remained, and up to that 
date he had received no bills for his official signature, have 
had the same under consideration and beg leave to report: 
First, that from a careful and thorough examination of a 
standard almanac, his point in regard to the time is well 
taken: and second, that the journal of the council appears 
to sustain the second count ill the indictment. We are 
happy to learn from his excellency that "I make this suggestion 
in no spirit of complaint." for we are certain that 
he has no cause of complaint, and had he complained we 
would have handed his complaint over to a people who 
have been cursed with too hasty, illadvised. and inconsiderate 
legation, lint when he says as a reason for prompting 
us to action, "Not on mv own account alone, but for the 

sake of the people, 1 requ 
hasten the public business." 
lenev that the same people 
down at a previous session. 

st that you will endeavor to 
we desire to remind his excelwliose 
will has been stricken 
by his veto, has sent us here 

:o own allegiance to no earthly power but themselves, and 
our oaths of office, and further that we represent thousands 

of freemen and hold our commissions from them, while he 
holds his from the 1'i-esident of the Inited States. The 
people are well aware that no legislature, a large portion 
of whom hold for the first time, can in the short space of 
twenty days, brinj.' legislative order out of choas. and establish 
.« judicious revenue system, construct an election law 
that will guard the biillot box. equalize the fees of all public 
officers, reduce the burdens of taxation by thousands of 
dollars, and place a future state on a broad and glorious; 
platform of constitutional liberty. But if it is a fact that 
we have been liv day and night Inlxiriug in this chaml&gt;er 
and committee rooms, in this l&gt;ehalf for 23 days, may we 
not. when successful, return to our constituents in conscious 
pride and triumph? In taking leave of this peculiar message 
we concur in the propriety of the following language </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
54 


in any way your more Meat*, or deliberations." From this 
avowal on his ]&gt;;irt. your committee recommend that the 
council continue to transact legislative business in its own 
•tay. determining its own movements and controlling iis 
own deliberations. 

On the &lt;&lt;th day of the tern Governor Black mni upon tlie 
legmtatvrc a veto BsemMge of "A bill prohibiting slavery in tlie 
Territory," which was promptly passed over his veto by a vote 
of 10 to .! in the council and :'.:; to 2 in the house. Of the votes 
in the council S of the 10 were cast 1&gt;\ republicans and 2 by 
)ouglas democrats. Of these republicans Dmidy became 
'nited Slates district judge, Klliert governor of Colorado, Maruette 
and Taffe representatives in Congress. Strickland, DoVgas 
democrat. Iniled States district attorney, and Tliayer and 
Tijiton 1'nited States senators, evidence sulTicient that the peo•lc 
were not misrepresented on tlie slavery question. On a 
notion of Mr. Upton tlie public printer was ordered to arcom 
¦any the governor^ message with the action of the Legislature 
n passing the bill over the veto, on which subject he delivered 
he following remarks: 

In niv hmnlile opinion this veto Message is a most remarkable 
production- remarkable on account of the pertinacity 

with which his excellency follows up this question of human 
freedom with ponderous documents, earnest protests, and 
unavailing entreaties. In its component parts it is equally 
remarkable, whether vmi consider it a system of dovetailed 
fallacies, special pleadings, or sublimated foolishness. 

If his excellency had a mint 
this legislature, anil we posse? 
captivating eloquence of our 
ceive the one and e\crt the 

of &lt;rold with which to bribe 
sed all the logical acumen and 
race: were we willing to reother. 
we could neither fjive 
force to its ((inclusions. The 

dignity to this document nor 

honest hearts of our constituents would consign us for our 
efforts to everlasting political infamy. 

Tbe republicans had declared in their Chicago platform, "that 
the normal condition of all the territories is that of freedom, 
and we deny the right of Congress, or of a territorial legislature. 
d\ ? ¦ i \f * 1 1 1 v iliilTViflll'il^ fik t r i \" i * 1 1 * **¦• 1 1 ii v i w t ( * 1 1 1 ¦ I ' If} 1 Tl &lt;1 Tl V </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
TKUIUTORIAL fiOVEKSORS. 

55 

-lavei v was national, and could follow the master at his pitas 
in-. The Douglas democrats, followers of the distinguished 
llinois senator, claimed that the people, as an act of "popular 
overeignty," could "vote it up or vote it down," according to 
heir preferences. Before the end of the session ( iov. I'.lack 
oimd numerous occasions to exercise his veto, and in no adiliional 
case did the legislature reverse his decision. On the last 
lav of Ilie session he concluded his last veto message with the 
ollowing sentences: 

This is the last ilay of your session, and this communication 
is about the last I shall have an opportunity to submit 
to the legislative assembly. When I had the honor to 

occupy a seat on the lwneh. I trust T was persevering ami 
firm in vindicating the great right of protection to life 
which the law extends to every human being. The position 
then occupied I am unwilling to change, even by a distant 
and remote conviction. Wherefore this bill, which seems to 
excuse, if it does not justify, a felonious homicide, is not 
approved. 

(Mi the 11th of January. 1881, when the hands of the clock 
ndicated final adjournment, as a passenger from the deck of 
he vi ssel waves a final adieu to friends on shore, the council. 
&gt;n niotidn of General Tkayer, sent to the house greeting: — 

liKSoi.VKn. That we hereby heartily and cordially endorse 
the official conduct of the executive of this Territory. His 
Excellency. Hon. Samuel W. ISlack, for his gentlemanly and 

.nek. for his gentlemanly and 

courteous treatment of th 

members of this legislature. 

and for the prompt, efficient 

!ind energetic manner in which 

has discharged the duti 

devolving- upon him during 

the session of this leirislatur 

and during his term of office. 

The :14th of the next month marked the departure of tb 
ernor to his native Pennsylvania, and on the following June 
dates the death of Col. Black, shot from his horse at the head of 
a I'nion regiment, leading a desj&gt;erate charge against a Con fed- 

erate army. A statement of his tragic death was communicated 
to the Nebraska State Historical Society hv his daughter. 1 

I \"(|| 1 Wf M'TH'* 04 ft»"&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
56 


ACTIXG-GOVEBNOH A. s. PADDOCK. 

IMS, l-i 

Him. A. S. Paddock HUM to Nebraska under the most favorable 
circumstances possible for ;i young man of ambitious tendi-iH 
ics. Im-iii^ twenty -seven years of Ife and pMMHtag a good 
education, free from all public vices, and with a "sound mind 
in a sound body." ptmned of fundamental principles of law. 
and the experiences of self-support. Pioneer neighbors naturally 
bailed him as one qualified for counsel and aggressive a«-tio:i, 
a new man. in a new country, where a new set of political is 
were beginning to monopolize public attention. Having 
inherited tint i -slavery sentiments from a New Kngland ancestry, 
his natural affiliations would be with Fremont as a presidential 
candidate in 18M, and for Lincoln in 1800. When, therefore, 
lie met New Yorkers in the Chicago convention in 1860, from 
whom he had parted as an emigrant in 1857. and was with them 
in voting for William H. Seward for nominee, a mutual co-operation 
in the future was easy and natural. With Lincoln elected 
and Seward in the cabinet, and the prestige of a campaign ma 
tor ;isso&lt; iated with the name of Mr. Paddock, the appointment 
was made and continued, and he entered upon the duties of 
S. , i.iiiiv of Nebraska April 1st, 1861. In 1864 he was candidate 
for nomination before the republican convention of He 
btaska. fur delegate in congress, with T. M. MttfMtte, I'. W. 
Hitchcock and T. W. Tipton as friendly comi&gt;etitors. Bacli 
being voted for separately, Mr. Tipton lacked four votes of the 
nomination while Mr. Marquette was a few short also. On the 
next ballot the first count gave Mr. Paddock a majority of one, 
but before the announcement a delegate claimed the parliamentary 
right of changing his vote, which left it a tie. Up to 
this ooint tin? f rionds of Air PI i tf'lif oolc 1m d tMH*n oflstinc com* </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
57 

TERRITORIAL GOVERNORS. 

plimentary votes to each candidate, and now that his time of 
trial had come, all were "returned with interest, 1 ' and he received 
the nomination. 

Blstili, while Mr. Seward was still in the cabinet of Andrew 
MB and many conservative republicans were sustaining 
dministratiou. Mr. Paddock became a candidate for Con- 

¦ receiving a conservative republican and democratic- vnt ¦. 
ailed of election by a majority of Mfl votes, in favor of 
Taffe. 

BIStiT President Johnson gave him the nomination of OoTCT&gt;f 
Wyoming territory, which was finally declined. Subsetly 
he was elected a senator of the United States, in 1875, 

of the United States, in 1875, 

and re-elected in 1887, while in 

t In* i uteri in he served on the 

I * t all commission. 

¦noug the many duties devolv 
was his preparation for the &gt; 
in the year IStiJ. 

in jx upon him as acting goveruibjugation 
of the hostile Indi- 

Omaha. Neur., Territory. Sept. !i. 1-fi 

Hun. K. M. Stantmi. Sec'y of Wur: Powerful hands of Indians 
are retiring from Minnesota into the northern 
counties of this Territory. Settlers by the hundreds are 
fleeing. Instant action is demanded. I can turn out a 
militia for&lt;-c a battery of three pieces of six pounders, 
and from six to ten companies of cavalry and mounted infantry. 
The Territory is without credit or a cent of money. 
Authorize me to act for the &lt;reneral ;ro\ eminent &gt;n providing 
immediate defense and I can do all that is necessary 
with our militia, if subsisted and paid by the povernment. 

A. S. Paddock, 

Src'ii ami l&lt; tbiii-Hornnnr of Xebraska, 

Authority beinfr granted, all preliminary steps were taken, 
the Second Nebraska cavalry organized and placed under the 
command of Col. Furnas, and a complete victory obtained over 
the savages in the battle of Wfciteatme Hills, with the Brules, 
Yankton and Blackfeet Sioux. 

En the legislature convened in January, 1867, the governor 
absent on official business, the duty of presenting the 
message devolved upon the territorial secretary, Hon. </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
58 



— \ . b I M il"l*J"'* ¦» • Mil™ I t I * I (^ 4 1 11*1 I 1 111 (^ *&gt; " 1, 111 4 4 I I I | ( 4 " ( " « »" ™ "** 
parti of state officers belonged to the administration of Governor 
Sa under*, while the secretary was entitled to full credit for 
must wise and conservative views upon the national land 
1 ••in. i-estilis of the war. impartial suffrage, and kindred themes 
of vital importance to the embryo state. 

The financial statement gare an available surplus of $01. Mo. 
whereas six years before, the date of the governor's first mesthe 
indebtedness was £!7.±M. The revision of the laws 
had been accomplished in an admirable manner. "The wise 
iTiiiiiunv" of the homestead law "had been no more clearly illustrated 
than in this territory." Said he. "How much wiser then 
the economy which gives to productive industry the possession 
of the national domain free of cost, than that which disposes of 
it in large tracts to simulators, in whose hands it remains unoc( 
upied and unimproved, a veritable obstacle in the way of the 
rapid settlement and development of the country. " Among 
numerous recommendations made to the legislature was that 
for a memorial to Congress protesting against any future cash 
sales of public lands, or withdrawing from market for proa 
]»¦&lt; the railroads, or locations by script or warrants unless for 
li.-u state uses, and also asking that government buy the 1'nion 
l'acitic mil n.a&lt;l lands and devote them to free settlement. It 
was also recommended that a liberal amount be appropriated 
• cure the active labors of immigrant agents, and to accomplish 
a geological survey of the Territory. In order to bring in 
closer relations, commercially and socially, the inhabitants north 
and south of the l'latte. a free bridge was urged as an unavoidable 
necessity. 

A very satisfactory review of the railroad situation was 
dosed as follows: 

Sncli brilliant railroad prospects liavi' very rarely, if ever. 
jin-sented themselves to the people of a new state or terrikm-.v. 
Nature l»as- marked this spot, equi-distant from the 
two preat oceans, as the pivotal center of the railroad 
Mstem of America, (iod grant that the Tnion Pacific 
railroad which is the true base of all prosperitv mav l)e </seg>


            <seg id="p059">
59 

speedily completed t,, the Pacific. Ma* i! form U additional 
bond of union to the states, a never failing source of pride, 
of glory and of strength, to the nation, and an equal sourc* 
of pride and profit to the brave and energetic gentlemen 
«ho engaged in its eonstnwtioa. 

After commending the admission of the Territory as a state 
of the 1'nion, and praMeriag cooperation in behalf of. greater 
efficiency in the common schools, the acting governor concluded 

his official communication with tcapente and patriotic 

allu- 

sion? 

I should hail with joy a radical change in the rule of 
suffrage which would give the franchise to intelligence and 
patriotism wherever found, regardless of the color of its 
possessor, lie who ean read understandingly the constitution 
of his country, and he who has fought in its defense, 
of whatever race or color, should have a voice in the choice 
of the nation's rulers. J should therefore cheerfully concur 
with .vow in a memorial to Congress, praying for an amend- 

nicnt of our organic law. in 
No change, however, should be 
franchise away from any pcrs 
existing laws. 

accorclance with this view, 
made which would take the 
in who now enjoys it under 

At the time lie delivered his 
significance in the following: 

message there was a pec 

uliar 

The kind offices of the peacemaker avail not. and the 
olive branch is cast aside, a withered and useless thing. 
How can our beloved country be united again in fact as 
well as in form? Mow can the Inion be firmly re-established 
in the hearts and in the affections of the people of all 

sections? For the patriotic love of the people is the soul 
of the union, its preservation is essential to the very life of 
the nation itself. I do not l&gt;elieve it can be done by depriving 
eleven states of loyal representatives in the national 

congress, when representation is the very germ ami essence 
of union. Only that which will win back the hearts of the 
southern people will give stability and enduring paaea to 
the Republic. 

In conclusion, jiermit me to assure yon that I shall most 
earnestly co-operate with y»u in every endeavor to promote 
the \aried interests of our Territory. Whatever measures 
may commend themselves to vonr wisdom and judgment as </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
60 


best calculated to promote the general welfare will receive 
my most cordial approval. Permit me to wish you a 
pleasant sojourn at the territorial capital, and after the 
labors of the session are terminated, a happy return in 
safety and in health, to your families and friends. </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
61 

TERRITORIAL GOVERNORS. 

GOVERNOR ALVIN SAUNDERS. 

May 15, 1861 to Mar. 1, 1S6 

Gov. Alvin Saunders 1 claims Kentucky as his birthplace, and 
was born on the 12th of July, 1817. At twelve years of age he 
was taken by his parents to the State of Illinois, and in his 19th 
year united his destiny with the small village of Mt. Pleasant, 
Iowa. AVith patience and luck he endured the vicissitudes of 
pioneer life, and as merchant's clerk and merchant, as postmaster 
and member of a constitutional convention, as representative of 
the people in the state senate and in the Chicago National Convention 
of 1860, which nominated Mr. Lincoln, he secured and 
held the implicit confidence of an honest, intelligent and patriotic 
community. Though of Virginia parentage and Kentucky 
birth, having developed an enthusiasm for "free speech, free 
soil, and free men,'' he was fully competent to stand guard on 
freedom's battlements during the stormy days of the Union. 

Ker discharging the duties of Governor for a term of four 
the circumstances attending the signing of his second 
ission were so peculiar that they are treasured up as a 
1 remembrance. 

I saw Mr. Lincoln, who told me to return home, as it was 
all right and he would attend to the commission. I started 
for home in the morning, and in the evening of the same day 
he was killed. I telegraphed back to find out what had become 
of my commission, and learned that the room had not 
been opened. When it was opened the commission was 
found on the table, unfolded, with his signature attached. 
It was not signed by Mr. Seward. I have the commission 
in Mr. Lincoln's name, but the appointment was actually 
made out by Mr. Johnson. 

' (Minnill Saunder*, father of Alvin SuiiiultTs. wa« a nativr af Loadoun Count* 
who oarigiatoa' to Baarbon County, Ky.. wham ¦ young man, ami thence to Firming 
v. Mi- kneeatrj m Kiiglisli. anil hi- wile, inaiilrn nain.- Mary M.m/y, wait 
of I'ulpopper County, Va., from Fremh family Alvin was out- of live mm. 
tf*iiiin -II w -lit to ri«'lil 1 I 'itioi't 1 "¦¦*!' </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
62 

NEBRASKA BTATK HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

Be fare be uinwd the duties &lt;»f Territorial Govenw of Se&gt; 
luaska. Ma; 13, 1 S&lt;;i . ten states had passed ordinances of 
¦okM, Davis and Stephens elected president and vice president 
of Hie Soutliern Confederacy, a call liad l&gt;een issued for 
7."i. i men at the north and for 32,000 at ilie south. Fort 
Slimier had l&gt;een bombarded by the rebels and Massachusetts 
troops Mobbed in Baltimore on their way to the city of Wash 
in^rton. and President Lincoln had ordered the blockade of 
southern ports. 

Ee days after (low Saunders' arrival he issued a proclaina!• 
troops for three years' service, closing with the follow in;; 
tic laafgr 

Effort! arc Ix'inp made to trample the stars and stripes, 
i lie emblem of our liberty, in tin- dust. Traitor* are in the 
land busily trying to overthrow the Oorernmemi of the 
1 niled Slates, and information has been received that these 
~ame trmiton arc endea\ orinir to incite an invasion of our 
frontier 1&gt;\ ¦ savage foe. In view of these faels. I invoke 

the aid of every lover of his country ami his home, to 
come promptly forward to sustain and protect the lame. 

I* ads and messages reveal the fact that during the four 
: of devastating war. his thoughts were ever with the nun 
answered the calll for troops. Whether they were in camp 
council chamber, their wants ami domestic anxieties urged 
o duty and called out his ready sympathy. 

to nineteen thousand throe hundred and twelve dollar 

This tax may be assessed and collected by otlice.rs to 1&gt;&lt; 

appointed by the Secretary of the Treasury, or may Im- 

" 1 by the Territorial Rovernment. In the lattc 

1 deduction of 1.1 |mt cent, from the irross amount will 

1h&gt; allowed the Territorv. I therefore recommend that von 

make the Beeessar} provhilon for its collection by addin 

tbf groRfl amount to the tax lew f'&gt;r the cnniiii" vear for 

II 

liis tiist mrwgr i&lt;i th&lt;- legislature, the Governor mid 

ConffTPSR, ;tt its 1: &gt;n, in providing mrans to lie 

Hard in )&gt;nt tiny down rebellion in ;i numJier of Southern 

st:iti'^ of tin' I iiion. ]«'\io&lt;l a liircct tax on the people. 

The Constitution of the United States provide* that direct 

tazea ihall be levied by CoagTea* in proportioa to the 
population. The proportion assi(rmil to Nebrmaka amounts </seg>


            <seg id="p063">
63 

for its payment as your wisdom may devise. Although the 

-inn to be raised is comparatively large, we should not 
beaiteta to he;ir our part of the burden. Each one should 
be willing- to exert himself to the utmost to avert the 
danger which now threatens the Union. \Ye would be 
unworthy descendants of the good and great men who 
pledged their property and their lives to secure our free 
institutions, if we hesitated to make any sacrifice necessary 
for their nreservation. 

The patriotism of those who assist our country now, when 
he is defending the Constitution and the I'nion against 

traitors and rebels, and who stand firmly by that flair, and 
those institutions, which have descended to us from the 
hands of Washington, will be held in grateful remembrance 
by the great and tlie good everywhere, and their nanidescend 
with imperishable honor to posterity, for having 
aided in preserving to their country and the world, in its 

&gt;riginal integrity and vigor, the freest anil Ix'st irovernment 
jn earth. 

5 committee in whom was referred the subject of the direct 
reported that inasmuch ;is CoagRH allowed the Territory 
iidd per year, for legislative expeMea, the legislature should 
lie .omened during the next rear, hut the xi'n.iMMl should !&gt;•• 
tied by the fjeneral yoverniiieni for tlie cancellation of the 

til to show the necessity of this, they instanced the financial 
tion of the people, illustrating with Doagbw County. 

County has a mortgage debt of $800,000 hanging 

itiznis. covering the majority of the real estate 

tv and bearing interest at an enormous rate 

month. The court records 

how a judgment debt of several thousand dollars 

The Count] Ims a debt of $50,000. So with the other coun- 

ties throughout the Territory. &lt;&gt;»r Territorial debt is 


leen hirber for three years than in anv state in the Union. 

Kisnillch as the pi'OgreM of the &lt; 'loveinineiit. in the supples 
of the rebellion, was the all absorbing qaeatloB, his - 
lie. in isc4. contained the following: 

Wli 

re last in session the rebels claimed all 
;ites and all of the territories -.outh of 

th. 



i ii t v iii the Territory have </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
64 


been steadily driving" them back from the loyal states and 
toward the interior from the coast, capturing fortifications 
and cities until now the stars and stripes float in 
triumph over at least two-thirds of the Territory then 
claimed by the insurgents. A few months more of vigorous 
and persistent effort on the part of the great armies and 
navies of the Republic, it would seem, will probably be sufficient 
to wipe out the last vestige of this gigantic rebellion, 
and establish the supremacy of the Constitution and the 
laws throughout the whole extent of all the states and 
territories of the L'nion. 

It must be :i source of profound gratification to you to 
know that the citizen soldiery of Nebraska, springing to 
arms from the peaceful pursuits of life, at the call of the 
President, totally unaccustomed to the hardships and deprivations 
of tlic weary march and camp life, and to the 
exposure and dangers of protracted campaigns, have performed 
their part so nobly in every trial of endurance and 
eonrmi 

A Nebraska soldier, whether called on by his country to 
confront the wily Mtvagea on the frontier, or the rebel 
hosts in battle array, has never shrunk from duty, quailed 
before danger, or turned his back on the foe. 

After u^ing that all poMiMe effort should be made for the 
oinfort of the soldiers in the Held, and of the sick and wounded, 
nd of widows and orphans, and for allowing the soldiers to 
ote for state and national officers, he passed to the subject of 
lonuments. 

I also recommend that you make the necessary provision 
for keeping a correct record of the names of all who enlist 
in the military service of the Territory, to be preserved 
among the public archives; and that the names of all who 
are wounded or fall in battle should be inscribed on a roll 
of honor, to be carefully preserved for the inspection of 
future generations. I also suggest that justice to this class 
of our feliow citizens seems to me to require that a monument 
should 1k&gt; erected at the eapitol, on which to inscribe 
the names, and preserve the memory of all from this territory 
who have fallen in their country's service since this 
rebellion commenced, or who have fallen during its continuance. 


He further elucidated the sups leading up to emancipation, </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
65 


the tinal ii-siilt. and declared in favor of an iinineiliaie p«we i mi 
sequent upon a restored union. In his message of 1MB, (lover 
nor Saunders made the following prediction: 

This war for the preservation of our national life, although 
protracted through more than three years of bloody 
strife, is at length happily drawing to a close: anil recent 
events would seem to indicate, with almost mathematical 
certainly, that the end cannot be far in the future. Slowly, 
but steadily and surely, the Union armies are exhausting 
the strength and resources of the rebel forces. Their 
lines are being rapidly contracted — their ranks decimated 
l&gt;eyond the possibility of recuperation, and the spirit of the 
misguided masses has been broken. Our armies and navies 
almost encompass them, while one of our greatest generals, 
with his victorious columns, has inarched through the very 
heart of the Empire State of the South, from the interior 
to the coast, and captured the most populous and important 
commercial city in the rebellious district, almost 
without opposition. The significant facts leave no room to 
doubt that at an early period the supremacy of the constitution 
and the laws will lx» restored in every' portion of the 
country, thus establishing human liberty, alike in the South 
and in the North, and vindicating the capacity of the people 
for self government. 

Ie year later he had the happiness to herald the loiisuuiinaof 
the jrreat work, in the following taagMge of his annual 
igt, of January, 1866: 

Our Hay. emblem of the unity, justice, power and glory of 
the nation. BOW floats in triumph over every part of the 
Ifepublic. Kvery foot of our national territory has been preserved 
intact. The supremacy of tin' constitution and laws 
is acknowledged by all the inhabitants, but this great Inon 
has been secured at a fearful cost of blood and treasure. 
Having thus passed through the lied Sea of disaster which 
menaced us. and for a time threatened to engulf and overwhelm 
the fair fabric of justice and liberty reared for us 

by our fathers, may we no 
will lx&gt; perpetual and disp&lt; 
time to the oppressed and 
asylum in this land of libe 
tyrannies of the old world. 

t 1ki|m- that our glorious 1'nion 
- blessings for all future 
downtrodden who may seek an 
rty and equal justice from the 

When the (jllestion of einaili'i 

ipatinf! tiara was dincn—cd, ;is ¦ </seg>

            <seg id="p066">

66 


v 


Look, if von please, at the effort put forth by t lie cun- 

ning politicians and traitors of our count ry. to prejudice 

the minds of the unwary airainst the President's proclama- 

tion emancipating the slaves in rebel district*. Thousands 

throughout Ike country liail their minds thus prejudiced. 

and for the time being poisoned, airainsl the measure; and 

yet. that icrv same measure has. perhaps, done more to 

&gt;rive us strength, both at home and abroad, than any other 

adopted by the administration. And perhaps we oagfct not 

to close our eyes to the fact, while dwelling on this subject. 

that many of the best and wisest men in the country be- 

Uere that if the slaves should all 1m' liberated, during the 

prog I en of the war. it will be a just retribution on those 

who originated the rebellion; for there is a universal eon- 

vietio] anionsr all classes, t !&gt; 
or indirectly, the cause of the 
ought to l&gt;e dest roved, and 
permanent peace I'lin possibly 

nt slavery was. either directly 
war. and that the guilty cause 
that without this, no lasting, 
cured. If it stands in the 

way of victory, of peace, of a restored and perpetual Union, 
let it die the death of the malefactor. 

Kilic -~&gt;\)i of January. Is(i4. Governor Sauiulrrs hail tin- mipleasure 
of |&gt;lacinj. r his signature to a joint resolntioa of 
•jrislaiurr oomplimeHted the territorial troofw: 

Kl soi \ in. That the thanks of tin' | pie of this territory 
re due. and are hereby tendered through their Legislative 

Assembly, to the brave men 
ritory to battle for the presi 
we look with pride and sat 
soldiers have made since 1h&lt; 

who have gone from our tcrrvation 
of our country. That 
sfaction upon the record our 
war of the rebellion was in- 

augurated, and that their unsurpassed bravery on every 
field, from Fort Donelson, where the blood of Nebraska first 

Nebraska first 

mingled with the crimson tide of the brave of other stal 
who consecrated with their lives the first preat victory 

rated with their lire* the Hrnt preat victory 

the war. down to the heroic 
where the sons of our territi 
one of the most brilliant an 

use of Cape liirardea 

ry. almost unaided, achieved 

lories that will 

adorn the annals of the present Htruggle, a record which 

commands the admiration of the world, and places us under 
a debt of gratitnde to those brave men which we can nerei 
repay. 

How llioron-rlilv tin- cmeim.i-s patriotic effort! were rappk </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
67 



iiit*QitHi i'\ I'm* woMit'ii ot tno icrniior»j &lt;ip jH.*iirs i rom iiicir con* 
tribulions to tin- St. Louis Sanitary Fair of is»i4, to the amount 
of f 10.00(1. antl to the Chicago Fair of 1865, to the amount of 
s_'.~,. immi. where Mrs. Alvin Saunders and Mrs. O. F. Davis 
MTCfC aciivc ]&gt;ai'tiri|&gt;aiits. The seiitimenis &lt;if loyalty and patriotism 
| iiM'laiiiietl bj the &lt; iovernor were amply supplemented by the 
utterance of the Legislature of 1m,1 _': 

¦t)i.\ hi). That, disavowing-, as we do, the right of any 

state or states to nullify the federal law or secede from 
the federal I'nion, we regard such recession or nullification 
as treason agaiust the United States, and believe it to be the 
tirst and holiest duty of the Government to uphold its laws 
and repress treason. 

To a resolution of a republican member of the Legislature — 
i:&gt; solved, tluit whenever an American Citizen unsheathes his 
sword ami shoulders his musket, at his country's call, he should 
leave the spoilsman, the partisan and the politician in a namegrare 
behted him." there came a democratic response: "'That 
WC hold rebels against our government to be outside the pale of 

its protection 

t messages furnish the landmarks of the Union Pacific 
d. In the tirst one. of December. lNf.l. we have the follow- 

\ Mere fiance at the ma| 

i of the country "ill eoininee 
he Plattc Valley which i 

every intelligent mind that 
through the heart, and HUM 
hraska. is t&lt;i furnish the 11 
road uhii-li is to connect Um 

nearly the entire length of &gt;*e- 

Ite for the Great Central Kail- 
Atlantic with the Pacific States 

and- Territories. Throiifrh Nebraska must pass, in a few 
vears, not onlv the travel and trade between the Eastern 

and Western portion of our 

country, but also much of the 
• Old and New World. 

ii nd travel between th 

In his message in .lanuary. 
Legislature: 

1894. he thus congratulated the 

Conprrss passed a bill, at 
the inaujniration of the pr&lt; 
for the construction of the &lt; 

the first regular w — jnii after 

"I ministration, providing 
ntnene- 

tac 1'iiith meridian, within the Territory of </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
68 


thence ucstwardly to the Pacific coast, with tliri-p branches 
from the place of bepinninp eastward to the Missouri Hiver. 
With these magnificent works successfully prosecuted, connecting 
directly with the great cities of the Atlantic and 
Pacific, with the l&gt;enefits of the homestead act, of a virgin 
and fertile soil, of exhaust less salt springs, with I climate as 
salubrious as exists in the world none can hesitate to predict 
for Nebraska gi^aatfc strides in the attainment of 
wealth and power. 

In January 1866, his declaration was: 

It will be gratifying to you. and the people of the Territory 
to know that the work on the frreat Inion Pacific 

Itailrciail. which is to pass 
Nebraska, is [W llgl I mlng at 
work of grading, bridging, 
LTi'ssinsr lunch more rapidly 
our most san&lt;ruine people. 

through the entire length of 
a very considerable rate. The 
mid preparing the ties, is pro- 

than had been anticipated by 
I feel fully authorized to say. 

that unless some unforeseen misfortune attends this great 
enterprise, more than fifty miles westward from Omaha 
will be in readiness for Ilie cars before your next annual 
meeting. 

In January. ls»;&lt;;, be reported tifty-tive miles of track &lt;&lt;&gt;m- 
Bitted, and grading and bridging for niety-five miles, and predicted 
that loll miles of the rand would be ready for the ears 
within twelve month*. Hut all apeenlatiou were to be exceeded 
daring the year of 1806, since on the 11th of January, lstiT, 
&lt;-ars were ranting a distance of 298 miles from the initial point, 
and 362 miles of track were laid, in that year. 

On the 2nd day of December, 1883, as one of the national (Nun 
missioners to locate the initial point of the road, with spade in 
hand to "break ground," the governor delivered the following 
addi-i 

Mr. l'nxiilnit. l.mlitx ami fit iitlntit 11 

We have assembled here to-day for the purpose of Inaugurating 
the greatest work of internal improvement 
ever projected by man. an improvement which is to unite 
with iron bands the shores of the Atlantic and Pacific, and 
to connect not only the jrreat cities of the Atlantic with 
Ihose of the Pacific Ocean, but to open the gatewav of com- </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
69 


In 


of 


which spans a continent, is destined to Ixrome the 
thorough f tire not only for manufactured articles of our own 
New Kn^land. the agricultural staples of the valley of the 
Mississippi, and t lie (fold and silver of the Kocky Mountains 
and the Sierra Nevadas. hut also the silk of the Indies, 
the inaniifai-tiires of England and France, and the teas of 
( 'hiiiii. It may indeed lie appropriately termeil the "Nation's 
Great Highway." 

This, my fellow citizens, is no mere work of fancy, or fiction. 
1 • 11 1 a substantial reality. The people, the irreat masses, 
ha\c taken hold of it. and the work this day so auspiciously 
inaugurated, is destined tci go steadily forwanl to coin- 

pletion. Whether viewed in tin 
measure or regarded in the litfht 
the Nation is so deeply interest! 
that it cannot fail. 

I i trh t of a prudential war 
of a commercial enterprise, 
¦d in its speeds" completion 

The parties who participated 

here today in this initial 

step, represent the diversity of interests which are combined 
to push it forward to a complete consummation. You behold 
here the engineer, the mechanic, the lalnirer. the physician, 
the lawyer, the capitalist, the editor, the telegraph operalor, 
all takintr part in the exercises of this hour and for sui'h. 
throughout the whole country, is composed of backers of 
this great enterprise. I cannot close these brief remarks 
without expressing the jrratitude which I feel to the President 
and the Congress of the Inited States for the "rood 
judgment which they have displayed la jfivinfj life to this 
ma^ic work, and conirrat ulat infr the people of the whole 
Union on its eommenccment and the eheerisjg prospeets of 
its early completion. 

advaurt* of f'onymn, th«* (iovtM'iior said in his mt»ssa*;t 

1861: "You should, in my opinion. Brge Comqnm to CMd ,\ 
Homestead law at its next session." And in that of 1XIV4, we 

the following: 

Anoig The ninny t*eiu*tu'ent arts of legislation, passed l&gt;v 
the Congress of the I nited States, since viiur last session. 
ihhv l&gt;e mentioned the '"Homestead Hill." In fact, its success, 
so just to the sett ler. and so wise as a measure of 
national policy, seemed hopeless, while the reins of government 
were held by such men as controlled the administra- 

tion preceding that of onr present chief ma^ist rate. The&gt; 
honor of the prompt passage of this jjreat measure, U duo 
to }*resi&lt; lent I iucoln and his iMtlitical friends in (onifres^ </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
70 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL BOCIETI 

This question received special attention in all his mess;i_ 
and after various efforts, congressional action was secured, and 
th&lt;' transition made from the territory to a state, (luring the terra 
of his incumbency. Without any exaggeration, his term of office 
included the most eventful period of our history, and 110 state or 

territory had a more faithful officer or devoted war gou 


than Nebraska. In the message of 1861, we read 

We are surrounded by trilx-s of Indians who are more or 
less tampered with by wicked men. and traitors of the 
I'nion: we are in the immediate vicinity of the battle fields 
of the rebellious states-, the regular troops, who have been 
recently garrisoning our forts, are being- rapidly withdrawn: 
large numbers of our beat and bravest young men have been 
summoned from their homes to aid in figtitinsr the battles of 
the Union: we have a long range of frontier settlements exposed 
to the tomahawks and scalping knives of savages. 
You should, therefore, urge upon Congress, in the strongest 
terms, the necessity of furnishing our people with the means 
of defending- their homes and families. 

The subject received attention in his official commuuic, 
January s. lstJ4: 


True. Nebraska has no particular calls made for tin 
ices of her militia lately: nothing, however, but the 
liberality of the general government in supplying our wants 
with government troops has prevented it. 

In I8fio his reference to the theme was as follow 

In the late call for troops to assist in protecting our 
frontier settlers from the Mvagcm, I found myself obliged to 
rely entirely upon the patriotism and liberality of the people 
in order to raise and ecpiip a sufficient force to give 
pro]&gt;er relief to the suffering people. 

It was recorded in the message of .lanuary !t. 1SC0. that: 

The Indian War upon our Western lxirder to which I adverted 
in my last annual message, still continues. It was 
hoped tuat with the close of the rebellion these troubles 
would cease: but this hope has proved trroundless. Emboldened 
by success, the savage tribes who have committed 
these outrages upon the lives and property of emigrants. 
and upon the Overland Stage line, and I'aeifio Telegraph, </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
71 


murderous forages; and outrages the most utro&lt;-i&lt;nis ami 
wanton in their character are of frequent occurrence. Nothing 
will, in- my judgment, give us peace upon the plains, but 
the employment of the most vigorous measures to hunt out 
and severely punish the authors of these outrages. 

After &lt;lov. Batter (of tin- Statei had e— retd a Legislature 
on the 4th of July. 18M, for tin- .-lotion of Ulitcd Stairs BMMV 
tor. CoagKM ordered the Territorial ( iiiviTiioi 1 lAlvin Sauu&gt;: 
to convene tlif Legislature for the purpose of adopting a "condition 
precedent" to tin- State's admission into the Union, hi 
cordingly he issued his proclamation February 14th. 1S»&gt;7, and 
his message to the Legislature February L'Oth. 1807. Against 
the slate legislature amending the provisions of the constitution, 
whii h as voted u]&gt;on by the people recognize*! only white voters, 
the democrats entered their protest in a series of state resolutions 
in lstiS; while at the same time there was not a unity of 
opinion among republicans on the questions of the right of the 
Siati- to act. and the policy of extending the elective franchise 
to tin- people of color. Indeed, (lovei-nor Saunders. the very embodiment 
of national republicanism, said in his proclamation. 

to the Legislature 

It no doubt would ha\c 

&gt;. 

«&gt; MM satisfactory to you. 
have l&gt;een to me. if CoafrreM 
this question directly to the 
&gt;ad of requiring of you. who 

;is 1 frankly conffss it would 
had piven the settlement of 
people of the Territory, inst 

were not particularly instructed on the subject, to tak 
upon yourselves the whole responsibility of deciding thi 
subject for them. 

&lt;»n I he other question he affirmed 

The day, in my opinion, is not far distant when property 
qualification*, educational qualifications, and color qualifications, 
as precedent to the privilege of voting, will be known 
no more by the American people: but that intelligence and 
manhood will be the only qualifications necessary to entitle 
an American citizen to the privileges of an elector. 

At this time the amendment to the t'nited States Constitution 
had not passed, establishing impartial suffrage, but in 1S70 two </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
72 


Ivniiii racy of Nebraska accept the adoption of all amendments 
of the fundamental law of the land as a formal settlement of 

tin- i|iiesiions disposed of thereby 

Tlie Stale's admission, and the suffrage (|iiestion both settled 
and out of the eontest. in 1S70 the republicans endorsed (irain's 
administration, commended congress for a reduction of the burdens 
of taxation and extended sympathy to (iennany in her 
stru^jrle with France; while the democrats resolved. "That all 
taxation, to be just, must be for a public purpose, equal, and 
uniform: that the national pwiUWll has no right to lew a 
lax upon one individual to advance or promote the interest of 
another." 

The condition, to which the state was to fire assent, was, 
That within the State of Nebraska there should bo no denial 

of the elective franchise, by reason of color or race." except to 
untaxed Indians. This having been complied with, the stale 
was formally admitted by the president's proclamation of March 
1. 1M7, when (iovernor Saunders was superseded by &lt; lovernor 
liavid Hutler. On retiring he indulged in a few parting words 
to a constituency that, in full, reciprocated his confidence and 


TO I'll K PEOPLK OK NEBRASKA 

Executive Office, 

Omaha. Nebraska, March ti, 1 

1 have i his (lav received official notice from the suite Department 
at Washington, of the President'* Proclamation 
announcing that the Legislature of Nebraska lias accepted 
the conditions proposed by Congress, and declaring the fact 
that Nebraska is admitted as MM of the inde|«Miilent states 
of the I'nion. The Coiernor elect under the state organization 
l&gt;einff now ready to take charge of the office, my duties 
as the Chief Executive of the Territory this day cease. 

I take pleasure, before retiring- from this office, in availing; 
myself of this opportunity of returning my sincere thanks 
to the people of the Territory for their uniform kindness, 
and for the alacrity and promptness with which every official 
demand upon them has l&gt;eeii honored, whether in war 
or in peace. No period of time of the same lenyth since the </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
7:5 


orpani/ation of our (loverninent has be.-n M &gt;\entful :nul 
full of interesting 1 history as h;is l&gt;een the six years I have 
been honored with an official connect ion with the people 
of Nebraska, and it j^ives me irreat pleasure lo know that 
peace and general prosperity now prevail throughout our 
whole country, anil especially to know that no country can 
truthfully boast of greater peace or more genuine prosperity 
than ran Nebraska. 

Especially do I feel proud of the financial condition of 
le Territory. Six years ajro the debt of the Territory was 
ullv two dollars for every man. woman and child in it. and 
ic warrants of the trea»nrv were selling at from twenty- 
V« to thirty cents on the dollar. Now her paperpar, 
and she is ready to pay every dollar of her indebtedc^s 
of whatever character, so that Hie new state can comence 
her career without a dollar of debt hauling- over 
ler. This condition of affairs, me far as my knowledge \¦nds. 
is without a parallel in the history of new states. 

iinse for mutual and jreneral congratulation 

While our officers and people 
finances of our country, they 

have beea so attentive to the 
have not l&gt;een idle or wanting 

other important particulars, for during the war Nebraska 
urnished as many troops as any other state or territory 
1 proportion to its population, anil no soldier from any 
larier showed more valor or made a l&gt;etter record for 
&gt;ravery or true soldierly conduct than did those from Neraska. 
So. viewing it from any stand|M&gt;int. I feel proud 
hat 1 have been permitted to occupy so conspicuous a posion 
among a |&gt;eople so patriotic, prompt, and appreciative. 
Vith my best wishes for the prosperity of the whole people, 
f our new State, and for its ¦freat .-uccess, I am, etc.. 

Alvin Saunders </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>