<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers II Protein Requirements for Growing Heifers</title>
               <date value="1923-01">1923-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">■ &gt; Bulletin |S4 January, !!&gt;•_'; Growth Studies of Dairy Heifers II PROTEIN REQUIREMENTS FOR GROWING HEIFERS MEN \IKV Ml -SB.WDKV AfiRTOlTLTUKAL EXPERIMENT STATION rilE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LTXCOLX </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">GROWTH STUDIES OF DAIRY HEIFERS II 1 PROTEIN REQUIREMENTS FOR GROWING HEIFERS DEPARTMENT OF DAIRY HUSBANDRY" Proper growth ami development depends upon a satisfac - tory ration. Such a ration must contain the right balance be - tween the various nutrients. Because it is so intimately con - nected with the body development, protein is perhaps the most important &gt;injrle nutrient for growing animals. Protein, there - fore, nay be and frequently is the limiting factor in successful grow tli of ilairv cattle. If any portion of the feed may be said to play a dual role, it is the protein. The nitrogenous part of the ration serves a necessary function in providing for growth of body parts and further may !&gt;e ued a&gt; a source of energy for the carrying on i.f UhIv functions. It mav serve in either wav. but not in both ivs at the Mime time. As a contribution to the subject of pro- is related to the growth of young animals, these data arc t METHODS OF INVESTIGATION For the experiment eight animals were selected, consisting ix purebred Jersey heifers and two purebred Holstein eifers. These were divided into two groups, each of which ontained three Jerseys and a Holstein. In the experiment, \\;i- exercised to pair related animals. In every case the pairs were half sisters and in some in - inces had "■"&gt; per cent of the same ancestral inheritance. The inscription of the animals used in this experiment is given in Fable 1. while the grouping is shown in Table 2. Group 1 in- led Jersey heifers Nos. 1, .'}. and 5 and Holstein heifer Xo. . I hi- group \va&gt; placed on a high protein plane of nutri- tion. Group -! consisted of Jersey heifers Nos. "2. 4. and &lt;&gt; and Holstein heifer No. -J."&gt;r.. and was placed on a much lower al - lowance of protein. The feeding trials were first started on January 1. 1919. with pairs I. II, and III (See Table 1) but con - siderable difficulty was experienced in getting the animals to 'Bulletin 181. "Effect of Light and Heavy Feeding of Wide and Narrow Rations." was the first of this series. This experiment was conducted by W. B. Nevens and J. W. Hendrickson. under the direction of J. H. Frandsen. The data were organized and prepared for publication by H. P. Davis and Benjamin Masurovsky. 'The experiment was carried on under a general plan outlined by H. P. Armsby. late Director of the Institute of Animal Nutrition of the Pennsylvania State College. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Kxperimkm Station Rii.i.ktin 1^1 J*f L 5 a ■ 3 ■ _^3 s .3 { F z z m z 1 .1 a a i I ! t 3 3 a o* cy 1 f I 1 "3 O O * I 1 1 i III W 05 O I s ill in 5^ =c x C ffft I H •-« i-H § § cm m no oo I &gt; £ g 0 o - = .2 1 1 I o o | I I t I I = Ji £ ■O B£St b£b£ a « « I | ! I I 3 3 3 a o&gt; c? -* 3T os l t- t- t- 1- S S K &amp;S S - S I I « 00 00 © N 1 1 X 34 04 r* r~* '^ S 2 2 til &lt; S &lt; 4 I* ■% &gt;^ &gt;^ -H N 5O I 8 &gt;&gt; &gt;■ -5 -: s c &gt;&gt; S 2 £ = = -t&gt; 33 35 10 3 S l M s a &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Growth Sti"dies &lt;»k Dairy Heifers 5 hv i in X I A r. l.v c; msiune the original ration. Chances were made in the ration by substituting &gt;n&lt;rar for a part of the starch. Collection of data coiiM'iiHi'iitlv cliil not l&gt;i&gt;gin until March. l!&gt;10. Pairs I and II were mi the ex]x»rini«*nt from March 7. 1!&gt;11&gt;. to November 28, 19, inclusive, or 2W&gt; day-. Pair III continued until April 17, l!&gt;20. or :i tula] of 4(&gt;7 da vs. Pair IV started on January 3, In calculating tbe rations to be used, the following points 1. The energy furnished must be of such quantity as to pport normal growth without material fattening of the ani- al- l'he quantity of pMtoia in the low protein ration must slightly greater than the minimum demanded by current feeding standards. The protein of the two rations was to be derived in ■finite proportions from the same feeding stuffs. i i — — J. The daily intake of energy per 1,000 pounds live weight i- to l»e a- nearly equal as possible. The necessary adjustments re to !&gt;e made by the use of commercial corn starch and sugar. Adjustment- in the bulk of the ration were to be made variations in the quantity of straw fables :*&gt; (A and B) and 4 (A ami B) present the variou 1920, and continued until September 11, li»20, a total of 252 days. were considered I'mu.f. 2. — Grouping of emperimeiUai heifer roup No. of cow 1 Breed J«»ey Name Neola Age in months No. of at beginning pair Ration of experiment H I J . 8 J CFBCy .... Nona 18 II High proteii 5 Jersey Gloaming 12 III 2 Holstein ,Jewey Quintelle Blossom 9^ IV j 16} I „ 4 Jersey Gladiola 14} II j Low •proteii 6 Jersey Buttercup 11 III 256 Holstein . Queen 9 IV j </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 ) ■y Y.-^\ Crude' Samole Kind of feed roa- Crude Crude' Crude' nit I na»a free True S.-&gt; Mined protein ftt Brer extrart protein '•niro Lb,. Lb,. Lb,. U /.'. ife.. 7&lt;.. FED MARCH 7 TO MAY 31, 1919. INCLUSIVE 1 18 Alfalfa K.50 1.03 .11 2.9! .W&gt; t»l 147 Wheat straw 3.00 .08 .ill 1.1 l.tl .01 It! &lt;"..rn meal 3.10 .34 .12 .OS 2!22 !m ■ 'ilmeal 1.75 .57 M .18 .62 .SO 2.C4 I.M 1.M Ml 1.78 .57 .12 .18 .62 .SO •anut meal 1.70 .72 ■ .21 Jl .76 .4. Surri. 3.52 .01 S.7(l Total 21.57 2.75 .S» 4.S2 10.5S 2.01 ll.W Crude nutritive ratio, irt. Nutritive ratio trut- protein to net eaercy, 1 FED JT'NE 1 TO JUNE IS, 1919. INCLUSIVE 14)1 \ Italia nWl 8.&amp;0 1.14 1S7 Corn meal LH M .13 2.93 2.74 Wi ■i.:n .21' 2.64 1« Oil meal I.TI .57 It ..Mi 1.5« Mf Pianut meal 1.70 .20 SI .711 1 IM Oat straw H.«l II l l« .OS 144 Starrh 4 Total I 2S.W t. Id Crude nutritive raUo, 1:5.84. Kati., * trur n'' 'n^rn FED BEGINNING JUNF. 14. IRIS TO CLOSE OF EXPER1M ISO QHiaw... 5.0 .17 148 Alfalfa meal X.o ! 1.14 157 Corn meal S.I JM 117 .11 180 ■ Oil meal 1.75 .57 145 Peanut meal 1.70 M ■_'.. 141 Starrh 1.70 Total 21.7S 2.94 .64 Crude nutritive ratio, 1:5.53. Ratio . 'Figures based upon chemical analysis -Computed from Bulletin 142. Pa. Agr. true protein to net enerr of feed*, i See Table 5. Exp. Station ■ hiily rations fVil to tlie animals throughout the experiment. Computations were made of the pouinl~ of true protein and tin- therms of net enerjrv of the rations used in this experi - ment. 1 For corn meal the corrected net enerev value of B&amp;j — — — -.__ .....^ # .. therms per KM) lbs. was used." For starch and sugar the esti united values of SI. 79 therms and M.:i therms jn-r KMt Ihs. dn matter, respectively, were employed. All the feeding stuffs used in this ex|&gt;eriment were analyzed Ta. A*-r. Exp. Station Bulletin No. 142 -Journal of Agricultural Research, Vol. 10. p. 612 'Sept. 17, 1»18 1 r."l-A. — High protein daily ration //&lt; r IJJOO pounds of /ir&lt; weight, Jersey heifer*. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">&lt; iRiiwni S'ii i&gt;ik&gt; di Dairy Hkikki:* . r vi MM •&gt;-!{. - -I.tnr protein daily n ttion per 1JKX) pound* of lire id lit. -I i rx 1/ heiterx F"« tampte XU4M Cru*, Cnrf* | Cnrf. Lit^S^i Tn.' ■ Net v aaiMd j protein fat fiber extract ! protein energy' I /-■-. /--&gt;«. It*..! Uu. (aj T:,r,n,. FED MARCH 8 TO MAY 31, 1919, INCLUSIVE '** *!'•"» h»y 5.54 .67 .07 IDS i us io , o,&gt; T AJlana nay 5.54 .67 .07 1 .95 1 68 3» 1 90 :l!» 1.90 1 Wheat ,traw 2..5O M .04 .«« % 01 IS m 1 fs s £ a \ 1 a Wheat «tra .04 ■ II .IX Corn mt'al OS .11. 1.47 ii 1.75 S; - 17 1J : 16 I i 3 HI meal m ii .12 !.O2 H Peanut meal 1.11 M J.l ■Jii IS 1.04 IMT .m l.»8 u« I ;tar,-h 5.18 4.2S Tnt.l JJ9M 1.80 .40 S.« 11.84 ~1J&gt; ~ ~l7.gO T..,al M I il.si ISO II. Ml I lie nutritive ratio, 1 *JK. Ratio of true protein to net mercy. 1*.«T. l^D JUNE 1 To JUNE 12, 1919. INCLUSIVE 'Y/ ,*, trmw , 600 •-" 08 2.05 2.59 .04 '.'IIS Alfalfa roea! 4.66 .fi) .07 1.60 160 l «n &lt; &lt;;rn meal 1.72 .18 .06 .03 Tl 98 Katio of true protein to net enemy FED JUNE 1 TO JUNE 12, 1919. INCLUSIVE 'I Oat *tra« .114 LM M Alfalfa me.! i: 68 S !o7 flSo tiw !m I «o « (ornmeal 1.72 .18 .06 .03 l « Ti ol i (Hi meal .97 .31 06 10 34 27 \rt P^nu.™.! .93 .38 .07 .IS I £ ifj 3 .i« M SlNtar 1.S9 . . iii | .,, *""* :^__!_ii!L!___ ::: i :^_ :: a T ""' «B.W 1.79 1 .«4 ».W ! lt.4» 1.1 » iTw iii Total JO.go 1.70 ll i.'&lt;l 1«.4» 1.15 11.80 &lt; rude nutritive rmno, 1:10.1. Ratio of trut b nutritive ratio, 1:10.1. Ratio of true protein to net energy, l:10.ZC. FED JUNE 18 TO JULY SI, 1»1» gtg ': s ? -8 :I5 S 'S i it SuUII- 1 " ,S S8 - 07 15 - 20 M •«* tmrrh ■■'■■ «■«• I ::: 6 ;S ;; 5 Ji ToUl ' 18.78 l.« ! .31 : 8.8S~! it.4&lt; 1.14 UM protein to net enerfy JLY SI. 1919 IIH.2H. FED JUNE 13 TO .11 1.39 1.60 Jt Peanut m»ii S««ar M MM .81 -.29 LM Total 19.73 1.6S .31 3.25 12.45 1.14 IIM le nutritive ratio, 1 :10.05. Ratio of true protein to net energy, 1:W.8S. ~ rmp *ocow 1 to august 31. i»i» I *«*" , 400 41 .05 1.37 1.73 .08 1.39 ade nutritive ratio, 1 :10.05. Ratio of tru. protein to net energy 1 iM.t.i. FEU AUGU8T 1 TO AUGUST 31, 1919 M Alfalfa meal 4.66 .ft! .07 1.60 ISO .« 160 M ( orn meal 1.72 .18 .06 03 1 -&gt;3 n 98 Corn meal 1.72 .18 .06 11 "il meal .97 .SI .06 .10 34 28 8« meal I M .:\'.t M Peanut me^ 93 .38 .07 .15 , .20 iss iS? Peanut meal fSSL 122 1 - 48 i-2i Sufar 1.48 *■■■■■ LM ... 4.88 5.89 _Ig*»L.-^__»j»_. ! '•«» ■« "si it.47 Ti"7 iT.it" T..a: 1.14 i I 80 l ide nutritive ratio, 1:10.06. Ratio of tn* le nutritive ratio. 1:10.1)6. Ratio of true crotein to net energy. 1:10.35. FED SEPTEMBKR 1. 1919. TO CLOSE OF EXPERIMENT nroM-in to net energy. FED SEPTEMBER I, 1919. TO ( LOSE OF EXPERIMENT 9S* J™» . 40 ° * &lt;» 1«5 1.54 .01 1J8 I VI Oat «raw 4.00 .24 I M Alfalfa m«l 4.6« ,6a .07 1.60 1.60 .33 160 Alfalfa meal 1.66 .63 !o7 ( i.rn meal 1.72 .18 .06 .03 1 23 n »« 1 Corn meal 1.72 .18 !06 !«!&gt; (HI meal .97 .11 .06 .10 28 86 Oil meal .97 ..11 !o6 Peanut meal 98 .38 .07 .15 .20 .39 181 144 atmrtk 7.47 ... ... 7.37 6 . u Total 19.75 1.74 2H 3.S8 | 12.28 1.14 11.81 ( rude nutritive ratio, 1 :9.4o. Ratio of true protein to net energy, 1:10.35. 'Figures based upon chemical analysis of feedn i See Table 5 &gt; Computed from Bulletin 142. Pa. Air. Exp. Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station 1U i.i.ktix 1&amp;4 Table l-A.—Hiyh protein daily ration //&lt; r I/KXJ pounds of lire weight. Hohtein heifer*. Ke«i Crude" Sample Kind of feed ! on- Crude- Crude Crude' nitrocen-free True Net No. { mined protein fat fiber extract protein nitty Body measurements wen- taken monthly of the height at withers, heijrht at hips, width at hips, heart girth, and length of IkxIv. In all cases three measurements taken the same day Ee averaged, except in the case of length of ImmIv where in ain instances only one measurement was taken. The weights p taken on one day each week and the monthly weight n&gt;ed was the last one taken during the month. ! U&gt;... U . I LU. Lh 4 . Uu. t Ltu. ! Therm: FED JANUARY 1 TO MARCH 31, 19W 154 Oat straw 4.00 i .24 .03 1.65 1.54 I .08 1.39 149 Alfalfa meal 8.87 ' 1.19 .IS 3.05 2.86 M 3.04 1ST Corn meal 3.28 .35 .12 .07 2.35 .21 2.80 l«0 Oil meal 1.82 .5S .12 .19 .M .52 1.(1 151 Peanut meal 1.76 .72 .14 2- Ix .7» l.tt 144 Starch 2.82 ... MM ... 2.21 — . , [■ - | Ilia Total I 22.S5 S.M I .M MR IU.55 2 12 ' 12.70 Crude nutritive ratio, MA Katiu of true protein to net energy. 1:5.99. FEI&gt; APRIL 1. 1920. TO CLOSE OF EXPERIMENT 154 Oat straw 5.0 .Hi .0* 2.07 l.K .04 , 1.74 149 Alfalfa meal 8.5 1.14 .13 Ml VU M 2.91 157 Corn meal ».l .34 .12 M M .2© 2.64 160 Oil meal 1.75 .57 .12 .18 M .50 1.56 151 Peanut meal 1.70 .70 .14 Tt .SC T'l 1.5t 144 Sureh 1.70 ... l.«7 ! H Total 21.75 1.05 .64 T.U MM 11.80 Crude nutritive ratio, 1 Ratio of true protein to net enerty. 1 Jk.1t. 'Fi|fur»s based upon cheanical Hnal&gt;&gt; s &gt;»t (■■■ .able K.I ('.imputed from Bulletin 142. Pa. Art. Exp. Station. for their fheniiea] composition as fi-cqijeotly a- new feed pur- chases were inadi&gt; (see Table •"&gt;). Complete daily records &lt;&gt;f feed consuniption were kepi a- aociirately a- powible. A de tailed account of feed consunied l»y each individual i- given ii Table 6 while Table 7 gives the nutrients consumed. The re- sults obtained in tlii-. work are based primarily upon the month- ly records of the animals showing jrain or loss in body measure nients. lxxlv weight, and the requirement of crude protein pel pound pain in body. EFFECT ON SKELETAL DEVELOPMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p009">(ntowTH Stvdies of Dairy Heikeks 9 I'ahi.k 4-11.— Low protein daily ration per 1.000 pounds of Hoe ireif/ht. Ilnlxtiiit heifers. FH.-1 Crude Sampl Kind at (end Crude' Crude' , Crude nitrorw-free True= j Nat N •timed protein (at !44 Starch 6.81 Total 20.75 2.06 .36 &lt; 93 12.16 . 1.M , 1X.70 ratio, 1:8.24. Ratio at true protein to net energy, 1:9.S3. FED M\Y 1. 1920. TO CLOSE OF EXPERIMENT 4.00 .24 4.66 .63 1.72 .18 .97 .31 M .38 7.47 .03 1.65 1.54 .03 1.39 .07 1.60 1.50 .33 1.60 .06 .03 1.23 .11 .98 .06 .10 .34 M -»6 49 Alfalfa m&gt; Cum meal I .,1 m.-ai ,14 M M Peanut .07 .15 20 .3* : .87 :)7 ti.ll rch T..i 71 .29 I 3.53 12.18 1.14 11.81 ratio, 1:9.4. Ratio at true protein to net energy. 1:10.35. s of feeds. I See Table 5.) based upon chemical analys imputed from Bulletin 142. Pa. Agr. Exp. Station. Height at hi]&gt;- i&gt; the height from the floor to the top of tli«' hook or hip hone. The width at hips is the extreme dis - tance from the outside of the hook or hip bones. Length of ImhIv i- the distance from the lower front point of the shoulder Uiiic t&lt;&gt; the rear of the pin bone. If the body of the animal Ik 1 considered a- a parallelogram, then the length of the body ooiTMfMads nearly to the diagonal. The measurements and weights of individual animals appear in Table 8. The ImkIv measurements showing skeletal development of the experiment*! animals were computed (see Table 0) as follows: 1. The average monthly gains of body weight ami measure - ments were calculated in the following way. The total gain for the entire experimental period was divided by the number of dare in the period, the quotient multiplied by 30 (average number of day- in month), and the product considered as the average monthly rain. aiwr i otnet protrin «ertjr&lt; I /.(.-. IJu. Lb,. LU. ; JUx. 1 /.',.. i TKtrm,. FED JANUARY I. 1980, TO APRIL 30, 1920 1.65 1.54 .06 ' 1.39 1.94 1.81 .40 1.93 .04 1.46 .13 1.73 .12 .40 .33 1.02 .18 .24 i: 1.06 S.71 ... 5.S7 54 49 57 60 51 &lt; )«t straw Alfalfa meal Com men! &lt;&gt;.! meal Peanut meal 4.00 5.83 2.03 1.15 1.13 .24 .76 Ji .37 .46 _4 .Tf .01] .08 .08 .08 .09 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nkhha&gt;k\ Km'kim \ik\t Station Hi i.i.ktin I s ! Table •"&gt;. — Anuh/tri* of feed mu-tl for heifer* on th protein experiment. The following taWK- jrivos tli«- ilati'- to whicli the ff&lt;«l analysis applies for the different animals on the protein ex periment equals total gain and N the niiinber of days in the experimental period. ~2. To find the average monthly &lt;rain in U«lv weight on the basis of 1.000 ll&gt;s. live weight of an animal, tin- weight at the beginning of experiment was used. 1.000 ll&gt;s. live weight. A\. M. (i. tM|iial- average monthly gain per ■■« . I. \V. equals initial weight T. (i. ■ •■'.&lt;! iMjiiitls tin- average monthly jrain. T. (i. At. M. (J. v 1.000 equals ;ivci\i«v monthly ira in per I. W. or body weight at Ix'friniiiiiir of experiment. M- Name of feed Water Ash Ether Crude extract Aber Crude • NitraajMi proteia free extract 1 Prr err '. ' /'■ Prr crni 44 M i~ i'J 50 51 53 56 s Starch Peanut meal Wheat straw Alfalfa hay Alfalfa meal Oat atraw Peanut meal Oat straw . Oat straw Wheat straw Corn mm! Unwed oil meal .81 .15 8.98 3.77 12.71 727 13.8S CM 11.41 IM 7.2K KXh 4.13 3.87 H.74 4.44 X.76 4.23 9.66 1.44 7.«2 C.45 I I .00 ; .00 11.8* 14. .Ml 1.61 I 1.39 lft.lt ! 1.55 :(1.16 I 1.44 'IS. til I 8.S5 16.3K I .70 ' 42.13 I .76 41.3S 1.67 38.80 1 S.95 2.13 &gt; 7.05 10.72 .06 .375 6.82 4S.M5 .46 2.875 1.95 12.187 2.16 13.50 If 3.437 6.60 41.25 .54 3.41 .M (.11 .(7 4.22 1.75 10.94 *J1 S2.63 \*.M&gt;-r, 37.055 M.Hi :I2.2« t:i.:ti:) 21.54 41.15 38.52 42.77 71.88 U.M 150 151 158 Name i.f Starch Peanut meal Wheat straw Alfalfa hay Alfalfa meal Oat straw Peanut meal Oat straw Oat straw . Wheat straw Corn meal Linaeed oil meal r feed From March ». 1 March 8. I91S March 8, l!«l'.&lt; March 23, 1919 March », 1919 April J. 1919 May IS, 1919 December 1. IMt October 1, 1919 December 1. MM November It, 1919 March 8, 191!) March 8. 19!9 To September It, I«M November 30. 191H May 14, 1919 April 3. 1WIH November 2'J I»1S September 13. 192»i September :t( i. l»l« September 13, 19*1 November 14. 1918 September IS, 1920 Ninemhi-r M), 1918 September 13. 19&amp;1 September 13. 1(T2&lt;I </seg>
            <seg id="p011">GanwTH Sti"i»ieh t&gt;r Daisy IIkhf.ks 11 itccun ■* worrx' a to is 3:©»Occ . 2sss a g S" .5 mmbt- •*- ■ • a : i_- *&gt; axMt&gt; .m . . "5. 5 * — ususeoeo w . . oo — = — ioiowsc w . . ao CvJt-CCOOlOOO 5§ggS ■V X — T» — t~ I •- ~ 3C Tlj Oi -^ CO U3 C 1 ! S 5 5 — t-^ as «c in' -^ ci 3; eg x x ao ■tjZ ' — _oo-*u5M— ec -w 71 . TOU5OO1NU5 I0003 —I ?:ioxnio »252 »t-awt- xo^5 -5 CO -^ »O »O !M t- ••&amp; *C 7^ t— . C XN«-Wt- *S CO . »O t' CO U5 ■** X Irt »A O B j J| — i — t-«CC-X 35O~«Oi« :Sz i5 "SSSSSS «-Nffl I feN . SSSSJg :£§§§ i-«*9 S: to oc -"i" co t- Nasot- us jZ acre — ©_— . n IS £o —^» t- ?i XI0U3O 3: 3SCCU5 -TxiViS &gt;» o X35t*o^"io«t*xor:'j ,^ / *—» »^ »■-• »™&lt; f"^ «— « 1-* f— &lt; 1—* »"^ &lt; " . ; . ; . : . : ; ; ; . i Hi 1 1 1 ! I j 1 ill? !1|I»» il§liii|i«»l = 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Xkbkamva Kxi-kkimkxt Station Bili-etin 1s4 12 Table 7. — Feed nutrient* cotixmiied by individual heifer* MM» Kind of feed Analysis Water number nalysis Water Ash Ether Crude Nitro«cn Crude free Ash Ether extract free extract jmber extract Rber protein extract I M» I «ik. I «•&gt; I Urn. I Ba Lbt. \ Lb.. HEIFER NO. 1 U.,. /.*«. U». 1.1; U, HEIFER NO. 1 Alfalfa hay i 148 I 7.M Alfalfa meal \ 149 i 165.09 148 7.80 I 3.91 I .78 I 19.84 1.09 1 6.87 I 17.18 3.91 .ti 19.84 1.09 6.87 17.18 149 165.09 98.68 22.43 498.63 31.25 195.33 I 466.76 914.68 22.43 498.03 31.25 195.33 IW.7* Corn nml .....'. J 157 ! 55!i2 1S7 55.22 8.23 22.58 12.18 10.00 62.54 410.90 8.23 22.58 12. IK 10.00 62.54 410.90 Linaeed ail meal I l—l ill ail meal . . 1(0 ! 28.73 Starch 144 ' 8.13 160 : 28.73 20.09 21.96 33.38 16.26 101.62 110.65 20.09 21.96 33.38 16.26 101.62 110.65 144 ' 8.13 . .68 .00 .00 .23 1.45 , 381.77 144 S.13 M .(Ml .00 .23 1.45 , 381.77 145 ! 27.16 I 11.40 3S.76 43.86 20.63 '■ 128.94 55.37 Peanut meal 145 ;«7.1« Wheat straw .... 147 15.2S Wheat straw 156 .82 Oat straw 150 35.45 Oat straw 153 2.52 11.40 35.76 43.86 20.63 UtM 55.37 147 15.23 ' 8.71 1.93 46.10 .55 . 3.44 : 44.39 147 18.2S 8.71 1.93 46.10 .55 3.44 44.39 15« ' .82 1.72 .:« 7.47 .82 .82 8.34 1.72 M 7.47 .82 M 8.34 150 ' 35.45 25.23 4.99 118.85 1.91 11.91 150.08 25.23 4.99 118.85 1.91 11.91 150.08 153 2.52 5.68 .46 27.HT .35 2.22 26.75 153 2.52 5.6K .Iti 27.37 .:(', 2«.7.i Total SM.15 ' JM.16 ' 184.23 111.22 807.«8 S3.** 515.14 1 .672*1 » HEIFER NO. 2 IM.L'.I 111.22 wim turn 515.14 ,&lt;n.u HKIFKK NO Alfalfa meal Corn meal 149 95.39 157 29.83 160 13.33 144 8.69 145 14.99 147 7.98 156 j .82 150 27.16 153 ' 2.5» 149 95.39 57.02 12.96 288.11 18.06 112.87 269.72 57.02 12.96 288.11 18.06 112.87 269.75 269.7 157 29.83 i 4.45 12.20 6.58 5.40 33.78 221.97 4.45 12.20 6.58 5.40 33.78 22 221.97 Linseed oil meul Starch 160 13.33 11.28 12.33 18.75 9.13 57.07 62.15 11. 2H 12.33 18.75 9.13 57.07 62.15 144 8.69 1.61 .00 .(XI .64 4.03 ! 1,058.79 1.61 .00 .00 ' .64 4.03 1 ,058.79 Peanut meal Wheat straw Wheat straw Oat straw 145 14.99 6.30 li'.74 24.21 11.39 ! 71.20 30.58 6.30 1!'.74 24.21 11.39 71.20 30.58 147 7.98 4.56 1.01 24.15 .29 1.80 23.25 4.56 1.01 24.15 i M 23.25 156 ! .82 1.72 Jt 7.47 M .82 8.34 1.72 .33 7.47 &lt;J 8.34 150 | 27.16 19.33 3.82 91.07 1.46 9.13 114.»» 19.33 3.82 91.07 1.46 9.13 114.»» Oat straw in 2.s» 5.86 .4? mm se 2.2H xt.tn H«.78 112.11 62.86 4(18.57 47.,-, 292.98 1.817.S* HEIFER NO. * 5.86 .47 **M .S6 Total ■m.h 112.11 62.86 488.57 47.55 292.* HEIFER NO Alfalfa hay- Alfalfa meal Corn meal 148 7.15 3.59 .72 18.19 1.01 6.30 1.V75 149 153.07 91.49 20.79 , 4«2.29 28.98 181.12 4ST71 157 49.05 7.31 20.06 10.82 8.88 55.55 364.97 Linseed oil meal Starch 160 21.84 I 18.49 20.21 30.73 14.96 98.53 101.84 144 2.90 .54 .00 .00 .22 1.34 352.73 UM1 (.11 ..... . Peanut meal Wheat straw Wheat straw Oat straw . 145 25.00 10.50 32.91 40.38 18.99 118.69 50.97 147 15.23 8.71 1.93 , 46.10 .56 8.44 44.39 156 .82 1.72 .33 1 7.47 .82 .82 8.34 150 33.40 , 23.77 4.70 1U.9S 1.80 11.22 141.42 153 2.52 5.68 .46 I 27.37 .85 2.22 26.75 Oat straw Total 3111.98 171.80 102.11 755.S4 76.5« 474.5 HEIFER NO. 4 Alfalfa meal Corn meal 149 100.59 157 31.27 160 13.87 144 9.28 145 15.78 147 9.77 156 1.10 150 31.95 153 3.37 60.13 i:i.U7 303.81 19.04 119.02 284.41 4.66 12.79 6.90 5.67 35.42 2:12.71 Unseed oil meal Starch 11.74 12.83 19.51 ».M 59.3* 64.65 1.72 00 .00 .69 4.29 129.93 Peanut meal Wheat straw Wheat straw Ctatatraw G.63 20.77 25.48 11.99 74.92 32.17 5.59 1.24 29..-&gt;7 .35 2.21 28.47 2.29 .43 9.96 .17 1.10 11.12 11.12 22.73 4.50 107.12 1.72 10.73 135.27 Omt straw 7.60 til 36.65 .47 2.97 IM1 Total MM 123.09 66.84 539.00 49.60 310.04 1,954.5 UM </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Growth Sttmes of Dairy Heifers 13 1'ahi i I' nil n'ltrii ntx nmxtiuied l&gt;y individual heifers. (Concluded.) Nitrogen* Nitrocen- Kind of feed Analysis Water Anh EtUr Crude Nitracen Crude free number extract liber protein extract Lb.. Lb.. Lb,. Lb.. Lb.. Lb*. Lb.. Analysis Water Eth*r Crude Nitroeen Crude j free K As number ; wtraet liber protein j extract I.' HEIFER NO. 5 HEIFER NO. 5 I I I I I Alfalfa hay 148 5.78 2.91 .58 , 14.74 .82 5.11 12.77 Alfalfa hay 148 i 5.78 2.91 .58 i 14.74 .82 5.11 12.77 47.04 I 294.02 702.58 14.17 | 88.55 581.82 Alfalfa imI 140 248.60 148.53 ■ SS.76 750.50 ; 47.04 ' 294.02 702.58 Alfalfa meal . 140 248.50 i 148.53 ' 38.76 750.50 Corn meal 157 78.19 11.66 ; 31.97 17.24 14.17 88.55 581.82 •&gt;rn meal 157 : 78.19 1 11.66 ; 31.97 17.24 Unseed oil mesl 160 34.82 29.47 I 32.21 ' 48.98 23.85 I 149.10 162.36 Unseed oil meal 160 34.82 ' 29.47 I 32.21 ' 48.98 23.85 149.10 162.36 Starch 144 4.16 .76 ; .00 .00 .30 1.92 505.65 tarch 144 4.16 I .76 ; .00 .00 M 1.82 505.65 Peanut meal 145 ' 23.74 9.96 ' 31.25 38.33 18.03 112.70 48.40 Peanut meal 145 ' 23.74 9.96 j 31.25 38.33 18.03 | 112.70 ! 48.40 l'eanul meal 151 14.99 7.42 I 14.99 29.42 11.86 74.08 38.68 rVanut meal 151 14.99 7.42 I 14.88 j 29.42 11.86 74.08 38.68 Wheat straw 147 12.61 7.21 1.60 38.18 .46 2.85 36.76 Wheat straw 147 12.61 7.21 1.60 I 38.18 .44 2.85 36.76 Wheat straw 156 1.36 2.82 .53 12.26 .21 1.35 18.69 Wheat straw 156 1.35 j 2.82 .63 12.26 .21 I 1.86 13.69 Oat straw 150 j 34.63 24.64 4.87 116.11 1.86 11.63 146.62 hit straw 160 84.SS I 24.64 4.87 116.11 &gt;at straw 163 3.41 I 7.68 .62 ! 37.07 1.86 11.63 146.62 Oat straw 153 3.41 7.69 .62 37.07 .48 3.00 36.21 .48 I 3.00 I 36.21 Oat straw i:,4 20.80 41.04 3.66 : 1M.91 4.69 28.72 180.47 t straw i;,4 20.80 41.04 | 3.66 1M.81 4.59 28.72 180.47 Total 482.98 294.11 166.94 1,296.74 12S.M 77»j0» 2.4*6.01 482.98 : 284.11 166.94 1.296.74 123.66 773.01 2.466.01 HEIFER NO. « HEIFER NO. 6 Alfalfa mral 149 139.93 8S.64 i 19.01 422.63 26.49 165.57 395.64 I Orn meal 157 41.76 6.52 17.89 9.65 7.98 1 49.64 325.52 Unseed oil meal 160 19.44 16.45 17.99 27.36 13.32 83.25 90.65 Starch 144 14.06 2.60 .00 &lt; .00 1.04 i 6.51 1,712.31 Peanut meal 145 13.84 5.81 18.22 22.35 10.51 65.71 28.22 Peanut meal 151 7.58 3.74 7.68 ! 14.87 6.01 37.45 19.56 Wheat straw. . .. 147 8.18 4.65 1.03 24.61 .29 1.84 23.70 Wheat straw . 156 1.35 2.82 .58 ! 12.26 .21 i 1.35 I 13.69 Oat straw ISO 25.27 17.98 3.56 ' 84.72 1.36 8.49 106.98 oat straw 153 3.41 7.69 .62 37.07 .48 3.00 36.21 Oat straw 164 M.M ! 40.6* 8.62 I 191.64 4.64 S&amp;JS 178.35 Total I S9TJS | 192.46 I 89.95 847.15 72.18 451.09 2.994.S2 HEIFER NO. 255 181.44 , 108.45 I 24.66 , 547.96 34.35 214.67 10.19 63.72 17.07 106.71 512.99 418.70 116.20 372.50 meal 157 56.27 ; 8.39 23.01 12.41 Unwed oil mval 160 24.92 I 21.09 23.06 j 35.06 Starch 144 3.06 .57 .00 .00 .23 1.42 20.94 130.86 8.36 52.29 Peanut meal . . .. 151 26.49 13.10 26.49 51.96 Oat straw 154 I 87.87 74.72 6.48 252.06 KM 328.58 Total 330.05 226.32 103.69 899.45 91.14 I 569.67 1,817.31 HEIFER NO. 256 Alfalfa m.»l 149 96.90 , 67.82 13.16 292.66 18.35 114.65 5.43 33.92 9.15 57.21 .72 4.51 11.22 70.10 8.27 51.71 222.85 Cum meal 157 I 29.96. 4.46 i 12.25 6.60 Linseed oil meal 160 &lt; 13.86 11.31 | 12.36 18.79 MM Starch &lt;44 9.75 1.81 .00 .00 I.;s7.36 Peanut meal 151 14.19 7.02 14.18 1 27.84 :)6.S0 324.92 &gt;at straw 154 37.45 73.89 (.41 349.12 201.60 156.41 68.37 I 695.01 63.14 332.10 2,1(18.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Tabi.k %.—MeHKiiifini-iit Hi &lt; i, nix. l&gt;my. Month Weight (i«in Height at Height Width Length Me., &gt;my. Month W«%kt Ciun He«ht« Height Width Length Heart in weight witners at hips »t hip* of body firth in anight witnara at hip. at hip* of body firth U,. i Lh,. ' C-. At. I Cm. 7m. HEIFER NO. 1 /'.. Lh: ' Cm. Cm. ! Cm. ( HEIFEK NO. 1 At beginning At beginning of experiment 562 of experiment M ■U l*t 1't — »Lo«« 116.1 1IU 39.1 132.0 MM 39.1 132.0 30 2nd 595 ■ ' U«!o 116.0 t»'.- IV 0 2nd 595 48 116.0 MS.O 39.8 IK 3rd 645 TJ\ 116.5 116.7 40.7 13K.CI IV;. I 31 3rd 10.7 I3K.ll » ! 4th 12 117:7 11718 42! I ■ 3&gt; "'th 69(1 IS 118.9 118.0 42.8 1 13 .:■ 15« » i 4th H77 12 117.7 117.8 42.1 139.3 "&gt;th 69(1 IS 118.9 118.0 42.8 11.1 IS 118.9 118.0 42.8 113!$ IW. «th 747 57 118.2 118]» 44^1 141.1 ISsio «th 747 57 118.2 118.9 44.1 ll.l.i 1R5.Q M " "th 764 17 12(1. x HH.d 44.2 141.1 !«.« 8th 15 120.5 119.7 4S.d l:l«6 168.2 7th 15.0 1.16 6 &gt;i» _J_I »«h N S» 120.1 121.7 44.» 148.8 1S8.0 tth 120.1 121.7 44.» 143.h At beginning of experiment 540 tat 6M thorn 109.9 110.2 40.1 121. ti At bj^innini of experiment 560 »« tm 2Lm 109.9 110.2 40.1 121.6 1 Ui.T M •° 2nd Mi 42 110.9 117.8 39.0 I3H.'I U&lt;i.l&gt; ■«rd *fj 42 112.2 111.2 40.0 l»6.:j IM.S 2nd 39.0 136.' J« 3rd 42 1 12^2 11 l.Z VI.O 186!:! 15* M ■" 4th 646 14 1122 111.8 41.1 I M.I 1,1.:! 5th 650 4 ■ 111.6 41.4 139.1 1S6.0 Sth 683 38 111.(1 111).? 42.0 140.2 !',-.(&gt; 4th II. 1 139.1 31 -,th 41 4 139.1 Jl 6th 683 38 1 I Ml IW.7 42^0 1«*J I h"M at ■ "th V.ih 15 m.s 113.1 41.9 K«.:l 160.7 7th 11.1 ia 1*1 31 8th 719 21 114.9 112.1 43.5 1S8.8 161.0 Nth IMJ «•_. 9th 751 I 113.5 112.7 48.0 135.7 MB ■ Hth I 113.5 112.7 43.0 1S5.7 l« m I ! i At hecinning At beginning of experiment 58* 1« 5M - 1L» 108.8 111.4 40.1 l.lO.li U.i.n uf experiment 24 Ut •* 2nd H2J 40 109.3 112.2 41.9 I4ll.il 130.3 M 2nd II. H 31 3rd 666 44 109.9 113.3 41.2 134. 3rd 1 1 J U 30 M 4th 666 0 110.5 113.9 42.2 117.,- 1 S2.0 5th 667 1 112.6 112.U 42.S 135.6 1th ■M 31 :,th It 31 6th 716 19 112.3 111.2 42.8 138.5 «th ;lh S"th 759 43 , 114.1 113.6 43.0 1:17. 1 161.0 Sth 749 — 10 Lam 114.1 116.3 44.0 141.0 162.8 30 7th W.i SS'h 749 —10 Lua. 114.1 116!s 44^0 14LU 162 9th 770 21 112.3 115.8 44.1 13.".. s 1&lt;S! »th 770 21 112.3 115.8 44.1 ISM M1.0 »ii " : IM HEIFER NO. 4 HEIFER NO. 4 At beginning At beginning of experiment 5*6 of eXf&gt;erimetit I« l»t IM 0 112.6 ' U2i 37.1 121.6 146.7 21 1st H7.1 ■ 2nd 580 44 114.3 114.4 S8.0 126.8 151.0 :l() 2nd ;tf.n 12n 151.0 *l 3rd «:!.-, 55 114.5 115.4 S».6 152.0 II 3rd ■M !M.» 152.1 ft 4th 653 18 115.8 117.7 40.1 133.* 153.3 M 4th lii.l 133.x 153.3 31 *l 5th 677 24 11S.8 117.4 41.0 IM.I 159.3 :,th 41.0 13&lt;i.l 1 ». 6lh 714 37 II8I2 118!3 Al.9 MM IUA *l 6th 714 37 118.2 118.3 41.9 l-;4i *» 7'h 750 36 118.4 116.4 41.8 13*.3 16S.3 *» "'h 7S0 36 118.4 116l« 4K8 l:i»I:i 16»!; SI 8th m 32 118.1 119.7 «.l 138.7 1S7.3 »l «th 7^2 32 licil 11917 42^1 138!? 167^ M ?&lt; »th 804 22 118.8 119.9 42.8 137.7 lM.G «th 12. s 137.7 em </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Growth Stvimes ok Dairy Hkikki:- 15 Tahi.k 8. —Measurement (C«Hlclll(ll'&lt;!.) ■ ■ '- ■ ■ :- ■ Record*. -■ . . Month j W«*t Gmi» EfaMrt.t H«,ht Width Len^h i IWt L*.. i LW. Cm. C. I Cm.~\ Cm. C'iT" HEIFER NO. 5 Gain Hafht at Heifht Width Leneth Vmn fawritfct withers M hip. .t hip. of brty girTh U.. At beginning i»Kinninit i al eineriment 475 xwriment 475 M »«=. -lOLo. 110.* 111.6 SS.6 124.0 in 0 -10 Ua 35.6 124.0 139.0 2"J gj H 111J U2.« S6.3 1S0.O 1420 2nd IM 36.3 2^ W ■ U2-« 113.7 37.6 127.3 lj|o 142.0 3rd IM 56 37.6 148.0 in 4th ■•■■' » 11*.» 11«.« «8.7 i I(M uj 4th 565 I a is iia » ! S S » 38.7 14S.3 6th 5*4 1H 39.4 127.9 1M.II &gt;;th «7 4:i -1'I.X 1.17.3 156.3 7th 648 ;■■ 21 40.8 ia«.5 1 -.«.:) 8th 67:; n &gt;«"h s j? us jib as BB I 41.8 135.5 159.0 9th M iy 41.8 138.7 165.0 10th 729 17 42.1 141.6 165.0 11th 78» « 43.6 112 K 1M.0 NIIS :!•) 13th "-" 121.5 120.3 U.» 1462 '"n 44.2 14(1 168.0 Mi l-&gt; 41.9 146.2 « ■ I 1*.2 121.4 Hi M?5 }??0 CTIFER NO. • H 170.0 Mi M IU 147.0 171.0 HEIFER NO. 6 b»tinr,. ~~j I j IK «p*rim«it 429 | UM 139.0 143.0 141.0 150.7 i h ill II HBIFER WO. 25&gt; 1 — 153.3 153.6 156.0 1 HJ 159.0 , 1M4 MM 164.0 167.0 HKIFER NO. 256 bnt»«it I I ; — At b*cinnin( 4 exp*-rimi-nt xperiroent S89 I ttiilflilil 1st K2I MJ 147.5 '.'nd m 40.4 1SJ.2 72.". 152.0 :lr.i 41.6 lip 154.0 10 Jth 42.6 139.3 .-ith ■r 157.5 44.0 114.2 161.0 M :ll II 6l h K7X Ml M4 Mi 44.3 MtJ 7th 166.0 45.6 143.1 165.6 Mh 47J HS:i Mth 47.S l.-.l.u 171.0 HEIFER NO. 256 At beginning of experiment { 6S2 lit 672 S7.2 126.8 2nd 625 141.0 38.0 132.0 145.0 11 3rd 637 40.1 1.1.1.6 Ml 4th 695 149.0 41.2 1S7.8 1 52.0 11 5th 723 42.4 1S».2 ;to 6th 763 15S.0 4S.7 1IJ.3 1S7.0 ;li 7th 796 44.6 1.18.6 :ll 8th 850 160.6 4S.8 14S.5 160.0 11 9th 848 46.2 147.0 16S.0 :i2 IW.O 11.2 12.6 IS.* 16.4 16.1 19.0 I17.C 17.* 19.8 21.3 21.5 22.2 I 1 l.D 112.6 113.7 I 1 i.6 117.3 116.2 117.2 I -''1.2 119.8 119.3 119.4 119.4 120.3 121.4 40 12 ■ 28 40 33 54 2 114.1 116.3 118.6 121.6 121.6 &lt; 124.6 124.2 I 126.7 127.8 11K.0 118.1 121.3 122.8 12£.l 127.6 128.6 131.2 129.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Kxpkrimknt Station Hrujrnx 1M 3. The average monthly gain in height at wither&gt;. height at hips, width at hips, length of body, and heart girth were calculated on the basis of the average monthly gain in live weight. The computation was Imx'd not upon the entire actual gain but upon 100 lbs. of gain in live weight. th Averages of each measurement were computed for the ip&gt; in order to facilitate the comparison of results. Table Si rs in detail the average monthly gains in bodv measure- From the data presented, there appears to be no significant difference between the two groups a&gt; showing that the protein plane had any effect upon skeletal development. It nin-t be renieml&gt;ered. however, that the low protein plane upon which (Jroup II waa fed was above the minimum required by growing heifers. The higher plane upon which Group I wa« fed hail an excess of protein. Tliir- excess does not ap)x-ar to have lia&lt; I any significant effect upon skeletal development. ProbaMv t!i- increased protein ingested l&gt;y Group I did not influence the mineral metabolism to any appreciable degree as determined by lxxlv measurement-. Wt Group No. of Breed Height Height W.drt, length H-arti W at withera at hips at hipn of body girth proton * J- 1:i ' 1-21 ■*• - :1 : " 25« H. Jfll 1.88 1.51 3.40 4.20 Average lor Group II 1.42 LSI 1.05 3.15 3.99 M.44 'Gain in skeletal development is calculated on the basis of 100 lbs. body sain *Gain in weight is calculated per 1.000 lbs. of live weight. Table 9. — Arentve imnit/i/i/ &lt;i Cm. '-• '"• 1 I 3 Hick • (■I 5 J. J. J. .87 1.07 1.43 l.il l.:ir&gt; 1.21 1 2(1 1.24 1.18 1.7* 2.84 IM 4.94 KM 34.1" :,v. m 1 M« | A rent* (or Group I . . . H. 1.68 1.80 1.27 3.90 Ml 4.M T4.7ti VI ll * i 1. .97 m .77 3.85 4.17 41.2C „ : Low 1. .0 ,:« M Mi 4.25 56.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Growth Sti dikk &lt;&gt;f Dairy Hkikkrs 17 EFFECT ON BODY WEIGHT The average monthly gains in body weight wore calculated on the liii~i~ of 1.(mk&gt; 11)-. live weijrlit for each animal of each group. The group averages, then, were taken for comparing re-ult&gt; obtained from high or low protein rations. Examining Table !•. it i&gt; found that Group II on the lower protein intake gained, on the average. (5O.3fi lbs. of bodv weight per month as compared with ."&gt;."&gt;.:&gt;."&gt; 11». of gain made by Group I fed on the higher protein ration when figured on the basis of 1,000 lbs. live weight . Table 1 * » points out the average amounts of crude protein consumed to make ;i pound of gain in body weight and the average daily gain in body weight j&gt;er 1.000 lbs. live weight exhibited by the two groups. Group I. receiving the high protein ration, rewired 2. - 2O Hi-, of crude protein per pound gain in body weight, while Group II fed on the low protein ration, consumed 1.17 lbs. of crude protein for each pound of gain in body weight. Fur - thermore, the average daily gain in body weight per 1.000 lbs. live weight was 1.84 ll&gt;s. for Group I. and "2.01 lbs. in the case of Group II. Crude Av. amount &lt; Av. daily No. of Total crude , Total : protein crude protein gain in body up Breed heifer protein i fain in consumer. required weight per cniumed weight per lb. gain per lb. gain \ 1000 lb.. in weight in weight live weight I'abi.k 10. — &lt; &lt;&gt;mpari*on of ptcteim requirement. Lbt. Lb: Lb,. /.'-. /.'■« to, '■ « 515.14 256 2.01 I Hi»h protein i. i. 3 ■ 474J8 778.B8 187 2.53 2.01 H. m -,«9.«T ,70 1.53 2.0* l.s I J. 2 SM.*8 201 1.45 II Low protein J. 1. 4 6 310.04 451.09 Mi 426 1.15 1.05 H. 1M :W2.1(I 316 1.06 1 IT ■&gt; 11 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Xkbkaska Kxi-khimkm Statiom Hi i.i.ktin 1M 18 CONCLUSIONS kl. The skeletal development of growing dairy cattle does seem to be influenced bv mi increase in the protein content a ration carrying slightly more protein than the minimum by feeding standards. An excess of protein apparently tends to diminish the rage daily gain or body weight ]&gt;er 1.000 lbs. live weight growing heifers. ;i. A high protein ration i&gt; not economical for growing dairy heifers. l&gt;ecanse there is more crude protein consumed ]xt ]H&gt;und gain in body weight than in the case of a ration computed according to current feeding standard- and there appears to l&gt;c no compensatory l&gt;enefit. BIBLIOGRAPHY 1. T. B. Osborne, L. B. Mendel, and E. L. Ferry. Carnegie Institute, Washington, Pub. 156, (19111 p. 111. Nutrition factors which influence growth. 2. L. B. Mendel Trans. 15 International Cong. Hyg. and Demogra - phy, Washington, 2, (1912) Sect. 2, pp. 429-438. The role of protein in growth. 3. T. S. Osborne and L. B. Mendel. J. Biol. Chem. 15 (1913) No. 2, pp. 311-325. The relation of growth to the chemical constituents of the diet. 4. T. B. Osborne and L. B. Mendel. J. Biol. Ch. 17. (1914) No. pp. 325-349. Amino acids in nutrition and growth. 5. E. V. McCollum and M. Davis. J. Biol. Ch. 19, (1914) No. I, pp 323-333. The influence of the plane of protein intake on growth. 6. L. B. Mendel. Bioch. Bui. 3, (1914) No. 10, pp. 156-176. View - points in the study of growth. 7. E. V. McCollum and M. Davis. J. Biol. Ch. 20, (1915) No. 3, pp. 415-428. The influence of the plane of protein intake on growth. 8. T. B. Osborne, L. B. Mendel, et al. J. Biol. Ch. 20, (1915) No. 3, pp. 351-378. The comparative nutritive value of certain proteins in growth, and the problem of the protein minimum. 9. L. B. Mendel. J. Araer. Med. Association, 64, (1915) No. 19, pp. 1539-1547. Nutrition and growth. 10. Bulletin of the National Research Council (1921) Vol. 2, Part 4, No. 12, pp. 219-288. [»M] </seg> 
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>