<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Types of Farming in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1930-05">1930-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 244 May, 1980 Types of Farming in Nebraska HAROLD HEDGES Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station F. F. ELLIOTT Diviaion of Farm Management and Co»t». Bureau of Agricultural Economic, of the U. S. Department of Agriculture ■ . / ■ ..■■'■ ... ■ •^rr—f^^. («AMD Hill CATTLtNL. - - f"l iVJB B™i**'T^''*\ Type-of-farming areas—based on differences in the prevailing farming systems in the state THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN j W. W. BURR. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 Geography of Nebraska's Agriculture. 4 Land Utilization 4 The Cropping System 5 The Corn Enterprise in Nebraska 7 The Wheat Enterprise in Nebraska 7 The Oats Enterprise in Nebraska ■ 9 The Barley and Rye. Enterprises in Nebraska 10 The Alfalfa Enterprise in Nebraska 11 The Wild Hay Enterprise in Nebraska ;. 12 All Hay and Other Forage Crops 13 The Pasture Enterprise in Nebraska 14 Crop Combinations , ;••... 15 The Livestock System - 15 The Hog Enterprise 16 The Beef Cattle Enterprise 17 The Dairy Enterprise 18 The Poultry Enterprise 19 The Sheep Enterprise '. 20 Combinations of Crop and Livestock Enterprises 21 The Type-of-Farming Areas 23 Historical Development of Nebraska's Agriculture 28 Changes in Utilization of Land 28 Changes in Size of Farms 30 Changes in the Cropping System 32 Changes in the Livestock System 36 Factors in the Agricultural Development of Nebraska. 39 General Considerations •' 39 Effect of Physical Factors. '■ 40 Effect of Economic Factors ; 45 Specific Conditions Determining the Type of Farming in Each Area in Nebraska 47 Northeastern Intensive Meat Producing Area (Area 1) 47 Southeastern General Farming Area (Area 2) 53 Southern Cash Grain and Livestock Area (Area 3) 54 Central Corn and Livestock Area (Area 4) 56 Central Hay and Livestock Area (Area 5) 57 The Sand Hill Cattle Ranching Area (Area 6) 58 Southwestern Wheat Area (Area 7) 59 High Plains Small Grain and Grazing Area (Area 8) 60 Irrigated Area (Area 9) 61 The Internal Organization of Nebraska Farms 61 Farming Systems Vary Within as Well as Between Different Regions 61 Method of Determining Typical Farming" Systems and Meaning of a Typical Fariri 63 Ways in Which These Typical Farming Systems May Be Used.... 70 Use of Results in Determining Profitable Long-time Systems of Farming 70 Use of Results in Interpreting the Annual Agricultural Outlook.. 74 Use of Results in Other Lines of Research Work 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Types of Farming in Nebraska HAROLD HEDGES AND F. F. ELLIOTT 1 6 - Of / arming " 2 s used in this bulletin is a term descriptive of a group of farms similar in size and enterprise tion -, Thu s » sroup of farms having the same kfnd! quantity and proportion of crops and livestock may- be said to be following the same type of farming. The term "type - of-farming area" refers to an area within which there i? a and inthp e^ Of - Un i lf °T ity type of farmin * PractSed and in the physical and economic conditions under which pro - duction takes place This should not be understood to mean that there is absolute uniformity either in farming systems or m other conditions. Such uniformity is rarSy tf e ™ &amp;*!" *?■ a J e « ° f any con siderable size. It is necessary' therefore, to define a type-of-farming area in terms of the farming system which is dominant in the area ™£ ™ ei » tiatan &amp; the agriculture of a state into areas in this YJZ Jf° rd l a m T uc^ c l e arer picture of the conditions in dif - ferent parts. It further gives county agents and other agencies advising the farmer a better idea of the limits within which specific recommendations may apply, and also affords KfT^ 113 - 818 for making such recommendations fnJ ?w Y llk | wise Provides a background of information for those engaged m agricultural problems of the state in that it defines the areas within which the problems of production and marketing are similar and further provides a basis for SJuKTE S 6 GffeCt Wh V C - h ? hanging econo ™c cSndftions hit S e y t0 011 Particular systems of farming. Just part of th7bune°tin. in * SPeClfiC CaSe iS illustrated in the latter tainpH £ t U &gt;f o e ? if a basis for th i s an aly«s have been ob - tained from the following sources : State and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics; Conservation and Survey Division University of Nebraska; Reports of the State Board of Agril Si r \ and A the - B H rea^ °l Labor; Department of Agronomy, Snsus Un1Sr| CU sSt ral S^ 6^ 6^ S i ati ° n; Bureau of t£ census, United States Department of Commerce; Weather in malcine special tabulations of 1925 census data* «„*.„* &lt; jJ nB A u8 i for cooperation federal statistician for Nebraska^ for makfn£ «1".5?ki F", A . nde ™on, state and dau. Credit is also due G. E CondS DLrector «f «J ni'? e - elal Uvesto&lt;:k «"d crop Soil Survey, and J. C. Russei Department trf aL Divu&gt; ' on of Conservation and for information on the soUs and topoVS D hl of N^ T y&gt; U J li S e ™. ity of Nebraska. Bureau. Lincoln. Nebraska, for cliSa?o™Bicalda^' and T * A ' Blair - w «t»&gt;e' </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 geography of nebraska's agriculture Nebraska is primarily an agricultural state — more -so, per - haps, than any other state of the Union. According to the 1920 federal census, 41 per cent of all persons gainfully em - ployed in the state were engaged in agriculture, forestry, and animal husbandry. For the United States as a whole 26 per cent were engaged in such pursuits. Furthermore, of those gainfully employed in manufacturing and mechanical indus - tries, in trade and in service occupations, the majority are engaged in handling and processing farm products or in giving service to those so engaged and to farmers. Thus, it is evident that a large majority of Nebraska's population are dependent directly or indirectly upon the agriculture of the state for their living. LAND UTILIZATION Land may be utilized in other ways than for crop and live - stock production. Forestry is a possible use for land, but Nebraska is not naturally a forest area and possibilities along this line seem quite limited. There is a limited need of land for industrial, business, and residential purposes. Still other possible uses of land and water surface are for recreational purposes, such as hunting and fishing, or perhaps for fur - farming or mining, but any extensive use of Nebraska land for such purposes appears unlikely. Our main interest is in the utilization of the land of the state for agricultural purposes, and the discussion which follows deals with how and why it is so utilized. In 1927, 48,208,000 acres, or 98 per cent of the total land area of Nebraska, was reported as land in farms. Much of the farm land of the state, however, remains uncultivated, a large pro - portion from necessity because of the lay of the land or the nature of the soil. Figure 1 furnishes a detailed picture of the situation in Nebraska as regards the proportion of the farm land that is cultivated. 2 The data were secured from the reports of assessors for 1927 and were on a township basis. For the state as a whole, 37 per cent of the land in farms was under cultivation in 1927, leaving 63 per cent which was utilized for wild hay production, pasture, farmsteads, and woodland, or was idle. In the eastern third of the state from 50 to 90 per cent of the farm land of the townships was under cultivation. In the Sand Hill area of northern Nebraska, where the land is used mainly for grazing and production of wild hay, many townships reported less than 5 per cent of the farm area under cultivation. 'Cultivated land does not include the acreage in wild hay — land which has never been plowed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 cupied 20 per cent of the cultivated acreage and 7y 2 per cent of the total farm area of the state. It is primarily a cash grain crop. On the average about 85 per cent of the crop moves out of the county where grown and smaller portions are sold direct to local mills, so that the part of the crop utilized on the farm for other purposes than seed is quite negligible. Only in cases of abnormally narrow spreads be - tween prices of wheat and feed grains is much wheat used for livestock feed in Nebraska. Experimental trials have shown ground wheat to be equal in value to corn, pound for pound, for fattening livestock. Wheat is essentially a southern and western Nebraska crop. It is confined largely to the territory south of the Platte river. Figure 3. — The percentage of Nebraska farm land in wheat in 1927 by townships. The only wheat area of importance north of the Platte valley is in the "panhandle" sections of the state. Figure 3 shows that the principal area of concentrated wheat production is in the southern tier of counties of the "panhandle" section and in the adjacent counties to the east. In some of the townships in those counties, more than 40 per cent of the farm land was occupied by wheat in 1927. If the percentage were determined on the basis of cultivated area, the dominance of the wheat enterprise would be even more evident. In several of the townships from 65 to 75 per cent of the cultivated land was occupied by wheat in 1927. A second area of some importance in wheat production is in the counties just south of the Platte river in south central Nebraska. The two areas of concentrated wheat production have a land surface that is level to gently rolling in character, one area being in the high plains region, the other in the loess plains. Hard red winter wheat is the prevailing type grown in Ne - braska, except in the northern counties of the "panhandle" </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">Types of Farming in Nebraska barley, and accounts, in large part at least, for the tendency to shift from oats to barley. Furthermore, the decrease in numbers of horses is reducing demand for oats while barley may be utilized as a fattening feed. Another small grain crop, even less important than barley for the state as a whole, is of some significance in certain areas of the state. This crop is rye. In a belt bordering the Sand Hill section of Nebraska, rye is rather an important crop, occupying as high as 10 to 14 per cent of the farm area in a few townships in Holt and Antelope counties. The fact that the percentage of farm land that is cultivated is rela - tively low in the belt where rye is most common gives it more significance as a cultivated crop in such areas. Rye finds its greatest usefulness on soils of light texture or of low fertility. THE ALFALFA ENTERPRISE IN NEBRASKA Alfalfa is the leading hay crop of the state from the stand - point of tonnage produced. In 1927 it occupied about 2*/&gt; per cent of the farm land and 7 per cent of the cultivated area of the state. The main use of alfalfa arid of other hay crops in Nebraska is as a part of the livestock ration. For the five-year period, 1923-1927, slightly less than 4 per cent of the hay crop of the state was reported as marketed and a large part of this went to livestock feeders within the state. However, the Platte valley is an important source of market alfalfa hay. • T-t »k.hi»v «tart*T«,a m my -wwnwa* w«t i«« Mv ciiit Figure 6.— The percentage of Nebraska farm land in alfalfa in 1927 by townships. Figure 6 gives the geographical distribution of the alfalfa crop m percentage- of total land in farms. Aside from the concentration of alfalfa production in the irrigated area of the North Platte valley, this, crop is of most importance in the eastern half of the state. The largest area of concentrated </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">Types op Farming in Nebraska hJSTP 6 *?" 8 " 6 ?* P a f ture - In the rotation pastures sweet CROP COMBINATIONS S e^f Pn ? es&gt; A n will be made of the differ S THE LIVESTOCK SYSTEM a Livestock holds an important place in Nebraska aericulturp As an average for the five-year period, 1923-1927 75 per ceni stock on the maps which follow (Figures 10 to 14) •BSla frZ N e^ 8 t a Agricultural Statistic. 1928. Data from Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, ml: </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 THE HOG ENTERPRISE Hog production is the most important livestock enterprise in Nebraska when measured in terms of gross farm income. For the five-year period, 1923-1927, 30 per cent of the gross farm income of Nebraska farmers was derived from hogs. Figure 10 shows that the distribution of hogs coincides fairly closely with the distribution of corn acreage. (Compare Figures 2 and 10.) The areas of densest hog production, however, do not correspond precisely with the areas having the highest concentration of corn production. Northeastern Nebraska is the most important area of hog production. Burt county had 327 head of hogs per section of land in 1928 and four other counties in that section of the state had over 250 Qihtoaunnwuo „ , i ,_„, i^i^yi^gZeffi.- ..." .-!...,' i-"SJJ ■ no head on Mont peo section." ■ THC LAQH1VT KUMRto or WU P«Q MCTIOH IN ANY COUNTY WAS 517 HEAD. Figure 10. — The number of hogs per section (640 acres) of Nebraska farm land on January 1, 1928, by counties. head per section. The Sand Hill section and western and southwestern Nebraska had the fewest hogs per section. The Sand Hill area is a region having a large percentage of hay and pasture land — and that not of very high produc - tivity — andj low production of feed grains. Western and southwestern Nebraska have more feed grain available but the types of hay and pasture are not as suitable for hog as for cattle production, because legumes are lacking. The data used do not fully reflect the relative importance of hogs in different parts of the state. For example, in northern and northwestern Nebraska where feeder pig pro - duction is a common practice, marketing has been practically completed by. January first, when estimates of numbers are made. In eastern Nebraska where production of slaughter hogs is the prevailing practice, a large proportion of the hogs on hand on January 1 are market hogs. However, a more satisfactory means of showing the geographical distribution of the hog enterprise is not at hand. </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 north central Nebraska. This area is even more important than is indicated on the map for reasons explained in the pre - ceding paragraph. 7 The areas showing the fewest cattle per section were the southern "panhandle" and southwestern sections of the state where the quality of pasture is low, hay is scarce, and the proportion of land in feed grains is relatively small. The kind and quantity of the feed grains, forage, and pasture largely determine the type of cattle enterprise — whether it is the production of feeding cattle, the raising and finishing of market cattle, or commercial feeding. The high proportion of farm land in hay and pasture in the Sand Hill section has resulted in the production of feeder cattle and, to a limited extent, of grass-fat cattle. The large production of feed grains, together with forage crops and pasture, has con - tributed to the development of commercial feeding, partic - ularly in eastern Nebraska. A more detailed discussion of this phase of the subject will come later in the bulletin. No statistics are available to indicate what proportion of the cattle marketed by Nebraska farmers come from outside the state. It is probably rather small. Data are available, however, to indicate what proportion of the cattle marketed from farms are produced locally. From statistics on cars of cattle forwarded and received at local shipping points, 8 it is found that for the four-year period, 1924-1927, between 35 and 40 per cent of the cattle forwarded from local stations were received there from other points. There were, however, wide differences between sections of .the state, as data pre - sented later will indicate. THE DAIRY ENTERPRISE Nebraska is seldom thought of as a dairy state and does not have any extensive area which might be considered a dairy section. However, the dairy enterprise is of consider - able significance in many sections of the state even tho it may be supplementary to other more important enterprises. For the five-year period, 1923-1927, receipts from the sale of dairy products made up about 6 per cent of the gross income of Nebraska farmers. Since 1920, the dairy enterprise has gained rapidly in importance and in 1928 it ranked next to hogs and cattle among the livestock enterprises, providing 7 per cent of the gross farm income. Figure 12 gives the geographical distribution, by counties, of milk cows expressed in number per section of land. The 1 The unequal distribution in the Sand Hill counties may be due, in part, to the fact that cattle are counted in the counties where ranch headquarters are located. ■From Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Types op Farming in Nebraska □ « ■ - - — - -v— :"?■■— -•-' ,'-*Si-L^f~£C?.u 4~V7« ■ « HEAD 00 MOM PW SECTION.* ' ' ' 1 ~ 1 "^ THE lAB&amp;UT NUMBU P» MCT.OH IN AMY COUNTY WA&amp; J9 MIAO. Figure 12.— The number of milk cows per section (640 acres) of Nebraska farm land on Januaary 1, 1928, by counties. highest concentration of milk cows is in counties adjacent to large cities, namely, Douglas and Washington counties, near Omaha, and Lancaster county, in which Lincoln is located Satisfactory whole milk markets have contributed to profit - able dairying near the larger cities. Aside from the counties named above, the distribution of milk cows is fairly uniform in the eastern third of the state. The areas of low concentra - tion are the north central, southwestern, and western counties (excepting Scotts Bluff county) , the lowest being in the Sand Hill section. Butterfat is the prevailing form in which dairy products are sold. Production of fluid milk is of major importance only near Omaha and Lincoln. Cheese manufacture is a growing, industry in the North Platte valley, particularly in Scotts Bluff county. Thruout most of the state, however cream is separated from the milk on the farm and sold on a butterfat basis. In some localities where dairying is im - portant, the butter is manufactured in local creameries but much more often the cream is assembled locally and shipped to centralized creameries where it is manufactured into butter. THE POULTRY ENTERPRISE Poultry ranked next below hogs and beef cattle among the livestock enterprises as a source of income during 1 the five year period, 1923-1927, but is now exceeded by dairying For ?■! aZ?^ P eri^. 1923-1927, sales of poultry products pro - vided 6y 2 per cent of the gross income of Nebraska farmers Commercial poultry farms are relatively unimportant in Ne - braska. The great bulk of the poultry products is produced on farms where the enterprise is handled as a side line In the majority of cases, the housewife cares for the poultry It </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 What is the relation of enterprises to one another in each area? Figure 16 gives not only the division of the state into type areas but also the combination of crops within each area. The proportion of the farm acreage which each important crop occupies in each area is given in the small charts super - imposed on the map. In Figure 17 is given similar informa - tion on the livestock enterprises and their relative importance in each area. Thus, by observing Figures 16 and 17, the sig - nificant differences in the cropping and livestock systems of the nine areas are seen. -V' ; . ■ ■ -I/..-"- . . : ■ -'■ \f®. .. . .■;. - - - - : ' ' . . ' ■ ' . ! ' - '" * ' . 1 ' .." ••'-■ . ' ' - ' ' •' ; ' ■ ■ _ ' ; . ■ . ' . ■ . " . - '■"'■ ■ y ' ■ ■ . i -. ■ - , ' . . ' . - • . ' ' ' »'■•.' Hogging down corn in the Northeastern Intensive Meat Producing Area Northeastern intensive meat producing area. — In this area the corn crop is of outstanding importance, occupying about 37 per cent of the farm area. Of the other grain crops, oats occupy about 17 per cent of the farm land. Barley and wheat occupy only a small part of the farm area. The hay acreage occupies about 12 per cent of the farm land, with tame hays of greatest importance from the standpoint of ton - nage, and, in the southern part, in acreage as well. Twenty - five per cent of the farm land is used for pasture. The out - standing importance of both beef cattle and hogs provides the reason for calling it an intensively meat-producing area. Southeastern general farming area. — In this area is a cropping system which includes the same important crops found in the Northeastern Meat Producing Area with winter wheat as an additional crop of some importance. The latter crop is substituted for some of the oats and corn. Hay and pasture occupy a somewhat smaller proportion of the farm </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Types of Farming in Nebraska Area i^J a " d h ° gS are also less im Portant than in Aiea l but still are major sources of income, while dairy catt e and poultry occupy a slightly larger place in the live- S&amp;KSn ThU h S er %V1 a Wide diversi * 5 sources ol income—hogs, beef cattle, cash grain, and dairy and poultry products— hence the name that is given the area J, S °Y THE ( RN CASH GRAIN AND LIVESTOCK AREA.— Here the wheat enterprise has gained in importance over Area 2 m«l ?i? P1 i M b ° Ut 22 P u er cent of the farm area. Corn re - thP fL^ a * r? cr °P' h ° wever . occupying nearly a third of 1 anriTinH ;*° at \ and *\ ay ? re l esa im Portant than in Areas »«£ k ' he W u , re land ' while nearlv as large in acre - age, nas a somewhat lower carrying capacity. The smaller f oY tTe fiFff f Tr g6S an V heir lower P productiiity account arLs o ?hl t^ are / ewe i cattle in this th an in the «ff f- f i £? th and east Feed « rains are relatively ?!??£ S' re ? ultmg J " a somewhat higher ratio of hogs to cattle than in any other area of the state. The dairv and relS to ?£ Pr 7v? h r VG ed somewha t in importance Jrf SS. ♦ Ot u her 1 ? vestock enterprises. The importance of Sinm aS 3 cash «S ain&gt; supplementing livestock as a source of income, accounts for the name given the area Central corn and livestock area.— This area is charac terized by having corn dominant among the cultivated crops. The hay enterprise is also quite important, more so than in ••■■ .. •. ' ■ ; . '. ?.. ■ . ■ A TYPICAL LANDSCAPE IN THE SOUTHEASTERN GENERAL F A R MI NC AREA zz^ H £S G 0 ™r and corn ' the — c ™ p "- </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 brought under cultivation. Crop farming is partially sup - planting and materially changing cattle production in this region. Irrigated area. — This area is confined in large part to Scotts Bluff county. Less extensive irrigated sections out - side the area are found along the Platte river valley and in other river valleys of western Nebraska. In the North Platte district, sugar-beet production holds a high place in the crop - ping system, with small grains, alfalfa, potatoes, corn, and beans of less importance. Sheep feeding is a major livestock enterprise and, together with cattle feeding, offers a means of utilizing the by-products of the sugar beet industry arid the hay and feed grains produced in the area. Dairying is an enterprise that is gaining. Hog production is relatively un - important. HISTORICAL DEVELOPMENT OF NEBRASKA'S AGRICULTURE Nebraska of the twentieth century is totally different from Nebraska at the opening ' of the nineteenth century. Scat - tered bands of Indians made up the human population in that early day. Herds of bison roamed over the broad plains. But few white men had entered the present borders of the state and they despaired of its agricultural possibilities. It was described as a desert waste by many travelers who crossed its broad expanse; Geographers of that early day called the wide area west of the Missouri river the Great American Desert. The great "desert waste" has been transformed since the first farmers settled in eastern Nebraska near the middle of the nineteenth century. Agriculture has been developed to such an extent that Nebraska has come to be a leading state in the production of farm products. That development is still in progress. CHANGES IN UTILIZATION OF LAND The first way in which Nebraska lands were utilized ex - tensively by man was as a grazing area for cattle. Nebraska was a midway point on the old cattle trails which extended from Texas to Montana and the Dakotas. Where the trails crossed the lines of railroads which traversed the state, im - portant loading points sprang up from which grass-fat cattle were shipped eastward to market. The passage of the Home - stead Act of 1.862 and other land-settlement legislation brought about a rapid settlement of the state. The sod was broken and cultivated crops came to occupy more and more of the land. More often than not the life of the early settlers was hard but the will to persevere and changes in farming </seg>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 . vated acres, of wild hay acreage, and of pasture, farmsteads, or idle land give the proportion of the total land area that is in farms. The data for 1928 in Table 1 are not fully comparable to those for the other years indicated, especially as regards land not in farms. For the period from 1899 to 1924, as given by the federal census reports, no material changes are shown in Areas 1, 2, 3, and 4 in the proportion of land under cultiva - tion. In the remaining five areas, increasing proportions of the land have come under cultivation, with the largest in - creases in Areas 7 and 9. The percentage of land area in wild hay decreased from 1899 to 1924 in Areas 1, 2, 3, 7, and 9, changed but little in Area 4, and increased in Areas 5 and 6. In Area 8 the pi'oportion of land in wild hay has decreased since 1909. The proportion of land in pastures, farmsteads, and waste and idle land has l'emained with but little change in Areas 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7. In the other areas, this percentage has in - creased since 1899 as the proportion of land not in farms has decreased. The agriculture of eastern Nebraska is undoubtedly on a more stable basis than is that of western Nebraska and there - fore less subject to material change. Even so, substantial changes in the agriculture of the eastern part of the state are well within the realm of possibility. Economic conditions may change and necessitate a shift in farming practices, or other situations may arise of sufficient import to alter the production program. It is therefore unwise to regard the agriculture of any area of the state- as settled and unchange - able. . CHANCES IN SIZE OF FARMS There has been a slight tendency for the size of farms to change somewhat, more apparent in some areas of the state than in others. Data are not available to permit a study of changes in size of farms by type areas prior to 1910. Figure" 18, however, presents the census data on size groupings of Nebraska farms by type areas for the three census years, 1910, 1920, and 1925. In Area 1, the Northeastern Intensive Meat Producing Area, there has been a slight tendency for the farms of the main size grouping, 100 to 175 acres (120 - and 160-acre farms, largely),. to increase in number at the expense of farms of larger acreage. The prevailing size group of Area 2 is the same as in Area 1 — the 100- to 175 - acre farms. Again there was a slight increase from 1910 to 1925 in the number of farms in this group, while farms under 50 acres and over 500 acres decreased in number. </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin' 244 has been a strong tendency for individual holdings in the Sand Hills to increase in size. In the Southwestern Wheat Area, farms over 175 acres in size have increased in number. In Area 8 farms of the 500 - to 999-acre group decreased in number from 1910 to 1920, while the number of farms in size groups above and below the 500- to 999-acre group increased. From 1920 to 1925 farms from 175 to 500 acres in size increased at the expense of those of 1,000 acres and over. In the Irrigated Area the trend from 1910 to 1920 was toward farms of smaller acreage. From 1920 to 1925, farms from 175 to 499 acres in size gained in numbers, while the number in the size groups containing 80- and 640-acre farms decreased. CHANCES IN THE CROPPING SYSTEMS The cropping system which prevails in a type area is con - stantly subject to modification. The same proportions of the cultivated land are not devoted to the individual crops year after year. Growing conditions may cause modifications. Winter killing may reduce the wheat acreage, and the aband - oned acreage may be put into oats or corn. Adverse weather at planting time may cut the corn acreage somewhat. Such changes are usually only for a season and a return to the normal acreage is made the following year. There are other factors, however, that may have more per - manent effect on the cropping system. Such factors as insect pests, plant diseases, development of improved methods of production, discovery of new varieties of crops or new uses for products, and finally, changes in price relationships may bring about lasting modifications in cropping systems. A later section of the bulletin will discuss such factors in greater detail. Figures 19, 20, and 21 show the changes in the cropping systems of the nine type areas since 1910. The area devoted to each crop is expressed in percentage of the total acreage in the principal cultivated crops for each year. Thus, the variations in the width of the bands extending across the chart for each area give evidence of the changes in the rela - tive importance of the principal crops of the area. In the Northeastern " Intensive Meat Producing Area, the wheat acreage has decreased materially since 1910. (See Figure 19.) Alfalfa gained in acreage from 1910 to 1916 but there has been little change since. Corn has gained more than oats from the decrease in wheat acreage. In the South - eastern General Farming Area the trend of wheat acreage has likewise been downward since 1910, while the corn acre - age has gained. (See Figure 19.) Oats have shown no material change in acreage since 1910. In Area 3, the </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035"/>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 in acreage — due in part to the varying extent of winter kill - ing. (See Figure 21.) It gained rapidly in acreage from 1910 to 1919, while the corn and oats acreages were declining. Then came gains in both oats and corn until 1923. Following that year, wheat gained in acreage, mainly at the expense of corn. Another significant development since 1921 has been the replacement of much of the oats by barley. In the High Plains Small Grain and Grazing Area, the increase in wheat acreage from 1910 to 1918 was largely at the expense of oats, and the increase since 1924 has been largely at the expense of corn. (See Figure 21.) Rye and alfalfa are two crops which, gained in importance until about 1918 but have decreased in relative importance, if not in acre - age, since then. It will be recalled from Table 1 that the cultivated acreage in Area 8 has nearly tripled since 1910, so changes in relative importance of the cultivated crops have seldom been in the nature of decreases in acreage, but instead one crop has gained in acreage faster than another. One interesting development in Area 8 has been the increasing acreage in barley, which is being substituted for oats and corn as a feed crop. The Irrigated Area is another where the cultivated acreage has increased rapidly since 1910. (See Figure' 21.) Sugar beets and barley are the two crops that have gained in im - portance relative to other crops since 1910, while alfalfa and oats have declined in importance. Wheat gained until about 1922 but has lost, in percentage of cultivated acreage, since then. Corn and potatoes have shown several periods of in - creases and decreases within the 19 years shown in Figure 21. CHANGES IN THE LIVESTOCK SYSTEM The livestock systems of the nine areas of the state are subject to change, just as are the cropping systems. There are variations from year to year due to changing feed condi - tions. There are cyclical changes — changes over a period of years — which are the result of periods of prosperity or ad - versity to which the enterprise is subject and of the way in which farmers react to them. For example, there are cycles of three to five years in the hog industry — production expands for perhaps two years and then declines for perhaps two years. Table 2 shows the changes in the numbers of the several kinds of livestock since 1910 by five-year periods for each of the nine type areas. Our interest here is in more than the year-to-year varia - tions and the cyclical fluctuations which result from changing feed conditions and price relationships. We wish to determine if possible any long-time trends in production or changes in the relative importance of the several livestock enterprises. </seg>
            <seg id="p037"/>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">Types of Farming in Nebraska cattle enterprises seem to have declined somewhat in im - portance since the early part of the 19-year period. The cattle and sheep enterprises are much less important in Area 7 than m the days before the sod was broken and wheat as - sumed a major place in the farming system. The same holds true in Area 8, and in addition the hog enterprise has gained materially in. importance. The unusual changes that seem to have taken place in the cattle and sheep numbers in Area 9 are probably due in large part to the inadequacy of the data. The cattle and sheep feed - ing enterprises are very important in this irrigated section, both classes of livestock being shipped in in large numbers for feeding. Differences in the extent of feeding, in the time of marketing, and the time at which a count of numbers was taken could cause material changes in the recorded number on hand. The hog enterprise in Area 9 has declined somewhat in importance while the poultry enterprise has gained. FACTORS IN THE AGRICULTURAL DEVELOPMENT OF NEBRASKA GENERAL CONSIDERATIONS In any area or region there are fairly well defined reasons why its agriculture has developed as it has. This is not to say of course, that the development in a particular direction has always been a wise one or that the farming systems followed t &amp; ? y P artlcular tim e are in complete or perfect adjustment. It does mean that farmers have made a conscious effort to Cattle in the Nebraska Sand Hill Area </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 adapt their organizations and practices to the conditions of production confronting them in an attempt to get a maximum utilization of the resources at their command. Following their economic interest, consequently, farmers have sought to economize on their productive resources by producing those commodities which will yield them a maxi - mum of value for the resources used. In doing so they neces - sarily depend upon securing from others commodities and services which they themselves are at a comparative disad - vantage in producing. The consequence of such a development obviously is that farmers in divergent areas or regions will follow different lines of production. Looking at the agriculture of Nebraska from this point of view it will be found that the development here has taken a similar course. Farmers in different parts of the state have apparently made an effort to adjust their organizations and practices to the physical and economic conditions prevailing. This adjustment has proceeded to the point where the agri - culture of the state can be segregated, as we have seen, into nine distinct types of farming. In order that the reader may have a better understanding of the basis for this segregation, a rather detailed discussion is given of the apparent effect which the various physical and economic factors have had in determining the organizations and practices followed in different parts of the state. In general it. may be said that types of farming result from two general groups of factors. On the one hand are included that large body of factors, physical and biological in character, such as soil type, topography, drainage, rainfall, evaporation, insect pests, diseases, and adaptation of plants and animals. On the other hand are those of an economic nature such as availability of labor and capital, relative prices of farm products, relative cost of the items needed for production, and changes in technique. . EFFECT OF PHYSICAL FACTORS Soil. — The character of the soil affects types of farming chiefly thru its influence upon the crops which may be grown. Certain crops are particularly affected by the texture of the soil, others by its chemical content, and others by its water - holding capacity. It is not so much, however, a question of absolute adaptability as of relative adaptability. That is, most crops will make some sort of growth on almost any type of soil but one may do better than another on a particular type and because of this fact will be given preference. The character of a soil with respect to its depth and permanency also will affect the type of farming. The fact that a soil is thin, resulting either from a basic lack of plant food material </seg>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044"/>
            <seg id="p045"/>
            <seg id="p046"/>
            <seg id="p047">Types of Farming in Nebraska Harvesting wheat in the Southwestern Wheat Area THE COMBINED HARVESTER-THRESHER IS IN COMMON USE EFFECT OF ECONOMIC FACTORS Obviously, however, farmers do not and cannot stop with a consideration of physical and biological factors in coS TW ™, f eC i! S1On ™ to .£!! at their system of Arming shaU be They must know m addition whether the crop or livestock enterprises yieldins.the maximum in physical urite wifl also yie d the maximum m value units. In other words thev want vJ?°i% WhlCl} enter PJ ise or combination of enterprises wUl Sources S"™" 1 ° f r6tUrnS in d ° llars and cen?s for It is at this point that economic considerations come into the picture in determining what is done. Two oDsmavh! not^ a f da S t6d tothe P h F*al conditions wiKiS aS arTye? not be at all comparable from the standpoint of net returns The Price of one may be entirely out of line due to conditions ?n Sl^/r 1 " P , arts of the world °r due to changes "J™" 4 Likewise, from the standpoint of econom? fn Sf kbor andTlso" t^T e T y re^ Uire a much waller aZunt or laDor and also its labor demands may fit in better with tViP i a v,?L den ?f nd ? °^° ther enterprises included in the 7armfn| of Jw, S- U t t0 lu e ing habits of different crops, ceS of them fit together into a farming system better than dS </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">Types op Farming in Nebraska such that they could shift readily to more profitable altern - atives the effect was very severe and even forced some out of farming altogether. Another factor which has an influence upon types of farm - ing and which comes about thru its effect upon cost and re - turns is that of invention and changes in technique. The introduction of a new method or a new machine such as the combined harvester-thresher may so cheapen the costs of production in areas where the machine is adapted that it be - comes profitable to grow the crop on grades of land which before were submarginal. 0 The result may be that production will expand to the point where the price is so lowered that farmers in competing areas are forced out. In other words the price of that particular commodity may be so reduced that farmers in competing areas find that the returns which can be obtained from it relative to the returns to be expected trom alternative enterprises in the area are so low as to make it advantageous to shift from it to another type of farming. Clearly, then, we see that economic factors play quite an important part in determining types of farming With this general discussion of the way in which physical, biological, and economic factors affect types of farming as a background we are now ready to understand better the effect each has had in determining the types of farming in Nebraska. SPECIFIC CONDITIONS DETERMINING THE TYPE OF FARMING IN EACH AREA IN NEBRASKA NORTHEASTERN INTENSIVE MEAT PRODUCING AREA (AREA I) xt ? efe ?ence to Figures 16 and 17 will reveal that this part of Nebraska is an area producing large quantities of corn oats beef cattle, and hogs. Both corn and oats occupy a larger, proportion of the farm area here than in any other section of the state. Likewise more beef cattle and hogs are found here per unit of area (square mile) than in any other part of the state. Our problem is to explain why this situation exists. .Let us begin by considering first the cropping system Corn occupies close to 37 per cent of the farm area in this section, which is around 2 per cent more than in any other area of the state. This high percentage of corn is a result of a number of factors which are highly favorable to corn production. In the first place the loess hill soil is found here which, because of its physical and chemical properties is a soil upon which corn does well. Added to this is a favorable rainfall, both from the standpoint of absolute amount and seasonal distribution, as well as a favorable summer tempera - ture. These factors have resulted in good corn yields — higher than m any other part of the state. •Submarsinal land is land which will not, over a period of years produce crons lame enough to pay the costs of producing them. »««™. proauce crops </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 In Table 4 are given the yields of the important crops that have been secured during the past 19 years in each of the nine areas of the state. Not only are yields shown for normal years but also for years when conditions were very favorable and very unfavorable. In Areas 1, 3, and 4, yields are given for two parts of each area, because of rather wide variations between the two parts of each of those three areas But yields alone do not tell the whole story. In addition to obtaining higher yields of corn this area also has less variability in yields than other areas of the state. (See Table 5.) This is particularly true in the southeastern part of the area where yields in poor years do not go quite so low as, and in good years go higher than, in other areas of the state. To put the variability in yields on a more accurate mathematical basis and also to permit a more direct comparison of varia - bility between different crops in the same area as well as be - tween the same crops in different areas, standard deviations and coefficients of variation were calculated for each of the important crops in each area of the state. In Table 5 it will be seen that corn yields have varied on the average in this ?oin %^° Ut n£ per cent from the average yield of tne peno,, 1910-28. This compares with a variation of 25 per cent in Area 2 in southeastern Nebraska, 41 per cent in Area 3, and oo per cent in Area 4. . ,, v&gt;p '^ n " f ! vsrisMUtv of corn with other crops grown in the same area, much the same situation is ?£" y - le , ! f S T^ on the whole ' hi S her and !ess vari - able than the yields of other crops. arJSf Sit * U f 1°? 5 eS !? lts J? corn P rod "cing not only a larger amount of total feed units than any other crop but also in returning a larger net income for the resources used. Be - cause corn has a comparative advantage over other crops it occupies a larger proportion of the farm area than, any other crop Because of the seasonal labor demands of the corn crop however, farmers find that, if the corn acreage is pushed too high, they have a peak load of labor during ground prep - ?wSl O «. Or f CUl ? Va^? n , which adds t0 their labor costs. Hence, fw finH ? f tan , d P 01 + nt of ret » rns from whole farm business they find it advantageous to supplement the corn acreage with other crops which require labor at other seasons of the year in this area oats and hay are the principal crops grown in asTwh™? . Wlth r cor !K Barle^ a i s °. is to some ° Sent" as is wheat in a limited way. Why, it may be asked are oats th»t W o fl t nSt h a - d ° f Whe - at? The Principal reason seems to be that oats, being a spring crop, fit in better with corn in this area than does winter wheat, which is difficult to put in with corn utilized as it is. Oats fit in well with corn for seasonal labor demands. Oats are also a good nurse crop for ?ed </seg>
            <seg id="p051"/>
            <seg id="p052"/>
            <seg id="p053"/>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 acreage and hence do not take into consideration the amount of abandonment. Were the abandoned acreage included the percentage variability would be greatly increased and would unquestionably show that wheat yields are more variable than oat yields in this area. The uncertainty of the crop, due to the hazard of winter killing, is one factor which discourages the growing of winter wheat. The hay acreage occupies about 12 per cent of the farm area and is composed largely of legumes. The legumes are high yielding and conserve soil fertility. The large amount of sheet erosion makes fertility maintenance a constant prob - lem. A large proportion of the legumes are annuals and bi - ennials. Such a legume as red clover fits in better with the last corn cultivation and small grain harvest, and gives a better chance for a seed crop. By growing red clover and sweet clover farmers are able to get over their land with legumes in a shorter period of time. Sweet clover, because seed is cheap and a stand is easy to get, is an ideal crop for soil improvement. It fits in well with the livestock system as a pasture crop and helps to maintain fertility. In the livestock system of Area 1, the hog and beef cattle enterprises are highly important— more so than in any other area of the state. In 1928 there were from 55 to 60 cattle and around 220 head of hogs per square mile in this area. This is distinctly a livestock country. The corn and oats are largely fed and but little is sold for cash. The explanation seems to lie in the fact that it is easier to maintain a per - manent agriculture in this area with livestock than with a grain system of farming, and to the fact that livestock is essential to a complete utilization of all the resources. Be - cause of the unevenness in terrain a certain amount of per - manent pasture is necessitated, as is the growing of legumes to aid in the maintenance of fertility. To utilize this hay and pasture, livestock is essential ; also, by providing winter labor, it affords a more efficient operating unit; also, it provides a market for low-grade grains and waste feeds which other - wise would not be completely utilized, if at all. Beef cattle and hogs are the principal kinds of livestock because the area is one which produces a large amount of the concentrated fat-producing feeds which are necessary for meat production. Corn is the principal crop and this, supplemented with legume hay, is an excellent fattening ration. Large numbers of feeder cattle are shipped in and finished. Table 6 shows that about 45 per cent of the cattle shipped out of Area 1 were shipped in from other points during the four - year period, 1924-1927, leaving 55 per cent that were raised within the area. There is the further economy of hogs fol - </seg>
            <seg id="p055"/>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 The increase in wheat acreage has come at the expense of both corn and oats. Wheat is a rather uncertain crop in Area 1 but in this area it is more dependable than either corn or oats. Wheat "yields have an average variability of only 21 per cent, which is 4 per cent lower than for the other two crops. Due in part to this low variability in yields it becomes a profitable crop, in fact a much more profitable crop than oats. Oats are grown for the work stock and for the young live - stock. The crop, because of the seasonal demands for labor, also fits in well with the corn crop and gives a better labor distribution than could be obtained without it. It also facil - itates getting the land from corn to winter wheat. Beef cattle and hogs are the dominant kinds of livestock. The unevenness of the terrain again makes some permanent pasture a necessity. To utilize this it is necessary to keep livestock. Beef cattle are kept rather than dairy cattle, due chiefly to the character of the feeds produced. The ratio of the corn to the oats acreage is still decidedly in favor of corn, which means a large amount of fattening feed. This favors meat production, giving beef cattle an advantage over dairy cattle. This does not mean, of course, that beef cattle are kept to the complete exclusion of dairy cattle. In fact, con - siderable dairying is done around Omaha and Lincoln, which afford good markets, but for the area as a whole beef cattle are dominant. As between beef cattle and hogs there are relatively more beef cattle than in Area 1, the number of the latter being gauged largely by the need to utilize the pasture and hay area. The additional corn available beyond that needed to finish the cattle is fed to hogs. SOUTHERN CASH GRAIN AND LIVESTOCK AREA (AREA 3) In this area there is a further decline in the proportion of the farm area devoted to corn, oats, and hay, and a decided increase in the wheat acreage as compared with Areas 1 and 2. Corn occupies about 31, oats about 8, and hay and other forage crops about 9 per cent of the farm area. Wheat oc - cupies 22 per cent of the farm acreage, which is materially larger than in Areas 1 and 2. In general, the land of Area 3 is quite level — more level than in any other area of the state. This, together with suit - able soils, is favorable to wheat production. The boundaries were determined largely on the basis of wheat acreage; here it occupies a larger proportion of the farm land than in any of the adjoining areas. The decline in the relative importance of corn in this area is due both to lower relative yields and to greater variability in yields. The rainfall, particularly in the southern and </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Types op Farming in Nebraska southwestern parts, is lower and the variation from year to year is greater than in Areas 1 and 2. (See Table 3.) There is also more evaporation. Corn yields vary as much as 41 per cent from their long-time average. (See Table 5.) This is not only very, high relative to the variability of corn in other areas but is high relative to the variability of other crops grown in this same area. Oats, for example, have a variability of 35 per cent while the variability in wheat yields is only 30. This situation results in reducing still more the compara - tive advantage of corn over wheat with the result that the wheat acreage increases relative to both the corn and oats acreages. The relatively low yield of oats, coupled with their high variability, results in returns from the crop which do not compare at all favorably with the returns from wheat in southern and western counties of this area. The oats acreage consequently is largely determined by work-stock require - ments and, probably in part, by the increased facility oats give for getting from corn into wheat, especially in the north - ern and eastern parts of the area. In the southern and western parts of this area considerable winter wheat is seeded in corn fields with one-row drills Soil conditions are favorable for this practice. Both weeds and grass are also less a problem than in Areas 1 and 2, because of a lower summer rainfall. Another factor which may have some bearing is the less rank growth of the corn. The hay acreage is slightly less than in Area 2 and the yields are likewise lower. The legume acreage is small— there 1S L ,1 s alfalfa on the upland. Seeding alfalfa back on old alfalfa ground has been found to give poor results except in subirngated valleys. Farmers, however, will probably con - tinue to grow a fairly high percentage of this crop at least until the yields decline to a greater extent than they have to date since it yields more than native hay. Barley increases in importance relative to oats, particularly in the western part of the area. Barley not only produces more pounds of feed per acre but also is a more dependable crop. For this reason, it is being substituted increasingly for oats. The uncertainty in corn yields may also be a factor in the increasing barley acreage. Since barley is a more fatten - ing feed than oats, it can be substituted for corn. Cattle are somewhat less important relative to hogs in this area than in Area 2. The number is determined by the pas - ture and hay area. The low. productivity of the hay and pas - ture land results in a decrease in cattle and the smaller amount of corn results in a decrease in hogs. In Figure 17 it will be observed that the number of cattle per square mile is ma - terially below the number in Areas 1 and 2, yet the relative </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 hay and pasture acreages have not changed a great deal. The carrying capacity of the pasture, except in the extremely northeastern part of the area, is considerably less than in the areas to the east and north. Dairy cattle are relatively more important in this area than in Areas 1 and 2. Dairying fits in as a supplementary enter - prise with wheat and utilizes family labor without adding to the out-of-pocket costs. It contributes to the stability of in - come and helps pay the minor expenses. Feeding in the southern and western parts of the area is localized in valleys where alfalfa is found. There is more feed grain sold — particularly corn — in this area than in either Areas 1 or 2. Just why this practice has developed is difficult to explain. It possibly may be due to the uncertainty of the rainfall, which increases the feeding hazard. In dry years with a shortage in both pastures and feed grains it becomes necessary to liquidate livestock. This is usually done at a big sacrifice, with the livestock in an un - finished state, resulting in heavy losses. To avoid this hazard farmers tend to understock rather than overstock; hence, they have excess feed grain to sell in nearly all years, par - ticularly in the years of good crops. CENTRAL CORN AND LIVESTOCK AREA (AREA 4) This area is characterized by a further decline in the rela - tive importance of corn and oats as compared with Areas 1 and 2, and in wheat and oats as compared with Area 3. There is an increase in the relative importance of hay and pasture as compared with all three areas. Conditions within Area 4 are somewhat variable, so it may be well to consider different parts of the area separately, namely, (1) that part lying no ? h ,.# the PIatte river valle y. (2) the Platte river valley, and (3) the area to the south and west of the Platte river valley. North of the Platte river valley the conditions are some - what similar to those found to the northeast in Area 1, but the land is more broken and hardly as productive. Corn oats, beef cattle, and hogs are the important enterprises. There is not as much livestock feeding as in Area 1. The land being more broken, there is more pasture. This has resulted in S /o me^ more cattle raising and less emphasis on feeding (bee Table 6.) Good legume hay is produced and this fits in well with both the breeding and feeding systems prevailing In that part of Area 4 which lies in the Platte valley, alfalfa is a leading crop, due to the presence of a liberal water supply furnished by irrigation and subirrigation. This part of the valley is an important source of commercial supplies of </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Types op Farming in Nebraska alfalfa hay. Cattle and sheep feeding operations are carried on quite extensively at various points in the valley. In the southwestern part of Area 4, corn is easily the lead - ing crop, but some wheat is grown. The acreage of hay par - ticularly of legume hay, is quite limited and pastures are of low carrying capacity. Consequently the livestock enter - prises are much less important than in other parts of Area 4 While a good many cattle are found here it is probable that the area is understocked and the broken, untillable land is not completely utilized. It would seem advantageous to increase livestock numbers somewhat. Because of the feed hazard due to uncertainty of crops, this would necessitate the carry - ing over of feed reserves from good crop years, but would increase the stability of farming. Soil and topography favor corn over wheat, making corn the more dependable crop Furthermore, wheat suffers from soil blowing. Lacking suf - ficient livestock to utilize all the grain grown in this part of the area, a large volume of corn is shipped out to market For Area 4 as a whole, corn and oats are more certain crops than in Area 3 to the south and also are more certain than wheat. While Table 5 shows wheat yields slightly less variable than corn the same situation is found here as in the northeast, where winter killing is quite a hazard. As was explained in the discussion of that area, the variability co - efficient is based on yields from harvested acreage and does not take the abandonment into consideration. Were it reck - oned with the variability for wheat no doubt would be con - siderably higher than is shown in the table. CENTRAL HAY AND LIVESTOCK AREA (AREA S) In this area we find conditions quite different from those found m the areas we have been discussing. This is a transi - tion area between the Sand Hills and the farming country to the east and south. Less dependence is placed upon crop farming and more upon hay production and grazing Condi - tions vary somewhat in different parts of the area In the northern part hay and pasture are decidedly dominant while m the southwestern part there is more grain farming. Ihe reason for this area being utilized mainly for hay pro - duction and grazing hinges quite largely on the question of physical adaptation. There is a large variety of soils, but all £L «« m V 6 S f ,!- more or. less sandy texture and relatively low in water-holding capacity. This area is characterized by an undulating topography. In some sections there are flat level stretches locally known as "hay flats". These "flats" produce excellent hay but are of little value for anything else. The light nature of the soil renders it very susceptible to blowing. Serious damage results if it is left bare; hence it </seg>
            <seg id="p060"/>
            <seg id="p061">Types op Farming in Nebraska region, except in limited areas. From this we get the ex - planation of why the land is utilized principally for grazing. The soil must be kept covered by native grasses or else it blows away. The principal grasses found here are the blue - stems, wheat grasses, and grama. These grasses, while very palatable, are not primarily of the type suitable for the pro - duction of grass-fat cattle; hence, cow herds are maintained and the young cattle from this area are usually sent to the corn belt for finishing before going to market. Cattle are the primary livestock handled. Sheep are not so well adapted. They graze too closely in flocks, and tramp and graze the grass into the sand. This adds to the blowing hazard. Constant attention to prevent overstocking must be given for the same reason. SOUTHWESTERN WHEAT AREA (AREA 7) Wheat, relative to other crops, is more important in this area than in any other section of the state. Corn, barley, and oats are also grown but wheat occupies the dominant acreage. The reason that wheat is the most important crop hinges again largely upon the matter of physical adaptation. Soil type, topography, and climate all contribute to making this a wheat country. The soil is a medium-textured clay loam or silt loam which is particularly good for wheat. Because of the rela - tively low rainfall, wheat does better than corn, which re - quires for best growth a larger and a better distributed rain - fall. The altitude in the western part of the area is too high for best success in corn production. More corn is found in the eastern part of the area, but here the soil is lighter, the altitude is lower, and the growing season is longer. All of these factors tend to favor corn, so that its advantage relative to wheat increases. Westward thru the area barley increases in relative importance, while corn decreases. Another factor which has favored wheat is the level or gently rolling and unobstructed topography. This permits the use of big-scale machinery, such as combines, big drills, and big hitches, which in turn, thru lowering the unit costs of production, enable wheat to be grown with a very small expenditure of labor. Even tho the rainfall is low and yields uncertain, with these big-scale methods farmers can grow wheat with profit on low-grade land in this area. This has been a big factor in the expansion of the wheat area in this region during the past few years. Kimball, Deuel, and Cheyenne counties grow some potatoes on a commercial scale. The high altitude with the cool nights favors potatoes. Disease has not been a serious problem as yet and fairly good yields are obtained. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">■ ■ . Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 The rough pasture land is utilized in a limited way by cattle. The pasture has a low carrying capacity; hence the number of cattle here is not very large. There are not many hogs produced in this area, due in large part to the low production of concentrated feeds and legume hay. HIGH PLAINS SMALL, GRAIN AND CRAZING AREA (AREA 8) This area is quite variable in character and might be divided into several smaller areas. Furthermore/it is in a period of quite rapid change. Such a high proportion of the land is in pasture that the data do not show clearly the rela - tive importance of the crops. In the discussion of the enter - prises, the part of the area where each is of greatest import - ance will be mentioned. In general the agriculture of this area may be characterized as consisting of small grains, corn, and grazing. This is the spring wheat section of the state and also is an important barley area. These two are the dominant small grains except in Box Butte county, where winter wheat is the leading grain. Despite the relatively high altitude, corn does fairly well in some parts of this area. The yields are low but the crop is quite certain. Reference to Table 5 will show that yields have a variability of only 22 per cent as compared with a variability of 26 per cent for wheat. Both, it will be further observed, are less variable than in Area 7. Most of the corn is in the eastern portion of the area and is grown principally on the sandier type of soils. Corn does better on this type of soil than does wheat. The sandier soil \varms up more quickly in the spring, thus giving greater assurance for maturity of the corn crop. The altitude in the eastern portion where the corn is grown also is not so high as in other parts of the area. Barley is grown more extensively than oats. Altho the barley yields are almost as variable as the oat yields (see Table 5) , barley produces more pounds of feed per acre. Alfalfa holds a high place among the cultivated crops of Area 8, particularly in the northern part. It is grown as a seed crop in Sheridan, Sioux, and Dawes counties. Box Butte county is the center of commercial potato production in the area — both table stock and certified seed being grown. The cool climate, good yields, and freedom from disease have con - tributed to making this section a certified seed area. Cattle are the principal livestock found in Area 8. The rougher land is utilized almost entirely for grazing, Sioux county in particular being a cattle ranching section. In the western parts of this area, the grama and buffalo types of grass are quite common tho it is not a typically "short- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Types op Farming in Nebraska grass" " country. Such grasses are more suitable for pro - ducing grass-fat cattle than are the grasses of the Sand Hill area. In the sandier parts, cattle ranching is quite similar to that in the Sand Hills. Hog production has not been an im - portant enterprise in the past but is becoming more so. In addition to hogs raised in the area, some are shipped in and fed out on barley and corn. IRRIGATED AREA. (AREA 9) The availability of water and the fact that soil and topog - raphy are suitable for irrigation has resulted in making this area distinctly different from those already discussed. Irri - gation has practically eliminated the hazard of limited rain - fall. The high investment per acre of land has led to choice of major crops requiring much labor but giving large returns per acre. Legumes are grown extensively as a means of main - taining the soil, which is drawn on heavily by such crops as sugar beets, which yield large volumes of product. This has contributed toward making sugar beets the dominant enter - prise and alfalfa second in importance. Corn, wheat, barley oats, and potatoes are the other important crops, and increas - ing acreages of beans have been planted in recent years. The large quantities of sugar beet by-products and alfalfa that are available have resulted in the development of com - mercial feeding of sheep and cattle on a large scale. Dairying is gaining in importance as a source of income. THE INTERNAL ORGANIZATION OF NEBRASKA FARMS This bulletin has thus far been devoted to discussing and explaining the geographical distribution of Nebraska's agri - culture and the way in which the various crop and livestock enterprises fit together into farming systems in different parts of the state. From the analysis the state was divided into nine regions in each of which the type of farming followed is distinct from that followed in other areas. These areas were determined on the basis of similarity in the dominant crop and livestock organizations followed and on the uniformity in prevailing soil and climatic conditions. Whenever there was a distinct difference in these factors, this was presumed to represent the breaking off of one type and the beginning of another. From this it should not be deduced, however, that there is assumed to be complete uniformity in either organiza - tions or physical conditions within each area. FARMING SYSTEMS VARY WITHIN AS WELL AS BETWEEN DIFFERENT REGIONS Physical and economic conditions within an area as a whole may favor the adoption of a particular combination of crops " "Short-Brass " is a term used to describe land of heavy soil types covered with the short erasses of the buffalo and grama types. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 and livestock in preference to some other combination. In certain localities and on particular farms, however, these con - ditions may be sufficiently different to justify the adoption of an organization which varies quite widely from the prevailing one of the area. Because of local differences in soil type, topography, drainage, and the like, farmers may find it ad - vantageous to get into a system of farming which is quite different from that followed by the majority of the farmers in the area. ' Another reason why complete uniformity in farming sys - tems is not found is the varying preferences and aptitudes of farmers. As is well known, farmers vary widely in their likes and dislikes and in the way they interpret given situations. Some farmers are more alert in seeking profits than others. They feel the acquisitive urge more keenly and Avill make rapid shifts in their production to take advantage of favorable situations. Other farmers are less "price sensitive.',' They are influenced more by custom and will follow along, doing about the same thing year after year, usually delaying from one to several years before making adjustments. Still other factors causing variations in farming systems within a given area are conditions of tenure, degree of en - cumbrance, and variations in the family labor supply. Tenant operators, for example, do not always have complete freedom of choice in selecting either the amounts or proportions of the crop and livestock enterprises that they handle. Thru uncer - tainty as to the length of time they may have control of the farm, they also will not get into a particular rotation or follow a particular soil treatment which they would be dis - posed to do were their length of tenure more certain and secure. Likewise an encumbered operator who is heavily in debt will likely behave differently from one who has his farm paid for and is free of debt. The former will be disposed to push his resources to the utmost. He will be inclined to make shifts in production with changing prices if he sees a chance to increase his profits by so doing. The unencumbered owner on the other hand may not feel this urge to the same degree This is particularly true if he has passed the prime of life He is not so concerned then with getting the last dollar out of the farm, but will work along in a more leisurely way Farmers with a large supply of family labor are likely to get into a more intensive system of farming than they other - wise would follow were it necessary to hire the labor. This probably accounts in large part for certain cash grain farmers including dairying as a supplementary enterprise. They see a chance; thereby, to utilize some cheap family labor and in - crease their income. . </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Types op Farming in Nebraska These are some of the more important factors causing variations in farming systems in a particular area. That it is important to keep them in mind when considering the farm - ing systems of an area or region seems obvious. Even tho there is a high degree of uniformity in physical conditions within an area, this uniformity does not necessarily lead to equal uniformity in the farming systems practiced. It should not be inferred, however, that the farming sys - tems are so different that each is in effect a law unto itself. Were minute differences considered, this probably would be true. In the same sense geneticists say there are no two organisms exactly alike, but there usually are enough things in common among them to permit grouping into common classes or groups. If minor differences are disregarded, this can be done with but negligible error. This tendency of the farming systems in an area to exhibit common group charac - teristics furnishes the basis for the tables and discussion which follow. METHOD OF DETERMINING TYPICAL FARMING SYSTEMS AND MEANING OF A TYPICAL FARM A special study was made of 1925 census data to learn more of the farming systems followed in different parts of the state. Acreage and livestock data were secured on every farm (about 7,500 in all) in approximately 90 townships scattered thruout the state. Analysis of these data was made to determine the character and variations in the farming sys - tems in several parts of each of the nine type-of-farming areas of the state. The farms in each representative township or group of townships were grouped on the basis of size and the most important enterprises. This grouped together the farms with about the same organization, that is, those following the same farming system. Thus, a typical farming system or typical farm is one which is representative of what is followed on a group of farms which are doing essentially the same thing. Figure 25 illustrates such a grouping of farms. This figure shows a group of 83 160-acre farms in two adjoining town - ships of Cuming county in Area 1. Each set of horizontal lines across the chart represents the crop and livestock organization of a farm. Since corn is the most important crop of that section, the farms have been separated into three groups according to the proportion of farm land in corn. Within each group the farms have been arranged according to the number of sows. It will be noted that corn occupies from 20 to 62 per cent of the land area of the different farms. In this connection it is well to keep in mind that these farms are all of the same </seg>
            <seg id="p066"/>
            <seg id="p067">Types of. Farming in Nebraska size — 160 acres. With such wide variation in corn acreage, it is obvious that an average of all 83 farms would not be representative of the group. There are so many farms with both more or less corn than the average and so far removed from it that the average could never be taken as a substitute for them. While the lack of a central tendency in the farms, as a whole is clearly indicated, there is a more distinct central tendency in certain groups of them. Thus there are 17 out of the 83 farms, or 20 per cent of them, at the top of the chart which have about the same amount of corn, or an average of about 55 per cent of the farm area in corn. Just below these farms there is another group of 31 farms, or 37 per cent of the total, which have less corn — only 40 per cent of the farm area. Then finally there is a third group of 35 farms, or 43 per cent, which have still less corn or only 30 per cent of the farm area in corn. There is less variation in both the oats and hay acreages. Thus the group at the top of the chart has on the average about 18 per cent of the farm area in oats and each of the other two groups has 22 per cent. The first group has about 8 per cent of the farm area in hay while the other two have 13 and 14 per cent respectively. With pasture, however, it is different; the pasture acreage varies inversely with that of corn. In the first group pasture occupies about 18 per cent of the farm area, in the second group 23 per cent, and in the third group 31 per cent. Thus the farms with a high acreage in corn have a low acreage in pasture and vice versa. When we come to consider the livestock organization it will be noted that there is considerably more variation. Even tho the cropping systems of the farms of each group are quite uniform, the livestock systems are quite diverse. In fact with the exception of horses there are at least two livestock organizations found in each of the groups for the same crop - ping system. The chief variation is to be noted in the hogs. For this reason the farms in each group have been subarrayed on the number of sows handled. Thus in the first group there are some farms with from 10 to 15 sows and others with none at all. In the second group there are some farms with around 20 to 22 sows, another group with from 10 to 15, and a third with 5 or less. Likewise in the third group the same tendency is to be noted. There is slightly more uniformity in both the cows and other cattle. By grouping these farms into typical groups in this way a much more precise knowledge of the prevailing organizations is obtained. Instead of grouping them all together to obtain a so-called average farm, they have been divided into three main groups, each of which is distinctive enough to be kept </seg>
            <seg id="p068"/>
            <seg id="p069"/>
            <seg id="p070"/>
            <seg id="p071"/>
            <seg id="p072">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 Sl!°^ an .organization with 75 acres in feed crops, and 46 per cent followed one with 95 acres of feed crops On the 240-acre farms 53 per cent of the farmers followed an organi- KoE^f 1 f 30 H acres of f « ed cr °P s . and 42 per cent one wfth 180 acres of feed crops, and so on for the other sizes. Figures within the parentheses under crop acreages and livestock numbers present the range from low to high in acres or numbers. In some cases, it will be noted that two sets of Thp^T Tlu ?°£,° ne °. r . more of kinds of livestock. These indicatethat the variation in numbers of that class of livestock is wide and the separation into two groups indicates the varying emphasis given the enterprise. indicates WAYS IN WHICH THESE TYPICAL FARMING SYSTEMS MAY BE USED The discussion of the uses of the material presented in the foregoing pages will be confined to three general headings! use of results in (1) determining profitable long-time sys - &amp; A ar %l ne lu &lt; 2 &gt; ,. inter Pjeting the annual agricultural out - look, and (3) other lines of research work. USE OF RESULTS IN DETERMINING PROFITABLE LONG-TIME SYSTEMS OF FARMING During the past few years there has been a great deal of Th ulZr to the working out of agricultural programs. The ultimate objective of these programs whether on a STJ&amp; 1 at6 ' ST nati ° nal ba8is ' is t0 help farmers both a? wWh a " a l a group ' to get into systems of farming S S 1 *T thein maximum returns for the resource! nrni T h + ? 1S tr - Ue whether the particular program be better o rotations, improved varieties of crops, disease control; S «?T/ ractlCes ,' adjustments to market outlooks, or what not. Before much progress can be made in this direc - fafaf JiT^' lt * 1 !». first neces sary to know what the situation w in each area of the county, state, or region. It is necessary feedta? SrLS su « h f thl , n e s a S the yields, and production and feeding practices, but also what variations in farming sys - tems are found so as to determine how the probable fondi- SenVareas^ *** 7em &amp;Pply t0 th( * e in «3J* h this fn f° rm ation on organizations and production Sw S - aS a - b^kground, the real problem becomes one of ?hp in" n K gf m B^ ht °. f Physical conditions in the area, the long-time outlook for yields, prices of farm products and the cost of items used in production, which of tne many pre - vailing systems of farming being followed in the area is likely to be most profitable for the group in the long run or ■to de termine if some system of farming not followed at present gives promise of yielding even greater returns </seg>
            <seg id="p073"/>
            <seg id="p074">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 The wide diversity in organization on farms of different sizes in the various areas and even on farms of the same size suggests the inadvisability of generalizing for the farms as a whole. Such blanket recommendations are not only question - able but are likely to be misleading. On the other hand, it probably is not feasible to attempt to give each farmer indi - vidual attention. When, however, the farming systems have been analyzed and grouped in a manner similar to that shown in the foregoing tables it is possible to make the interpreta - tion in terms of groups of farms which are doing about the same thing. Farms taken as representative of these groups are as near the individual farm basis as it is possible to get without considering each farm individually. Just how these typical farming systems may be used in arriving at a decision with respect to the relative returns which can be expected from different farming systems over a period of years will now be indicated. The organizations used in the illustration are taken from representative town - ships in Kearney county in Area 3. In this area the 160-acre farm is the dominant size. On these quarter-section farms, according to the special tabulation of the 1925 census, there were three organizations commonly followed. (See Table 9.) To illustrate the method, a budget or estimate of receipts and expenses is shown in detail for the organization having 50 acres of wheat. More of the 160-acre farmers follow this organization than any other. The returns from two of the other organizations (those having 30 and 75 acres of wheat, respectively) are also calculated in the same way but only the final results are shown. . Since, in this illustration, we are interested in showing the probable returns which can be expected from these organiza - tions from the long-time standpoint, both long-time yields and prices are used in calculating the budgets. The yields used are the average yields of the last ten years in Kearney county and the prices are the average prices received by farmers in Nebraska in the past five years. The prevailing production and feeding practices for the different classes of livestock and the machinery and cultural practices used in the area are assumed in figuring out-of-pocket expenses. The indicated returns of $1,693 shown in Table 11 are not net by any means and should not be considered as such. Only out-of-pocket expenses have been deducted or only those ex - penses which will vary as the organization is changed. No charges have been included for taxes, insurance, interest, re - pairs, etc., all of which would have to be taken out to get a net income figure. Since in this illustration we are inter - ested in showing the relative returns from one organization </seg>
            <seg id="p075"/>
            <seg id="p076"/>
            <seg id="p077"/>
            <seg id="p078">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 the result would correspond very closely with the figure shown in the table. Taking the other two organizations having 30 and 75 acres of wheat, respectively, and calculating the expected returns from them, using the same yields and prices, we get the following results which are compared with the returns from the organization having 50 acres of wheat: Organization with 30 acres of wheat $1,580 . Organization with 50 acres of wheat 1,693 Organization with 75 acres of wheat 1,778 Thus, at average yields and prices which have been ob - tained in this area, these results indicate a slight advantage in returns for the organization having 75 acres of wheat. The nature of the other enterprises of these three organizations may be noted by referring again to Table 9. While the organization with the high acreage of wheat has the highest returns, there are other factors which the farmer considers. With a larger wheat acreage than either of the other organizations, labor is distributed less evenly thru the year and more dependence must be placed on hired labor at harvest time! A larger outlay of cash is therefore required. Increases in wheat acreage beyond 75 acres would result in still less even seasonal distribution of labor requirements. Following this same procedure it is possible to determine fairly accurately about what return on the average can be expected from any organization which might be handled on this size of farm. Such a method of attack will enable inter - ested persons to determine which of any number of organiza - tions will likely prove most profitable under the physical and economic conditions of production existing in the area. USE OF RESULTS IN INTERPRETING THE ANNUAL AGRICULTURAL OUTLOOK In a similar way these typical farming systems may be used in interpreting the meaning and effect of changing price relationships upon the relative profitableness of different farm organizations. A farmer cannot stop with the selection of a general system of farming to be followed over a period of years. Some short-time adjustments in the general plan are usually necessary. This may be desirable due to failure of a particular crop or to prospects for either more or less favorable prices for the products in a particular year. In the following table the relative effect which changing prices have upon the returns from different organizations is illus - trated. For this purpose the same organization used in illustrating the calculation of the budget (Table 10) will be used. In this organization as now handled it will be noted that both corn and hogs are sold. While 6,000 pounds of hogs </seg>
            <seg id="p079"/>
            <seg id="p080">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 244 hog prices are high and corn prices low, both Organizations No. 1 and No. 2 show a higher return than does No. 3, which has only a few hogs. In other words, this table simply illustrates that as prices change the returns to be expected from different organizations likewise change. Hence, if a farmer is to follow his economic advantage, he must take changing, price relationships into account when deciding what is the best thing for him to do any particular year. When the annual outlook report comes out these typical farming systems thus afford an excellent basis for interpreting its probable effect to the farmers in the different areas of the state. USE OF RESULTS IN OTHER LINES OF RESEARCH WORK These type-of-f arming studies are also useful in other ways. By differentiating the agriculture of a state into type-of - f arming areas a much more detailed and accurate picture of the situation in each part of the state is obtained. It further gives a better idea of the limits within which specific results from experiments or special studies may apply and also affords a more accurate basis for determining the degree of generalization that is permissible. Studies made with the view of determining standards of performance, yields, production practices, etc., will be more reliable and trustworthy if confined to type areas in which there is a fairly high degree of uniformity in these factors. Likewise income studies would be more realistic and sug - gestive if the results were analyzed from the standpoint of type-of-f arming areas and further restricted to show returns from farms of the same size and type. In these and many other ways the results of these studies should be of help in adding greater precision to other lines of research work. • ■ [BM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>