<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title> </title>
               <date value="1904-06-30">June 30, 1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Twki-iKtii Annual Kktort OF THE Dkpaktmext of Banking SHOWINU THK CONDITION OF THE Building and Loan Associations OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal War Ending June 30. 1904. Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board August 20, 1904 HY tOYSE, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Department of Banking OF THE STATK OF NKHKASKA Board HON. &lt; HARLKS WKSTON . .Auditor of Public Accounts and Pre* PETKR MORTKNSKN State Tr.-a HON. F. N. PROUT.. .Attorney Omen! K. RoVSE . ...Seci A. N. DODSON . ..Chief i MAUDE HOGK .. - enoffraphm KXAMINKHS FRKD WHITThaiOKK K. K. Kmmett. L. V. Baskkll. .Iacoh F. Haijjkkman </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Ktatk of Nebraska. Department of Bankin To His Excellency. John H. Mickey. Governor of Nebraska, and thi Honorables Charles Weston. Peter Mortensen. and F. N. Prout. the Stat Banking Board of the State of Nebraska : Gentlemen In compliance with section 8a of cha] f the Compiled Statutes of tin of Nebraska : eqniringthi of the S '.anking Hoard' o the Governor and State Banking Board annual have the honor to submit herewith the twelfth annu; »rt of the department of banking for the period beginning uly 1, 190:5, and ending June 30. 1904, showing the conn f the building and loan associations of the state of N t the close of business June M, 1004, compiled from annual reports of the several building and loan associations nitted to the State Banking Board, in accordance with the &gt;rovisions of the building and loan act, approved April 4. \ibulated statements, detailed reports, and such inforn nd comments touching this rejx&gt;rt as is deemed \nrn ill be found on the following pagi Very respectfully, K Royse, Secretary State Banking Board Lincoln. ArtirsT i'ii. 1!k&gt;4. &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT TAL NUMBER OF ASSOCIATIONS, NUMBER OF SHAKES IN I AND TOTAL ASSETS. FROM 1892, THE FIRST YEAR THAT AI'THKA REPORTS WERE MADE. DOWN TO THE PRESENT TIMK. NO. OF NO. OF SHAK TOTAI ASS'NS IN FOR' ASSET! VKAK ASSETS 71 4T).O12J $2.!*&gt;2..V 1893 *4 til.!W4.1 H.tKJ.ov 1894 TL23U ;{.khx.imh 31 xi 70,«lfi 3,929.7- 7.1 t.4.8911 3,n i«n cn.fivu 189W tM&gt; 89.492 19«t in) 106,825 W7.3K OH 1901 M 119, 4.:U4.74 i:«».()83 4.7- 5H 153.424 174.022 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Sl'MMARIKS OOMPILED FROM THE ANNTAL REPORT* OF BUILDING AND LOAN ASS(H IATIONS FOR THE YEARS FROM I*&lt;r2. THK FIRST YKAR RKPORTS WERE RECEIVED, TO lt«H IN»Ll' SIVK. SHOWING THE TOTALS OF ALL MOLDING LOAN* ASS(KIATIONS IN THE STATE FOR THK YK ABOVE STATED. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December. 1*92. Assets. First nu&gt;rtfra^e loans. *2. :&gt;:{.-&gt;. M4." Loans secured h_v stock of association. 175.1' Heal rotate 50.141.7:; Expenses and taxes paid ~i&gt;. «»:ti?. tv»i ( ash with treasurer tiU.994. 1* All other : Total $2,902 Liabilities. Capital stock paid up 11,024,* Premiums paid Mi. lo;j. !&lt;• Interest received 4H4.- Fines collected Xi.~ Other liabilities 116,013. (KJ I ■•***•*■***■«■■■•*■ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 SUMMARY &lt; &gt;F SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT RECEIPTS AND KXPKNDITl'RF.S FOR THK YEAR KNI)IN( OKCKMBKR 31, l*&gt;tJ. Receipts Balance on hand December M . 1W1 Dues Interest Fines lo.MW.88 Loans repaid ' Other receipts Total Expenditures. Loans M41 Salaries 17. v lo.: Withdrawals i nher expenditures i on hand Total •1,02-4 Recapitulation Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled Number of shares in force at this date </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE STATEMENT OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK TRK STATK OF NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of December. \W.i. Assets. morttfajre loans %&gt;,tikH,3lti.M Loans secured by stock of association MX\. L33.0I Real estate x«i. 1 Kxpetises and taxes paid 102, i fash 73.4rtl.tt: &lt; &gt;ther assets not enumerated above :N2. Total $3,«o:i Liabilities. Capital stock paid up $2,525. - Premiums paid 443." Interest received 511. -i &gt;, collected 31, H61.sk other liabilities. . 140." Total $3,663 086.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER .10, 1*93. Receipts. Balance on hand December 31. 1892 *7!).O5B.69 Dues Interest 213. 1 Fines Loans repaid 217 . &lt; Hher receipts Total »1.2«t Expenditures. Loans $741. • Salaries 22.141.11 &lt; Kher expenses Withdrawals .117,620.88 Cash on hand Miscellaneous expenditures " 117.:- Total «1 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEA I Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during current year Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled Number of shares in force at this date Recapitulation. Numberof associations in force December 31, 1892 Number of associations discontinued during year Number of new associations during year . . . lh Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December Assets. First mortgage loans $2. v Loans secured by stock of association 27 1 . • Real estate 117.' rises and taxes paid i;K&gt;. r assets MV.:. Total $3,88X.iHH.:il Liabilities. Capital stock paid up $2,694. I'remiums paid 411. Interest received 001. 1 Fines collected IVi. : All other liabilities l^.l.H.^f </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. rARY OP SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RE( AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YKAR KNDING DECEMBER SI, 1894. Receipts. Balance on hand December 31, 1893 "75. Interest Fines Loans repaid &lt; &gt;ther receipts " Total 12".'. - • Total '■■■■ Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans »671,896.81 Loans •671,896.81 Salaries Salaries Other expenses Other expenses Withdrawals 421 ' Withdrawals 421. " &lt; Wher expenditures on hand Total $1,444,9 &lt; Wher expenditures ( &gt;n hand Total $1,444 \PITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE APITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE i ENDING DECEMBER 31, U ENDING DECEMBER .11. Number of shares in force at last report 61,059 1-10 Number of shares in force at last report til. 059 1-10 Number of shares issued during year 2H,712i Number of shares issued during year Number of shares issued during year 2K.712J Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled lti.540 1-10 Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and canceled lti.54&lt;) 1-10 Number of shares in force at this date 71. 2 ■ Number of shares in force at this date 71,231] Recapitulation. Recapitulation. Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 Number of associations discontinued during year. ... Number of associations discontinued during year. ... Number of new associations during year Number of new associations during year Vy mVw&gt;r of ftssooi f&amp;tions in f oiv4* Doofmhoi* H"! 1 H^^4 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December, 1895. Assets. First mortgage loans .' $2,818. Loans secured by stock associations 197,643.48 Real estate 150,245.20 Expenses and taxes paid 130,043.38 Cash with treasurer 62.880.84 All other assets 486.&lt;5ti9.5.f Total $3,92!" Liabilities. Capital stock paid up $2,"44, 413.&amp;5 Premiums paid 338. i .138,i', Interest received 505, | Fines collected 37 0M.2K II.0t8.aH All other liabilities 300. ' Total $3,«2Si </seg>
            <seg id="p013">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIAT1 13 SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK YEAR ENDING DKfKMBER 31, Receipts. Dues Interest 215,!' Fines Loans repaid Other receipts Total . ..$1.44-'. Expenditures. Loans Salaries Other expenses Withdrawals Ml Other expenditures &lt; ash on hand Total *1 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. X umber of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year Number of shares matured, withdrawn,- and canceled . Number of shares in force at this date Recapitulation. Number of associations in force December 31, 1W&gt;4 ... Number of associations discontinued during year Number of new associations during year ... 3 Number of associations in force December 31, 189-"&gt; . . .81 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI&lt; S I'M MARY (IK THE CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the ;Ust day of Deoembei Assets. loans *L' - loans in process of foreclosure 117. Real estate 177. -I Furniture and fixtures -.1 Due from shareholders Expenses and taxes paid 109,497.20 ( &gt;ther 1517. .772. 4'&gt; Total ..$3,771.' Liabilities. paid #2.r&gt;*-2. Premiums unearned 100,5 Profits undivided including reserve fund Profits apportioned to shares in force shareholders on incomplete loans </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITl'REK FOR THK VKAR KNDIN&lt; DKCKMUKR 31. 1896. Receipts. Balance on hand December 31, 1895 ■ Interest Fines Loans repaid .... &lt; Hher receipts Total Expenditures. Loans Other Exjx Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, duet Matured stock, earning- &lt; ash on hand Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARK. TRANSACTIONS FoR TH KMBKR 31, ENDING DEC Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares matured during current year Number of shares in force at this date r umber of loans made for payment of homestead UK during current year ttl t umber of shares issued during current year . . umber of shares withdrawn and canceled during current vear &gt;f loans made for building purposes during current year Number of shareholdf r2.14~&gt; Supplemental Report. No. of shares of stockissued since organization 141,116 No. i if stock issued since organization Number of ahaxM of stuck withdrawn and canceled Number of mortgages in pi re Amount of mo :i process ot foreclosure $111. Ptal appraised value of real estate and improvemei curitv 4.44m,98».lO "—-•-»• ■ Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the associate as collateral security "2.444. 1 Value of other real estate held by the association^ Shares Statement Total number of series issued ~&gt;Xt Total number of shares issued Total number of shares withdrawn 41 - Total number of shares loaned on Total number of shares outstanding Recapitulation. Number of associations in force December 31 Number o -continued during year Number of new associations during vear XI W # ' ♦* t S J~\ * It-. 11 1 ftfMf </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATE OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December. 18H7. Assets. mortgage loans *2.i&gt;72. 1 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure HO. Real estate 209.' Furniture and fixtures 2.^' Expenses and taxes paid 69,8 Due from shareholders 75,927.4!' Other assets 382.443.2i&gt; Total $3,554,788.08 Liabilities. Dues paid 82,368, 117. u". Premiums unearned "&gt;2.' ■■ Profits undivided including reserve fund 2SK&gt;. ' Profits apportioned to shares in force 36fi. Due shareholders on incomplete loans --"4.74 Other liabilities 443,100.48 Total $3,554,788.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Receipts. Balance on hand December 31, l*S#i t55.Tl~.Ui Interest Fines Loans repaid ; - Other receipt! 1- ; 1'otal Expenditures. Loans S2.41 Salaries ( Kher expenses Hit Withdrawals, dues HHi Withdrawals, earnings 87, 1V7. 12 Matured stock. dut~ Matured stock, earnings ♦ ash on hand Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARK TRANSACTIONS FoK THK VEAR ENDING DK&lt; KMUKK 31. 1807. Numlwr of shares in force at last report Number of shares matured during current \t ;i Number of loans in force at thi&lt; date Po. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages dur - ing fiscal rear Number of shares issued during curi -1.14- No. of shares withdrawn and cancel- j current year. . . No. of loans made for building purposes during currei Number of shareholders ll&gt;21 Supplemental Report. No. of shaivs of stock issued since organisation No. of series of stock issued since organization Number of shares withdrawn and canceled Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure Total appraisal value of real estate and Improvements hel&lt;i •urit.v Amount of insurance in force and assigned t&lt;&gt; the Association security as collateral security Value of other real estate held h\ the association* 1* •. 114. 1T+ Shares Statement Total number of series issued Total number of shares issued Total number of shares withdrawn Total number of shares loaned on Total number of shares outstanding 47. U'n ; Recapitulation. Number of er :tl. 1*!*&gt; Number &lt;«• during year Number of ne« Number o1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATE SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATK OF NEBRASKA. On the 31st day of December. \W*. Assets. First niortjratre loans 12,821,703.11 First mortpatre loans in process of foreclosure "&gt;»i. Real estate 192,450.98 Furniture and fixtures 2.0 ( ash 1-Hi. . Expenses and taxes paid Due from shareholders 47.4tt4.:{* &lt;Xhei 114. 047. i4 Total *:i. 4J- Liabilities. &lt; apital stock pa : d up 18,906. &gt; Profits undivided, including reserve hind 330,2 *2.M&lt;N, - Premiums unearned 47,517.51 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 1U.47-V 1* Advance payments Matured stock unpaid. . 11(1. 1 Bills payable Other liabiliti. Total S3.428. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 RKCF.IITS AND KXl'KNDITrRKS FOR THK FISCAL VKAK ENDING DECEMBER 31. U Receipts. Receipts Balance on hand December 31, WC Balance on hand December 31, 1897 I nUrest Loans repaid ; Loans repaid ; '. " receipts l**.ti:M. Total receipts l**.t&gt;:M. In Total Expenditures Expenditures. Loans :ies ex(&gt;enses Loans Salaries expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Withdrawals, earnings M atured stock, dues M atured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings on hand 14&amp;.254. Total Matured stock, earnings on hand i I' Total APITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE 1 KNDING DKCKMBKR 31. l&gt;er of shares in force at last report Numbers of shares matured during current year Number of shares issued during current year Number of shares withdrawn and canceled during current j • IO,2H8 Number of shares in force at this date Number of loans for payment of homestead mortgages during current vear •&gt;f loans made for building pur)K&gt;ses during current year :&gt;er of shareholdei 12,752 Supplemental Report Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure Amount of me »il api ilue of real estate and improvements held ■uritv ■"&gt;. Is.'!. 247. 1 &lt; • :int of insurance in force and assigned to the Association collateral security Value of other real estate held by the association- Recapitulation. Number of associations in force December '.\\ . Number of associations discontinued during year Number of associations in f </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SUMMARY Or THK CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA. &lt;)n the SOtfa (lav of .Tune. A. I). Ifltd Assets. On the 30th day of June, A. I). 1899. Assets. ! mortgage loans S2.H58.U10. mortgage loans 12,858,910.7- • loans in profess of foreclosure ilT.L First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure M.. Real estate 1«5.&lt; Furniture and fixtures 2.-._ . .. 14&lt;i. Uti uses and taxes i&gt;aid . . . 41. uses and taxes paid . . . 41. from sh»r. r2- from shan 4J- &lt; nher assets :$H.4". 17 &lt; Hlier assets :5X.4T". 17 Total *:t. :;:(::. 7si..;: Total Liabilities. Liabilities. Capital stock paid up fc!.Ht&gt;M.;Un.44 Capital stock paid up fc!.Ht;x.;si!i.44 Profits undivided, including reserve fund 27o. L32.55 Profits undivided, including fund 27n. Premiums unearned 46,3 Premiums unearned +.'i. Due shareholders on incomplete loans 31," Due shareholders on incomplete loans 31," Advance payments 24.&amp;U.1X Advance payments 24.&amp;U.1X Matured stock unpaid 7x.&lt;I»m. 1 1 Bills payable !i.T !• liabilities 4,fil </seg>
            <seg id="p021">BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 21 RKiKlI-TS AND KXPENDITURES FOR THK SIX MONTHS K N I) I N * i .11 N 1" '*• &gt; 1 VMi Receipts on ham - repaid p receipts. . . . Total Tola Expenditures Expenditures Salaries Withdrawals. dm j s. . . . Withdrawals, earnings _ . Matured dues Matured stork, earnings Cash on hand IU.Tm; Total - . _' ■ Recapitulation N uml Nutnner of -liaivs in foive at tli . Num </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BVIUHNC AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. SUMMARY OF Tl ITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATK OF NERRASKA. On the 30th day of June. A. I&gt;. 11MMI. Assets. 13. I.,.". loans in process of foreclosun Real estate Furniture and tixtu - 2.7 Delinquent interest. premiums, and fin - - paid . . . : d 1..V 1 '■ Total 13.09" Liabilities &lt; apital stock running 12.71" Full paid stock ... ve fund. I'ndivided profits 150,841.57 -hareholders on incomplete loan- H iums unearned ... Advance dues : , Adva ums .")..". B !!^ i." All other liat): </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FoR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE :$o. 1 Receipts. Receipts in hand Julv 1. 1- balance on hand July 1. L8U running stock lull paid &gt;tur ims - full ]iaid sta lntere&gt;t liums Fines •'ilH'S Membership and transfer ft lemberahip and transfer fees paid jians repaid iial estate sales - rec eipts ttber receipts Total Total 1 Expenditures. Expenditures Loans H.12* Salar .'.'.'..'..... 31.415.11 : 'ommissions )tht-r expenses &lt; 'omu - Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings ; Withdraw ing* • Matured stock, dues I"".: Matured stock, dues '."" Matured stock, earninuis. . . . 21 Matured stock, earnings. ... Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Full paid stock, earnings &lt; ash on hand ( ash on hand Hills payable ' -' Hills payable Total SHARES STATEMENT. issued since organization . issued since Organization . (1 during fiscal year, d during fiscal year . matured durii withdrawn du withdrawn du of runnii ■ this dafc of full paid stock in force at th loaned on . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 BL'ILDIXN AND LOAN ASSOC1AT] SIM MARY UTION i&gt;F THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATE OK NEBRASKA. On the *&gt;th day of June. A. D. 1901. Assets. loans l3.A41.462.tfH loans in process of foreclosure 2"&gt;. • 123.K1UM) 110.2 Furniture and fixtures - \'.i. 1 1 h 1«2 Delinquent interest, premiuma and tines ;i:&gt;.' - and taxes paid Insurance paid &lt; &gt;thei Total.. lt&gt;4. Total Liabilities. Liabilities. ( apital stock running ( apital stock running Full paid stock 522, 4 15. 4« Full paid stock 522, 4 15. -W ve fund ve fund fndi fits &gt;n incon)i&gt;letf loans Undivided profits Pram arned U7.214.&lt;i&lt;i Adva' 20.1 Advance .nd premiums Bills payable Other liabilities Total ...•4,314,744.* </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 BUILDING AND LOAN RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 3D, I'.mU. Receipts. Balance on hand Julj 1. 1»*X» * - running stock) I - Dues I full paid stock) Interest Interest Premiums Premiums - "*•'_ Fines Membership and transfer §w Membership and transfer 1&lt; ■• — repaid te -ales - repaid Hents &lt; &gt;ther receiptH - Total Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans Salarit Salaries ommissions ►ther expenses » ommissions ( fcher expenses Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Witlidrawals. earnings Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Matured stock, earning! •Hill paid stock, dues -\ill paid stock, earnings ash on hand Full paid stock, du Full paid stock, earning t ash on hand Bills pavahle Total SHARES STATEMENT No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares issued since ■ No. of si) ed during fiscal ye No. of shares matured duri .111. t/l BUBl^a lliovun" v*«i i No. of shares withdrawn during ;tr No. of shares of running stock in force at th No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat« No. of shares loaned on i in which ares sub &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BUII-.DING AND LOAN SUMMARY OF THE CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATK &lt;)K NKBRASKA. On the :il&gt;th day of June. A. I), lit).'. Assets. loans • loans in process of foreclosun . .TTti.l" 141 Real in.: Furniture and fixtures .{.42.!. 1 st, premiums and fines :i&gt;&gt;. and taxes paid Total Liabilities , running Full paid stock ■nd .■ si incomplete loan&gt; uurus unearned - IT.' and premiums 1.7&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI 27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KoK THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE 30, l«fi. Receipts. Balance on hand Julv 1. 1901 running stock) full paid stock! Interest ■ 17"&gt;. 12 Premiums s iip and transfer fees aid 17.' Rents Other receipts + 1 v». 1" Total Expenditures. Salaries Withdrawals, dues l.n Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock. dues 141 Full paid stock, earnings on hand ( &gt;ther liabilities Total SHARKS STATEMENT No. of shares in force at tl No. of shares issi, - issued during fiscal |&gt;&lt; • if shares matured dur: No. of shares withdrawn di No. of shares of running stock in foi of full paid stock in f' No. No.. No. • • cancellation for i </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BCII.DING AND LOAN - SUMMARY (IF THE CONDITION OF' THK BUILDIX&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATK OF XKBRASKA. On the Kith day of June. l'tiK Assets. $4.i. • loans in process of foreclosure 24. l"&gt;4.iij 15»i.(» 102,153.89 Furniture and stationary 'i4.&lt;il 2Ui. nquent interest, premiums and fines 32,3 -paid 1- !l!i. Total *:&gt;:m Liabilities. ( apital stot-k running. ( Dues and dividends) 14,204, Full paid stock T»*» •_ _ ind 102,470.31 Tndi vided profits 158,1 ■ n incomplete loans :i!t.271 . M s unearned 2H,1 Adya&gt; 14. i Advance interest and premiums 3,1" Total ¥&gt;..i4.. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VI ENDING JUNE 38, I Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand June 1. IW2 running stock) (full paid stocki Balance on hand June 1. \W2 running stock) (full paid stock) I nterest I nterest Premiums Premiums Fines Fines Membership and transfer fees Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid Loans repaid K'-al estate sale* Ri'al Rents ( &gt;ther receipts Total Total Expenditures. Expenditures. Salares &lt; ommissions &lt; ommissions &lt; Kher expense! &lt; Hher expenaei Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, dues 1 +4.4;.':; Matured stock. earnings 49. 1 Matured stock. earnings Full paid stock, dues : Full ]&gt;aid stock, dues ; Full paid stock, earnings Full paid stock, earnings &lt; ash on hand &lt; itsh on hand &lt; Hher expenditures Total SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT. &lt;&gt;f shares in force at this date of shares issued since organization No. of shares issued during fiscal year &lt; Hher expenditures Total SUPPLEMENT \I STATKM ENT. i if shares in force at this date No. of shai iranization .. M7 + No. of shii during fiscal year No. of shares matured during I r No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares withdrawn during r No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year i of running stock in force at this date. ... 114.47* No" of shares of running stock in force at this dat&gt; 11 1 No. of shares of full paid stock in force at th : &gt; dat- No. of shares of full paid stock in force at th : &gt; date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which d linquent non-pa\ • No. of mo! amount of same. No. 2W No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and tl amount of - No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-bo i No. of minors hold ation rerage rab during fiscal year Average rate per cent of divid- Average running time of stock n </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 SUMMARY HE CONDITION OF THE BUILDINCi AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATKOK NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1W4. Assets. mortgage loans $5,493, loans in process of foreclosure 27. 227." Real • Furniture and stationary . . Delinquent interest, premiums and tines 2*.:il!1.7:; - paid 24. " llii. 122.47 Total W.217 Liabilities. &lt;&gt;ck running-. (Dues and dividends) $4. Hoi.. Full paid stock 883,331. 13 ve fund 144. I'ndivided profits 191,(1 -hareholders on incomplete loans ;irned 2H.U Adva 10,627.15 Advance interest and premiums 1.4 liabilities 3!i, </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 BUII*IMN(i AND '&lt; KIITS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE V AH KNI)IN( JINK 30, 1 Receipts. Receipts. Balance on hand July 1 . L903 Balance on hand July 1. 1903 running stock: full paid stock) running stock full paid stock) Interest Premiums Premiums p; nes .'&gt;.&lt;!' Fines Membership and transfer fees ■ I" Membership and transfer fees ■ I" Loans repaid 1.1 lo.. ■state sales bians repaid 1.11". 24.117 Rents' : &lt; nher receipts &lt; nher receipts Total Total Expenditures. Expenditures. Loans Salaries Salaries ( &lt; immissions &lt; tther expenses Withdrawals, dues 1 Withdrawals, dues 1 Withdrawals, earnings Withdrawals, earnings M atured stock, dues M atured stock, dues Matured stock, earnings 4 Matured stock, earnings - 4 Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earnings Full paid stock, earnings &lt; ash on hand ( ash on hand &lt; &gt;ther expenditures 4 • Total SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares issued since organization No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares matured during- fiscal year ■ withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this dai No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No . of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dm ro. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ;&gt; amount of same. No. 224 $14.. I amount of same. No. 224 No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, andtli. amount of same. No. 3!t No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders of minors holding stock in the Association Fverage rate per cent of interest charged borrowers di al vear kverage rate per cent of dividends during fiscal year verage running time of stock matured during fiscal year.. 1"' No. of loans made for building purposes during year fo. of loans made for payment of homestead n &lt; duri </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. Fifty-eight Associations submitted to this department de- tailed reports of their condition on June 30, 1904. During the period covered by this report two Associations discontinued and paid all liabilities in full and four new ■■•iations have been organized and authorized to do business. Two Associations had not commenced business June 30, 1 The following Associations ceased to do business and paid all liabilities in full, to wit : 1. Chadron — Loan and Building Association of Chadron. 2. Leigh Building and Loan Association of Leigh. The following named new Associations have been organ during the period covered by this report : 1. North Loup -Loan and Building Association of North Loup 2. Tecumseh — Building and Loan Association of Tecu I 3. Humboldt — Building and Loan Association of Humboldt 4. Beatrice Building and Loan Association of Beatri RECAPITUL ATIO N . Number of Associations in force June 30, 1903 dumber of Associations in force June 30, 1903 Number of Associations liquidated during the year Number of Associations liquidated during the year 2 Number of Associations organized during the year 4 Number of Associations organized during the year I Number of Associations in force June 30, 1904 Number of Associations in force June 30, 1904 There is an increase of three Associations over the numbt There is an increase of three Associations over the numbe i porting last year. The reports submitted indicate a prosperous porting last year. The reports submitted indicate a prosperous condition generally and a very satisfactory and gratifying condition generally and a very satisfactory and gratifying growth during the year closing June 30, 1904. growth during the year closing June 30, 1904. The total resources of the Associations reporting are SH.217. The total resources of the Associations reporting are $6,217. 850.40, being an increase of S^73,921.(»2 over the assets of the S5O.4O, being an increase of §H73,921.02 over the ■ : the fifty-five Associations reporting last year. By comparison im- fifty-five Associations reporting last year. By comparison im- portant items are found to have been increased and diminished portant items are found to have been increased and diminished during the year as follows : during the year as follows Loans increase $803,0f Loans increase §H03,( IJ Stock loans increase 71,642.92 Stock loans increase 71,642.92 Real estate decrease 9,4- Real estate decrease 9,4- Furniture and stationary increase 2,."&gt;4r\ 1 1 Furniture and stationary increase 8,548. 1 1 Cash decrease 16,tV Delinquencies decrease </seg>
            <seg id="p033">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI 33 Expenses and taxes increase 6. 1 7 Other assets increase 16,9: Kunning stock increase 647. 4- Full paid stock increase 1 Reserve fund increase 41, » Undivided profits increase The receipts and expenditures of the Associations for the Ear ending June 30, 1901, were $4,469,832.87. In other w ?se Associations did a business of nearly four and a half mil n dollars at an expense for salaries of $54, 161.47, and i expenses of $39,705.00 or a fraction over two per cent. Of the $5,493,71*.*? in first mortgage loans only the small sum of 147,110.00 are in the delinquent class, and but $36,*21 .&lt; process of foreclosure. There are 174,02:2 shares of stock in force which is an inc of 20,598 shares over the number in force at the date of th» report. There are 23,499 shareholders of which number 000 minors. (The Associations made 2,322 mortgage loans during the which number 1,061 were made for building, pur] 246 for payment of "homestead mortgages. ' The law enacted by the last session of the Nebraska ture governing Instalment Investment Companies, placing such companies, both domestic and foreign, under the jurisdi and supervision of thf 1 State Banking Boartl, has by its en t ment proven very effective, and has served well the purpo - predicted in the last annual report of the Department.) in tfcting our wage earnirfg people and others against the i ations of the many so-called Home Co-operative and get quick concerns heretofore doing business in the State. Following is a list of Instalment Investment Companies which have applied to the State Banking Board for permission b business in Nebraska, all of whose applications, after thorough investigation and careful consideration, have been reje&lt; ••■ authority to do business in the State refused : t Reserve Investment Company of Omaha, Nebraska, applica - »n rejected October 19, 1903. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 BUILDING AND LOAN' ASSOCIATIONS. Equitable Endowment Company of Omaha, Nebraska, appli cation rejected October 19, KKUi. Hathorn Mutual Commission Company of Minneapolis, Min ita, application rejected January 14, 1904. The Farm Land Investment Company of Omaha. Nebraska. application rejected March "&gt;. 1904. k National Bond Company of Denver, Colorado, application re - nted February 9, 1904 : rehearing had and application again re •ted April 20, 1904. The application of the Saint Louis Fair Guessing Association of Hastings. Nebraska, for permission to do business in the . was dismissed for want of jurisdiction on November 10, This action on the part of the State Banking Board 1 upon an opinion rendered by Attorney General Prout, a copy of which follow STATE OF NEBRASKA OEFIC'E OF ATTORNEY GENERA] Lincoln, November 9. 1 The Hon. Banking Board, Lincoln, Neb ntlemen :- I have had under consideration the application plan and articles of incorporation of "The St. Louis Fair (i ing Association" referred to this department by yourhono board for an opinion : 1st. As to whether or not the banking board has jurisdiction • over concerns of this character: and if so (2), is the scheme sented by said association a lottery or game of chance within the meaning of the statute and hence its business proscribi If the banking board has any jurisdiction it must be dei from chapter "29, laws of 1908, being an act to provide for the government, regulations and examination of certain cor] tions and associations therein fully described and placing the business of such companies under the control of the state bank - ing board. Section 1 of said act defines fully what oompa etc. shall be known as "Instalment Investment comparers' the purposes of said act, as follows : "Every association, other than building and loan associat savings banks, insurance companies or fraternal benet^ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">bli1jT)In&lt;» ant&gt; 35 sociations organized under the law of this state, or admitted un - der the laws of, this state, to do business herein, which is be organized for the pu r • raising money from &gt; - or others, by means of stated instalments or payment be held, invested or disbursed by s ■ iation. wbetbei money so contributed is paid in for shares in sucl or is held by tli&lt; tion for investment and accumul for the benetit of the contributors, or as advance on men dise. or property of any kind, to be delivered in the futun is held by tl mtion to l&gt;e disbursed among the com or any of them, in accordance with any agreed plai me, and whether the relation of the contributor to tl ■ sociation be that of a iut mber, shareholdei beneficiary of a trust : and every incorporate tion whether organized under tie laws of this or any i iritory or government, and every individual doing or attempting or offering to do business in the Nebraska, in form or character similar to that herein s&lt; shall be known, for the purpose* of this act. as an insl investment company An examination of ti nent and other papers til. the applicant shows that the object of the corporation in this artich ile of tickets to pera ring toguess the number of admissions on the opening day of the Forld's Pair April 30, I'M * * to distribute prizes among the persons purchasing t. to the extent of S;T&gt;.o&lt;&gt;!) and other amounts as fixed in other ■-, in such manner as is hereafter decided upon by said &lt;•&lt;' ation and fully set forth in the by-lawsof said company." Th« ital stock of the asscxiation is S40.000 divided into shan SUM) each, the company to be authorized to commence bus whei '(&gt; of th&gt; is subscribed by bona fide scribers said stink to be raid for in instalments as called l&lt; the board of directors. of said capital stock i&gt;. ing to the sworn statement of tl now subscribed. It is not easy todet' this gu&lt; sociation falls within the provisici hapter -\K lav unincorporated association. ev&lt; partnershi] </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 for the persons who buy tickets and have "guesses coming. " It does not collect money from its patrons by means of stated instalments to be held invested or disbursed by the association. In fact it promises its patrons nothing but an opportunity to "guess" upon the number of people in attendance at th&lt; Louis Fair on the first day and to pay certain specified prizes to the nearest guessers. And while the scheme is, possiblv vicious and demoralizing to the public in general and the indi - vidual guessers in particular as the diamond tontine and other like schemes, still it &lt;loes not in my judgment come within the provisions of chapter 29, Laws of 1908. You are advised, therefore, that in the opinion of this depart ment your board has no jurisdiction over the proposed corpor - ation. Having reached this conclusion, it is unnecessary to in - vestigate or determine the second part of the reference whether or not the scheme is a lottery or game of chance. Respectfully yours, F. N. Prout, Attorney General. Many such foreign companies have applied to the Department for information concerning the law governing concerns known as instalment Investment Companies in this State and after having been supplied with a copy of the law never made appli - cation for admission to the State for the purpose of transacting business ; others that have heretofore been doing business in the State defiantly persisted in continuing such business disregard ing absolutely the law and the State Banking Board. Criminal proceedings have been brought against a number of the repre - sentatives of these concerns, whose cases are now pending in the district court. Such proceedings have apparently served to materially retard the progress of the so-called Home Co-oper - ative business and twentieth century enterprise in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">HTATKMKNTK r OWING THK CONDITION OF THK FIFTY-KIGHT Bl'ILI' AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS IN THK STATE OF NKHKASKA AT THK CLOSE OF BUSINESS ON THK ;Wth DAY OF JUNE, 1904. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ALBION BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. ALBION. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1904. Officers. P. A. KRACSE President WM. WEITZEL Vice-Pre- D. V. BLATTER Secretary F. S. THOMPSON Trea- V. A. DOTEN Att. Directors. H. P. BULL, E. H. MULLOWNEY. F. A. PITTENGKR, E. J. KINGHAM, G. B. McGILL. F. B. PETTI H AND THE OFFICERS Assets. First mortgage loans $5&lt;i. 7i « •. i * t First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans 12,100.00 Real estate Furniture and stationery None I.:,: Delinquent interest, premiums and fines. Expenses and taxes paid Other assets, tax sale certificates Total $7ii Liabilities. Capital stock running. ( Dues and dividends) Full paidstock \ 15. . Reserve fund l.v Undivided profits 47.41 Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Total $70. . </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 RKCKIPTS AND KXPKNDITTRKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAR ENDING JUNE 30. I»&lt;t4. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. 1908 Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent). Par value of each share of stock . -bares Issued during fiscal year. ired during tlscal year ires withdrawn during fiscal year .. Formerly serial, now permanent .eriali • Dues (running stock) full paid stock) uns earned, chanced, premiums unearned Membership and transfer fee - Loans repaid Tax sale certificate paid Insur»nc» repaid Tot*l .... *lt.MM» 13 Expenditures. Due treasurer July I, 1903 . expenses Withdrawals, earnings Unearned premium returned Matured stock. &lt;1 Premiums earned, credited to protit ar&gt; Matured stock, earning Pull paid stock, dues withdrawn Full paid stock, earnings on hand.. tie certificate bought Insurance 1 Total. . ' shares of rnnniiig stock in force at this date ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date tned on ... 4tf Nil of shares on which dues are d 14 ftjeet to cancellation for nonpayment of dues None Total amount of dues delinquent at this date MMi Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders |H ■ mt of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid f4i • r mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of xame. om t\ M H f mortgages in procens of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same None Amount of loans on improved real estate MMM Apppruised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ' ,, . . g«n (l( Appraised value of improvenif. - Amount of loans upon unimproved real esta* - Appraised valueof unimproi ■ &gt;n which loans have been made I67.SHMW Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral ■urity. Fire and Tornado MMMlM ' loans made for building purposes durii . made for payment of homestead mortiranes during Hscml year Amount of advance payments of loans durinir fiscal year . .. JU.800.0U ' borrowing stockholders. -w No. of non-borrowinu stockholder- MO • minors holdinx stock in the Associate Average rate per cent of interest chanred borrowers durinic Qscal ) I Average rate per cent of premiums charired borrowers during fiscal year. Flan of premium . M" Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year ft*i.ia&gt; Amount credited from reserve fund to proti illl.lu Amount of losses chanted to reserve fund durinir fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal ft • M KM ■ Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year. fun i Average rate per cent of dividends declared durin . </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ALLIANCE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. ALLIANCE. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. VMH Officers. B. F. GILMAN President W. H. BARTZ Vice-President A. F. BALDRIDGE Secretary W. CLARK Treasurer H. F. GILMAN Attorney Directors. W. H. BARTZ. C. C. SMITH. A. F. BALDRIDUE. D. C. MCINTYRE. GBO. W. CLARK. GBO. E. DAVIS. L. B. JOHNSON. R. M. HAMPTON. Assets. mortage loans |U7,H00.&lt;H) • mortage loans in process of foreclosure None •n loans 1 (10.00 Real estate '. „ None Furniture and stationery !i!(. 14 .{04.24 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines W4.O4 Kxpenses and taxes paid 33. 13 &lt; Hher assets None Total *18.4:JO..V&gt; Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) W. «&lt;&gt;!». •"&gt;■"&gt; Full paid stock 11,200.00 ll.200.oo Reserve fund 45.00 I'ndivided profits None Due share holders on incomplete loans None Premiums unearned None Advance dues 376.00 Advance interest and premiums None Toul *ix.4:io. .v, </seg>
            <seg id="p041">BUILDING AND LOA&gt;- 41 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK F ENDING JUNE 30. 1!M4. Receipts. Balance on hand July I. 1808 (runnintr stock) (full paid stock) Interest Premiums Membership and transfer fees I^oans repaid Real estate sales Rents Total Expenditures e *7 MMt other expenses Withdrawals, due^ Withdrawals, earninir- Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earnin. Full paid stock, withdrawals iid stock, earnings ... •n hand »l on money borrowed... Repayment of borrowed money 1 ?'«' mi Total *II &lt;••■► Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent &gt; I'finiincil Pmr value of each share of stock **J»' ■•' if serial) . ' shares in force at this date 411 I shares issued since organization. ' shares issued durirnr li»eal year IIS No shares matured durinir Hscal year .ares withdrawn durinir fiscal year . . ' shares of running stock in force at this date 3ftA ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date M No of shares loaned on ... I") which dues are delinquent ' shares subjeet to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Totml amount of dues delinquent at this date MM Amount of dues owinir by borrowing shareholders. f4» M Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid foreclosure and the airirreirate amount of m • mortiraires in process of foreclosure and the ate X reirate amt. of &gt;» Amount of louns on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made *■!••■*. ■ Appraised value of improvements. Appraised value of improvement* .Not appraised separately Amount of loans on unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate u|K&gt;n which loans have been made rount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as colln • security ... ■ MlM No. of loans made for building purposes durinif fiscal yemr . . « No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortiraires during tlsckl year . Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year. N'on&gt;- No. of borrowing stockholder - SB No. of non-borrowinir stockholder- T6 No. of minors holdini? ntoek in the Ash*&gt;' - Average rate per cent of interest chanted boirowers durinir rbtcal year A veraire rate per cent of premium s chanred borrower* durinif rtscal year Plan of premium Eunt credited to reserve fund durinir flscaiyear unt of losses chanced to reserve fund duAif fiscal year unt of dividends declared on running stock durinir fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock durinir Hscal year A veraire rate per cent of dividends matured durinir fiscal year . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. • STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE ASHLAND LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. ASHLAND, NEBRASKA. On the 3Mh day of June, 190*. Officers. On the 3rtth day of June. 190*. Officers. Ft &gt;LS( )M President Ft &gt;LS( )M President F. H. CHECKERING Vice-President F. H. CHICKERING Vice-President \V. BURT CLARK Secretary \V. BFRT ( LARK Secretary K. A. WIGGEHORN. Jr Trea K. A. WIGGEHORN. Jr Tre;i W. BURT CLARK AM. ■ W. HURT CLARK Attorney Directors. Directors. C. N. FOLSOM. F. H. CHICKEKING. W. BUST CLARK, 0. N. FOLSOM. F. H. CHICKERING. W. BUST CLARK. K. A. WICiOENHORN, Jr. L. R. BRUSH. J. A. RE1 WICiOENHORN, Jr. L. R. BRUSH. J. A. Kl A. S. V. MANSFELDE. Assets. A. S. V. MANSFELDE. Assets. First mortgage loans $«.. First mortgage loans 9t\. - First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans ISiNt.oii ISlNt.OII Real estate 1, 12 Real estate 1,12 Fire proof safe Fire proof safe (ash (ash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 2'J4.m&gt; Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid litvl* Expenses and taxes paid -its. real estate contracts real estate contracts Accounts receivable 47."&gt;&lt;i Tax sale certificates Total *«.'. _ Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) $ti,4!i".:J"&gt; Full paid stock ■ rve fund Undivided profits 1,42 Due share holders f Premiums unearned Advance dues «. Advance interest and premiums Total .... </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 RKCKHTS AND KXPKXDITl'KKS F( )K THK FIS( VI YEAR KNDING .Tl'NK *&gt;, 1WH. Receipts. Balance on hand July I. n« : 'inning stock) Dues, (full paid nock Interest and tines (latter very sma Premiums K practically II and transfer fee - ... - Taxes repaid Total. Expenditures. Ix»ns. Salarie expenses Withdrawals, du Eidrawals. earnings . ired stock. &lt;! ired stock, earning paid stock, i paid stock, earning on hand Accounts debi Tota Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent Permanent Par value of each share of stock MM i ill n twin il since organization (if serial) 'orce at this date ISO ■ shares issued since organization ea issued during fiscal year ■ ured during fiscal year -hares withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date IM ' shares of full paid stock in force at this dati ■ shares loaned on ' -hares on which dues are delinquent 14 'or nonpayment of due- Total amount of jent at thi- MM Amount of • bareboUen H9.(» Amount of interest premiums and tines due and unpaid. MM No of mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same two ' mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same... Amount of loans on improved real estnw M.WLM Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made *i ixmd.ho Appraised value of ini *~ WLtt Amount of loans on unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral Kir.- ♦llSB5.nl security. Fire and Tornado No. of loans made for building purposes durinir fiscal year. . I ' loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year. I Amount of advance payments of loans durii None No of borrowing stockhol(i&lt;- I non-borrowintt stockholders H ' minors holding stock in the Association . Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during Hscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. . Plan of premium . Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal s'o change, total 1500.00 Amount of louses charged to reserve fund d mi Amount of &lt; -d on runn Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock d Average rate percent of dividends declared during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SOUTHEAST NEB. BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. AUBURN. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 11*04. Officers. A. H. GILMORE President W. B. SMITH Vice-President R. M. GILLAN Boa \V. H. HAY Treu ('HAS. O. FRENCH Attorney Directors A. H. GILMORE. W. H. HAY. \V. B. SMITH. R. M. GILLAN. B. MELLOTT. J. M. UII.LAN. Assets First mortgage loans $!.{!'. _ • mortgage loans in process of foreclosure &lt; loans 1,060.00 Real estate Furniture and stationery (ash : Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 4."- Expenses and taxes paid 4."&gt;&lt;&gt;4.74 Dividends paid and credited 12. ' Rea: Id on contract 3,4 Real estate bought for building site 1 , 8o Total $182. Liabilities. Capital stock running. ( Dues and dividends) 151,046.00 Full paid stock 06,700.00 rve fund H.ixmi.imi Undivided profits «.:• Due shareholders on incomplete loans Interest, premium and fines ltt.' Adv.i Advance interest and premiums 141.86 flcate fees 81.00 Rents 340.35 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDINU JrNE.M. 1!*&gt;4. Receipts. Balance on band July I, l!*tt *T :*«' M ( running stock) ISJH.lt 'full paid stock) »,W Premiums Membership and transfer fee- Loans repaid 17 &lt;C4 i»i Real estate sales Renus IMI s and withdrawal fees «;&gt; e Insurance and taxes . 18.15 Total rll3.4ia.5l Expenditures. U.ans Salan,- im.m Other expen Withdrawals, dues mnui Withdrawals, earnings. Undivided profits Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues. Full paid stock, earning: ii hand m Insurance and taxes . . Real estate purchased 1U.4H.U Total Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Permanent Par value of each share of stock MM No. of series issued since organization, if serial it this date t M shares issued since ortranization 0 5S4 re« issued durinir fiscal year. i ■ ured during fiscal Tear 9t ires withdrawn during tlscal year 1 irs running stock in force at this date 1 &lt;*V ■ shares of full paid stock in force at this datr No. of shares loaned on 1 M ' shares on which dues are delinquent. -hares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues . Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders . Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid MJMfl F of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same, ave mjtmm No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same, one Amount of loans on improved real estat I jl38.&gt;M.n Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made M tttM Appraised value of improvement- Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate MM Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made.. (UMlll Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security. .. ?1S0.455l«io No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durinir fiscal year 51 Amount of advance payments of loans during Hscal year No. of borrowing stockholders. . M No. of borrowing stockholders. No. of non-borrowing stockholder- las No. of minors holding stock in the Association . . Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year « Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year « Plan of premium monthly Amount credited to reserve fund during tlscal year .... Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during tlscal year None Amount of dividends declared on running stock during tlscal year *."&gt; *w *i Amount of dividends declared on running stock during tlscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year . '.ISBlOB Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during tlscal year. ~t months </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATl STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK AURORA BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. ATRORA. NEBRASKA. ()n the H(&gt;th day of June. l'.HM. Officers B. A. MTNSON President. J. B. HINTKR Vice-] 're- JAS. 8CHOONOVER Seci W. E. LAINSBURY 1 .1. H. GROKVKSNOR Directors B. A. MUN - JAS. JOHN- J. D.MCDOV J. B. HUXTKK. J. A. ISAMAN. A. HKXRIK X. J. ROX1X. W. E. BEBER. JAS. Assets loans $1L'. Iihi.imi First mortyrajre loans in process of foreclosure Iini.ok Reai Non&lt; Furniture and stationery (ash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines - and taxes paid I'ndivided profits overdrawn , Total - ! J Liabilities ock running-. Du&lt; L 50: EH v., $151. 15 ♦:;. Full paiil stock fund Undivided profits Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned None Adv; Adv;, ;ind premium&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p047">BUILDING AM) ; 47 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THI KIS&lt; A I Yh ENDING JUNE 30. 1!«H Receipts. Expenditures. Supplemental Report 3 -J N*». ol iiiayment ol .nd unpaid -are and the airifreifal amount of Nn. (if niortifiitfe* in process of foreclosure, and the aiwexatt Amount of loans on improved real ■ &gt;■ on which loans have been made Pe of unimproved real estate upon » I made Amount of insurance in force and assiifi,. :nade for tiuildin* purposes durinir tt.se.* -;iires durin^ « j-ed borrowers during wers durin Plan " Amour .-rve fund during I! Am&lt; M " ' ind during I Amour ■•&lt; durinir lis. Amoui *^i»^«» u " u p J till • UI9I I1SJ 1 ■ it! or i**ri- !i..n &lt;if &gt;*-r ii. nt II. O' drawn dur </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BEATRICE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. BEATRICE. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1SH4. Officers. DR. C. P. FALL President KRNEST SCHAKKLE Vtoe-PrMidmt \V. B. WILLIAMS Secretary F. B. SHELDON Trea Directors. DR. C. P. FALL. EKNEST SCHAEKLK. W. K WILLIAMS -UELDON. C. A JAN Assets First mortgage loans None ■ mortgage loans in process of foreclosure None k loans Real Estate Furniture and stationery h M66.W Delinquent interest, premiums and ttnes Expenses and taxes paid Other asset-; Total »2, r Liabilities »iital stock running. (Dues and dividends) fcl.V 1 paid stock rved fund Undivided profits . . None Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues None Advance interest and premium^ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 RBCEDT8 AND KXF'KNDITIRKS FOR THK KISC A I. VKAK KNDING JUNK 30, l!»04. Receipts Balance on band July I. iwii inninir stock! Dues. (full paid stock) interest 4ULCTOI Premiums « I TIIII UIIJ.S Membership and transfer fee: repaid ij»*»u* rcrpttiu ... Real estate sale&gt; Kl CWLttlC S»l«*&gt; Total Expenditures " expenses. WitMrawals. dues Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning? FuU paid stock, dues .id stock, earning 'i hand Total Supplemental Report Plan of association (aerial or permanent) Par value of each share of - No of series issued since organization, (if serial) " shares in ' - date ted since organization led during fiscal year shares matured during fiscal year ires withdrawn durinir fiscal year. No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid paid stock in force at this date None »of shares loaned on of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to concellation for non-payment of dues None Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders E2 Amount of interest, premiums and Bnes due and unpaid \on No of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same No of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made None Appraised value of improvements A mount of loans upon unimproved real estate ESI Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made »- ,_- Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral I loans made for building purposes during Hscal year ....... None • loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal rear None t&gt;unt of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No,,,. of borrowing stockholders. None of non-borrowing stockholder ■ * mo No. of minors holding stock in the Awn&lt; Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. . None Plan of premium. Fixed premium. (B per cent per annum) Payable monthly Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year None Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year None Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year None Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year None Average running time of stock matured during rtseal year . Nolle </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE STATE SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSN T . BEATRICE, NEBRASKA. On the :S&gt;th day of June. 11X14. Officers. THOS. J. ( HIDF.STER President F. D. KEES Vice-pres O. J. WILCOX Seen LOUIE GRAPP Trea L. It. PEMBERTON Directors. THOS. J. CHIDESTEK, F. D KEES. f-OUIE GKAPP. A. H. PHELPS. 1£. C. LKjL* n Assets. First mortgage loans 188,170.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 1.111.&lt;"&gt; Real estate K.0OO.ih» Furniture and stationery 847.50 Cash 2,873.23 Interest, premiums and fines unpaid 1,02 Expenses and taxes paid Othei 1,2 Other . Total $106. 17&lt; i.ol Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) 133,500.45 Full paid stock B4,i Full paid stock 64,600.00 Reserve fund l.tlOO.mi Undivided profits 3,254.04 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 3.T " Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums 1 OTA I *••*■■•»#■•«&lt; B llju. L •■■•**1 m. via i ..•.. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YEAR ENDING JI'NK 30, 1WU. Receipts. on hand July I. IS* -inninif stock! .... IntereM mlders Tola Expenditures •mi mam I Sl."» T't Withdrawals, dur ■iin^s Matured stock, di '1 stock, earnings : Full pa ■rnin^s I MLS I Kl ■*■( Profit and loss New boiler and furniture Total Supplemental Report. Plan of Association (serial or permanent) Permanent ilue of each share of - No. of -■ No. o&gt; • •s issued dunnj.' No. of shares matured durin No of shares withdrawn (turn No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No of shares of ! .'k in force at th No. of - ent of dues unount of dues delinquent Amount of dues owing by h mt of interest, premiut npaid ■ N'o. of morttraices suhjeet to fort ,1 the atriiv mn! of ue. one rnortsraifes in process of foreclosure, and the airirreirsr ■ Amount of loans on improved real ■ ue of real estate upon which loai • n made ■ Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collatera -14-; MiuM - made for huildinit purposes duriru No. of loans madi ~tead mortiraires during Ssoa Amount of adyai year S non-borrowini: st minors holding s er cent of in iced borrowers during Averat:. ent of premiums chanted borrowers during Plan of Premium Amount of d ■ ared on runnin^ mt of divii: ,-d on full paid stock during Averaiferai. .fdivideni! Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year Premiuii: - Membership and transfer f I&lt;oans repaid E of Premium Vf&lt;&gt;! unt credited to reserve fund durinir </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE BLAIR BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. BLAIR, NEBRASKA. On the :toth day of June li*V*. Officers. F. W. KENNKV, SR President F. W. ARNDT Vice-president WM. KELLY Secretary C. A. SCHMIDT Trea Directors. IW. KENNY, Sr., W. NEWELL, F. W. AKNDT, W. G. HARRISON, ( . A. SCHMIDT DR. E. R. STEWART Assets. First mortgage loans *2».40&lt;un&gt; First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash : 2.2-M1.42 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total «31. Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) S29. 121.08 Full paid stock rve fund •rve fund I'ndivided profits 1,710.10 Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Delinquent interest and premiums 14 s . 4&lt;&gt; Expenses and taxes paid Expenses and taxes paid. Total «31. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 RKCKHT.S AND KXPKNDITl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL YF.AR ENDING JUNK 30, 1&lt;N&gt;4. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. I90S Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid stock) Interest Premiums Pines Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid Real estate sale: Tola: Expenditures. .'nmmission: Other expenses Withdrawals, due Withdrawals, earnings. Matured stock, d Matured stock, earning- Full paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earning? &gt;n hand .... Tota! Supplemental Report. ■] (serial or permanent I Permanent Par value of each shai .mization (if serial) . . N irly record* shares in force at thisdatt- K»' t-d since organization. N early numfc No. of shares issued during Hsoal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year Nm. shares withdrawn during fiscal year SI Eof shares of running stock in force a.t thisdatf of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on S*i No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 6ount of dues owing by borrowing shareholder* ount of interest, premiums and Ones due and unpaid fof mortiraires subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of. same. No. I. Mi M mortiraire* in process of foreclosure, and the airirreKate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real esttit&gt; Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made *4' Appraised value of improvement** Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made. Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral rarity HMH ■ No. of loans made for building purposes during Hscal year I loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year. Amount of advance payments of loans during ti^&gt;- No of borrowing stockholders. ' non-borrowinif stockholder* No. of minors holding stock in the Associate " A veraire rate per cent of interest charired borrowers durinic ILical year 6 Averaife rat,e per cent of premiums charged borrowers durinx Hscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinir fiscal yeai *]"*» ■ Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during tlsca! ■ . • Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal yen *s.t»M *■ Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal eai Average rate per cent of dividends declared during tec Average running time of stock matured during fiscal yeur mh mooUn* Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE CLAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. (LAV CKXTKR. XKHRASKA. On the 30th day of June. liMl-t. Officers. H. r. MCDOWELL President .JOHN C. WARD Vice-Pres : dent .!. L. &lt; AMPBELL Secretary W. W. CAMPBELL Treasurer Directors. BDETWEILEK. . ORR, • C. A. OVERSTRKF.T, (JEO. S. WARD. L. B. SENYTER. E. W. ORR. Assets. mortgage loans 110,860.00 •Mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery h 14.66 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines • rises and taxes paid Mte, tax certificates 8.15 Total »n,0?3. i)4 Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) $1-V Full paid stock Bfiit i u ?*wji :n rve fund 220.00 Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues 360.00 Advance interest and premiums Bills payable / Vr\i 1 4 1 "* ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 HKCKHTS AND KXPHNDITURKS K()R THr KISCAI KNDING .Tl'NK Ml 1WH. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. 1*03 runninir stuck! Uuev (full paid stu.-k Interest Premiums Membership and transfer fee repaid .. . . i. r able Total Expenditures. !rawals. dm Withdrawals, eurninifs Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning Full paid stock. &lt;i nd stock. &lt;■ ;irniriu •n hand Supplements! Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent &gt; IVrmanent I serial) :ei -:iares tamed since organization efl issued durintr fliacal &gt; Mf i ' ured during fiscal year 1 1 drawn durinit Uv runninii stock in force at th :»u ' shares of full paid stock in force at tn ied on . . . . ten on which dues are delinquent nent of due^ Total amount of -f ■ Amount of dues owinK by borrow IM ■ Amount of interest premiuo inpsid WtM BKtrtoKM subject to foreclosure and the aicgretrate amount of same one -:«•'.« No of morttraties in process of foreclosure, and the axirreirate amount of sanir Amount of loans on improved real esta 1 - RUM •■(I value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans on ui i ••• MM Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made — MMi Amount of insurance in force and I ihe association as collateral Kourltj H ti«"&gt;' So. of loans made for building purpose Kof loans made for payment of hmi ear. &gt;unt of advance payments of loans durin:; fiscal yen' rl M iiorrowinif stockholders I iion-borrowinit stockholder^ I minors holding stock in the As&gt;. S Averaite rate per cent of interest cbarired borrowers during fiscal year Averaite rate pt- ■;»! year Plan of premium. mal monthly payments. Amount credited HMi Amount of losses chanred to rese Amount of dividends declared on Amount of dividends d Averaireratepe- A veraite runnitu iok matured durinv UscaJ year 7"montli^ ilruto-al fee: &gt;n-iui&gt;n faired property Total </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE COLUMBUS LAND, LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. COLUMBUS. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June, I!X&gt;4. Officers. P. J. HART President G. A. SCOTT Vice-President HENRY H(K KENBF.RGER Secretary GU8 G. BK( HER Trea W. M. CORNELIUS Attorney Directors ■ J. SCOTT. L. LI OTT. W. M. CORNELIUS, J. C. ECHOI W. M. CORNELIUS, rND, J. K. JOKON i. H, JOHONNKS. Assets Assets. First mortgage loans $158. - ortgajre loans $158. - First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure '.'■ ortgajre loans in process of foreclosure '.'■ Stock loans 57,900.00 jans f)",H(Mt.(H&gt; Real estate tatf None Furniture and Stationery None re and Stationery None a ■ -T. &lt; ash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 992. 15 lent interest, premiums and fines W2. 15 Expenses and 'taxes paid ."&gt;.4" m and 'taxes paid .~&gt;.4" Other assets None Total KW,040.95 Liabilities Capital stock mnnmy. (Dues and dividends) ♦I&gt;&lt;&lt;&gt;.4I*.ini Full paid stock Nont rve fund Undivided profits -47. 1 Due share holders on incomplete loans None Premiums unearned Advance dues 4Huxt Advance interest and premiums Total *22x. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL YKAR ENDING .TTNE3O. V.HH. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. 180S Dues. ( running stock) *T :**• ■ Dues, (full paid stock) Inter.- 1 1 &gt;*' Wt Premiums Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid Real estate salei Rents Total Expenditures. Mission Other expenses . . . Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earning*. . Matured stock. &lt;)'. Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock. &lt;i Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand . . . Tota Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Par value of each share of stock *ti&lt;&gt; H No. of series issued since organization, if serial 1 1 ' shares in force at this date No. of shares issued since organization No. of shares issued durinir ilscal year «K ' shares matured during fiscal year HMM No staiires withdrawn durintt tiscal year No- of shares of running stock in force at this date ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on 2.0SI ' shares on which dues are delinquent ' shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues M Total amount of dues delinquent at this date •M Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owinir by borrowing shareholders ; l m* M Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid *«•_•'■ Fof morttraires subject to foreclosure, and the aiurreirate amount of same. of morttraires in process of foreclosure, and the amrregate amount of same None Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made MMM "' Appraised value of improvement- HJIUi Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate *~ Ml n Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made.. MJMkfl hount of insurance in force and assiirned to the Association as collateral security No. of loans made for buildinir purposes during Ilscal year i« No. of loans made for payment of homestead morttraires durinir fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans durintr fiscal year None No. of borrowing stockholder - i.VS No. of non-borrowintr stockholders No. of minors holdinir stock in the Association Averaire rate per cent of interest cbanred borrowers durinir fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durinir tiscal year l«-i ■ Plan of premium Premium is bid. deducted from loan in a lump sum Amount credited to reserve fund durinir fiscal year Amount of losses chanred to reserve fund durinir Ilscal year. Amount of dividends declared on running stock durinir Ilscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock durinir fiscal year Averaire rate per cent of dividends declared durinir Ilscal year Averaire running time of stock matured durinir Ilscal rear . </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 I ' * ] J * 1 1 . * V M * fc A ■ ■ f L^ V * **i * * *kA"*^7 * X ■ \ 1 I STATEMENT OF' THE CONDITION OF THK CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSX. CRETE. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. l!»i&gt;4. Officers. HA IGHT President M. H. FLEMING Vice-Pres IB. G&lt; X )DELL - )DKLL Tiv., Directors. Directors ). H. HASTIN F. J. RADF.MACHK.lt A K. MtAlI, F. J. RADKMACHKH. A K aMAf J. M. E. HAKJHT. C. B. GOODELL fATEKMAN. M. E. HAIUHT. C. B. OOOtMLL. &gt;. W. BALDWIN C. » ANDERSON C. ft AND1 Assets iQortfratre loans *l:i. mort^a^re loans in process of foreclosui"e None Real Estate Furniture and stationery 2.2(14.21 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines LOO - and taxes paid Total »14 Liabilities Capital stock runninp. (Dues and dividends) $14." Full paid stock ' fund Undivided profits -hare holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned None Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total $14 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATE RECEIPTS AND K.XPKNDTTrHKS FOR THr \L Yr Alt KNDING JINK 30, 1!*14 Receipts. Balance un hand July I. 1ft iinninu stoel ■ ill paid -lock) Premiums Membership and transfer •I Real estate sale Totn Expenditures Supplemental Report. fwociattoo (serial or i&gt;ermanent) value (if serial) .if *h., ■natured durinit fiscal j ■ Nil shares withdrawn during flscu Bof shares of running stock in ' of Khan nt this date. • payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of -nnumsii! . ind unpaid K ire and to. &gt;unti'- '.proved real esi ~ed value of improved reul • ivhioh loans have heenmade ' value «&gt;f imp' Amount of loans on unimproved re.. Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whn Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Assooi security ■oses durinir flseu -atres during fiscal year Amount of advance pa\men' Bof hoirowin. of non-borrowinn P. « Tniums charved lurinn Hscal year Plan of premium n Am. e fund dur: int of losses .•hurtred to reserve fund .: Amount of dividend* declared on running sto&lt;»k during ' mt of dividends declared on full paid stock durinir fiscal year Averatre rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year . . . Average runnii. itu red durinir fiscal &gt;e.ir 1 « Exchange acct.. drawing paper*, etc Mutur* »mintf*&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE FAIRFIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FAIRFIEI-D. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. li*4 Officers. WM. KMKRICH President A. A. BAKER Viee-Pre* r. ANA WALT Secretary T. P. SHI VELY Treu Directors. J. E. SPATZ. c. L. lewis. W. L. BAYLEY. WM. HOEVET. LOU EMRICH. i;. w. imxjnr, Assets. mortage loans *14j First mortage loans in process of foreclosure None k loans Real estate Furniture and stationery &lt;a*h L5 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid Otht- Total * l.Y Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) 115,155.55 Full paid stock None Reserve fund 315.00 Undivided profits 294. 1 1 Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums None Other items </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RKCKIPTS AND KXPENDITfRKS FOR THK FIS( A I YKAR KNDING JUNE 30, VMH Receipts. Balance on hand July I. 1003 running stock). ill paid stock Interest Premiums Membership and transfer fee g.«t Miscellaneous item ineou-iteni- Total . 87.MO.U Total Expenditures. Expenditures. Salarie &lt; oiuinissioD-s Other expenses Withdrawals, dut- Withdrawals. earning-. Matured stock, di .• Matured stock, earnintrs Full paid stock, dw Full paid stock, earninjrs hi hand . exi&gt;enses fefl Withdrawals, due-. Withdrawals, earning - '-*' ' ' Matured stuck, d:.- Matured stock, earning- lt;l " s: Full paid stock. due- Full paid stock, earnirv- - ■ in hand. 1 MM &lt;lintr and abstract^ Total. *T M i i wmM ■ tinir and abstracts Total Supplemental Report. Supplemental Report Plan of awu&gt;&lt; &gt;al or permanent) Permanent I'lan of ass. ial or permanent) Permanent Par value of eac - Mt« No. ol (if serial" N.me ' -hares in force at th:- iKT led since organization **2 ie&lt;l durintr fiscal year ' shares matured during fiscal year •hdrawn during fiscal year -•animation (if serial) f shares in force at Ibis &lt;1 a : &lt; 3K7 ted since organization **2 -ued durintr nscal year No. of shares matured durinir nscal year 1 hdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ' shares loaned on . ' shares on which duet- are delinquent ;i ' shares su 1 Mediation for nonpayment of due~ 4 shares of full paid stock in force at this date ■ shares loaned on which duet' are delinquent il shares su' I'ellation for nonpayment of due~ 4 Total amoin ••Iinquent at this date I H&gt; not keep ••iinquent at this date IH» not keep Amount of dues o win* by borrowing shareholder- account Amount of dues owin* by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premium- and fines due and unpaid ... Amount of inter. us and tines due and unpaid MM No. of mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amount of same, one •;."» ■ if mortgages in process of forecloHure. and the amrrerate amount of same) No. of mortiraires subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amount of same. one.. •-'■"» ■ rot m4&gt;rttcaires in process of foreclosure, and the amrrerate amount of same) . Amount of loans on improved real estate *M IWO.OP Appraised value of improved real estate on which loans have been made Appraised value of improvement* Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate . Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made.. None rount of insurance in force and assigned to the asxociation as collateral security No. of loans made for buildinir purposes durinir fiscal year I loans made for payment of homestead mortifaires durinit fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans durinir fiscal year f borrowing stockholders :« ' non-borrowintr stockholder^ ill No. of minors holding stock in the Association Average rate per cent of interest cbarired borrowers during nscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durinir fiscal year . . Plan of premium, paid in 50 e&lt;iual payments Amount credited to reserve fund durinn tlscal year . ta&gt; M Amount credited to reserve fund durinir Amount of losses chanted to reserve fund durinir tlscal year Amount of dividends declared on runninir stock durinir nscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock durinir flsca Averaire rate per cent of dividends declared durinir ttstfal &gt;«-,ir Averaire runninir time of stock matured durinir nscal year ears </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FRKMONT. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1!*&gt;4. Officers (HAS. H. MAY President FRANK HAMMOND Vice-President ARTHUR TRUESDELL Sera (HAS. R. VKAZIK Treasurer RGE U X ).MIS Att. Directors. BUR TBUESDELL. FRANK HAMMOND. FRED BADER. K FOWLER. GEO. L. LOOMIS. GKO. A. MIR GEO. L. LOOMIS. GEO. A. MUKRKLL. B. H. MAY. CHA8. VEAZIE. J. C\ LEE. Assets morttrajre loans |6f,800.fl0 ■ mortjrayre loans in process of foreclosure None k loans 1,150.01) Real estate 1,821.52 Furniture and stationery None h 2.^7.44 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines s and taxes paid -I.:.- Total *7n.^4."&gt;. 85 Liabilities Capital stock running. Dues and dividends Full paid stock None Undivided profits None holders on incomplete loans 1.0(1 liums unearned Iimi.ui Advance dues Advance interest and premiums r liabilities Total $T(i. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">dLILI)1N(t A^L) i 63 RECEIPTS AND KXPHNniTCKKS FOR THK FINCAI YE ENDING JUNE 30, 1!m&gt;4. Receipts. e i m band July I. 1 inning stock) Premiums Membership and transfer fee: repaid n withdrawal: T Expenditures Low I'ommiMtaBs Other exi&gt;enses With' Witt). Matin i irnin 'idrawn 1 . able.. Other i Tota Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or i&gt;ermanent). &lt;;ue of each share of stock . anization. (if serial) Mo. ol No. of shares iss:. janization. :t.:ws ' shares issued dunnii : • - matured during flsc» * ithdrawn durinjr Use.. ' shares of rnnniin.' stook in force at this date 7HB ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of «»J No. of .vblehduesare.l ■ cancella ent of dues Total Amount of dues owiru Amount of &gt;nd unpaid ■ Fof morttfat^es hu I the atfirre^fate amount of same, three ro. of mortiraifes in process of foreclosure, and the airvreifate amount Amount of loans on improved rea. ■ Apppraise. uproved real estate upi&gt;n which loans have been made I Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the ollateral ■urity. Fire and Tornadi loans made for building purposes during Hscal year ■i ■ loans made for payment of horn- s durinit Hscal year 19 Anumn! of ..triv:im&gt;*&gt; tiuvments ikf inuns Aurimr H*u^ll] ve.ir . •!' £C ~tt Amount of advance payments of loans durintr fiscal j'ear. . . . So. of I Average rate per cent of interest chaived borrowers during fiscal year . Averaif e rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers durinir fiscal year. . Ean of premium mount ■■ efunddur »* ! Amount of losses char &lt;&lt;1 «i Amou- N Iff tM A mount oi _ _r^r^ . "^ </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE NEB. STATE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. FREMONT, NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 19(4. Officers. T. L. MATHEWS President S L. HAMMOND Vice-President PAUL COLSON Secretary J. T. MAY Trea- W. J. COURTRIGHT Attorney Directors. T. L. MATHEWS, PAUL, COLSON. C. C. MCNISH. ROSS L. HAMMOND. W. J. COUKTRIGHT. R. B. SCHNEIDER. J. T. MAY, E. R. UURNEY. \VM. FRIED. Assets. First mortgage loans MS, 721.68 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure B74.00 Stock loans 1,475.00 Real estate l'._ Furniture and stationery 2.HMI.M Delinquent interest, premiums, fines and dues Expenses and taxes paid Other assets, real estate sold on contract -~~&gt; . i * • Total »10tt.44!i.:&gt;2 UaMNties. tpital stock running. ( Dues and dividends) 960. 11 paid stock 5,12 5,125.50 Reserve fund .'i.250.O(i Undivided profits 1,21 Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues : Advance interest and premiums 11.75 Bills payable Paid up stock 27. H Total $10ti </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE VKAR ENDING Jl'NK M, l!»t&gt;4. Receipts. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. 1808 MM! i running stock) full paid stock &gt; Balance on hand July 1. 1808 E; (running - I (full paid stuck) rest . i m m Premiums ;ind transfer fee* Premiums ;ind transfer fee: Meml Memt- Olher receii&gt;:&gt; Total ... jgo.: Other receif Tota; Expenditures Expenditures Sataiie I .an ■ i .«■&gt;(«. Commission &lt; 'omrnissions jxy .] Other expenses Other expenses Withdrawals. du&lt; '■.« wal- earnings Matured stock, d Matured stock, earning? Full paid stock, dues Pull paid stock, earning - in hand Withdrawals, due^ "iW .1 ■Y 1*S&gt;« ~»J Withdrawals, eurninus iSS Matured stwk. dues Matured stock, earning Full paid stock, dues Pull paid stock, earning m hand I MM ivable cancelled Other expenditure^ &amp;.CS.44 Supplemental Report. flan of Association (serial or permanent i Par value of each share of stock ■&gt; issued since organization (if serial! . e» Issued since organic • on es issued during I &gt;4\ es matured during fiscal year . . hdrawn during ti running stock in force at this dati' I shares of full paid stock in force at this date shares loaned on . *hich dues are delinquent . i^ellation for nonpayment of due^ amount of dues delinquent at ttr IM • Amount of dues owing by borrow Amount of interest .premiums and tines due and unpaid N"t» of mortg '"t to fore' id the atrtrrekrate amount of same, eleven. No. of morttfatfes in process of foreclosure, and the atrifretrate amount of same x *• «7"&gt; tt Amount of loans on improved re:i UM Appraised value of real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements - - .j Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made rount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security *um.»mm No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgage* during fiscal year *• Amount of advance payment of loans during Itea M ■*! «" No. of borrowing stockholders Su&gt; ' non-borrowing stockholder- No, of minors holding stock in the Association Unknown Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. Plan of Premium . Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year. #»«m«' Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during tiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during tiscal year ■?&gt; W i i Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during **.'•' i« Average rate per cent of dividends declared during Hsim Average running time of stock matured during tlsca! year . IM months </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE GERING BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. GKRING. NEBRASKA. On the 3()th day of June, 1U04. Officers. A. B. WOOD President . BONHAM Vice-Pre- PETER McFARLANE Secretary PETER McFARLANE Tw m Directors. A. B. WOOD, C. W. BONHAM, PETER McFARLANE, E. S. DELAMATTF.R. J. A. BURTON, Assets. First mortgage loans t9.2oo.iNi mortgage loans in process of foreclosure k loans , -KHUN* Real estate . . ..\ None Furniture and stationery None ( h h '* 1 0 VI Delinquent interest, premiums and fines None Ka and taxes paid r H&gt;set&gt; 3I!t.2&lt;&gt; None Withdrawals Total «lo Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) S~.«&gt;1— . &lt; h t Full paid stock None rve fund None Undivided profits, interest and fines ~hare holders on incomplete loans None mms .I.!* Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total Wo.- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 KNDINO JUNE MK l'.m-l. Receipts Balance on band July 1. IMS 'running stock) trull paid at Rn£' UmS Membership and transfer fee Loins repaid . . Total Expenditures i| ,..,., Sii'.une Tiission; Er expense^. idrawals. du&gt; idrawals earnings paid stock, earnings on band :: Tota Supplemental Report Plmn of association (serial or permanent! .!iie of each share of - (if serial). f shares issued since organization ~ued during es matured durin awn durint : unnintf stock in force at this date full paid paid Nt&lt;&gt;. ;it this date shares loaned on -nares on which dues are delinquent -hares subject to concellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent Amount of dues owintr by borrowing shareb* Amount of interest, premiums and ttnes due and unpaid No- of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same N.i of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the airtrreirate amount of samf Amount of loans on improved real • -::: -ed value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate A ppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral i&gt;ans made for buildinir purposes during fiscal year nans made for payment of homestead mortira'ires during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loans during Hscal year No of non-borro ■ olders M nunors holding stock in the Ass.i. Average rate per cent of interest charred borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiun norrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Vdvanc- Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund durin j Amount of dividends declared on running stock during tlsca Amount of dividends declared on full paid si Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year . RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITl'RES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR No. of tM&gt;rr&lt;i &gt;lders. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. GRAND ISLAND, NKBRAXKA. On the 30th day of June. L!K&gt;4. Officers. LOUIS VKIT President (HAS. G. RYAN Vice-Pn- ( . W. BRININGKR Secretar v ( :. F. BKNTLKY Trea JAMKS H. WOLLKY Attorney Dlrectors. rHARD GOEHRIXG E. SINKE, H. C. MILLER, L. T. (JEER. R. R. KORTH, R. J. BARK. «'. B. NORMS. Assets. First mortgage loans 1273.' mortyaire loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans 11, U •273.' Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationary Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid, tax sale certificates rer asset*, balance due on loans, shares matured or can - celled ."&gt;.:; Total *:KKi Liabilities Capital stock running-. (Dues and dividends, f: Full paid stock rve fund 9.!"" Undivided profits None Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned 517.90 Advance dues Advance interest and premiums L'i&gt;!*.4i&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI' RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FIS4 ENDING JUNE Ml V.m. A I YKAK Receipts. ice on hand July 1. 1903 running stock I *.« m *. i full paid stock) ind transfer fees i's redeemed Payment on settlement ba . Total - Expenditures. tnu &lt;"omiii 'irawals. di. - • •ning&gt; Mstun amint FuU paid stock, dues aid stock, earnin i &gt;n hand . h fi*t .!/, it paid on overdraft Total nmau Supplemental Report Plan of association (serial or permanent) sss Par value of each sha ' serial) f share* Lwued dunn/ No of jred durin- Nil of sharps withdrawn liurinif nS ■ shares of runnin/ in shares (if full paid stock in force at th shares loaned on No of shares on which dues are delinquent ect to cancellation for nonpayment of dues amount of dues delinquent . m Amount of dues owinir by borrowing shareh Amount of inter* ind unpaid Kind the mf-j.n- amount of •me. iw.i nortifaires in process of foreclosure .and the airxreirule amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate on which loans have been made lised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real A i 'praised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been mad.- Amount of insurance in force and assimied to the association as collateral security ioans made for buildinx purposes during tlscal year mode for payment of home- .-itires durinit fiscal year »• Amount of advance puymerr No of borrowing stockholders s non-borrowintf stockholders No of minors holdinx stock Average ra luring ttsca Average ra' i Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during rtsc Amount of losses charged to reserve fund dur: Amount of car . Amount of dividends declared on full i Average rate per cent of dividend during Hsoal year Average running ■ilium- repaid on matured loan sale- pureha- ■&lt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HARTINGTON BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HARTINGTON. NKBRASKA. On the .{Oth day of June ltXU. Officers. \V KST&lt; &gt;X President A. B. GABLE Vice-president F. O. ROBINSON Seer FRANS NKLSON /T.Trea Directors. WKSTOW, A. B. GABLE, FRANS NELSON. O. LCBELEY, UEO. F. SC'OVH.LK. Assets. mortpapv loans 120, 7( First mort^ratfe loans in process of foreclosure » loans 150.00 Real estate Furniture and stationery Delinquent dues, interest and fines • I - and taxes paid Total *21 Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) 119.2 Full paid stock ive fund l.V &gt;.&lt;•»» Undivided profits 1,531.42 Due shareholders on incomplete loans "_'"J.H1 Premiums unearned Advance dues ll!i.."&gt;2 Advance interest and premiums ... None Bills payable </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOC1AT1' KKCKlfTS AND KXPKNDITl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL Yr Alt ENDING JUNE 30, V.*H. Receipts. i- on hand July I. lsra Dues, (running stork ' ill mint stock Interest 1.9C0.U Premiums Membership and transfer fees &amp; ~t ' K Real estate Tot li Expenditures. ommission Matured stock. (1 Matured stock, earning irninir Cash on hawi .... I :*: t* Supplemental Report. Plan of no Par value of ea&lt;- -date vanization . ' shares matured durin withdrawn during M it this date - of full paid stock in foiv^ at th &gt;ed on •wires on w iniuent M &gt;ayment of dues II amount of Amount of dues n» in Amount of inter&gt; No. of mortt losure. and the axirreirate amount of same No of morti;aii?sin pro-ess of foreclosure, and the awrexate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate g~ &gt;ed value of impi upon which loans have been made Appraised value of imi Amount of loans upon unimproved rea! • Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made rount of insurance in force and —llllllili to the Association as cullatera security IV JAM loans made for huildintr purposes durinir fiscal year •it of homestead il year No of borrowing - « w minors holding stot'k Average rate i«r cent of interest chanted borrowers durinir ttscal year Average rate i&gt;er cent of premiums chanted borrowers durinit fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount or rve fund durinit tlsca Amount of dividends declared on runninir stock dur Total . Amount of ad van &gt;MH tiunn. ' non-borrowing Btockh* </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THK HASTINGS BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HASTINGS. NEBRASKA. On the :$&lt;)th day of June. l'MU On the :$&lt;&gt;th day of June. l'MU Officers. Officers. GEO. H. PRATT Prat GEO. H. PRATT frv- HENRY SIEKM ANN Vii-e-Pn-- HENRY SIKKMANN Vlee-PrM \VM. M. LOWMAN Scev \VM. M. LOWMAN See* W.M. ML LOWMAN Trea - W.M. ML LOWMAN Trea- J. H. FLEMING AU. J. H. FLEMING AU. Directors. Directors. GEO. H. PKATT, HENRY SIEKMAN.V, JNO. SNIDER. BUCHANAN, FRED PEASK. K. I-AN'JEVIX. ri. H. PKATT, F. BUCHANAN, HENRY SIEKM ANN. JNO. SNIDER. FRED PEASK. E. LANQEVLK, H. B. CORSEUUS. H. B. CORNELJUS. Assets. Assets. First mortage loans f"&gt;9. First mortage loans §59,1 First mortage loans in process of foreclosure , First mortage loans in process of foreclosure , Stock loans «.:.' Stock loans «.:' Real estate None Real estate Nont* Furniture and stationery Saft- Furniture and stationery Nafr- i 2.+l».:U Cash 2.41&lt;" .14 Delinquent interest, prvmiums and fines Noacct.kpt. Delinquent interest, prvmiums and fines Noa.cct.kpt. Kxpensf s and taxes paid Kxpensf s and taxes paid &lt; &gt;ther assets Delinquent taxes paid Total Liabilities Kpital stock running. (Dues and dividends) 1t\t\ 11 paid stock None Reserve fund Undivided profits 1,(12 Due share holders on incomplete loans Nonr Premiums unearned None Advance dues Advance interest and premiums None Total </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 KKCKI1TS AND KXr'KNDITURES FOR THE FIS( AL Y ENDING JUNE MK 1!*»4. Receipts. Halance on hand July I. 19C ski ssts (full paid stock) Inler.- umi Premiums Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid id drawing papers lent taxes repaid iiient insurance repaid Total III l,&gt;...| Expenditures Kes and attorii. issions Other expenses Withdrawals, dues. Withdrawals, earnin i.KC M Biuent insurance paid red stock, du- I&gt;elin&lt;iuent taxes paid ed stock, earnin; Directors' fees ■paid stock, dues, paid stock, earning i on hand Rebates account of advance payment* Total Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent). njm'ni Par value of each sh;i &lt;| i .ion. (if serial) 2 Trti .'animation ;, an arm withdrawn during Hscal year &gt;K ' shares of rnnninif stock in force at this date MM ' shares of full paid stock in force at this date . ... med on . ' shares on which dues are delinquent. «s I shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues &gt; Total amount of dues delinquent at this date BHMi Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid Kof mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of »me. four -I M ■ f mortvaires in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same IMM Amount of loans on improved real estate . . $30I^^^| Apppraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made fiW.tSO.on Appraised value of improvements Wot appraised nepa Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate. . . . Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whichloanMhave been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral ' I rarity. Fire and Tornado I tire JMS.9K.M ' loans made for buildintr purposes d urine Oacal year . ' loans made for payment of homestead mortirave* durintr fiscal year 9 Amount of advai luring nscal year, loans repaid . . II 1 minors bolriint! stock in the Association . IB A veraire rate per cent of interest chanred borrowers durinic fiscal year . Average rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers during fiscal yea? Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve funddurinif Hscal year *Si&gt;6 4« Amount of losses chanred to reserve fund during llscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during nscal year tl *^* ■ Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during Hscal year. Average rate per cent of dividends declared during nscal year Average running time of stock matured during Oacal year </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HAVELOCK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HAVELAX'K. NEBRASKA. On the MKh dav of June. 19&lt;&gt;4. Officers. Officers. L. HINKLE President SAML. HINKLK President JOHN RENNAN Vite-Pn - .loHN RENNAN Yice-1'ivsident F. L. SUMPTER Kev F. L. SUMPTER Baa F. B. YOUNG Tre ;i F. B. YOUNG Treu Directors Directors. SAML. HINKLE. K. B. YOl ■ SAML. HINKLE. JOHN RENNAN. F. L. SUMPTER. JOHN RENNAN. THOMAS BIBBY. F. B. tOOl THOMAS BIBBY. FRED KROEHLEK. FRED KROEHLKK. ARCHIBALD ADAMS. O. W. ANDERSON. V. F. HOFMANN. ARCHIBALD ADAMS. O. W. ANDERSON. V. F. HOFMANN. Assets. Assets. inortgape loans W-7 ,810.00 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure UM5.on Furniture and stationery Knquent interest, premiums and fines - and taxes paid 139.7!: Expenses and taxes paid Other Total KO,4O7.53 Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) $27. +•&gt;&lt;&gt;. m Full paid stock U.100.00 ive fund "Jllt.^t; Undivided profits 8,62 -hareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Bills payable 2,000.00 Bills payable Total *.".n. 4i c. :&gt;:; </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 ied during fiscal year iires matured during fiscal year .ires withdrawn during tiscM unning stock in ' N full paid stock in force at tl 71 -hares loaned on which dues are delinquent : -'-' ect to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Totml amount of dues delinquent at this date * ■ Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholder-. &lt;^ i-l Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same one ' mortgages in process of foreclosure and the aggregate amt. of same Amount of loans on improved rea Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made. ♦»• *•»"•' Appraised value of improvements. Amount of loans on unimproved real estate *!'■' ■■' Appraised value of unimproved re &gt;n which loans have been made &lt;«■&lt;■•&gt; Fount of insurance in force an. -elation as collateral security M Kof loans made for building purposes during fiscal year of loans made for payment of nomestead mortgages during fiscal year . Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year. -&gt; ■ •" borrowing stockholder * ■ stockholder- • 1 |T 7 No. of minors holding stock in the Ahs. .. Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year .. None Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year . Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year . . Average running time of stock matured during fiscal jear.. . Nonr RKCKIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR Tl K h KISC.J L Yl KA K KNDING JINK 30. 1S»O4. Receipts. tee on hand July 1, 1903 . TT (running stock) (full paid stock) . . M ' ind transfer ■• m . t\ &gt;ayable . J Expenditures. « real estate other exi)enNes ■ irawals. dut- ■ trawals. earnin&gt;r&gt; Matured stock, dues ;irninirs Full i amines i in band . . ■uyable . . Total ... Supplemental Report. tof association (serial or permanent) value of t'ui'li share of ■...-,. ..f -, ries issued - (if serial) of shares is. m </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HOOPER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. HOOPER. NEBRASKA. On the 30th day of June. 1!H&gt;4. Officers. ,T&lt; iHN F. HEINE PrM .)( )K BAUEB8 Vice-pn- OBO. W. HEINE Secretary GEO. W. HEINE Secretary ED. TEHLING Trea-utvr ED. TEHLING Trea.-uivr B. MONNICH At!. B. MONNICH Attorney Directors. Directors. JNO. F. HEINE, JOE SACERS. OEO. HEIN'K, EF. HEINE, UEHLl.^ tS G. FRITZ. JOE SAtTERS. AUG. TILLMAN. GEO. HEIN'K ED. UEHL1.- AUG. TILLMAX. JNO. SAl'EKS. (.'HAS. HOFFMAN'. CARL KKOEUER Assets. First mortgage loans *1 1 . - tst mortgage loans in process of foreclosure ck loans 1,000.0(1 Real estate Furniture and stationery Cash 2,821.05 Delinquent interest, premiums fines and dues Expenses and taxes paid Other Total *!»;. Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) Jlti. ! til paid stock serve fund iMT.IMi •rve fund Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total *lii </seg>
            <seg id="p077">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATI' 77 RKCKHTS AND KXFKNDITl'RKS FOR THK VI KNDING JUNE 30, 1!H4. Receipts. Balance on band July 1. 1003 i running stuck) - &gt; ((ullpaid stock) Inter. Premium* Fine- Kmbership and transfer fee eal e Xents Total J7.7W.15 Expenditures L&gt;&lt;&gt;iios Salaries Mission Other expenses r Withdrawals, dues Withdrawals, earnings. . Matured stock, di:- Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, di Full paid stock, earnings ii hand . Total Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent) Par value of each share of stock **•&gt; ■ No. of series issued since organization, if serial No. of shares in force at this date ii 1 No. of shares issued since organization ■.- ; I shares issued during fiscal year. No. of shares matured chirm* fiscal year 1 ' ;ires withdrawn during fiscal year 19 Kof shares of running stock in force at this date of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on ■ ' shares on which dues are delinquent . # No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of due* Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid *:t-J &lt;' No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. two .... MM ■ No. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same None Amount of loans on improved real estate jll.KM.0t Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made m «' M Appraised value of improvements ?16.30O.q6 Amount of loans upon unimproved real estui • Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made . . Amount of insurance in force and assiirned to the Association as collateral ] lire security tor. f5.™i&gt;.00 No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortiraires during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year. . . ?»&gt;' " ! No. of borrowing stockbolelc i» No. of non-borrowing sw&gt;ekholder^ -V No. of minors holding htock in the Association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year "7» Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year. Eount of dividends declared on running stock during Bscal year fw»» «2 ount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year None Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year 6 Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year . . 131 mlti </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE « HUMBOLDT BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSN. Hl'MBOLDT. NEBRASKA. On the 30th dav of June. 1S*&gt;4. Officers. .1. F. WALSH President TU( KKR Vice-President F. R BUTTERFIELD Secretary A. A. TANNER Treasurer Directors J. F. WOZAB, J. F. WALSH. E. A. TfCKEK, H. P. MARBLK. L. HOW ELL. W. SKALAK. H. K. BOYD. A. A. TANNER, F. R. BUTTERFIELD. Assets ■ mortgage loans mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and Stationery 13.75 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid Expenses and taxes paid Total $!'- Liabilities Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) $774. (Hi Full paid stock Reserve fund . Undivided profits 100.90 Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned. Advance dues . .■ Advance interest and premiums. Total </seg>
            <seg id="p079">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 79 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FIS( AL V E \R ENDING JUNE 30. 1904. Receipts. l'aianee on hand July I. 1903 ( running stock ) Dues, (full paid stock Interest Premiums Fines Membership and transfer fee - repaid Real estate sale Rents Total. Expenditures. L.oans Salaries Commission: Other expenses Withdrawals. du&gt; Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning Full paid stock, dues . Full paid stock, earning m hand Furniture and stationery Total Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or permanent) . . Par value of each share of stock -eries issued since organization (if serial) No. of shares in force at date of last rt-port . ' shares issued since organization No. of shares issued during fiscal year . No of shares matured during fiscal year - No. of shares withdrawn during fiscal year . No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on 4 [ shares on which dues are delinquent 3 No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of due~ Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest premiums and lines due and unpaid . . ' mortgages subject to foreclosure and the aggregate amount of same. Veil mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvement- — Amount of loans on unimproved real estate None Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Nor e Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral •urity ■*■•' M No. of loans made for building purposes during fiscal yea if loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year. " Amount of advance payments of loans during Uses! year No. of borrowing stockholders I No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the Association . Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year. Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during r Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate percent of dividends declared during fiscal year . </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THE HUMPHREY BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSN. HUMPHREY. NEBRASKA. On the 3&lt;»th day of June. 1!MH Officers C. H. SWALLOW Vice-Pres P. E. McKILLIP Se«-: McKINLEY Trea IE. McKILLIP Attorney Directors Directors. }S. OTTIS. C. H. SWALLOW. P. K. M« KILUR C. H. SWALLOW. P. K. M« KILUR W. M CONDON. 1. C. McKINLEY. '. McKINLK W M. CONIKIN Assets Assets. ■st mortgage loans K,400.W mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery I.- Del inquent interest, premiums and fines Expenses and taxes paid Other assets Total *S Liabilities Capital stock running. Dues and dividends $3. ■ Full paid stock rve fund Undivided profits Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total $3.' </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 BUIIjI)IN(.t AN D 1 ■ • m : * ■ ■ :l RKCKIITS AND EXPEND1 ITKKS FOR THK Kisc AL KNDING JUNE 30. 1!HM Receipts. ■e on ha ml .1 running st ill paid stock Premiuir .ership and ■e repaid Expenditures. nt Supplemental Report .drawn durinir fi- nr at this date -hares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on « Amount of interest, pi inpakl No. of mi&gt;rtifa^es in pnn'ess of foreclosure, and the aifjrreifate amount c sarii' Amount i&gt;f loans on improved reu: Appraised value of improved real estate on which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real i F .raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have made Amount of insurance in force and assiimed to the association as collateral security No. of loans made for building purpose* durintr fiscal year No! of loans made for payment of homestead mortiratres during Hs. Amount of advance payments of loans durinir ttscal year No of borrowing stock! non-borrowing - No. of minors holding -tock in th&lt;- Average rate per ceni oharired borrowers during ; Averaife rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers dunny l*lan of premium Amount ere' Amount of in^ during ttsc*;» Amount &lt;&gt;; int of divui- ■. 'tim s*oc» aunmrnwea A verutife r, Withdraw i Full paid stock eamir on hand Chin i)1 Par val.. No of si No! of- So' &lt;if share- sul &lt;-nt of due&gt; amount of &lt;1 Amount of due-* owinu For morttmn ' he »«n»«»t« umoun same </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Hl'II.I)IN&lt;; AND WAX ASSOCIATIONS. STATEM ENT i&gt;K THK CONDITION OF THK LAUREN IULLDING AND LOAN ASSN. I.AIKKU NKBRASKA. Om the :ttltli day of June. 1!«I4. Officers. .1. M. FKLHKK Civ- \V. T. (iKAHAM VU-e-lYe- F. P. VOTER Seen t.iv wiukon Ti., Directors. rFKI.HKK. WILSON. c. f KURLKY. NKVIN. VOTER. W. T. UKAHAM f. K SAlKKTT r. p. Assets. 'noil j_ r atrf lo»M mortgage loans in (inn-ess of foreclosure. .. k loans Ni.i Real estate Noi Purniture and stationery (|iient interest. |)i-enii\ims and fines Noi and tuxes paid Total 13 J1V1&gt; Liabilities. 1 ;i]iitiil «to«-k running. (Due* and dividemi'- Full paid -Nick . . ... Nm rvf fund I'ndivided prufita shareholders on incomplete loans Nothii :iiunis unearned Advance dues i ad premium* ."&gt;7."'i </seg>
            <seg id="p083">.nd.lui* I. 1i« Membership and tran 1 nission: Em. (if serial No. „• So. or Nti- of shares matured durin ires withdrawn during Vmounl Appnitsed value of impr Amoun -state A Pi&gt;raised value of unimproved real estate U|x&gt;n whioh loan Amount of ii force and assigned u- So! of loans made for payment of homestead morl No. of borrowing stockholders No of nnn-borrowiiv stockh No. of minors holding stock Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durin^ if premium Amount credited fund durinw AllloTTTTt of 1*'- M1IWUUI. in Amount Amount of in . \ i is *t i 1 1 _e rnniilli!.' repaid expense--, trawals dm I !ie^ . arninir tcif share* of running -tovk in I • 1 pairt stock in I of -h;i' of shun al union uunt of due- owin. mint nf interest, premium- and tine- due and nni'.i of mortmiire- -uhject to for. of mortjraires in proc»«* of foreclosure, and the »-■ -ume loans-mude fur buildinir purpose* duni. Amount of advance payment of loan-, durin- A vt- rune rate per cent of In </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION &lt; «•' THK AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSN. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. On the :50th day of .hint-. l!tt&gt;4. On the :50th day of June. 15104. Officers. Officers. A. W. LANK Pres \NK .!. H . M.( LAV Beeretarj (LAV 'IT .1. H. \VKS( ( )'1T TreaMini A. W. LANK Att. \NK Directors. Directors .1. H. AUKK. R. K. H. MARSHALL. QDO. K. H. MARSHALL. CJBO. C. MASON. A. W. LANK. \K. J. H. WESCOTT. W. A. SHI. J. H. M'CLAY. W. A. SELLF.CK Assets mortgage loans ♦tt.r.uuHi mortgage loans in process of foreclosure None - loans : 24. oo Non-&gt; Furniture anil stationery 311.10 f)uent interest, premiums and tines Nona and taxes paid Total ♦U.iHi-t.tU Liabilities ;il stock running. (Dues and dividends) Full paid stovk ft.000.ltal rve fund Undivided profits ~hare holders on Incomplete loans 2,130.00 liums unearned None mce dues Advance interest and premiums Total II </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Bill. DING AM) LOAN AS.SIX1ATI 85 RKCEIPTS AND KXPKNDITIHKS KOR THK KIS( \L V K A I KNDING .TTNK W. 1(*&gt;4. Receipts. ■e on hand July 1 'running stock' ran paid stock aneou Expenditures. - i*ompleted ilicitio lornm other expense Withdrawals. du«- Withdrawals, earnings ed stock, dtu &gt;-d stock, earning lid stock, il Full paid stock, earning &gt;n hand. Hooks and stationery Furniture and fixture Supplemental Report. i- tn of association (serial or permanent! r valii' hare of stm- led during fiscal • -hares matured duriin No of shares withdrawn during ti~ No. of shares of running stock in I Eo of shares of full paid stock in • o. of - No ,if . neb dues are delinquent Amouni Appraised value •■ "IH&gt;n which loans h;. .rte Appraised value i Amount of loans on unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real ■ upon which loans hav. made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collatera eeurity - K - made for huildin* P"&gt; - made for iwymenl of idvance paymenW of loans during 'lorrowinir stockholders No of non-t)orrowin»t stockholders &lt; No of minors holding stock in thr II ill ' ■ ' i i I * 1 » I 1 I ■ p£ ' ■ ■ &gt; II \veraue rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durum I Average rate per cent of premiums chanted borrower- dunn Plan of premium Amount creditei! during tlscv Amount of losses ohar&gt;;ed I Amount of dividend- declared on runmntt st , Amount of dividends declared on full pam»i«H k iiunnn n« ai &gt;c»r ,je rate percen Average runninif time of stock matur*"' kr in s .■rshi|&gt; and transfer fee repaid flo of - 'in (if seriali So. of share ■'" ,,{ . .;i&gt; ment of due* Total amoui Amount of &lt;l \mount of '' No of morttr; ■■ ;inrt the ayirreirate amount i No. of mortiiatres in process of foreclosure, and the ai«retfate amount of </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION (IK THK NEB. CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. On the -UKh day of .Tune. l!HU Officers. HOMER K. BTRKET President .!&lt; &gt;HN (M HS&lt; &gt;N Vice-President M. \V. Ft )LSOM Secretary T. N. BURKET Trea - E. 1\ LEONARD Manager of Agvnci.- Directors. K. P. LEONARD, T. N. BURKKT. JOHN GIBSON M. W. FOLSOM. HOMER K. BURKET. Assets. First mortage loans •MS,013.6ff ■ mortape loans in process of foreclosure loans i:uo:;.&lt;h&gt; Heal estate 4,605.42 Furniture and stationery t&gt;. r &gt;2..!i&gt; 2K.2IT.22 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines rises and taxes paid 21s. :u&gt; Expenses and taxes paid &lt; Kher Real Estate sold on contract :!.4:{!'.7!» Total 11,042. 24W.75 Liabilities. Capital stock running". (Dues and dividends Full paid stock H1I72.OHO..11 ve fund 2O.1H4.2:; Undivided profits tt.fl75.lM Due share holders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues ince interest and premiums w 1 i B^l* * 1 1 I » </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES F()K THr KISi Al. Yl ENDING JUNE »). 1!*&gt;4. Receipts. 'ill paid RtOOk ' and rim-- • rship and transfer fee ve fund. Total Expenditures t'onui. Other ezpenaea . Withdraw.. Withdrawal^ ■k. dues ■k. t-arni Jrt5 ivti .{I EL-e furniture h on hand. . it*. . I'ndivided prott Total. Supplemental Report. permanent). I Vrnianen' lillf Of P» No ol esi^ueddunn*- No. of ek in force at th which due, are, ■ eanoella iiayment of dues Tot^auK,., Aniouni of dues owinx by borrowing shareh' m n rof mortKaKes in proves- of foreclosure, and the airirreirate an of same, thirteen A mi &gt;in Ai&gt;pi&gt;rai*e&lt;i roved real eKtate upon which loan-shave been made Appraised value of inn Amount of loans upon unimproved real ■ •»d value of unimproved real estate upon which loa n made Amount of in^urai and axxivned to the A Uateral nd Tornado No of loans made for buildintr purposes during nscal year s No. of loans made I t of homestead moruatre* during tl»cal year Amount of advance payments of loans durinir fiscal year, loans repaid No. of borrowing - MS ' non-borroo No. of minors boldin* - tverane rate per c rowers durinir tlictl year . . veratre rate per cent of premiums •■named borrowers durinir litcal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund i Amount of losses ehanred to reserve [ Pount ii" ount ol &gt;n full paid « « A reraire rate pet ared dun ■ &gt; Averatre running i bund July I. IOUCI running stofkl I-oani repaid fount of interest und h of n jt d the atrvreirate amount of same. Hfty-two. •&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATEMENT Or THK CONDITION OF THK MADISON BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSN. M ADIS&lt; &gt;N. KCBRASKA. On the aoth day of June. UKH. M ADISc )N. XKHRASKA. *m the MM\ day of June. liHl-t. Officers. Officers. PETER Hl'BKNDALL President PETER Hl'BKNDALL ...PrwMent .1 A&lt; &lt; &gt;B HKNnKKS( &gt;N Vice-president K. A. MOIjOXV Set-iftarv K. A. MOLONY Secretary C. K. l'l^VSS Treasurer * . K. PLA88 Trwwuper Directors. Directors. IB. BECKKK. SCHVVKNK. H. B. BKCKKK. M. F. THOMAS. JKXS JENSE.V. IIWENK. W. C. HAWKINS. M. F. THOMAS. Assets. mortgage loans H2.On0.0O Kit »t mortgage loans in process of foreclosure k loans Iini.ihi loans Real estate and stationer) -l.iHO.Ts ijuent interest, premiums tines and dues x:tl\x!» - and taxes paid - Is. tax certificates Hills receivable 41."&gt;" Sundry acconnts 352. Ml Total •1?,4S».~ Liabilities. ( 'apital st&lt;K'k running-. ( Dues and dividends! Ill.41o.o0 Full paid stock rve fund Tndivided profits ."..24&lt;t.:i!i -hareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums t'A.'l ry accounts Itto. *'• Total </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 BUILDING AND IX&gt;AN ASSOCIATI RK( KIl'TS AND KXPHNDITTRKN FOR THK KIS( A I \ k \K KNDINc; JUNE 30, 1!«&gt;4. Receipts. Dues (full paid stock) Premiums Kines and transfer fe&lt; Membership fees Ens repaid I Expenditures kss « t 'ommiNsion- Other expei^ Withdrawals, due Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, due^ Matured stock, earnint Full paid stock dues Full paid stock, earning i &gt;n hand . . 4 Tax certificate other payment Total Supplemental Report. Plan of Association (serial or (termanent) Par \ on. (if serial) ' shares issued since ory.im/.ation ted during tiseal year . shares matured during fiscal year So. of shares withdrawn during H»- shares of running stock in ! shares of full paid stock in So. of shares loaned on So of shares on which dues are delinquent So. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues imount of dues, inters ■- Amount of dues owini? by b« i Amount of interest, premiui md unpaid • mortitaires subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amount ■ Sit. of mortjfat^es in pr»K»ess of foreclosure, and the atrtrretrui' same Amount of loans on improved real Appraised value of real ■ i which loans have been mode Appraised value of inir Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans ha\ i Pount of insurance in force and assijfned to the Association ;i - securit- II So. of loans made for huildintt pun&lt;oses durin* tisv.i No. of loans made for payment of homt- &gt;raires during Bk No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the Association if interest charted borrowers during Average rate i&gt;er cent of premiums charged borrowers durint Plan of Pr. Amount credited to reserve fund during tlscai Amount of losses charged to reserve fund dur Amount of dividends declared on running si Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock durinir lisca Average rate i&gt;er cent of dividend \veriiiTt* runoinif time &gt;&gt;f stook muture&lt;i durii ■ - ■ hand Julj I. ittK &lt; running stock » Hills rr Other receipt Total =: Amount of advance payment of loan* durinir Hscu. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THK MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. MADISON. NEBRASKA. On the :«»th dav of June. 1WH. Officers. SNYDKR Pres J. L. (1RANT Vioe-President GEO. K. RICHARDSON Seen T. F. MKMMINGKR Treasurer Directors I- VYDKR. A. MAi'SHN. J. Li (IRANI 1. K. G. MOSSMAN. JACOB HENDF.RS &gt;V. &lt;;Ku. K. UCHARI Assets loans tJ-M'ei.ixi e loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate MO.WI Furniture and stationary 1 1". ■"&gt;•' cjuent interest, premiums and fines Tax - ( Khe Total •27,(K« Liabilities «:...- &lt; a pit a 1 stock running. ( Dues and dividends ) Full paid stock Reserve fund Reserve fund. Undivided profits 1,044.33 Due share holders on incomplete loans. Premiums unearned Advance dues. Advance interest and premiums. Total </seg>
            <seg id="p091">BUN, DING AND I 91 RK( HUTS AND KXPENDITIRKS FOR THK KIS( AJ KNDINCJ JUNE :t". 1!«U Receipts. Balance on hand July I. r«&gt;:i running stock) ■ full paid stock) Premiums Membership and transfer fee Loans repaid Real estate sale •• certificates Sundry accounts Total Expenditures. Commissions other eipen-r- Withdrawals. dn. Withdrawals, earnings. Matured stock, i Matured stock, ea Full paid stock, d Full paid stock, earning *n hand . Tax sale certificates Tota Supplemental Report. Plan of MM* al or permanent) Par value of each sb.i No. of series lamed since organization if serial ■f share* iswied sin.-, organization :* * shares matured during tLscal Tear ires withdrawn durin. No. of shares of running stock in force at this date shares of full paid stock in force at tli shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues .1 [ shares sub payment of dues Total amount of i Amou Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid r of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and th&lt; amount of Hve r of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same . Amount of loans on improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of inn Amount of loans upon unimproved real • Appraised value of unimproved real estate ut«n which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security. lilding purposes during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortiratres durinir Use Amount of advance p:. ians during No. of borrowing - :c tion-borro^ No. of minors holding stock in the Association Average rate per cent of in -'ed borrowers during fiscal A veratre rate per cent of premium* charged borrowers durinir fiscal year f Krcrn! J per, -en. Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during rts&lt;v ; Amount of rve fund durinir fiscal year. Amount of dividends declared on runninx stock durinir Bsc Amount of divi^U -d on full paid stock during Average rate per cent of dividends declared durinir fiscal year Average running I '•&lt; matured durr No. &lt;&gt;f sbarex issued during tt- </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT UK CONDITION nKTHK MAYWOOD BUILDING AND LOAN AKSN MAVWOon. NEBRASKA. (&gt;n tl«- M*th day of June. l!Mi4 Officers. V. M. SPARHAWK : President W. B. VOTAW Vice-President N. H. BOGIK Secretary A. C. BARRY Treasurer Directors E. B. MURPHY. J. H. HAMILTON. \V. B. VOTAW N. H. BOOCK. I. SPARHAWK. Assets. mortgage loans 92.800.(10 mortage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationery Delinquent interest, premiums anil fine--. 11.60 - and taxes paid 21.10 ( Hher Total *"J - Liabilities. Capital stock runninjr. ( Dues and dividends! t2.550.46 Full paid stocjf rve fund if fund Tndivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned , '514. V&lt; Pi-emiums unearned Advance dues • Advance interest and premiums Total ♦"-' ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 RK&lt; KIITS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THr FIS&lt; AL Yr Ml ENDING JUNE M*. V.m. Receipts i full paid Mock) Inter.- Premiums Kines Membership and transfer fee* Expenditures. StUrie stock, earnintr stock, dues slock earninir hand Tola Supplemental Report Plan of mboc Hi .nutation (if serial). ■ shares matured during Hs*.* i a ithdrawn durir. shares of runnintr sti ■ No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ied on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent ent of dues imount or Amount of dues owinx by borrow Amount of ns and tines due and unpaid No. of mortt' re. and the axtrreirate amount of same No. of mortitaifes in process of foreclosure, and the axirretrate amount of same Amouti ue of improved real estate upon which loans have been made used value of in,, Amount of ,. • •d value of unimproved real estate upon which loans han made rount of insurance in force and assitrnei'. .H'iation as collateral securit • s made for huitdintf purposes durin_ No. of loans made Amount t»f advari'' &gt;ansdurink. r I fion-tM»rrow in^r stockh' minors holding stock i r cent of ii growers durinir fiscal year Kje rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers duriri- I Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during risen Amount of losses charge* Amount of dividends declared on running sti&gt;ck dur : H.i.iim-.- on hand July I h«i:i 'runninir stock) Par value of eaoh share of ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 BUILDING AND A.TIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK IfcOOOK CO-OPERATIVE BUILDING AND BAVTNGS ASSN. He* ( k &gt;K . N K BRASKA. On the :tmh dav of .1 vim-. 1&lt;N«4. Mi-C(K)K. NEBRASKA. Officers. Officers. T» »S. B. * AMPBELL l'iv~ THi »S. B. ( AMPBKLL Pre&gt; \V. S. PF.RRY Vii-.-l'n - W. S. I'KRRY Vii-.-l'n - F. A. PKNNF.LL Sa: F. A. f'KNNKLL Eton L. THORGRIMSt &gt;N Trea L. TH()R(;m.\IS( )N Tiv:, V. K. KLDRKD ( . K. KLDRKD ■ Directors. Directors r»S. B. (AMHBKI.1.. H. Mil S. K. CAMFBKU.. VV. S. PERKY. .1. K. KKI.I.V. I'EKKY. •I. E. KKI.I.V E. HA w . H. Mil. C. K. I.KHN. E. SAMSON. C. P. LEHN. J. H. BENNKTT. J. A. WXLOOX. M. K1MMK1.I.. J. H. BENNKTT J. A. WIU'IIX. K. M. KIMMKI.I Assets Assets. Cirst mortgage loan- loans in process of foreclosure. . . morttrH-re loans in procest* of foreclosun :U&gt; loans Keal ■ Kurniture and Stationery Furniture and Stationer* ' +:IT.41 y.::.u Delinquent dues and interest Delinquent dues and interest - and taxes paid 1 -M&gt;.*»' - and taxes paid I-W.txi 44.56 44.55 Total t56.Htt.21 Total ■ - Liabilities Liabilities &lt; apital stork i-unnin«r. (Duel and dividends ; •K.72J.* Full paid sttK-k •und l.JW.tWi t'ndivided profits 1.." Oiarn holders on Incomplete loMM Premiums unearned M4K74 Premiums unearned iiTT.txi ind pi-emiuins i:ii . ujjijiklu I 44H( in* </seg>
            <seg id="p095">HIIIJ)IN&lt;; AND 1 95 HK.c KI1TN AND KXPHNDITIRKS FOR TH K K AL yy A I KNDINC; JUNE :h&gt;. l'»4 Receipts. •■•e on hand July I ■nmniiii.' stock) [full | laid stock) a Premiums II Membership and tra repaid Heal e Rents Tax sale certificates redeem iiayabi To Expenditures alaries Commi - otber. Withdraw., Withe! Matured stoek. dues Matured stock, earning Premiums return- -;»rnin: • Supplemental Report. Plan of asso.- ermanent I Par tbIu • ries iwued siDoe oriranization. (if serial) ■ ■e ornanl, ' share* issued durinn n ■d durinir fiscal year . withdrawn during fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in ?■ date So of shares of full paid stook in force at th&gt; N'o. of shares loaned on • So of shares on which dues are delimiuent So. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of due Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of duesowinx bj horro» Amoui -'iinum!* and flnt- No. of t tountofMMBC ■ •l-'^'ire and the a^iTeirate umt. nf^me ' improve) uponwhi&lt;-: • made Appral^ilaMle.-f ,„„....■..„...,.- ■ e upon which loans have been tnud? of insurance in force and assigned to the Association ..in., made for tiuildintf purposes durin_ made for i a] &gt;ear Amount of advance p;&gt; ians durioK taea ■iation Eera^e rate i&gt;er cent of interest chanted borrowers during flscu eraite rate per cent of premiums charired borrowers durintt tt^, ,n of premiun. Amoi. : during fls.- Amon A mo i. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THE NEBRASKA CITY BCILDINCi AND LOAN ASSN NEBRASKA CITY, NEBRASKA. &lt;&gt;n the 30th day of June. 1!«&gt;4. Officers. MIKE SEL.ZER Vice-President W. H. PITZER Sevretar&gt; H. F. MEYKR Tre;, W . H. PITZER \tt, Directors. fr. hctt. A. BADEK. r. MEYEK. W. VV. MKTZ. S. T. DA VIES .IOHN W. STKINHAKT. HKN'RY SCHWAKE, W. H. HITZf:K. MIKK ■""■ MIKK SEINER. Assets. uiorttra^e loans *:^{.4!C &gt; .*.' 1 First morttratre lt&gt;ans in ]&gt;roi - ess of foreclosure Real estate li.L 1 .".:;. 1. Furniture and stationery h *».72*&gt;.r&gt;&lt;f Delinquent interest, premiums and tines 681.24 Expenst &gt; and taxes paid 57.011 2i*t..M. Total *4:S Liabilities. Capital stock running. ( Dues and dividends) 135,614.011 Full paid stock. ive fund U17.ini Divided and undivided profits ~..T77..V&gt; Due share holders on Incomplete loans iiums Advanc-i Advance interest and premiums ■^ O vo i </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 KKCKIJTS AND EXPENDITURES KuK THK KIS( XL KNDING JINK :$n. 1!*U. Receipt-. ■enn hand July I. IMCI runnirik.' stock I ■full paid BtoeU Membership and transfer fees Loux repaid. .-state sale' Expenditures W ■ •hdrawals. Aae- Withdrawals, earning Matured stock, due- Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, ci Full paid stock, earninirs •.hand ■ertitieates Iteul estate improvement Supplemental Report ii (serial or i&gt;ermanent) I'fi iiianent ■ .f each share of stot-U -sued since organization (if serial) it this date ' shares issued since organization ' share* issued durinit fiscal year shares matured during fiscal year I .res withdrawn during fiscal year. ■ -.hares of running stock in force at this d»te • -hares of full paid paid stock in force at this date -hares loaned on ures on which dues are delinquent -hares subject to concellation for non-payment of dues .mount of dues delinquent at this date ■it. of dues owinit by borrowing shareholders int of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid nortiraiies subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amount of same, nine nort inures in process of foreclosure and the airirreirate amount mi Amount of loans on improved reu. ■ NfcMMi -&gt;-d value of improved real estate iiimhi which loans have been made A ppraised value of improvements Amount of loans ui~&gt;n unimproved real • Apprmiaed value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security loans made for building purposes durinir fiscal year « No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortituifes during fiscal &gt; - ear. .-it of advance payment of loans durinir fiscal year ■ •orrowinif stockholders. non-borrowinif stockholders minors holding stock in the Association M rife rate per cent of interest chanted borrowers ilurin. _e rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers durini; fiscal year &gt;f premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinir fiscal year Amount of losses chanted to reserve fund durinit fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock durinit fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock &lt;: Averaite rate per cent of dividends declared durinir flso.. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 STATEMENT OF THK rONIHTION OV THK NELSON LOAN AND BUILDING. ASSX. NELSON. NEBRASKA. On tin- :»lt)i d:i\ of JutW. l!H&gt;4 Officers H. F.. (JOODRK'H Pre* HKNRY FOX. .Tk Yice-President \\". (i. BRADL.F.Y Seci M. A. R1BLR Trea- K. D. BR&lt; )\V N At* Directors fK)DKKH. . W. HAWI.KY. I), —mil. J. M. LINKS. l&gt;. W. KURD. C. R. STONKR. KI&gt;. .1KNSKN. I. O. FOSTKK. HF.XRY FOX. Jl Assets ruortjra}?*' loans ♦l!t..M'-.4I First taorig%ge loan&gt; in proems of foreclosure Stook loans Real estatf 1:w&gt;.cni trnituiv and stationery sh ' &lt; ash Delinquent interest. pieniiunM and tines Kx]&gt;ensHs &lt; nher assets . Delinquent dues, and stock cancelled 2,(M4t."W Tax sale certificate 44. s i. Total *-l-l.:,2\X»i Uabilttles • 'apital sUK-k ninninjr. Dues and dividends *M.irJlt.2" Full paid stock J3.451.tai ive fund 1*44.011 I *ndi vided profits '.xi.TT Due nhare holdei-s on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues iincf interest and premiums Total t2"J.-'«l' l.iii; </seg>
            <seg id="p099">BIII.1&gt;IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. 99 HKCKiriS AND KXl'KNDlTl'KKS KOK THK K KCAL Yh \i: KNDINC. .H'NK :«). 1IHI4 Receipts. •e on band July I. I ■ ■iimmu' stock) full paid stock) tnteresi 1'remiunis I • rship and transfer fee 1 M ■ • ~tate Mile* ■ rtirteates ••■rtirtcates tccounta Aeeouaia Total Total Expenditures Expenditures. - i&gt;ek. earnings ■ n hand MJI e eerUSeataa I'rofli and loss Total Supplemental Report Supplemental Report. ■11 i »enal or permanent! on i serial or i&gt;enn»nenti line of eurh share of Ktoek. ■ur value of euch share of Ktoek it. ol iif serial I . (■' irinjf rtsoal year 'iiatured duriiiir fiscal \ear withdrawn during rtseiil yen running stuek in force a of shares of full paid stock in foro I shares on whi&lt;- N.i. of si ion. lif serial) S., ol No ol -ani/.ation. I w s»ued duriiiif tl- ■ .iiured during H-m \n shares withdrawn during rtseal year So. of snared of running stoek in force No of shares of full imid stock in force v S.&gt; of shares on » leni r nonpayment of dues payment of dues Total amount of ■ Amount of i mount of A mount of inter*- paid mount of No. of mor' line i mount fif same No. of mor: nd the aififrexate ami of s*me .iid I he axu'reirate ami nfskme Amount of mount of Appraised value •• ui«in which loans havelwen made |.|m in which loans ha velwenma. Appraised value i»f improvi Appraised value of imi Anuiii on unimproved real esi . ised value of unimproved real estate uiKin w I A moii' »ri unimpn i Appraised value of unimproved re; Amount of insurance in force and assigned • security ' loans made forbuildii * loans made for puyn • ait of advance payments ttf lou&gt; ' borrowinn stockholder* if non-born&gt;win^ stockholder - f minors holding stock in t f ■ ■ r; Amount of insurance in force and assU security So. of loans made for building i»urjM»s»-^ during ris ( - . loans made for payn ■ Ann&gt;unt of advance paytnen So. of borrowintf stockholder- 41 Average rate i&gt;er cent of interest chaivexl borrowers during tts- Average rate per cent of premiums chanred borrowers during nscal rear 1'lan of premium Amount credited -- fund during fiscal year Amoui ear Amount of Amount of divider d~ d full paid stock during fiscal ] ear . ■■ • .ire rate per N declared during Us.- </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 STATEMENT (»■ THK CONDITON OF THK NEWMAN (iKOVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY NEWMAN (JROVK. NKBRASKA. *hi the :»«h day of Jun* l!*&gt;4. Officers. A. T. RODMAN Prmideni A. B. MILLER VU-e-pn- C.A.RANDALL Swr B. H. OERHART. Trea C. A. RANDALL Attornrj Directors. C. A RANDALL. IH.VKK'K A B. Mll.LKR E- H liKKHAKT S M JIKI.SUN Assets. inortjrajre loans ll2.alin.tHI First mortfra^e loans in jmxkvss of foreclosure Sttx'k loans Rfal estate Furnitui-e and stationery &lt;a.h 7*.«S Delinquent dues, interest and fines uses and taxes paid 'Jl^.txi &lt; Hhev . Total *l:i&gt; Liabilities. Capital stot-k ninninjr. ( Dues and dividends i •!!&gt; Full paid stock ive fund 4lo. 7"* I'ndivided profits l.(ilv&gt;i -hareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues unce interest and premium.* Total </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 \K Receipts. ioe on hum) July I. I UK ■ runnin* - 1 . •• ■ U » full |i.ll&lt;l -i l^remiums Membership fee Loans repaid ate salt lent-s repaid Tot* Expenditures UhereuMOM. .^rninjf 1 ud stock, dues &gt;id stock, earning - ►n hand meat Total Supplemental Report. icimtion (serial or permanent) . *f each share of stock lurinjt Osc» drawn durii it this date S.i of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on in'iuent \'.. n t nonpayment of dues ;it this date ~ \nuiunt of dues owin* h\ burro* Amount of tnlums and Ones due and unpaid rt»f inortifa^es * and the uiftrrefcrtite mM same. two. Ho. of mortiratfes in procetw of foreclosure and the atrtrreifute amount oi sani&gt; Amount of loans on improved real • -ed value of real estate U|x&gt;n which loans have been mad« Appraised value of inn \ mount of loans upon unimproved real ■ ■■il value of unimproved rra n which loans have been made ri&gt;unt of insurance in foi security loans made for huildinv purposes during fiscal year • No of loans made omestead tnorttraires durinir fiscal year \inount of adv;i S 1 non-borrowing stockh minors holding stock lire rate per cent of in --ed borrowers durini; fiscal year A i ••raue rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers durin . if Premium Amount erei e fund durimt I Auumnt of di. Amount of dividen&lt;' &gt;n full i&gt;aid stock durimt tK rate i&gt;ei -e running Rl'.i F.ll'TS AND KXPHNDITTRKK FOR THK KIHCAL Yh KN'DINC .H'NK :ii». 1J*iv*. ' serial * ■.-,«» charirt" ••funddurit </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 STATEMENT OF THK icixiHTluN OK THE ELKHORN BTILDINi; AND SAVINGS ASSX NOKKOHK. NEBRASKA. «&gt;n the :5&lt;&gt;tli da.i of June. I'MU. Officers. Officers. DR. H. .1. COLE. ...fiv- DR. H. .1. COLE. Pnes A. DEGN1 Vtoe-Pna ■ &gt;DIORNE Sam MEMMINGKR f* A. DEGNER . Vice-Preti omoRNK SMivtui r. F. MEMM1NCKR ...Tw«hui Directors. Directors DR. H. .1. &lt; DI. K. H. C. MATKAV. T. ('. otMOK^ iKT. A. DBIXER. II. « . fAUOB. DR. H. J. I H. C. MATH AS. T. «'. OIMOKVK iiKT. A. ttt&gt; II. f. W.\1.KVJ Assets. Assets 121 121 _•■ loans in jirocess of forevloKun _•■ loans in process of foreclowun - Furiiitiire and Htationeri . ' *n.;s» M&gt;; .;•&gt; IV-lintjiient dues and n ■ ami taxo paid ■ounty warrant Ta&gt; t-ertififates Total fc£3.&lt;Wl."»2 Liabilities. i«-k iiinninjr nd dividem - ~ x +'i.'! Full - U.L21.&lt;n 4.HMHI id incomplete loans •rned i tid premiums &gt; . ' H » 1 . . )_ </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 I V RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KoKTHK ENDING Jl'NE :$•'. 1!"&gt;4. Receipts ■e on band July I. I innini; stoc i full paid v lntere-r Premium* Membership and transfer fee: repaid Iteal esi Kent- Tota Expenditures irtvert Withdraw.. I rninirs ! t -«l stock, dues. Matured stock, earning aid stock, due- Kull paid slock. earnini &lt; ash on hand si paid I'ota Supplemental Report I- if association (serial or permanen ilue of each share of stock N No. of shares of rnnniutr stock in force at this shares of full paid stock in force at this date shares loaned on No of shares on- which ii N'ii! of shares subject I lent nt dues Total araoui Amount of Amount of interest mm ■ ' i tans on improved real i ■ilue of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of imr Vniount of loans up &gt;n uninipr iliieof unini- i whichloanshaveheen made Nil of !■ Amount of advance payments of loans during tlscal year ■ Eo. of borrowii o. of non-borrow minors hol&gt; ■ \ veraire rate per rinif tiscal year . Avenge rate per cent of pre i rired borrowers during fiscal year if premium Amount cre&lt;1' Amount of lumiochaiv AmouUtofdivid.!.. Averaife ratr ' teaoa ogciareci 1 1 A veratre rum ■lunBB ■*e»i ear N.i of - .red during N'n shn 1 wn during No ,, f ,„,„,. .nd the aKifrettate amount of No. of mat%iuiii» hi i the airirreifmte anu&gt;uni </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 STATEMENT Of THK CONDITION OK THK NORFOLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. XORKOIJv. XKBRASKA. &lt;.hj Uw :{(tlh ilay of Juur. I'.to-J. Officers. Officers. I'ASKWALK IV.- H. A. I'ASKWALK f V. - DK. ALKX BKAK Vice-Preii \ LEX BEAR Vice-Pvea &lt; . B. DTRLAND Secretary K \V. ZPTZ Trea K \V. ZITZ Trea- M AJ'KS ft HAZEM Attoin.-v - M AJ'KS ft HAZEN Attoin.v - Blrectors. Mrectsrs. H. A. PASKWA1.K. I. M. MAI Y. I. I*AN. AFFORD. I&gt;K. ALEX BKAK. J. A. WILL£Y. . i-HKISTOPH. IR I'HI.^ INTlIN BITHHOI.17. H A. PA8BWAUC. I. M. MAI-Y. S. (.'. DEAN » KFORD, 1&gt;R. ALEX BKAK. J. A. WILJJ5Y. iHKISTOPH. IK UHI.t AXT1IX BTTHHOLIY. Assets. Assets. ■ loans fS2.tiiio.INI loans +#ni.*M m i.i m » Kt mortgage loans in pnK-ess of foreclosuiv k loans and real estate sold on contract l»,342.K! mortg'ajrf loans in pnK-ess of foret'losuiv St&lt;H - k loans and real t-stat&lt;' sold on contract SUx-k loans and real estate sold on contract . l»,342.K! Real estate tt.817.Hn Real estate ii.MT.in&gt; Furniture and stationery 143.75 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 4."&gt;4. V 4 and taxes paid l.ix, and taxes paid l.o. ' Hht B advance payments ln-&gt;ui-ancc ... li«».i;4 Total Mn.fl Insurance ... l««».t;4 Total LtoMlities. Liabilities. Capital &gt;t&lt;K - k running. ( Dues and dividends! I0.54O.OU Full paid stock i ve fund 1. 1155. 21 l'ivmiuni&gt; X'A. 11 Advance payments I'.l - 1 accounts 70. " •st on loans .'.TlM. Profit* :!2n.7'.i ,tion fee +ti.2o ToUl m.lGt3.2."i </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 \| YKAK Receipts. lialance on band July I. r«&gt;: mnintr stock) ill paid -.took Interest premium* and tin Bills receivable SB Taxes Membership and transfer fee repaid . Real • is aod advanced paymc Bflb« payable Insurance Tola Expenditures. Salaries Bills receivable i &gt;ther expenses '. *&gt; 1 1 Withdrawals, dues and earni With*' 1 ninifs. Sr Taxes and insurance -e and profit Total Supplemental Report. ment ) Par value of each share of * No. of - ' serial N.i ..' if nlMinu h» So .if shares issued dun No. of shares niaiured during ttsoul year ■ ires withdrawn durinir Bhci shares of running stock in force at this date N'n of shares of full paid stock in force at this date ' shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent Total amount of - date Amount of dues owin^ by borrow -Iders Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid No of mortuatres subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amount of same five ... No. of mort if aves in process of foreclosure and the avtrreirat' s»m&lt;- Amount of loans on improved real • £E .•&lt;1 value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real • t&gt;raised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been nadc Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collatera security. loans made for buildin? purposes dun: No of loans made for payment of home- Amount of advance payment No, of borrowing stockholders. in non-borrowinif stockholders No of minors holding stock in the Averaire rate per cent of interest chanced borrowers durinv rise* Average rate per cent of premiums chanted borrowers durint Plan of premium Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year. Amount of dividends declared on running stock during I tit of dividends declared on full i lineal year Average rate per cent of dn ared durinir fiscal year RKTKIPTN AND KXTKNIHTIKKS F&lt; )F&lt; THK KIS( KNDING .M'NK 3it. 1!N&gt;4. f share-* »»ul &gt;f due: s: : Amount cr&lt;- 'und during dues * varii^^ TMinninj/ t j n i h * ► f sf n* ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Hl"ll,I&gt;IN&lt;; AND ! ATIONS. STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OK THK &lt; &gt;K THK COWDITIOII OF THK NORTH LOOP BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. NORTH LOCP, NEBRASKA. On th^ :iotli da\ &lt;&gt;f June 1 ( h»4. NORTH U&gt;rp BUILDING AND LOANASSN NORTH IjOI'I*. NF.HRASKA. Officers. Officers. (;IY DANN I'n- Ot'Y DANN I V. m. B. LOVE Vice-presu K. LOVE , Vice-pres K. JT. BABCUC'K... Seen K. JT. BABOOCK. . . Secret 5. MAYO ... Tretm MAVo Ti&gt;-;, HARCOCK K. J. BABCXX'K Directors. Directors. H. H. AI.VOK1&gt;. OUT IIAXV. i;K(). K. .KlHNScN .V. T I.. K. I.KWIS. K. LOVK, I.. K. LEWIS, K. U)VK. c;k&lt;&gt;. s. mayo. Assets. • loan&gt; morttratrt' loans in process of foreclosure loans Heal estate Furniture and stationer; I5.WI Eloquent interest, premiums and toes - and taxes paid 33.441 - paid Total 1'i.ck» Liabilities. &lt; apital stock running. | Dues and dividendsi i ..V Full paid stock. rve fund I'ndivided profits shareholders on incomplete loans 141. -'■ B rned 4T.«n&gt; ind |&gt;remiunis is not vet adjusted </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 ril lijlllISt* ;\ .' I ' I *' ' A •* ATSiM. r\ 1A I H'.Nr^ V r A I ENDING .HNK 30. I!*t4 Receipts. Premiums Membership and transf Kents r examination of abstract of title Expenditures. Loan Othe, Withr M Matured stock, earning Full paid stock. dues Kull paid stock earning Cash on hand • la Supplemental Report Plan of a-soeiation (serial or iwrmanenl I I Par value of each share of - So. of - on (if serial' N No. of -hares in force at date of last report ■vani/ation hdrawn dui inoelled and not taken -hares of runnintr stock in force at this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shar« No. of share- on which No. of shan &gt;r nonpayment of dues No. of mort traces subject to foreclosure and the a^irresfat • ro. of mort^atres in process of foreclosure, and the akftfretfate amount same Annan, estate upon which loans bare been made Appra Amount of loan- on unimproved re.. Fppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loan - made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as co No. of loans made for buildinn purposes during Hscal year ..ails made for payment of homestead morttrairesdurii: Amount of &lt; ments of loans during .•Iders No. of Aver chanted borrowers durinu Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durin. Plan of premium Amount ert A mourn Amount of Averai Avera- KK( KU'TS AND KXPKNDITl'RKS F&lt; &gt;K THK KM AL hand Julj 1 i running stock) lock' I ,«i;in-- repaid Real &lt;■- S'i&gt;. &lt;&gt;' ured dunni; ttso.i Total amount &lt;&gt;f &lt;l\ie- delinquent Amount of dues n 1, Amount of inten- »nd unpaid </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 imildim; and loan ass &gt;, iations. STATEMENT ( &gt;K THE CONDITION Of THE MUTUAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSX. NORTH PLATE, NEBRASKA. Oh the :«»tli dav &lt;»f .June. l!*»-l. MITFAL HL'ILDIXi; AM) LOAN ASSX NOKTH PLATE. NKMRASKA Ou the :u»tli dav &lt;»f .Tune, litit-l. Officers. Officers ("HUM AS ( . PATTERSON 1'iv- THOMAS ( . I'ATTKKSC &gt;N 1'iv- VICTOR VAN (JOKT7. Vice-PresidenI VICTOR VAN GOETZ Vim-Pmidtiii SAMUEL C&lt; x «EF ... . . . . .Se&lt;-i SAMUEL C&lt; x )ZKh . . S.-c PRANK K. BULLARD Tnm - KKANK K. BULLARD Trea&gt; WIU'OXA HAU,I(;AN \tt..m,v. WILCOX &amp; HALUGAN utomev. Directors Directors. IKA I,. BARK :.. BAR*:. AKTHL'K Ml'SAMAIIA. K. T. KK1&gt;M&lt; &gt;NI&gt;. AKTHTK MCNAMAUA. F. T. KKltMuMi. J. K. CI.ABAl'CH. TBOA. C. PATTBMON. I.KSTKK WAI.KI J. K. CI.ABAl'CH. TH(». V. PATTERSON. I.KSTKK WAI URO. W. FINN. JA.MKS M. KANNIK. VICTOK VAN W. FINN. JA.MKS M. KANNIK. VICTOK VAN Assets. Assets. loans M3H.4IIU.4lil i*- loans in iirnvesx of foreclosure :&gt;• loitns in |iriK.*esM of foreclosurt 5.*1».W» 4.3S Real -. 4.3SB.1J Furniture and stationar\ " &gt;M l&gt;'-linquent interest, premiums and fines i-ei-i ideates i-ei-1 i tii-a tes Interest paid 270.90 Total M33.3R7.31 Total ♦!*!. UaMlttes Liabilities Capital stot-k running'. (Dues and dividends - ■ Capita] stot'k running'. (Dues and diridends) . +114. Full ]&gt;aid st&lt;H-k ive fund l."i Full paid stock rvp fund 1 .1 ' . rve fund I'ndivided profits :'.. 1 I'ndivided profits :'.. 1 \u.:&gt; Due share holders on incomplete loans ;inn»d 13.770. IK -hare botden on incomplete loans arned 13.770. \* &lt;iMT JN&gt; mil pmniunm 211. '"» ' </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 RWKIPTH AND KXHKNDITl'RKS M)RTHK K!S&lt; \l YKAK KNDINC; JINK .Jo. V*H Receipts. Balance un hand ,Iuh Dues (running st4&gt;ck) Dues &lt;full paid stock! Interest Premiums Membership and transfer fees Louis repaid Real estate sale Rents Taxes and insurance Furniture sold Tola Expenditures. Salaries Commission Other ex|)enst-s Withdrawals dm- Withdrawals earnings Taxes and insurance Matured stock, earnings Pull paid stock, dues Full paid stock, earning (ash on hand Total Supplemental Report Plan of association (serial or permanent) Par value of each shar So. of series Inwed sure organization (if serial) No. of staarr No of shares issued since organization N"i&gt; of shares issued during Hscal year No. of shares matured during fiscal year -hares withdrawn during nscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this dale No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on. »v?» No. of shares on which dues are delinquent ft* No of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date -_i M Amount of dues o win* by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid No. of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. So. of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same . . Amount of loans on improved real estate Ml Appraised value of improved real estate on which loans have been made Appraised value of improvement- Amount of loans upon unimproved real e-' a I • Piraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral I Mi • No of loans made for building purposes during nscal ye.ir ■ loans made for payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal \ ear Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year, average per ■ *.■»♦• &gt;»■ I borrowing stiK-kholders No. of non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in th&gt; n Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during nscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers dun: I 'Ian of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during ttscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during ttscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during tlscalyear . ?9.547.mi Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during ttecalyear Average rate per cent of dividends declared du Average running time of stock matured durir </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 KlIUHNc; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT thk cownmoN &lt;&gt;k not HANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSN. OMAHA. NEBRASKA. On tl«- :tnth da; of June. 1*m&gt;4. Officers. OMAHA. XKHKASKA Officers. HiiKl'. (HUNK President tGEP. C'RONK I'nsid.-nt \V. D. LIN( OJA Vice-Prat \V. D. LINCOLN YK-t-l'ivsi.leiiT •:. V. SMITH Heen SMITH Sec, L. H. KORTY : L. H. KDKTV : THOMAS I). (RANK \tr. . THOMAS I). (RANK Vttnrwj Directors. Directors. IE P. CHO.VK. W. I». LDtCOUf. I.. H. KOKTY. \S U. CKANK. JAY I). MiSTK.K. K. HrcKIM .H AM. IW, H. VANCK LAMB. K. V. SMITH. Assets. loan* •22.71B.to ■ li&gt;an&gt; in |&gt;i-&lt;H - t-SN of foivt-losuiv .'!. ikki.ini ".'.'.'.'. '.'.'. '.'.. '..'.'.'.'.'. '.'.'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 24*oll.-»4 k loan. l.liHt.u. 34.011.iM Kurniture and *tationerv , 275.JIII Furniture and fttationery &gt; Tlh.tW H04.W IMH.Hti (|&gt;ient int^n'st. preminBUi sad Hnea :WHi.iHr and taxes ]&gt;aid . qiwnt interent, preminBUi sad Hnea WO.tiM - ts. n ittidrawals . ."». ) Total Liabilities tal stuck i-unniny. (lhit~&lt; and dividends/ t2N.:M4..15 Full paid stock is. :!+»;.:,•( rve fund vided proflti 1 .1MM&gt;.24 ~liare holders on incomplet&lt;' loans None liunis unearned est and pirraiums </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 RECEIPTS AND K.XI'KNDITrRKS KoK THK KIS( A I. Vf \H ENDING .1 NK SI, 1!«&gt;4. Receipts. Balance on band July I. MM i running stock! Premiums Membership and transfer fee * i-ayinir all l Advance payment Expenditures. Salarie ommission other exi&gt;en: Elhdrawals. (I 1 . tbdrswah t-arninirs took, earning 'lues Full paid stock earning • n hand Tot; Supplemental Report. Piano! !: (serial or permanent) I I'ur i S.i of- i, &gt;n (if serial) ' shares issued since or - issued during tl^. No. ol ired during Use i 1 :"iiwn durint: es of full paid stock in I No ofntaarealOMiedoo on which dues are delinquent •r nonpayment of dues Total amount of dues d Amount of dues owinir by borrow Amount of interest premium- 1 unpaid ' mortiraires subject to fi&gt;reclosure and the aittrreitate amount same So of morttfaifes in process of foreclosure and the airirreirate ;i i siimef two Amount of loans on improved real estate Appraised value of improved upon which loans have been mad Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real • Piraised value of unimproved real estate ut&gt;on which loans bare made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association So. of loans made for buildii. • during fiscal year No. of loans made for payment of home- during Ms.- Amount of advatv So. of borrowing - So of non-i No. of minors holding stock Averaire rate per cent of interest charired borrowers during li~ Averaife rate i&gt;er cent of premiums charred borrowers durin_ I'lan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund during Hsch Amount of In- •• fund durinif tis. Amount of dividends declared on runninir stock during ri^. Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock durinic H- Averaire ra'. Averaire ruti I&gt;iie&gt;. I full paid sti&gt;ok Interest Real . es of running Mook in I </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OF THK CONSERVATIVE SAVINGS AND IjOAN ASSN OMAHA. NKKRASKA &lt; hi the 30th (lav of June. IH&gt;U. Officers. Officers. F. GILMORE 1'ivsident F. GILMoKK President ( HAS. ( . GK( &gt;RGK First Vice-President ( HAS. ( . (JK&lt; )R(iK First Viee-PNwMMl .1. A. srNDKRLAND Second Vice-I'i e&gt;ident .1. A. srNDKRLAND Second Viee-President •1OHN F. FLACK Seer •1OHN F. FLACK 8«en OBO. F. GILMORF. Tre;.- OBO. F. GILMORE Truw F. OIUfORE ... F. GILMORK ... Directors. Directors U M. BAIKI). E. A. BENSON. KANDAIJ. K. BROWN, U "M. BAIKI). E. A. BENSON. KANDAIJ. K. B8OWM, ISAAC W. CARPENTER, ROBT. DEMPSTER. (HAS. C. GEORCJK. GEO. F. GILMORE. ISAAC W. CAKPKNTKK, ROBT. DEMPSTKK. JOHN F. FLACK. JOHN F. FLACK. (HAS. C. GEOKCJK. GEO. F. GILMOKE. BYRON U. HASTIN KOBINSON. J. A. SUTHERLAND. H. A. THOMPSON. GEO. F. GILMORE. J. A. SUTHERLAND BYRON R. HAST I J. C. ROBINSON. H. A. THOMPSON A. P. TUKEY. C. K. URQUHART. CHAS. M. WII.HELM A P. TUKEY. C. K. URQUHART. CHAS. M. WII.HKI.M. Assets Assets. rnortsraye loans ♦I.OTH.i ■ mortjrapp loans in prtK-ess of foreclosure .... ."&gt;. 1 . Stock loans 36. &lt; mortsrayf loans + 1 .o7 K . _ ♦I.OTH • mortjragp loans in prot-ess of forwlosuiv .... .'&gt;. 1 . SUxrk loans Stock loans :f&gt;.( Heal estate Furniturf and stationery Furniturf and stationery • ash «.(l Delinquent interest. ]&gt;reniiums and fines •_'.4:U.4I Hxpenses and taxes paid None &lt; &gt;lher assets IMinquent inteivst, ]&gt;reniiums and fines 2.434.41 ■» i Kxpenses and taxes paid Hone &lt; &gt;ther assets ral fund wan-ants (&gt;W..V OftilMtM of daposit (National Banks) lti.(MN).(Mi Keal estate sold on contract 7.H.TJ.7-"' Total »1 .1*&lt;K - Iteal estate sold on contract ~.W2. Liabilities • 'apital stock runninif. ( Dues and dividends! F74a.241.U7 Full paid stock :«»&gt;.•■ ve fund 31.641. 5« I'ndivided profits »..". -hareholders on incomplete loans 3B.4fl8.3H f't-eminms unearned Atlvance dues Advance interest and premiums Total M.I* </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 It ■-■.(• KIPTS AND KXl'KNDITl'HKS FOlt THK KIMCAI VKAH KNDING JUNE ■!". 1!*&gt;4 Receipts. U.i.unce on bund Jul.v I. I'm l.Hies. (running stock I . uil paid stock i . Interest I .nan fees, etc I'rortt and loss account Members lip and transfer fee Loans repaid. Itents from sub tenant Warrants and certificates of dei»osit Foreclosure account •s on contract a ■1 I :i .:. if.. -:. Expenditures. - ; M ■ Hills receivable Bber expenses, inc.udin* rent ithdrawals. dues and earninn ithdrawals. interest on Warrants and certificates of deposit Accrued interest and premium on above Full pa Full paid stock earnin • in band . I&amp;M &gt; 17 awii:! ■ e fund and undivided profit Tota i m m n Supplemental Report t'htu of association (serial or permanent) . ue of each share of stock i 'ernijtleM' N'o. of series issued since organization, if serial So. of shares in force a! tnis date No. of shares issued since organization . . No. of &gt;*d during fi-eal year. . Nu. of ired during fiscal year No shares withdrawn durintr fiscal year No. of shares of running stock in force at this date N'o. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date N'o. of shan No. of shares on which &lt;1 elinquent Daytonplan.no No. of share- on for nonixtyment of dues Total amom. iimuent at this date DaWouplan.no Amt&gt;unt of d . iy borrowing shareholders I&gt;ayton plan. n*» Amount of ii :niums and fines due and unpaid re rec No of ti 'lered by board of direc tors, ai ' tine twelve No of aioris ire. and the airxrevate amount of same, three Amount of loans on improved real i Eppraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made ppraised value of improvements Amount of loans uiion unimproved real estate A ppraised value of unimproved real estate u|x&gt;n which loans have been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security. No. of loans made for huildintt pun*&gt;ses during No. of loans made for puyment of home- during Hsc Amount of advance payments of loans during No. of borrowing stockholders Nit. of non-borrowintr stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the A veraire rate per cent of intei 'I borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durinif fiscal year I'ian of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durr Amount of looses charged to reserve fund ii Amount of dividends declared on runt. Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during • aire rate per cent of dividends declared dun Iteal Keal estale ftoooun Poreckwore on contract , </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 KTATKM ENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN OMAHA. NEBRASKA. &lt;hi the .With &lt;lay of June. 1!«M Officers. WILLIAM N. NASON (Deceased Pres \V. .T. C. KKNYON Vke-Pretudt-ni (i. M. NATTINGER Sect &lt;;. If. NATTINGER Trea • . W. HALLER Attorney Directors. C. KKNYON THKO. I,. KINOWAI.T ('HAS P. SOUTHARP H .1 RYNER C. K REYNOLDS M. NATTIXCK1 Assets. iuaiiN H,iaO.*»i First inoi-tatri- loans in process of foreclosure 1.4" Stock loans l,2tl Real estate 4.1'' Keal ■ il on contract l.l'J &lt; 'ash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines !Ki. 4*&gt; Kxpenses and taxes paid Other aimeti Total *14 Liabilities. rial stock running. I Dues and dividends 1 paid stock rve fund •. Undivided profits I toe share holders on incomplete loans 4.V&gt;. 4.1 Premiums unearned 14. 1 1 Advance dues Advance interest and premiums 4&lt;;i; .&gt; Total ' . ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p115">KlIl.DlNc; AM) UlAS ASSOCIATIONS. 115 RK&lt; KIPTS AND KXPKNDITrRKS FOR THK PIKTA1 VI- AH K\niN&lt;; JINK 30, 1WU. Receipts. ee on bund July I imci 'running stock) '! paid stock) Premiums Membership fee - l.oans repaid Krai estate sale NurK'ries . Tola Expenditures -a wiiK. due: ■nings Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning Property improvement and expenses Total Supplemental Report Plan or &gt;n i serial or permanent) I'ar -. So of s, organization (if serial) M So. of shar. ■ shares issued idnce organization ' shares issued rtunnt No of shares matured during nsci N-&gt; of shares withdrawn duru No of shares of running sto it this date N.» of shares of full paid stock in force at this date So of shares loaned on N»» of shares on which dues are delinquent So of shares subject to can &gt;r nonpayment of dues Total amount of dues is date Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareh" iiu of interest premiums and tines due and unpaid So of mortiraires subject to foreclosure and the airtrreirate amount of same, one S.i of mortiraicesin process of foreclosure, and the aitirreirate amount of same, one V mount of loans on improved real - vppraised value of real estate upon which loitn-s hare been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans ui&gt;on unimproved real e Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whb Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Ass&lt;m - security -- ■ ■ • No of loans made for buildinir purposes during fiscal year No of loans made for i /aires durinir ris. i Amount of advance payment of loans during ' No. of borrtiwin^ stfwkholders NO of non-borrowinir stiK'kholflers No of minors holding stock in the Average rate percent of interest charged borrow. - anilnrt-iM Average rate per cent of premiun. ltan of Premium Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal Viuount of losses charged to reserve fund during ns&lt;- Amount of diyiden I on running stock during rU- \mount of dividends declared on fun paid stock durin. A verage ru of dividends declared during dscn Average running • \ stock, due*. &lt;&lt;• &lt;l ■.took, earning &lt; BKb on haml </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 ' STATEMENT (IF THK CONDITION 1 &gt;K THK NKBRASKA U&gt;AN AND BlILDINc; ASSN. OMAHA. NKMKASKA. * Mi the .'^Uli da\ t » f .lun*' I'*o4. Officers. THO8. A. KKY I'iv~ MAJ. R. S. WIUOX Vice-pr- - \l A.r. R. s. Wll&gt; ox Vke-pi¥« D. H. CHRIST! K Seci D. H. ( HR1STI K Sen. D. R. KNNIS Treasiir. i D. R. KNNIS ...Tit-i!- JOHN L. KKNNKDY \tt( JOHN L. KKNNKDY \ttorn. &gt; Directors. Directors. tv A KifY wouxrrr !V HAJ. R. S Wll. l&gt;.U"IliiMI.K MAJ. R. S WU.i ox JOHN K. BHANIxr H. VANCE LANK. DAVID r&gt; R. EN JOHN It. BHANIxr IHis F. GODFREY tOUXtn. H. VANCK LANK ('HAS. K TUHNKI &gt;H AS H TURNED Assets. Assets. inortjra^re loan&gt; *1(|."i.."iL'7."hi First niortjrajfe loans in process of forerkMure • mortjrajfe loans in process of forecltMare k loans +.1" vte li.n- R«-a) estate K.1M Kurnitui"*' and stationery &gt;ijuent inteivst. pivmiums and fines 1.4: nses and taxes paid 4lHi.."&gt;!i Knrnituiv and stationerv ijuvnt intfivst. pivmiums and fines 1.432.K1 &lt; nher assets due r&gt;n i-ontracts and real estate ... '.i.~»~ Total 9125.011 Liabilities. &lt; a pi t;i I stock running. Dues and dividends i Illl.OWT.tfl Full paid stock ive fund t, 544.1' 1'ndivided profits shareholders on incomplete loans, paid on contracts and loans l».541.7&lt; mnis unearned Advance dues and interest, consolidated paymentM 1.171. VI ince interest and ]&gt;remiutns Total .. • --..oil. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 KNDING JUNE My UMH. Receipts running stock ' i full paid ~tiK'ki oekhoMen vship and transfer Expenditures 1en earnir hand. . Advance pavm c;i Supplemental Report N.i ..- No. of - of full paid -.tock in force at Chin date No. of shares loaned oi A mom Amount of S,, ,,f m orl ;ind the airitreirate amouri ■ .-.■- durii &gt;f premiums eh;i mium ve fund during (1 Amount Amount of di Amount of divm.M 't- •:) Averatte rate V \ eraife rui .nd sundrv ee payment* So. nf »harr- No. of hI nent of due \o &lt;if mortiriiue^ to i&gt;roce« of foreclosure, and the .imitant of Kanie No. of i </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 STATEM ENT OK THK COXMTION OK THF « OCCIDENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN o.MAHA. NEBRASKA. &lt;hi the :\&gt;nh dav of Tun.-. 1!HU. Officers. 1OHN F. FLACK 1'iv- F. (ilLMORK Yice-IVesid.nt F. (ilLMORK Sec. I. A. srNDERLAM) F. (;II,MORK Directors. JOHN K. KI.ACK. F. (JII.MOKK. .1. A. SUNUKKJ K. A. UrKACHBON. A. P. TUKEY. IVlVKI.I.. Assets. ii&gt; . |3ti EKHtgagc loans [nprocma of loans -old on contract uent interest, premiums and tine - ies and taxes paid •at&lt;'s of depoult Total TT..'i toreeloiiun .!, l't'.i.j K&gt;,OllO.iii - B.311.+ stock loans .!. lit'.i. 2AMA li.i Delinquent interest, prvrniunis and tine^ iin^-. and taxes jiaid « Vrtiticat&lt; j s of dciMoit .(."&gt;. inki.i mi Total TT. *."&gt;( • ; . : V 1 1 . 4 1 UaMlltles. Liabiltties. 1 stock running. I Din- and dividends Full paid sUK"k 175,1 ■■i-ve fund 1!».."i»m,. I'ndivided proCtfl 1.581. 1 4 -hait- holders on incomplete loan I 'renmims Advance dues nice interest and premium* - &gt;.:!11.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">KNDING .Tl'NK 30. litiM Receipts. i»n h.inil J - innintr 'uU paid Premiums I.. i. hi and ' Warrants and certificate** »»f dev&gt; ln-urar ' Expenditures '•mniissior her expe Withdraw.. ■losur &gt;n hand Tot a Supplemental Report X.i of n N . . • shares is- Vmoui Ke. and the uirirreiiate amount of Rof loan^. on impri • &lt;i value of innmiv ed real ev tA value of ii n whieh loans have heen made MUM \ mount of loans on unimproved re;&gt; \|.praised value of uniiniiroved n 'l«&gt;n which loans hare been made \ in.iiiiit of insurance in force and . lateral • So of loam made n« of horn. - rturin* rtscal year X.i. of borrowing - HO. of : 1 1 year Vveraite rate iiereent of dividends declared durinir Itvul \ '•■ir Toopakl &lt;K&lt; KI1TS AND EXPENDITURES K&lt; )I&lt; THK KIS( Al. VKAR ElidrawuN. eani n.- cleimsit ■re&gt;t on warrant* and certificate I'iir value of eae! N.i. ,.- ired durnu So. of share&gt; withdrawn dur id not taken N'ci n! il stock in force at this date N&lt;». of ' rtue- todtheitKL ■ :■ . No of loan* made for buildinit pur|w&gt;M&gt;~ durinir Bacti ulyanee payment \D1OUI mount of dividers II paid »t&lt;&gt;-- ... hI M III * ■ ■ Mu .l^..l.,ruil rl l : </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 Brn.iMM; and loan associations. STATEM ENT HTIc IN i &gt;y THf OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSX. OMAHA. NEBRASKA. on (be :unh day &lt;&gt;f June. I!*&gt;4. OMAHA. XKHKASKA Officers. IV. UXtMIS IV. s KLMKR K. HKVSON Vio-I'r. - M. NATTINiiKR.. LEWIS S. RKKI) FRANK H. GAIN1 - .Attorn x Directors - WHICH! H. J. PEXFnM). THi&gt;S. J. FTTZMORH ■ KIi A. FAH.MKI.KK. .IOHX H. BfTI.KK. W. SCOTT KIN( W. LOOM ELMER E. BKYSOX. UBO. M. WATTI1 KI.MKK E. BHYSHS". ■ M. X ATTI \i . I I- Assets. 7»h;.k ins in process of foreclonun (i._ 24.114. T.i . Kurnitm-f and ■tetionerj ijuent interest. premiunnH and fint-&gt;. .»' Kxjiense-i and taxes paid l.&gt;: 1'otal Liabilities. tal stock runninu. (Does and "dividends *T:&gt;_ Full paid stot-k . . vc fund . 17. -I fund nn incomplete Io;n - K).42». - unearned </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 A I H K' K M ' I*S A N 0 KX1 t.Mm 1 I i\ r.N M'K I M r FINDING JTNE 30, l«M. Receipt - Receipt- ■•• on band oekl ick) g|_| ProiuiaiiM ~liil&gt; and ti •I Memliershii' un&lt; .•paid Expenditures Expenditures. other • ■ n hand Furniture and ttxtu nsures ture and tixiure- ■losure- Tntal Supplemental Report. Supplemental Report &gt; » Amount of inter ire. and the airirret' ile amonn vmount of loan* on improved rr A™,'! "f unimproved \rnount of insurance in • Amount of i»mn»&lt;&gt;e in fo, ■ i i' ■ ■ i ile for liuildin^ pi Hi I Ho. of nun.. &gt;&gt;f minor&gt; holdin \ vei Plan of premium Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinir n- Amount . Amount of d </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 BUHJMNCJ AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT cpk rn ooMnrnoM or nus HE CONDITION OF THK PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND Bl'lLDINi; ASSN PAWNEE CITY SAVINGS AND BUILDING ASSN. PAWNEE CITY, EfEBRAHKA. On the :tntli day &lt;«f June. 1'.k&gt;4. PAWNEK CITY. NKBRASKA. On tin- Mnh day of June. l'.*&gt;4 Officers. Officers. I W. BILLAKI) IV. - \\ . BILLAKI) l'iv- \V. M. HILLFH Vice-Pivs \ M. HELUEB Vlcp-Prwiideol R. W. STORY Sec . W. STORY Sect ■• Mc.MASTKH Trww McMASTKR Tn-i Directors. Directors. BUI.l.AKIl. W. M. HI1.LKK. &gt;H\ . I. W. BULI.AKH. M'MASTKH. I. r. CKIFFITH. W. M. HII.L.KK. STOKY M'MASTKK. C. H. KILLKK. K. W. BTOKY. C. II. Fl'Lt.KK. K. VV. STOKY. r. CKIFFITH. ';. K. BKlKKK. &lt; &gt;1l&lt; • vacillir E. KK.KKK. inn' vai'iiiu'\ Assets. loau* - KW.WI are loans in process of foreclomin are loans in (H-iK'ess of foreclomire. . Stock loans -M».&lt;mi R&lt;-al estate Furniture and stationery. . None Furniture and stationery. None «.» IMinquent interest, premiums anil tines ... 81.24 delinquent interest, premiums and tines ... 81.24 Kxpenses and taxes paid . - and taxes paid . None &lt; &gt;th«'! Total Liabilities. Liabilities. &lt; upital stock running. I I &gt;nt •— and dividends] Full paid stock &lt; upital stock running. I Dim and dividends i. ... Full paid stock rve fund 190.011 rve fund lito.im Individed Profits 142.22 Individed Profits 142.2L' Due share holders on incomplete loans +."&gt;(&gt;. &lt;*• I Vemiums unearned None Advance dn.-« ... 1.256.0(1 md premi ■ i on advance (hie* iflO.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">BUILDING AND I,(&gt;AN \ IONS \l Receipt! hand July i runnn • i full paid ■ aemtirrsiKii anc insurance premium rer TOU Expenditures Withdraw.. 2 MtttUD • Matun ■ M-k. dm took, ea m hitna Supplemental Report. l'«-nnaner n (if sen i. . withdrawn durin •sof runnit it tbixdate es of full paid stork in force al th .miiunt of dividends declared on fu veraire rate i&gt;er c&gt; , RWKIPTS AND KXPHNDITTRKN K&lt; &gt;R THK F!S KNnim; JUNE :w. ii«»4 iinrc** inkucu dunni? fix* at ured durii - loaned on - riftr*"* on 9 I'otal amount of cl e amount s; !&gt;■ iites in i&gt;roc re mid the uKirretrute ami. of flame i us on improve*) ■«• of imprc ih&gt;ii whioh loans have been i ins on unmii&gt;n&gt;ved ren ■d value of unimprovt'i -urance in force and a- So of iion-horrowi' so of minors bolriii A ver»K i \veniK f ' ers during I </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 BUIlaOINCi AND STATKM KNT &lt;&gt;K THE ciiNKITKiN i &gt;K THE LTVTNGOTON LOAN AND BUILDING AS8N PLATTSMOCTH, NEBRASKA. On the 3001 ilav of June. 1!K&gt;4. . Officers. Officers 1). B. SMITH IV. - 1). B. SMITH . ...1 '!«-. MARSHALL . . . Yice-I 'resident IYR.GERINO.. Beeratar) MARSHALL... Viee-Presideni KUINt;. KKKD W. EBINGER KKKD W. EBINGER MAS WALLINC THOMAS WALLING Directors. Directors l&gt;. B. SMITH. MAKSHAM.. FRED W. KHINl.KK. l&gt;. B. SMITH. MAKSHAL!.. KKKI) W. KHIXl.EK. SKY BBOCA HM. A. WHI WM. HOIJ&gt;V. HKKOI-I). \VM. A. WHITE, WM. HOI I.V WM. HASSI.KK. H. M. SOEXNIt ' HSKN :. HEXRV R. OKBLH HASSI.KK. IIKXRV K ■'.KIN Assets. Assets. loanK • loan?* in process of foreclosure None e Iomm in process of foreclosure None Real Non.- Real estate None Furniture and stationary . ujuent interest, premiums, tines and dues . . taxes paid . Furniture and -^tationai'v . iquent interest, premiums, tines and dues 7:&gt;4."'&gt; - paid 874.81' K74.80 :■•■ contracts .!T,4: s.:t:&gt;7.4:'. ranee and taxes paid and advanced 1.141.71 Insurance and taxes paid and advanced. . . 1.141.71 Total Total IK5.455.1 Liabilities Liabilities Kital stock running. ( Dues and dividends - +-"&gt;1. paid stock . . erve fund B74.W ■ ;il stock running- ( Dues and dividends - +-"&gt;1 Full paid stock . . rve fund I'ndivided profits 13,220. !•"&gt; -hare holders on incomplete loans. lums unearned ince dues Nuin anoe interest and premium* None </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 RK&lt; KIITS AND KXPKNDITl'KKS KoRTHK KIS( ENDING JUNK »l. l'»&gt;4 Receipts. running stix-ki nil paid Premiums 1&gt; ami transfer f« '-"a"- repa"! Real e Tacts Delim men! dues an M m «• • Expenditures. :rawals. di Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, (i Matured stock, earninn lid stock, il ud stock, earnint Supplemental Report lanent) Par value • irii/atit»n (if serial* shares issued sinrc ■&gt;' . ' shares issued during fiscal - withdrawn during tlscal \ ear - &lt;&gt;f running stock in force at this date - of full paid stm'k in force at this date i«Mi on ■ -hares on which dues are delinquent **nt of dufN 3 amount of dues deliniiuent .. Amount of dues owin_- nt of interest premiums and tines due and unpaid No of mortifas^es sutijeot to foreclosure, and the a»rirreifitt&lt;- amount i&gt;f \o of mortgage* in pr«K'es^of fore&lt;*losure. and the atrirrejrate amount «»f Amount of loans on improved real ■ \ppraised value of improved real estate on which loans have heen m.i.l. Apprmised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate ~fd value of unimproved Teal estate upon which loans have Ix-en made I of insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security oans made for building pun&gt;oses during fiscal year N'o of loans made for payment of homestead mortiraires during tls. Amount of a&lt; - of loans durintr fiscal year, average per m'th No of borrowing - non-tM»rrowinkr sti»ckholder^ No. of minors holding stock Average rate per cent of ir ■ borrowers during Averaire rate per cent of premiums charired born&gt;wers durinir fiscal year Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinic fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund durinx One Amount of dividends declared on running stock durinir Hscalyear nt of dividends declared on full i inrin*f ttsA'.t Average rate per cent of &lt;i durinir fiscal A veraire ninninjr time of sto&lt;*k mature*! durir No. of &gt;hare*» matured durin^ ia&gt;.l«K.i&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 biiumnc; and i,oan associations. STATEMENT (&gt;K THK CONDITION &lt; &gt;F THK PLATTSMOUTH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN PLATTSMOITH. NKBRASKA. (hi the ."Kith dav of June. 1!H»4. Officers \V. J. WHITK Ptvsident W. SMITH Vke-Preuideni 1' M. PATTERSON BecraUr) PATTKRS&lt; )N Treasure U. B. WINDHAM Attorne) Directors BOFFKKKS AMI BARWICK. D. HA WKSWOKTH. W'M. BALLAMCE CHA8. KYDBKWi. J. H. HAI.USTKO J. H. HAI.I-STKOM. Assets mort|f&amp;Sfe loans I35.ttl2.7t5 mortfraire loans in process of foreclosure Stock loans !.:'&gt;' Ueal estate "-'. Hr2.'A Furniture and stationery Non»- 2.(NK&gt;.41 njuent interest, premiums and fines uses and taxes paid ~.T' 418.2K Total l6O.2!8.a» Liabilities • &gt;i-k running. Dues and dividentl- Full paid stwk None rve fund None 1'ndivided ))rofits 15.332.211 &gt;hare holders on incomplete loans None 1 'ivniiums unearned None Advance dues None Advance interest and premiums Non»- </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 KKi'KIITS AND KXPKNDITrRKS K( &gt;K THK KIS( AL Yr AR ENDING JINK *'. I!m4 Receipts. Halance on band July I Mi Dues, (running stooki Dues, (full paid stock) Imerr- Premiums Embersbip and transfer fe« ins repaid Expenditures. l.,an Salute ■ommission: Other expenses. Withdrawals dm Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dm Matured stock, earninir- Full paid stock (1 ■■•k earninir Keal i Total Supplemental Report. Plan of asw inent) Par v .rnzation (if serial). No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares issued since organization. So. of shares issued during Hs. No. of shares matured durin. ires withdrawn during No. of chares of runnin it this date No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No. of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent »&gt; No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues. Total amount of dues delinquent at this date « Amount of dues owinir by borrowing shareholders. Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid. f. of mortifajfes subject to foreclosure, and the airirrejrate amount of same, six . of mortifatres in process of foreclosure, and the axirrerate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate ~~ Appraised vane of improved real estate upon which loans have been mad Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate A ppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hm - made hount of insurance in force and assiiraed to the Association a - securit* No. of loans made for buildintc pur)&gt;oses durinit fiscal rear No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortjrajfes during fiscal year Amount of advance payments of loans durini; No. of borrowing stockholders Z No. of non-horrowinir stock)] So. of minors holding su»ek in the • A veraire rate |&gt;er cent of interest charired borrowers durinc fiscal year A veraue rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers during Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinir fiscal year Amount of losses charired to real estate fund during Ducal year Pount of dividends declared on run lurinif fiscal year ount of dividends declared on ful year Average rate per cent of dividends declared duritn A veratre running time of sti&gt;ck matured duri' PI estate sale*. •- rest on &lt;le\x&gt;sit es collected Total </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 Bi:iUMN«; AM) I.DAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK SCHUYLER BUILDING AND U)AN ASSN. S&lt; Ht'YLF.K. NKKRASKA On tl\.- :;&lt;itli da\ of June. 1!H&gt;4 Officers. II. L. WKAVKH I'.-. - I. A. PKNCK Vice-Pn- FRANK K. M(X)RK Hem .!&lt; )HN .1. GAKTH 'lie;, &lt; . .T. PHKLPS Att. Directors. M. L. WKAVKK. .1. A. PSKCE. AKTHTK V AX H« ■: KKANK E. MOORK. V. MAI.Y. John j. i.;akth S. X. WHI'IR. IOHN"SON. K. H. PHKU'S Assets. First niort£ai;f loans ' mortgage loans in procna of forwlosurt' Stock loans. Keal estate 4. 1 Furniture and stationery fash '. 2." (ash. Delinquent interest, premiums and tines Kxpenses and taxes paid &lt; 't her assets Kills receivable l.wm.tm Tax sale certiticati ■- Total : Liabilities &lt; apital stock running. ( Dues and dividend- I32,1WI. Full paid stock rve fund e fund I'ndivided profits. Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues . .( In ••( iipital sUn-k running Advance totocval and pivmiums .... . ... 11. -•"&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KoRTHKKISi A I \ r Alt ENDING JUNE 30. \*H Receipts. hand July I u«i:t Ihies (running stocUl Ihies (full i .aid stock) IntereM l*remiums Fines . Membership and transfer fees Loan* repaid... Koreclosure T.ix ~ule certificate ■|'&lt;il:i Expenditures. .ok dues aid stock, earnini. .11 hand Heul ' ve . . . Tot Supplemental Report ■i (serial or permanent i if each share nf stock Nil of series issued since organization (if seriali Mo. ii" Mo. of shares iapucd sin«-«* or^an; iiini'.int of dues rielitl'i \ii. of mortirutfes in pr&lt;H*ess of foreclosure, and the atrtrreirate .itnouni &lt;&gt;f Amount of kNun • ,se&amp; value of impnived real estate i»n which loan?* hare been made iised Talue of improvement* Amount of iasurance in force and assiirned to the association as collatera I security No. of loans made for huildinir tmrpose* duriny tLs**.. No. of loans made &gt;l \ear No of non-Nirrowinx - No. of minors holding si A venire rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durinir tl~. Average rate per cent of premiums charired borrowers durin.- l»lan of premium Amount credited ''.md durint \mouni t- fund durinir tts. Amount of dr ired on running stock dun' Amount of dividends declared on fi. K durinir n~ Averaire rate ikt ■ ared duiin^ Suspens) &lt; ommissii »ns « &gt;ther expen-' VVithdruwuls. dut*** ■d during i ea matured durr bdrmvn du e fs on w hit* h dues are (!■ K ect tt&gt; cancellu u»a&gt; ment &lt;»f dues ;&gt;■ Amount of dues owtn* b&gt; borrow Amount of b minus and ind unpaid No. of mortv rid the ittrtrretfut same, five Amourr eon unimproved real estate ' unimproved real estate u)»m which limns hare hern made ■Amount of adyai So. r&gt;f borrowing ' </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 Hl'II.DINCi AND LOAN ASSOCIATI' STATEMENT Or THK fONDITION OK THE SEWARD EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. SKWARD. NKBRASKA. «)n the SMh day of . Inn.-. l«»t&gt;4. Officers. JOHN Z1MMKRKR Pres G. F. DICKMAN Vice-Pr. - H. A. GRAFF... Sen V. K. LANG WORTHY Tre;i I. TH&lt; iMAS . \- J. .1. TH&lt; ).MAS . , Directors. Directors t. F. GEES! t'. K. HIMPHREY, . \V. (iOKHNKK. JOHN AMSLEH, . F. GKEs C K. HTMF'HKEY, V. H. FUANKLIN. i tl II KUAN KLIN. . \V. COKHNKR. JOHN AMSI.EU, G. H. TKRWILLK THOMAS GRAHAM. t TEKWILLJGEK, THOMAS GRAHAM. Assets. Assets Kirist niortg-aK*' loans $T»:{. : •'ir&gt;st mortjraii-e loans $T»:{.: First mortpajre loans in process of foreclosure 'irst mortpajre loans in process of foreclosure Stovk loans :',.i« JUH'k loans :&gt;.('&lt; Keal estate Leal estat*- Furniture and Stationery ■"urniture and Stationery ' t ash Delinquent dues and interest )elinquent dues and interest Cxpt taxes yaid &gt;ther a&gt;- -:ile certificates Insurance 1:{.."&gt;ii Total fc*. Liabilities Capital stock i-unninp. -id dividends) Full paid stock f und 71O.H3 Tndivided profits .14 holders on incomplete loans N&lt; ■• Premiums unearned Advanc&lt; Advance interest and premiums HT&gt;. ~~ Trea - i wn 1 i 'Idl </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 HKCKIFTS AND KXPKNDITTRKS Foli THK AL Receipts. ee on hand July I. 1908 {running stock) Ml paid stork l*reniiums Membership and transfer fe - repaid Real estate sale Ken.- rurer overdrawn Total. Expenditures. % Supplemental Report. No of -.■■.■- issued since organization (if seriali ~ date a lion - issued durimr tiseal year lurinir flsca Mo of shares withdraw! Kof shares of runnii this date of shares of full paid stork in farm at this date ' -hares loaned on No of shares on which dues are delinquent iwyment of dues Total amount of uent at thi- Amount of dues owinir hy borrovi Amount of interest premiums and tines due and unpaid No of mortifaires subject to foreclosure and the atcitretrate amount i two No. of morttra&gt;res in process of foreclosure, and the aiurreirate amount of sanif Amount of loans on improved real estate -t-d value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made . -ed value of imp A mow ate Appraised value of unimproved real ■ upon which loans ha\ • made [it of insurance in force and assigned to the association h ■ seourity loans made for building purposes durin: - made for payment of horn. Amount of advance payments of loans during No of bi&gt;rrowinir stockholder- mortifatfes durit;. • non-borrowing stockli No of minors holding stock in ihe Aswt" ■ ige rate per cent of interest chanred borrower during ttsoal year Average rate per cent of premiums chanred ln&gt;rrowers during tls«al year Plan of premium Weekh Amount credited to reserve fund durii Amount of lo***e* charged to reserve fu Amount of teclared on runn Amount of dividend^, declared on full p i re rate i&gt;er ■ p v&lt;l durin x KNDIN&lt;; .Tl'NK 30, 1&lt;*4. Tux vile certificate In»uran.-&gt;- earning n hand ertificates Total I'Uin o' ixrmanent) </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 STATEM KNT OK THK CONDITION OF THK SIDNEY LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. SIDNEY. NEBRASKA. On the *nh day of June. l!n&gt;4. Officers. Officers. A. GRAKNEMAN President A. GRAXNEMAN Pmkfcnt If. RADl UFF Vict-1 'resident If. RAJX LIFF Vire-Prenident &lt; HAS. (ALLAH AN Seeretari "HAS. (ALLAH AN SeerwUri A. PEASE Trcismvi A. PEASE. . . TrpMMrpr Directors. Directors L. JASSKN'. C M WfOGHT, F. B, TOBIN. L. JASKEN. C. M. WKMiHT, F. B. TOBIN. M .1. BAHDBBK, C. P. CHAMBERS. M. .1. SANDERS, C. P. I'HAMBKKK. Assets. Assets uiortsra^re loans ♦X.W.'i..!! inortsrajje loans in pruoma of foreclosure k loan;. tMHi.iHi Real Kstate. . Real Estate. Furniture and stationery Kurnitur»&gt; and stationerv '.....-. ss:.:4 ..-. Delinquent inUMvst. pmnioOH and fines :5»i.."&gt;&lt;&gt; uses and taxes paid tM.iio uses and taxes paid tM.iio Total. HO.22»..Vi Liabilities • n-k itinnin&gt;r. d dividends) I8,fll3.2tl Kpmid stock ■ve fund l+:(.(i^ •■ fund fndivided profits I'M."). ill share bolder* on incomplete loans ;iuro* unearned I.128.1C! Pivmiuras unearne&lt;l mce dues ince interest and premiums • lied stock Tote) </seg>
            <seg id="p133">Bl'Il.DING AND L.OA" 133 RKCKIr'TS \NI&gt; KXPKNDITl'RKS KOK THK KIS( \l. ENDING JINK :KI. 1«&lt;4 Receipts. H.iian.-e on hand .lull 1 r&gt;o running stock' i full paid Hi and transfer fee Total Expenditures Withdrawals, due - nif - ■••k. earnintr* ies . nd stock, eurnintr ■ n hand Total Supplemental Report rial or permanent) No of shaf ' share* twined since organization - issued durintr Bscal year shares matured durinif lacu ires withdrawn durinif nsc:i es of runnii force at this date ill iwiid stock in force at tri ' &gt;hares loaned on on which ri ' shares s U &gt;. UnouDt of inter- ran »ncl ftne^ due and unpaid ■ of mortifaf ire :indthe awretrate amount of same une . No of morwaires in procewM of foreclosure and the ayirreKate amount of same Amount of loatis&lt; -I'd value &lt;i! upon which loans have been made Appraised value of inn \m. .unt of loans ui&gt;on unimproved real estate ■&lt;1 value of unimproved real estate u|mmi which loans have been made ■ount of insurance in force and assigned to tl iteral So of loans made for huildinir purposes dui-intr bei No. of loans made for \&lt;*\ m&gt;- Amount of advar So of borrowing No of noo-borrou « No. of minors holding stock in tb&lt;- I ■r .-ent of interest chanted borrow t Average rate per cent of premiums charged borrowers durin- i'lan of premium ■ \ mount credited 'und durint Amount Amount of divideti' on running ml of dividends declared on full paid stock dunn. A veraire ra r • ireddurin. •k matured durin ilue of eac Amount of dues owinif by b&lt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 BfH.1)IN&lt;; AND LOA.V IATIONS. STATEMENT UK CONDITION UK THK SOUTH OMAHA LOAN AND Ml'ILDIXCi ASSN. SOITH OMAHA. NKURANKA. Ob the :t»»th day of .lunt- Utm. Officers. PATRICK J. SHKKHY f'resici. i.r •JOHN HKNRY U&gt;K( HNF.R Vtee-prcsidrat T. KITZCKRAIJ) ... Sevretrai H. C. MILI-KR.... Trea A. H. Ml'HIKK-K Att. Directors. C. A. MEU'HEK MEIjCHKK. \V. P. ADKINS. K. C. WALKER. \V. P. ADKINS. JOHN HENRY I.()HX'HNKH. P. MRCHBLL, F. M. SMITH. KN HKNKY LOBCHKER, P. MITCHELL, . O'HRKN. V. 1. SHKKHY J. K. O'HKKN. V. 1. SHKKHV. K. 1.. HOWK. P. .1. SHKKHY. Assets. Assets. First niortjratrt- loans IWll.4flH.tt4 First IIHlgBgH loans tiiHI. ; ■ mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Kt mortpajfc loans in process of foreclosure k loans '2.'.- Stock loans '.'. '. - Real estate on contrai-i l.s_ Rra\ estate on i-ontrari l. v - Furnituif and stationers T.Vi"' Furniture and stationery • ash :'..■:■ Dflinquent interest, premiums and tines 24H.5K nses and taxes paid ;ind taxes paid &lt; HJhtr fc— tUm Total. *K»h."' Total tlOH.7n2.sL.' UaMHtics. Liabilities ' apital &gt;t&lt;u'k mnnin«r. (Daen and (iividei n • ' Capital stock mnnin«r. I)iu*s and dividei n • • Pull paid stock.. »,«l rve fund 2.7O0.IMI Full paid stock . '.I.Whi.mi &gt;-ve fund 2."(*i.&lt;«' 1'ndivided profits "2!i7.44 1'ndivided profits '!'■&gt;', 4t Due shareholders on incomplete loans. Due shareholders on ineOBtplete loans Premiums unearned Premiums unearned &gt; . . . md iiivmiums ... ■»:(.!&gt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 RKCKIlTs AM) EXPENDITURES KOK THK KIS&lt; A I, "&gt; KAK RNDING JUNE 30, 1!N4 Receipts. ■e on hand July I. lull Hues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid Mock Interest Premiums Membership and transfer feex l..i.ins repnid Keal estate Kents borrowed Tot» Expenditures. Withdrawals, dues \\ nhdrawaN earninifs Matured stock. &lt;1 . • on contra Total Supplemental Report elation iserial or iwnnineotl .ion &lt;if serial). No. of So. o( issued during fl- 2 No. of shart 'Jurintf ttsc i ares withdrawn during E- of running stock in f" So. of shares loaned on i m which due* are delinquent So. ol &gt;r nonpayment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date "Si Amount of dues owinit by borrowing shareholders. Amount of interest premiums and tines due and unpaid No. of mortiraire-* re. and the aiorreirate amount of same r. of morticaxes in process of foreclosure, and the atrirrexate same . Amount of loans on improved real - Appraised value of im|&gt;i q&gt;on which lour i made Appraised value ■ Amour. Pd real estate u|M&gt;n which loans hav&gt; - made Amount of insurance in force and a-~ , . e.Associu lilaterijl security. N.i. of loans made for liuildinif purp&lt;i*es dunn^ No. of loans made for' payment of humr- lurinif rtsc;. . Averaire A verajre rat' I'lan of premium Amount credited to reserve fund durinir Hsim Amount of losses &lt; fund durinit fiscal \ear Amount '&gt;n running stock during tlsi Amount of dividers on full paid sti&gt;ck durin/ tt* \ veraif e ra i ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 STATEMENT Oh' IKK CONDITION OK THK CITIZENS BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVING8 ASSN. KI'PKKIOU. NKBRASKA. KIl'KKIOR. NKBR.YSKA. &lt;&gt;n the :&amp;&gt;tli day &lt;&gt;( June. Hhi4. Officers. Officers. W. S. V&lt;)( N(, President VOCNG Pivsident W. P. LOW Vh-h-Piv~ W. P. \A'\ VU-e-lYi- r. H. 8TTBB8 Seen K. H. STlBBs Seen \V. A. M V KRs Treasur. . W. A. MVKRs ...Trea F. H. RTTBRfl r. HL 8TTBBS Attorn. &gt; Directors. Directors. ri. SOUTHAKI). .1. BLLJOTT, BOOTHABD, 4. M. SILVKK. a. B. MOMHiffftf I . A. B. MAKSHAM.. W. .1. BLLJOTT, J H. KKSTKltNON. Assets. Assets. *2-i.4&lt;ni.i mi ■ mortjrafre 1(ihh&gt; in procens of foi-ec-losinv imirtirajj*" loans in process of foreclosure .'HMI.ini 500.(10 Keal estau- Furniture and stationerv (liient int&lt;&gt;i-»'st. premifunx and tinc&gt; and taxes paid . None "■ts Furniture and stationery 1.834. 1U ((iient interest, premiumn and tinc&gt; and taxt's |iaid . ■-ts Now Total K1.734.1!! UaMlltles. Liabilities. • apita! stock ninnin«r. i Dm-, and dividends* I1C.241.34 Full paid Block . . ».» rve fund .Vn.v". 1'ndivided proSta shareholders on incomplete loans Premium* unearned l.o.V..i»&gt; Advance dues inoe interest and premium- Total </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 KK&lt; KMTS AND KXPKNDITrHKS FOR THK KIS( A I. VK AK ENDING JUNE MK 1!n»4 Receipts. ••e on bund Jul&gt; I. IMC ninninir stock* Kill! paid stuck Membership anil transfer fees l»ans reimid • ink-* Total Tola - Expenditures. Expenditures Salaries ssioTlN : II - ■ Supplemental Report. Supplemental Report. .il or permanent ' . .il or permanent ' . non (if serial! Par vu! on (if serial) - issued dur 5* withdrawn during Bieu es of rnnnii it this date es of rnnni e at Hi- date km &gt;ied on . b dues are dellmiueni which due« are delinquent. 'it of inter** iik\ unpuid f mortKattes subject to foreclosure, and the airirreirate amour f mortKatre-. Nubjeot to forerlosure. and the aitirretrate ■'■ TtKaites in process ( &gt;f foreclosure, and the avirreirate an: m improve value of improved real estate upon which loans have heen made mortiraifes in process of foreclosure, and the aKirreirate anioiim m improve* Apppraised value of impnn • . &gt;n which loans have been n Amount of loans upon unini; alue of uninipr*»^ i**urunee in for&lt; - »«Mrit.» ■ turinir nv^ - made for t ear Amount of udva- • ■ per cent . Avermire rate per cent of pi Plan of premium Amount credited to reserve f uml ilunin.- fcteul ■ charged t ■ i of dividt" Amount of divide' Aver»ire rate per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT UK CONDITION UK THK TEA IWISEH BUILDING AND Ii)AN ASSN. TW IMSKH. NEBRASKA. (hi (he :K&gt;th dav of June. l'MU. Officers. P. A. BKCNDACK Pres A. O. SHAW Vice-Pres t &gt;K ANDERS* )N Sen KRKD E. BOD1K Treasurer .1. B. DOUGLAH \tt. Directors. P. A. BKUNDAUE, JOHN R. PIERSON, ROSCOE ANDERSON A. O. SHAW. C. .1. CONON. I.. M. DAVIS. P. H. HOPKINS. c a. woods, HARRY PHKL.P8. Assets. .. * ' loUIlS 'rfl.OO Kirst mortfratre loans in process of foreclosure Now •'irst mortfrayv loans in proeesn of foreclosure Xmu ook loans None eal estate None Stock loans Nun.- U*-al estate None Furniture and stationary 1 l^.!t&lt;» "urniture and stationary 1 l^.!t&lt;» ash ." H33.12 i a&gt;h Delinquent interest, premiums and tines .17 elinquent interest, premiums and tines .17 Kxpenses and taxes paid In*. 10 •^xpenses and taxes paid In*. 10 t Hher asset- Hher asset- Total t2.0O4.2U Liabilities Capital stock running. ( Dues and dividends) ll.525.5l* Full paid stock None rve fund None fndivided profits None &gt;hare holders on incomplete loans None 1 'remiums None Advance dues Advance interest and premiums None mce fees, interest, premiums and fines 17!'.7!» Total K IHM.2M </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 RK&lt; KI1TS AND KXPKNDITl'RKS K()K THK KIS» \I. VI- KND1NG .U"NK :M&gt;. liNM. Receipts on band July 1. 1WE •lc&gt;. |i and transfer fe* ( 1 a Tc Expenditures t 'om mission* irsiwiiN duea Withdi Matured stock, ri Mm in .trnintr i!&lt;1 Nt»M*k. dues aid stock, earning -n hand To! Supplemental Report Plan of association (serial or i»ermanentl Pur value No of -■ on. (if serial' * aharea lamed Mm'e urbanization iiirinir Bscal awn during ill paid paid stock in force at thi- date es ioaned on -:iares on which dues are delinquent ■i**nt of dues amount of Amount of due&gt; owiii. Amount of interest, premium*, an .mil unpaid ■ of mortiraires subject to foreclosure, and the airmreirate amount of same '■ mortifaires in process of foreclosure, and the airweirate amount same Amount of loans on improved -cd value of improved upon which loans have been made Appraised value of improve: Amount of loans ui&gt;on unimp -ed value of unimproved re i&gt;on which loans hu\ ■ made ' of insurance in force and assigned to the Association made for ouildintr pun»&gt;ses during ttsr. ii of homestead mortiraites durir Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No. of borro' 'i the kmov i ers durinic ftsca Avem. of premiun ■orrowers durin. \m&lt;nn lerre fund durintr Hsc;. Amount of losses cbmrved e fund duriutr ti^. Amount .ired on running st«H'k durir Amount ... : fttockdurii aredduritit i en "iinninit ■"'" </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 BUILDING AND LOAN STATEMENT Or THK CONDITION OK THK TRENTON IjOAN AND HllLDINi; ASSN TRKNTI &gt;N. NEBRASKA. On the .5&lt;»tli day of June, VMH. Officers. &lt;&gt;. K. REYNOLDS 1'iv.i.l.nt S. HILL Vice- President s. HILL Vtap-Prpsktom ( ( (LLETT Been ( ( &gt;I,LKTT Stvi- A. E. RKYNOLDK Tivasur.-. A. B. REYNOLDS Tnwwuer Directors. Directors. «'. K. RKYXOI.I&gt;S. S. H1LI. W. S. OOUPT, «'. K. BTKOLO8. a. e. nmouM, ' '. W. UK WXIAK s. mu- a. e. reynoi.ik*. (has. nrrmr c. k. kviu, • . UK WAI.l). C. L. At. .1. I&gt;. KIl.HK.lfl". i MAS. SEK1.KV. t-. I.. ATT iWT Assets. l(ian&gt;. . . til morttra^re loans in process of forecloxun k loan-* 7ini.ini Real estatf trniture and stationti sh Delinquent interest, premium* anil tines \.\.~ii&gt; and taxes j&gt;aid &lt; nher a »1 Liabilities &lt; apital stock ninniny. (Dues and dividend* Kull paid su&gt;&lt;-k 4,8OO.« e fund Tndivided Profits • holders on incomplete loan&gt; l*remiums 2.017. M Advance dues. Advance interest and premiums Interest s, transfer* and ito Total </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 Y A I Receipts. Premiums ■ and transfer fee Real esute sales ;il accounts Tot 11 Expenditures ■ mines stock, dues stock, earning - stock, dues stock, earning and expei. Knd on certificates of stockholders Tot a Supplemental Report. permanent &gt; i &gt;n. (if serial &gt; d dunn* n~ • d durintr Usi- awn during tlson ~ of full paid sti&gt;ck in force at th ■ ex loaned on •&gt;.nres on which d HHiuent ' shares sul [Kiyment of dues: amount of dues deliniiuent and the ainrreitate amount of same No of re and the airtrreitate amt. of same 1 ■ •as Amount of loans on Improved ■ u|H&gt;n which loans have been made ilue of i tii i ins on unim Appraised value of unimproved real estate u|x&gt;n which loans have been made isurance in force and assigned to the &gt; iuriniftlscu ■lunna Hm'»I \ear No. of roven during Bh** I'Iud of ]»reniiuni Amount credit «h1 to reserve fund &lt;lurintr ■nea banred to i - ■iared on running Amount of d; iared on full p*iid stock dur A Tenure rut- * dividends declared durin- Averaire ninninjr I ■ ured durin _ RKTKIPTS AND KXPKNDITKRKS K&lt; &gt;R THK K KNDING JINK :io. I!«&gt;4 I 1i«« </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THK VALENTINE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN. VALKNTINK. NEBRASKA. On the ttith day of .Tune. IMm. Officers. HENRY HOKNK; President W. E. HALF: Y Vic-t-Ft-esidenf 1 .1. T. KEELE Y ' Secretary REECE Tiv;, Directors HKNRY HOKNK ; W. E. HALEY. C. H. CORNELL. J. T. KKKLKY. C. S. REECE. FRANK FISCHER. R. H. WATSON. LEWIS SMITH. H. F. MILLER. Assets. mortgage loans fcJx.-fcMUN' mortjrajre loans in process of foreclosure None mortjrajre loans in process of foreclosure None -. loans Real estate ifl'.iNi Furniture and stationery .V&gt;.im&gt; Delinquent interest, premiums and fines - and taxes paid &lt; Hhe ' Total fcSt.54K.2:&gt; Liabilities. ( apital stock runninfr. ( Dues and dividends i *2.-&gt;. :.'*«). 27 Full paid stock None rve fund .')2.").&lt;K» Undivided profits \.'.i~ Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned i, 403.44 Advance dues None Advance interest and premiums None Interest, fines and membership fees 2,321.5' Total </seg>
            <seg id="p143">BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATE 143 RRCKIPTS AND KXPKNDITVRKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAR F.NDING JUNE :&lt;0. \i*H. Receipts. Hatlance on hand July 1. wtl Dues, (running stock) . Dues (full paid stock) Interest Premiums Membership fees Loans repaid Real estalf Rents Delinquent interest and tin Total * Expenditures [&gt;..n: Salarie Other expenses Withdrawals, dm- Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues Matun imintrs Pull p;i i krnintfs Cash on hand Premiums, withdrawals Total Supplemental Report. Plan of Association (serial or permanent) I? No. of No. of shares issued during fiscal year No. of shares matured durinic fiscal year N'i&gt;. of- tr;iwn during n~'- No of shares of running stock in force . ■-hares of full paid sti&gt;ok in force . No. ol No. of shar. payment of dues imount uf dues dr.iri'tuen' ~ Amount of dues owint' Amount of interest, pr ind unpaid f. of morttfat^es subjer ■ and the atrtfretrute amount of same, eiiflu r. of mortiraifes in process of foreclosure, and the airirrexatr same Amount of loans on improved real HS Appraised value of real i ins have been made Appraised value of inn Amount of loans upon unimi * ■ Appraised value of uninn &gt;n which loan- bave been made Amount of insurance in force and asMirned to the Association as collateral ritj No. of loans made for buildinif purposes durinit nsc.i No. of loans made /aires durinir tls.- Amount of advan No. uf borrowing -&lt; No. of non-borrowing si So. of minors holding si Aver; r cent of interest oharired borrowers during Averut: '*ent t&gt;f premiums charged borr»jwers during Amount crediteri ;&lt;i durinir nst-a: Amount of losses eharired to reserve fun&gt; Amount of &lt;1 on running Amount of divid. .-d on fuD I Areraire rat. ATera«erunninif I Par value of each ■.hare •li/atiun. i ' </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 BIII.DING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS. STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK SWEDISH MUTUAL LOAN AND BUILDING ASSN. SAUNDERS ( iicntv. NKHRASKA. On the Mhh dav of June. 1!«&gt;4. Officers. ABRAHAM HKLSIN( ; Vice-Presideni .1. .1. JOHNS! &gt;N Secretar* ALFRED HELSING Tr&lt;;i Directors. A UK AH AM HEL3INU. U. .1. HOLM. 'HAS. VASS AX1&gt;KKSON. I'HAS. NOKDAHI.. H. »'. ROSENtiKRN. Assets. mortgage loans II7.4MHMI First raort^rayf loans in process of forecloHure Stock loans Real estate Furniture and stationary ."*«.«• [V-linquent interest, premiums, tines and dues I.U32.K2 t~ and taxes i&gt;aid . ier asset- 4:51. til Total IU.W54.2!* Liabilities Cauital st&lt;K-k rtaadttg. I Dnen and dividends 10.281. 4" Full paid stock rve fund 211.7 s Undivided profits Dufe share holder* on incomplete loans I'remium* unearned ... Advance dues Advance iimis </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 I RHCKIPTN AND KXPKNDITl'RKS FOR THK FISCAL VKA1 KNDING JUNE :fc&gt;. V.*H Receipts. p on bund July I. 1 full paiditto Interest Premiums p and transfer fe Real ' Expenditures kSSS. &lt; nmn. ( Uher expen Withdrawal- due Full paid stuck. (1 Full paid stork, earning n hand Hue treasurer July l. i&lt;» Tax sale certittoa Total \ Supplemental Report. Plan of association (serial or i&gt;ermanent I P»r value of eac 1 -erie» Lssue&lt;1 on. (if serial) ' shares issued &lt;t: ires matured du ires withdrawn durin^ -hares of runnintr stock in ' -nareN of full paid stock in force ; No of shares on which dues are delinquent celUtion for nonpayment of due* Total amount or duesdelinn Amount of dues owinvr by rn ait of intere-t premium- a: So of mortirairt' No. of mor Appr . eapon which loans havetieen made a.ueofim,, Amo.r Appraised value of unimproved re : Pount of insurance in force and aasit security N.i of loanit made for build:* No of loans made for payment o' ntl tl-c»l v &gt; Amount of advance payments of loans durii ' borrowing stockholde No of non-borrowint' stockhi ■ tera»e rate pel eraire rate per cent of premiums charved Ixir- f premium nount credited to reserve fund durintr li lount of losse- chanred .mount of divide Amount of dividends declar A veratre rate per Arerairerunninir </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 STATEM BNT OK THK CONDITION OF THK \VAH(K» MUTUAL LOAN AND BriLDINC; AKKX. WAH(K). NKBKASKA. On tin- :»&lt;»th da\ of June, 1!«&gt;4 Officers. Officers. HEN. I). HUPP Ptm MKN. I). \U'}'V l'i-.- BDW. KILLIAN . Vic-President KDW. KILLIAN Vic.-l'r. - H. M. STRATH )N . . . . filUlKMlJ H. M. STRATH UK .... filUlKMlJ ERNST HANS* &gt;N Trei E. E. GO &gt;I ) Atti ■ Directors. Directors. K. K. (i&lt;K)l). F. R. CLARK. I.. .J. KUDKNA. K. R. CI.AKK I.. J. KUDKNA. M. A. PHF P. J. KIKt'HMAN. K. J. KIK( HMAN. JAS. O'DONNKLL. M. A. PHEI.I Assets. Assets. First mortage loans t-"&gt;4." First niortayv loans in jiriK-ess of foreclocure ... First mortage loans in process of foreclosure Stock loan&gt; ... l.OTi Rt'al estate Furniture and Stationery ... fash Delinquent interest, premiums and fines ... Total Liabilities. Capital stock running. (Dues and dividen - .. 154, "3 Full jiaid stock und pd profits U". s i&gt; Due share holders on incomplete loans F'remiurns unearned i Advance dues Advance interest and premiums ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p147">RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL ENDING JUNE M. V.m. Receipts p and transfe Expenditures Flfs. irninu' - stook. dup - stock earnini llllf - earnin n hand. Tutu Supplemental Report -hare* i«ued during Us.- N'o of v \«i of share- Total amount of i \mount of dm \mount of : I tbe aifirrevate ' morttraire* tab same, one N'o. of morttfaites in process of foreclosure, and tbe uificreirate annum' of same rotate upon which !•• en made So cjf loans made for buildinu purposes ilvear ..,rrowin,s l mount imount . Pi' unit oi eraire rate i» e ratre runnii Matured dorins fl- Eee on bund .lui (runnin. f nil pairt utoek .res withdrawn durinir llseml Tear it this date No. of il stock in force at th No. of ■ Punt &lt;»' value of unimpp unt o: &lt;1 ussi^nei 1 eral ecurii • wer&gt; durii ■ rowers durin* tlsoul year. r premium H it credited t&lt;» reserve fund during rtscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 HlIl.DINC; AM) LOAN ASKOOATIOXS. &gt; STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OK THK SALINE COUNTY lUILDINK ASSN. WILBER, NEBRASKA. «&gt;n tlie MKh day of June. 1!«U «&gt;n tlie MKh day of June, l«M. Officers. Officers V. L)f HAS ... I'n- C. DURAS I'n- HO6POD8KY.. Viee-Pie* HOSPODSKY. Vice-Pres .1. K. MALL AT Seer .IK. MALL AT Sm K. .T. SI'IRK. K. .T. SPIRK. . . InaMii Directors Directors. \STIV. P. S. SAPAKIK. J. N. VAN I' V. P. S. SAFAKIK. J. X. VAN D J. J. MKI-fKK. MKI.fEK. -KPH CBBUY. V. ». I'ld'CHA. •H CERl'Y. ». HINCKH. V. H. PK0CHA. J. H. HKT. ». MltlWi. I ■H.VXK SASKK J. H. HKT KRANK SASKK Assets. Assets kMUM - ' Ioan&gt; lol hi- in prtK'ess of foreclonun of foreclosuii '.•■"- '.•."- KurnituiT and stationery ... Kurnitun* and stationers ... h .: 2.M1.51 2.041.51 1 . premiumx and fines '. premiums and fine* - )&gt;iiid Tott Total Uabilltles Liabilities &lt; apital stock mnnintr. Dues and dividends .. +»&gt;7._ Kull paid Rtoek rve fund I"ndivid«»d profits -ban- holders on incomplete loans iunas unearned Advance dues ... + » ; . 7 ■". inns • </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 Receipts ce on hand Jub I. lire &lt; running Htoek) full paid U •rship and transfer fee: I fit, r •&gt;&gt; ijl uwoi repaid Kents Total Expenditures. - Supplemental Report. I'tTtniinent 1 . nares issued riur re (lettmiuent amount ol Amount of &lt;1i;' Amount of interest premium^ and I ■! unpaid rof ii)ort/au .mount ■-anie Amount of .nan- on improved reai ■ ,inin uhioh loai i made Anioi. Hie of unimproved rt i|K&gt;n which loai made rount of insurance in force ami asMimed n&gt; tl - No. of loans made for buildinit puri»&gt;se~ So. of loans mad Amount of ailvai lan- during tl-c.&lt; No. of borrowing - Avera/e rate per cent of premiums ch of premium edited to reserve fund during A mourn 1 RKCKIPTS AND KXl'KNDITrRKS FOR THK KIS( KNDIX; JINK M). 1!K»4 Witti&lt;i -nitnr~ irninir ■ irk. earning i thdruwn durin- - of running Mix-k in ' - date So. of shar. No. nf r. Qount </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 Hril.I)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIi STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION oh' THK WOOD RIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSN \V(K)I) RIVER, NEBRASKA. t&gt;n the .tilth dav of June. l\»H. \V(K&gt;I) KIVKK. NEBRASKA. t&gt;n the aoth dav of Jane. l*H. Officers. Officers. ROUNDS V WHITE Vice-I' A. C WHITK VMce-Presideni \V. L. RPRAGUE S W. L. SPRAGl'E BeereUr; W. C. WINGEKT T W. C. WINGERT Tiv;, Directors. Directors. K. T. HIH-NIiS. A. C. WHITK. OMO. W. Mil. I'ONMNCHAM. T. A. BVA1 H. M. .1' A. MIL1.KK. H. II. JONES. U. HAKRK'K. m. A.CIIIAVKI.I.. JnHN H.Mil'K JOHN HAKl'KK. Assets 1(NI.IM&gt; w Kurnituif and Rtationerv 1.+ iquent interest, premiums and fines s paid 11H. l"i i HIhm- Total ■Mti.tio; Liabilities. ;il st&lt;K ¥ k running. (Dues and dividends | d profits 1.1 -liareholders on ineomplete loans.. None i urns unearned </seg>
            <seg id="p151">BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIAT1 151 RK( KIITS AND BXPENDITURES FOR THH KISCA1 Receipts. Premium' Member&gt;hip and tninsfe Expenditures Supplemental Report. 1|M&gt;I1 Whi.' of insurance in force omestead mortnaifes durin -~ — .No. of s N.p of Aver, iriMkn Plan oi Amount .&gt;( Amount Avera KNDING .11 ".\ uly I. !!« inning -.lock) ' ill paid Nit. IntereM ■ * »ther expert tlttlld No &lt;' r ick in fi)n-. f mortiratfes in process of for. ind the »ir_ tme i«.n which </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 STATEMENT (IF THK CONDITION OF THK :k mutual building and loax askx YORK. NKHRASKA. &lt;&gt;n the 30th day of .Turn-. 1!*»4. Officers. Officers. U;K W. SHKKCK ....Pres W. SUKKt K ...I'll- i HAKLKS A. McCLOUD Vic.-iY.- - tGE R. REED ...S.vi RGE \V. 1«OST I HARLKS A. Mcl'UH'H Vice-iY. - UGE R. KKKD . ...Set-i KGE W. POST I n WILLIAM W. WYC'KOFF WILLIAM W. WYCKOFF Directors Directors. HAKKIS M. CHII.HS. AI.FKKI) B. CHRISTIAN'. NATHANIEL A. Dl CHARLES A. M'CLOUD. UBOSaC W. P IMO— K. KKKD. DA VII WICK. GUBUnC W. SHKKCK. WII.I.IAM W. WYlKOH HAKKIS M. CHILI'S. AI.KKKI) B. CHRISTIAN'. NATHAMKI. A. Dl CHARLES A. M'CUHTD. UBOMaC W. P IMO— K. KKK1&gt;. DATS WliK. GUBUnC W. SHKKCK. WII.IJAM W. \VY( KOKK Assets. Assets. ■ loans in process of foreclosure loanv 5. 200. IK • Real ■ Kurnituiv and stationar N quent interest, (nvmiunis and fine* - | &gt; H 1 1 1 N'oin Total Liabilities • auital st&lt;R-k runniny. Duex and divided Kufl paid st,K-k ncomplet* loans Advai ... Included in &lt; .-. Advg mil premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p153">1 ■ ■" K I &gt;■ RECEIPT8 AND EXPENDI1 I'HKS FOR Ti r.NK 30. 1!N»4. ENDING .1 Receipt; Expenditure! ' i &gt;ek. du&lt; •&lt;'k. eai * msa on nano Supplemental Report ■in (seriiil or iiernmner 0 : :" • ■ -- V.. ,.f . " MO. nt s] ■ . -^««. (m Niianr&gt; limnt i \.i. of "tul an mount ■ \TiiMimt i 1 mount i ,.. nd th&lt; I 1 I - 1 « • made mount of in-ursincf in fo sHi'iiriT \ i-' ro. of - during i T '■ 5! i'priii'#* ninnT T </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>