<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth AT BEATRICE TO THE Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings, DECEMBER 1, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT —OF THK— Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth —AT— BEATRICE — TO THE — Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings DECEMBER 1, 1902 1902 THB FBEMOBT TRIBCDl Fukoit, Nbb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. Ezra P. Savage Governor For Term Ending January i, 1903. Hon. J. H. Mickey Governor For Term Ending January 1, 1905. BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. For Term Ending January i, 1903. f. Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings President Hon. Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary Hon. Wm. Stuefer State Treasurer Hon. Frank Prout Attorney Genei al BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. For Term Ending January i, 1905. t. Geo. D. Follmer, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings President Hon. Geo. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary Hon. Peter Mortensen State Treasurer Hon. Frank Prout Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p004">v RESIDENT OFFICERS. A. Johnson, M. D Superintendent Emma Miller Matron SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Marie B. Armstrong Principal TEACHERS. Clara L. Smith. Mae Appel. Francis E. Atwater. Lucretia G. Leigh. Jack O'Donnell, Band Instructor Wm. Pollock Supervisor Boys' Department Ida A. Holt Supervisor Girls' Department W. C. Alford Supervisor Boys Department, Hospital Nellie Alford Supervisor Girls' Department, Hospital Nels Nelson In charge of Farm Department Thomas Irvine In charge of Carpenter and Brush Dept E. F. Stevens In charge of Bakery J. C. Harbert — In charge of Laundry Minnie L. Jones In charge of Sewing Room </seg>
            <seg id="p005">TABLE NO. 1. :OVEMENT OF •optjlation for the year 1900, and Ending December Begin 1, 1901 J 7. I i I Pber enrolled at beginning of period ber admitted during the year ber returned from parole during the year. 111 43 1 110 26 1 221 69 2 Number discharged during the year Number died during the year 4 7 9 4 13 11 - - Number remaining at end of year, Dec. 1, 1901 -5 TABLE NO. 2. Movement op Population for the Year ] 1901, and Ending December Jegin: i, 19a nNG IER 1, i i I Pr enrolled at beginning of period r admitted during the year r returned from parole during the year. 142 30 1 128 29 2 50 3 kber discharged during the year ber released on parole during the year ber died during the year 9 9 8 » 3 5 4 6 4 4 -s f umber remaining at end of period, Dec. 1, 1902 '. .i r. ■ i J I I 1 / Pr of children in school department r of children in custodial department. . . r of children in Asylum department 80 30 60 80 10 44 160 40 104 Number of children admitted since organization Per capita cost for biennium Litt 8 ?? </seg>
            <seg id="p006">• </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT. Hon. Ezra P. Savage, Governor of the State of Nebraska, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: In accordance with the laws of the State of Nebraska, I hereby submit the Ninth Biennial Report of the Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth for the period ending November 30, 1902, with such remarks and recommendations as seem to me to be proper. At the beginning of the biennial period the number of inmates enrolled was 221, and at the end of the first year 268, an increase of 47. At the end of the second year, November 30, 1902, the number of inmates enrolled was 304, an increase of 36 during the last year of this period. It will thus be seen that the population of our institution has increased by 83 during the biennial period, so that we now have over one-third more inmates than we had at the beginning of this biennium. The health of the inmates has been unusually good durin I past two years. We have been fortunate to pass this bien period without the appearance of any epidemic of disease ing the first year of this biennium there was quite an ep tie of smallpox in Beatrice, but by establishing a very close rantine, and vaccinating our children, we escaped without le case at our institution. DIVISION OF POPULATION. The institution naturally falls into the following groups : ( 1 ) School, (2) Custodial, and (3) Asylum. Eie School division includes all of those children whose men - indition is susceptible of improvement under proper school ods, the training given being on moral, mental, physical and lal lines. The Custodial division includes those who have passed through the school period, either in the institution or elsewhere, and who remain as permanent wards of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">216 Eie Asylum division is made up of those with a low state of ty, both mentally and physically. This class require con - watch and care, both day and night, as they are entirely ipetent to care for themselves. SCHOOL DIVISION. Eis institution was established by law to furnish the means of ition to tha't portion of the youth of the state not provided any of its educational institutions. See sections i and 2, er 52, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1885. Kor this purpose schoolrooms are provided and furnished 1 special apparatus and an efficient corps of teachers main- Iis intended that each child admitted shall receive such degree ducation as his enfeebled capabilities will permit, the train - given being on moral, mental, physical and manual lines. Where mental deficiency exists, there exists, also, in most cases a deviation, as it were, from the average normal moral and physical standards, and much time, patience and perseverance must be devoted to the improvement and correction of these deviations, and go hand in hand with the training and arousing of the mental faculties. It is not expected that any degree of what is known as higher education can be attained, but any progress, be it ever so little, is beneficial and will tend to lessen the burden of care and responsibility after the school age is passed, thus making each individual not only helpful to himself, but useful to others. To reach this object manual training is early introduced into the curriculum of all modern progressive institutions for feeble - minded children. Our method of instruction is based upon a modification of the kindergarten idea as taught by Froebel. Our school children are classified much as are the children in the lower grades of the common schools, with a regular pro - gression from the lower to the higher, although much special - ized effort must be made by the teacher for each individual. No pupil is in the schoolroom more than one-half of each day, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">217 Krest of the day being devoted to manual or industrial train - physical drill and out of doors recreation, thus securing thy change and variety. In deciding upon the school exercises, we bear in mind the natural limitations of our pupils. Leasing says: "Educa - tion can only develop and form, not create." We do not create a faculty, but we "draw out" what may not be evident at first, but, nevertheless, is there, and it is a question how much devel - opment is possible in each case. As a class the feeble-minded have dull perceptions, feeble powers of attention, weak will-power, uncertain memory and defective judgment. It is useless to attempt to arouse these dormant faculties by forcing upon them the abstract truths of ready-made knowledge. The child must be made to do, to see, to touch, to observe, to remember and think. We utilize to the fullest extent the varied and attractive occu - pations and busy work which are so important a part of the modern graphic methods of instruction for normal children. Object teaching in its broadest sense is a prominent feature in our educational scheme. In the lower grades the pupils are taught form and color by means of sphere, cube and cylinder, sticks, blocks, pictures, flowers, etc., to cut and paste, to perforate and sew, to form strokes on slate and blackboard preparatory to writing, to dis - tinguish one object from two, to articulate distinctly, to speak words, phrases and sentences, to sing simple songs by ear, or form habits of attention and obedience, to obey commands, to keep time in marching, to keep step. In the higher grades the pupils are taught to read and write, to know something of arithmetic, geography, language, history and physiology, the value of money, to tell time, to do free-hand drawing and crayon work, letter writing and fancy needle work. Nearly all of our pupils receive daily systematic physical training. Mental awakening generally follows as a direct result of increased physical development. The pupil must be closely attentive; he must quickly hear and understand; he </seg>
            <seg id="p010">218 a uhysicHi drill. Vocal music is taught in classes and chorus singing comprises most of the work accomplished in this line. Our band recently organized is doing well. Those capable are taught to read music by note. Certain daily duties are assigned to each boy and girl, and these duties are changed often enough to make each child famil - iar with different kinds of work. Khe boys take great interest in both farm and garden. They i, harrow, and cultivate, weed, hoe and rake. Some assist carpenter and engineer, while others do work of various s in kitchen, laundry and ward. I he girls do much of the sewing, mending and darning for large household. They are taught to wash dishes, make s, wash windows, clean and polish floors, sweep, dust and h and iron. Iur Sabbath devotional exercises have been both interesting instructive. In the morning at 9 o'clock, the entire school mbles for Sunday school, and in the afternoon at 3 130 for an ■'s devotion, which is made as non-sectarian as possible. The ices are led by clergymen from town. As the work progresses in wisdom and righteousness we may hope that the education of all children, both normal and abnor - mal, may be upon one plane, the right of every human being to receive the highest development attainable by him as an indi - vidual. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS DONE. We have been very busy during the last two years. Not only because we have had so many more inmates than usual to care for, but also because of the run down and dilapidated con - dition of the buildings and sidewalks, which all had to be repaired and rebuilt, to say nothing of the neglected condition of the lawn, drives and flower beds; also the gross neglect in not planting shade trees, for when we took charge of the institution the grounds surrounding the buildings were nearly as barren of </seg>
            <seg id="p011">219 iie trees as they were before the institution was located. It ue we found a great many holes in walking over the ground?, eating that some trees had once been planted there, but hav - died and been pulled up, none had been put in their places, also found a few trees still standing that had been planted the year before, but as they were really too large to trans - plant, nearly all of them were dead. We have tried to overcome this neglected condition by plant- I nearly one thousand shade trees, also a number of evergreens a lot of shrubbery. A number of new flower beds have been laid out. Quite a little grading and sod laying ha* 1 done, and hundreds of loads of cinders have been placed on drives. Three thousand four hundred and twenty-nine ire feet of brick sidewalk has been built during the biennum, much other work done that has added very materially to the beauty of the grounds and lawns. The schoolrooms and all of the children's dining rooms have been repaired and painted. All of the halls, rooms and dormi- V' s in the Girls' Cottage have been painted and kalsomined. i is also true of the Boys' Old Cottage, which was in a very condition, in fact much worse than the Girls' Cottage. Our bake oven, although it had been used but about two months when we took charge, has been rebuilt at an expense of $125.00. It was very poorly constructed, being built of noth - ing but common brick and mortar, and this, when heated, crumbled to pieces and fell in. We used the best fire-brick and fire-clay in the reconstruction, so that it will now last a long The building referred to in the last biennial report of this institution, as having been built over from a laundry building to a carpenter and brush shop, had simply been moved to its pres - ent location, but had not been fitted for the purpose intended. This building has since been covered outside with corrugated iron, the inside has been boarded up with flooring, the brush machinery has all been placed in position, so that it is all in good running order. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">220 money with which to build a green house. It is not very large, it is true, being only 24x40 feet, but it answers our purpose very well. Besides the enjoyment our children get from the flowers, for they do enjoy them very much, the green house has been very useful to us, as we have raised our early lettuce, our cab - bage, tomato and other plants in it, and thus we have been able to supply our tables with vegetables very much earlier than we would have done had we raised them out of doors. A new horse barn and corn-crib has been built, and many other improvements have been made about the barn and feed - yard. The appropriation made by the last legislature has been suffi - cient for the needs of the institution. In fact we have now, December 1, 1902, a surplus, after spending our monthly allow - ance of $12,854.99. The monthly allowance has been over - drawn in but one fund — that for Repairs and Improvements, but as all of the needed repairs have now been done, very little will be needed for this purpose until after the new appropriations become available. RECOMMENDATION. I Physician. — This institution has now reached the age and ins the population which makes it absolutely necessary that should be added to the staff of officers a physician. I the legislature, during the coming session will make the sary appropriation in accordance with this recommendation. NEEDED CONSTRUCTION. A School Building. — As our present schoolrooms and Assem - bly hall are too small to accommodate our school children, and «lso on account of the fact that our children have to walk up two and three flights of stairs in order to get to them, I would recom - mend that a school building be provided. We now have a num - ber of children, who are otherwise reasonably bright, but crip - pled to such an extent that they are unable to walk upstairs to the schoolrooms, and therefore they derive no benefit at all from </seg>
            <seg id="p013">221 I schools. If we had a school building with most of the x&gt;lrooms on the ground floor and the Assembly hall on the &gt;nd floor, these crippled children could go to school, and the wded condition that now exists would also be overcome. The us that are now used for school purposes could be used for ndants' rooms, and the attendants that are now rooming in cottages and hospital moved into these rooms, and we could i make more room for our inmates by letting them occupy rooms vacated by the attendants. Addition to the Kitchen. — Our kitchen is very much too small; in fact, it is the same old kitchen used ever since the insti - tution was opened. The bakery is located so that the east end of the kitchen could be torn out and the north and south walls connected with the bakery. We would then have a kitchen twice as large as it is now, and the cost would be very small indeed, approximately about $1,00000. Cold Storage. — Enlarged and improved cold storage facilities are very much needed. The present building used for this pur - pose being originally built from discarded lumber, cannot be used for this purpose any longer. The investigating comn.ittce sent by the last legislature, recommended that a cold storage be built at that time, but as no funds were appropriated for that purpose, nothing could be done. From observation and investi - gation, I am convinced that the modern cold storage system — the ammonia process — is desirable, and I believe a necessity. They now have such a system at the Hastings Asylum, and I am told by Dr. Kern that it not only gives entire satisfaction, but that it can be operated very economically. The opinion of those who have compared refrigeration by machinery with that of ice is in every case most emphatically in favor of the former, for the following reasons : It is labor-saving. It will keep a lower and more even temperature than ice. It keeps the atmosphere perfectly dry, thus tending to prevent decomposition of stored goods. Estimated cost of storage building and machinery, $5,000 00. Additional Water Supply. — The water supply at this institu- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">222 tion, at the best, has always been defective. Our present water supply, except drinking water, which is taken from a well, is secured from Bear Creek and pumped into the stand-pipe. This water is always more or less muddy; in fact, after a rain it becomes so muddy that it is entirely unfit for laundry or bathing purposes. I have had experienced men give their opinion as to the best method of purifying this water, and they all seem to agree that the only thing that can be done is to build two or three settling basins into which the water can be pumped from the creek and then after it has settled, pumped into the stand - pipe. It will cost, approximately, $6,000.0 1 to make this improvement. The question of an abundance of pure water, however, is of such vital importance to the institution that it mer - its full and careful consideration, and I do hope this matter can be attended to early next spring. Improvements of Grounds. — I have not asked for a special appropriation for this purpose.for I believe we can do in the future as we did in the past, use part of the money belonging to \he fund for Repairs and Improvements, for I certainly believe that the work of improving the grounds that was begun during the last two years ought to be continued. Bhave now briefly referred to the most important matters :ting our institution, and trust that the necessary funds will irovidedso that the recommendations can be carried out. K desire to extend my thanks to His Excellency, Governor 1 P. Savage, and to the Board of Public Lands and Build - for the courtesies and acts of kindness which they have all ided me. I also wish to extend my sincere thanks to all of the employes for the faithful services they have rendered. Respectfully submitted, A. Johnson, Superintendent. RECOMMENDATION FOR APPROPRIATION FOR PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS. One new fire-proof school building $25,000.00 Additional water supply 6,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">223 Cold storage plant, complete $ 5,000.00 Addition to kitchen 1,000.00 Re-setting boilers 1,000.00 ESTIMATED FOR I. F. M. Y., APRIL 1, 1903, TO APRIL 1, 1905 Employes' wages $25,000.00 Fuel and light 17,000.00 Maintenance 32,000.00 Repairs and improvements 2,500.00 Furniture, bedding and clothing 1,600.00 Farm implements and vehicles 300.00 Farm supplies and feed for stock 400 00 Office supplies and postage 750.00 Telegraph, telephone and express 300.00 Drugs and dispensary supplies 1,200 00 Additional live stock 300.00 Industrial and school department 500 00 Library and periodicals 200.00 Amusements and music 300.00 Teacher's salaries 4,800.00 Superintendents' salary 5,000 00 Physician's salary 2.400.00 Matron's salary 1,200 00 TABLE OF SCHOOL ATTAINMENTS. SPEECH. Speak a few word3 only 26 Speak indistinctly 46 Speak distinctly ■ 104 t Speak fairly 30 Speak well 51 READING. Know no words 39 Know a few words 25 Read on chart 26 Read in primer 19 Read in first reader 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">224 Read in second reader 12 Read in third reader 7 Read in fourth reader 7 Read in fifth reader 20 Able to read books for amusement 34 WRITING. Make no attempt 30 Nothing but scribble 7 Form a few or most of the letters 10 Write easy words 20 Write from dictation 41 Write from print 52 ARITHMETIC. Have no idea of numbers 15 Count to five 10, Count to ten 18 Count to thirty 15 Count to fifty 31 Count indefinitely 4.7 Combine numbers to 5 24 Combine numbers to ten or mort 50 Work in addition 62 Work in subtraction 30 Work in multiplication 29 Work in division 2 g Work in fractions j8 Work in interest Work in U. S. money, including special work in bills 6 Work in reduction of denominate numbers 6 TIME. Know neither hours nor minutes 66 Know some of the hours 63 Can tell time to a minute 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">225 GEOGRAPHY. Know something of location and direction 46 Know something of local geography 23 Know something of general geography 13 LANGUAGE. Know use of capital letters 37 Know use of punctuation marks 40 Know name words 36 Know action words 36 Know simple sentences 36 Know compound sentences 8 Know singular and plural forms 36 Know the use of the apostrophe 28 Know initial letters 28 Know abbreviations 28 Write letters with assistance 20 Write letters without assistance 41 DRAWING. Draw simple forms 75 Map drawing 26 Freehand and crayon work 3 COLOR. Know only one or two colors 25 Know only the primary colors 38 Know both the primary and secondary colors 05 Can match compound shades, but not always name them . . 90 VALUE OF MONEY. Know a few coins 80 Know all U. S. coins * o Know value of money to 25 cents 40 Know value of money to $1 30 Know value of money to $5 23 MUSIC. Seem to have no interest in musical sounds c Pay some attention to musical sounds 155 Sing simple tunes by ear 85 Play in the band ! 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">226 GYMNASTICS Have no idea of drill 17 Stand at attention 99 March only 21 Execute simple calisthenic movements with apparatus .... 50 Execute difficult movements with apparatus 23 HISTORY. Know something of U. S. history 12 PH-i SIOLOGY. Know something of elementary physiology 12 KINDERGARTEN WORK. Can perforate and sew 95 Paper folding 62 Paper weaving 93 Paper cutting 35 Paper pasting 84 Alternate with two forms only 25 Alternate with more than two forms 91 Use the peg-boards methodically 63 Do work with blocks and tablets 65 SEWING. Overhanding 42 Hemming 25 Drawn work 7 Embroidering 3 Crocheting 1 Knitting 1 Pillowcases 75 Tea towels 801 .ace work INDUSTRIAL CLASS WORK DONE BY HAND. 30 8. lapkins </seg>
            <seg id="p019">227 HEMSTITCHING. Doilies 25 Carvers 2S Tray covers 1 S Centerpieces 10 Lunch cloths 3 1 Dresser scarfs 35 Table scarfs 10 Towels 59 Pillow cases 36 Table covers 6 DRAWN WORK. Centerpieces 4 Dresser scarfs 6 Table covers 14 Commode covers 4 Chiffonier covers 6 LACE, BATTENBURG. Centerpieces 2 EMBROIDERY. Doilies. 12 Centerpieces 6 Dresser scarfs 1 MISCELLANEOUS. Comforters 18 Mufflers 13 Candy sacks 325 SEWING ROOM. ARTICLES MADE. Sheet. 636 Pillowcases 455 Comforts 67 Roller towels 132 Bath towels 339 Bed spreads, hemmed 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">228 Curtains 210 Couch covers 2 Pillow covers 4 Aprons, kitchen 28 Aprons, ward 24 Aprons, dining room 15 Aprons, bakery 3 Aprons, cold storage 2 Dining room coats 2 Caps, bakery 4 Laundry bags 2 Wash rags 15 Table covers 25 Tea towels, hemmed 42 Iron holders 98 Suspenders, pairs 48 B^ 46. Straight jackets 12 Dresser scarfs 6 Table cloths Skirts, under 256 Shirt waist s 44 Night gowns 370 Drawers 262 Combination suits 105 Chemise 6 Corset covers 29 Sleeves 2 Collars 6 Underwaists p Bonnets 6 Elastics, pairs IO p Sanitary napkins 2 10 a. auit ciuiuo . # II K.:::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::-3 Aprons 291 Skirts, dress 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">229 Uiapers ••........ "xa.i Supporters 21 Shirts 345 Nightshirts 345 Overalls 6 S&amp;NDING WORK. Comforts -. 20 Sheets 400 Pillowcases 250 Blankets 50 Bed spreads 116 Roller towels 174 Bath towels 222 Table cloths 82 Napkins 98 Diningroom aprons 270 Ward aprons 98 Diningroom coats 4 S raight jackets 42 Bibs 108 Aprons 2310 Diapers 194 Skirts 2230 Undervests 1020 Shawls 1 10 Shirtwaists 372 ' &gt;mbination suits 782 : oak. 142 'orset covers 1 28 'hemise 180 &gt;resses 5036 )rawers 3544 lightgo wns 1421 Camisoles 86 loods 72 anitary napkins 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">230 Underwaists 39 8 Bonn ets I72 Hose supporters 58 Collars 26 O """* 3596 Overcoats 36 Pa ° tS ' *9*&gt; Shirt8 --: 4028 Shirts, night 652 Jackets IOO Mittens 5 ARTICLES PREPARED FOR TABLE USE Jelly, apple IOO glasses Jelly, grape 75 «« Jelly, plum 50 " Butter, apple 25 gallons Preserves, tomato .- 25 gallons Preserves, apple 25 gallons Raspberries, canned 36 quarts Tomatoes, canned 200 " Apples, canned 25 gallons Pickles, tomatoes go « Piccalili 25 " Sweet corn, dried IO bus. FARM PRODUCTS, ETC., FOR THE YEAR 1901. H*y 11 tons Bound oats n u Cane l8 „ &gt;hirts, under 786 Juspenders 368 *■ «* 'f' ••-■ 7&gt;* Vaists, boys' 2O 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">231 Cabbage 860 pounds Peaches 5 bus. Strawberries 5 gallons YEAR 1902 FARM PRODUCTS, ETC., FOR THE Wheat 675 bus. Rye 74i " Oats 1,374 " Corn 2,000 " Potatoes 2,000 " Sweet potatoes 50 " Sweet corn 7,000 pounds Pop corn 25 bus. Hay 9 tons Millet 16 " Cane and kaffir corn 12 " Turnips 50 bus. Carrots 30 " Onions 50 " Radishes 10 " Beets 30 •« Wax beans 30 " Cabbage 500 heads Tomatoes 115 bus. Peas 6 " Lettuce 150 dozen ..affir corn 16 tons •ats 450 bus. Lye 56 ■ 2,373 •• otatoes 640 " weet potatoes 40 ct 'urnips 'arrots 100 IO M M teets 10 M "omatoes 10 it </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>