<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs</title>
               <date value="1931-08">1931-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 259 August, 1931 Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs s — A. D. WEBER and H. D. FOX Department of Animal Husbandry ■•'«* «®| j|f^ ■.■■ ■•' Champion Rambouillet Ewe at the Nebraska State Fair, National Western Stock Show, Ak-Sar-Ben Stock Show, and American Royal Live Stock Show, 1928. Bred and Shown by the University of Nebraska. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. A comparison was made in three trials of alfalfa hay, alfalfa meal, alfalfa molasses meal containing 30 per cent beet molasses, and alfalfa molasses meal containing 30 per cent cane molasses when fed in conjunction with linseed meal and a heavy feed of corn to fattening lambs. Data were also obtained on alfalfa molasses meals containing 20, 30, and 40 per cent molasses. Shelled corn and cracked corn were also compared. 2. The lambs fed alfalfa meal and those fed alfalfa molasses meal were kept on feed more easily, consumed more grain, and made larger and more economical gains than those fed alfalfa hay. 3. Alfalfa meal and alfalfa molasses meal had approximately the same value when fed to lambs that were crowded to the limit on corn. 4. Beet molasses and cane molasses were of equal value when each comprised 30 per cent of an alfalfa molasses meal. 5. There were no significant differences in either the rate or economy of gains made by lambs fed alfalfa molasses meals containing 20, 30, and 40 per cent' beet molasses. G. Lambs fed cracked corn consumed more feed and made larger gains than those fed shelled corn. Where shelled corn was fed the lambs picked out the grain and left the alfalfa or alfalfa molasses meal until the last, while those receiving cracked corn were forced to eat roughage along with the grain. 7. There appeared to be a correlation between the opportunity afforded the greedy lambs to overeat on grain and the percentage of death losses. The death loss was 12.7 per cent in the alfalfa hay lots, 3.4 per cent where shelled corn was mixed with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal, and 0.7 per cent where cracked corn was mixed with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molsses meal. An unusually large amount of grain was fed per lamb daily in all lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs A. I). WEBER and H. D. FOX ' Alfalfa molasses meal that was 50 per cent cane molasses and oO per cent alfalfa meal was fed to lambs at the Nebraska Experiment Station during three winters, 1919-20, 1920 - -21, and 1921-22. It was found in these trials that, while alfalfa molasses meal did not improve the appetites of the lambs, adding a small amount of it to a corn and alfalfa hay ration increased the gains 6 per cent (1)-. Practically the same results were obtained where alfalfa molasses meal was added to a ration of shelled corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay. A fourth trial conducted during the winter of 1923-24 re - vealed that when fed in conjunction with shelled corn and alfalfa hay, the replacement value of a pound of alfalfa molasses meal decreased as the amount of this feed increased (2). In this trial it seemed to serve primarily as a substitute for the alfalfa hay in producing gain. "Fox (3) reported a fifth trial in which the addition of approximately one-half pound of alfalfa molasses meal, con - taining 30 per cent cane molasses, to a shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay ration caused the lambs to consume more feed and make larger and more economical gains. He also found that cracked corn produced better results than shelled corn when fed in conjunction with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal. The lambs fed ground ear corn, on the other hand, made materially smaller gains than did those fed cracked corn. Because alfalfa molasses meal must be . sold at a higher price than alfalfa hay is worth on the farm, the results of these trials indicate rather definitely that it is not profitable to add even small amounts of alfalfa molasses meal to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay. However, alfalfa molasses meal is ordinarily fed as the sole roughage. The argument advanced for this method of feeding is that more rapid gains can be obtained with less danger of a high death loss than where shelled corn and alfalfa hay are fed separ - ately. A relatively short feeding period is desired by large feeders who operate near the Omaha market, since they must 1 H. I). Fox supervised the trial which was carried on during the winter of 1025 - -2fi. The rest of the trials were supervised by A. D. Weber. a Kiirnres in. parentheses are references to bulletins listed on page 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 259 depend upon a quick turnover for their profits. Farmers are also desirous of obtaining a rapid finish on heavy, growthy feeder lambs that have been pastured on weeds and grass durng the fall. The only way this can be done satis - factorily is to crowd the iambs on a heavy grain ration. However, there is a direct correlation, as the work of Newsom and Cross (4) shows, between the amount of grain fed .and death losses, especially when the grain is fed in bunks and the hay is fed in racks. Lambs cannot be self-fed grain with the same degree of safety as can be done in the case of fattening hogs or even cattle. Kammlade (5) hand-fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay 21 days and then started the lambs on self-feeders. There was over a 50 per cent death loss within a week from over - eating. Kammlade commented as follows, "This result sug - gests that perhaps the chief difficulty in self -feeding lambs on shelled corn and alfalfa hay may be in starting them on feed, since these lambs did not show any ill effects of self - feeding after the first week." Gramlich (6) found that there was no danger in self-feed - ing lambs when they were started on a full feed of linseed meal. Corn was gradually added to the linseed meal. Prairie hay was fed as roughage. This method of feeding, however, can not be recommended as an. economical means of fatten - ing lambs unless a feeder has a special purpose in crowding them for an early market. Even then, the price of linseed meal during recent years would preclude all possibility of profit. Since there are times when it is advisable to get lambs ready for market as quickly as possible, the three trials reported in this bulletin were planned to determine whether or not alfalfa molasses meal could be used to advantage when lambs are crowded to the limit on grain. Because of the increasing interest in this feed, it was also deemed advisable to compare beet and case molasses when incorporated with alfalfa meal, as well as to determine, if possible, the per - centage of molasses that such a mixture should contain. OBJECTS OF THE EXPERIMENTS The objects of the experiments were as follows: 1. To compare alfalfa hay, alfalfa meal, and alfalfa molasses meal when fed in conjunction with linseed meal and shelled corn to fattening lambs. 2. To ascertain whether shelled or cracked corn should be fed with alfalfa molasses meal, and with alfalfa meal. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs 3. To compare beet and cane molasses when mixed with alfalfa meal. 4. To determine whether alfalfa molasses meal should con - tain 20, 30, or 40 per cent molasses. LAMBS USED White-faced Wyoming lambs of medium to fine wool type were fed in the first and second trials. In the third trial, black-faced Utah lambs of medium wool type were used. FEEDS USED Most of the corn used was yellow and graded No. 2 and No. 3. The alfalfa was good-quality, and of the second and third cuttings. The alfalfa meal fed separately was the same grade as the alfalfa meal used in the molasses meals. An attempt was made to obtain alfalfa hay of the same grade as the alfalfa meal. The alfalfa molasses meals were special mixtures prepared by an Omaha firm having modern equip - ment for mixing feeds of all lands. Old-process linseed oil meal was fed. PRESENTATION OF DATA The data obtained in the three trials have been averaged and are presented in the tables which follow. In every case the gains are based upon feed-lot weights. The figures repre - sent weighted averages. ADDING LINSEED MEAL TO A RATION OF CORN AND ALFALFA HAY Fourteen experiments have been conducted at the Nebraska Station, in which 1,114 lambs have been used to determine the advisability of adding linseed meal to a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay. The feeding periods have averaged 76 days. The addition of linseed meal to this standard ration has increased the average daily gain from .32 pound to .37 pound. One ton of linseed meal has on the average replaced approximately 40 bushels of shelled corn and one ton of alfalfa hay. Since linseed meal is a valuable feed from the standpoint of shortening the feeding period, it was fed to all except one check lot in the experiments reported in this bulletin. One lot was fed shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay in order to make a direct comparison with alfalfa meal and the various alfalfa molasses meals. Table 1 shows that the addition of linseed meal to a shelled corn and alfalfa hay ration increased the average daily gain .03 pound as compared to an increase of .05 pound in the fourteen trials just discussed. The replacement value of </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 259 Table 1. — Adding linseed meal to a shelled corn arid alfalfa hay ration — average of three trials ; Shelled corn Shelled corn Alfalfa hay • Hiff/ 1 meal J Alfalfa hay Number of lambs 75 75 Average number of days 48 4y , ,, , . , ■ i Pounds Pounds ■ Average final weight ; . . 83 1 • 84 9 Average initial weight 66 2 66 5 Average gain .:.... •■ 16.9 lS^ Average daily gain .352 .385 Average daily ration: C?™ ::. 1.32 1.30 Linseed meal 15 Alfalfa hay . . ., lloT l.'eo Alfalfa refused — per cenl. &lt;».59 9.80 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Corn. • : . ■ 375 . 337 Linseed meal ; . . . • • ' 40 Alfalfa hay . . . : .-..•;. . • 444 .j j 6 Death loss — per cent . . . . . 10.67 14.67 one ton of linseed meal in the three trials under consideration was 34 bushels of shelled corn and 1400 pounds of alfalfa hay, or somewhat less than the average value obtained from fourteen trials at the Nebraska Station. However, with the exception of the first trial, the addition of linseed meal to the standard ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay was decidedly beneficial. ALFALFA HAY VS. "ALFALFA MEAL It can be seen from Table 2 that the lambs fed alfalfa meal consumed more feed and made more rapid and more eco - nomical gains than those fed alfalfa hay. One ton of alialfa meal replaced 2,878 pounds of alfalfa, 130 pounds of shelled corn, and 7 pounds of linseed meal. No alfalfa meal was refused or wasted, while approximately 10 per cent of the alfalfa hay was refused, which accounts for a part of the high replacement value of the alfalfa meal. The difference was more pronounced in the first two trials in which 60-to-65-pound lambs were used than in the third trial when heavy black-faced lambs were fed. The lambs fed alfalfa meal were easier to keep on feed. They were also </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs Table 2. — Alfalfa hay vs. alfalfa meal — average of three trials Shelled corn Shelled corn Linseed meal Linseed meal Alfalfa hay Alfalfa meal Number of lambs .'•...'-. 75 75 Average number of days ; 48 48 Pounds Pounds Average final weight ......,....'..:......., 84.9 86.6 Average initial weight 66.5 66.3 Average gain ....'. 18.4 20.3 Average daily, gain .385 .424 Average daily ration : Shelled corn 1.30 1.35 Linseed meal. .15 .16 Alfalfa hay 1.60 Alfalfa meal 1.23 Alfalfa refused— per cent. '..., 9.80 0 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn 337 318 Linseed meal. ......... 40 39 Alfalfa hay: 416 Alfalfa meal . : 289 Death loss— p&lt;-r_cen/ | 14.67 4.00 apparently better able to handle the heavy grain ration, as evidenced by the death loss, which was almost 15 per cent where alfalfa hay was fed and only 4 per cent where alfalfa meal was fed. In most cases, the lambs were found dead in the morning. None of them was noted to be out of condition before it died, which seemed to indicate that overeating was the cause of death. In a test at the Illinois Station, if was found that lambs self-fed alfalfa meal and cracked corn ate more feed and gained more rapidly but required more feed for 100 pounds gain than lambs hand-fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay. In .the trial conducted at the Illinois Station, however, one-third of a pound more corn per lamb daily was consumed by the self-fed lot than by the hand-fed group. In the three trials re - ported in this bulletin an attempt was made to cause the lambs receiving alfalfa hay to consume as much corn as was consumed by those getting alfalfa meal. In doing this, it was difficult to keep the lambs fed whole alfalfa on feed, which doubtless contributed to the larger amount of feed being required for 100 pounds of gain. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 259 alfalfa meal vs. alfalfa molasses meal By referring to Table 3, it will be seen that alfalfa molasses meal and alfalfa meal were practically equal when fed. to lambs crowded to the limit on corn. No significant differ - ences were noted so far as feed consumption, gains, or feed required for 100 pounds of gain were concerned. The results obtained in these three trials agreed with those reported by Fox (3) in that the substitution of cracked corn for shelled corn when fed with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal caused the Iambs to consume somewhat more feed and to make larger and more economical gains. How - ever, the differences are small. The principal advantage in feeding cracked corn was that the lambs stayed on feed better. The death loss was also lower. Possibly the reason for this may be attributed to the fact that the lambs did not pick out the corn as they did where shelled corn, was mixed with alfalfa molasses meal. TABLE 3. — Alfalfa meal vs. alfalfa molasses meal — average of three trials Shelled corn Shelled corn Cracked corn Linseed meal Linseed meal Unseed meal Alfalfa meal Alf. mol. meal Alf. mol. meal - ' (30';;, beet) (30% beet) Number of lambs 75 75 IT Average number of days 48 48 48 Average find weight 7 6 "t' W Average initial weight ..; ssi! lU IU Average gain 20.3 20.3 2°5 Average dally gain .424 ~au Average daily ration: Shelled corn 1.36 1-37 Cracked corn 1 JA* Linaeedmeml !.. , J«4 "165 ibr Alfalfameal 1.23 - I6S - 168 Alfalfa molasses meal 1.29 1.30 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: SheUedcorn 318 325 Cracked corn Vi d " ' L^eed n»«l '■ ■ . 89" "&amp;!" 38 Alfalfa meal _ 289 Alfalfa molasses meal ■ 305 " ' 292 Death loss— per ant 1 4.0 40 1M SHELLED CORN VS. CRACKED CORN Cracked corn and shelled corn were compared when fed with linseed meal and alfalfa meal. The lambs fed cracked corn consumed slightly more feed and gained .036 pound per head daily more than those fed shelled corn. The feed re - quired for 100 pounds gain was practically the same. The results are shown in Table 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs Table 4. — Shelled corn vs. cracked corn — one trial only Shelled corn Cracked corn Shelled corn Cracked corn Linseed meal Linseed meal Linseed meal Linseed meal Alfalfa meal Alfalfa meal Alf. mol. meal Alf. mol. meal • ■ . (30% cane) (30% cane) Number of days 60 60 50 60 Number of lambs 25 25 25 26 . . . Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Average final weight 92.6 94.4 93.0 94.8 Average initial weight 73.1 73.1 ' 73 .3 78.0 Average gain 19.5 21.3 19.7 21.8 Average daily gain .390 .426 395 ]436 Average daily ration: Shelled corn 1.42 1.48 Cracked corn 162 1.52 Linseed meal. .169 . .181 .i73 .181 Alfalfa meal 1.06 1.18 Alfalfa molasses meal 1.15 1.18 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn t 363 374 Cracked corn 357 ' .... 360 1 meal 43 43 44 42 Alfalfa meal 272 276 Alfalfa molasses meal 290 ' 270 ' Death loss — per cent | 8 0 0 I 0 The advisability of cracking corn when fed with linseed meal and alfalfa molasses meal containing 30 per cent cane molasses was tested in one trial. Here again the lambs fed cracked corn consumed more feed and made larger gains than those fed shelled corn. The beneficial effect of grind - ing shelled corn in these trials is doubtless explained by the fact that the lambs were virtually self -fed. Thus feed con - sumption was greater where the corn was cracked and mixed with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal because the lambs were forced to eat roughage along with the grain. But where shelled corn was fed the lambs picked out the grain and left the alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal until the last. Therefore, in order to keep the consumption of roughage at somewhere near the same level in all lots, it was necessary in most instances to feed less shelled corn than cracked corn. BEET MOLASSES VS. CANE MOLASSES Beet molasses and cane molasses, each comprising 30 per cent of an alfalfa molasses meal, were compared in three trials. The average results are given in Table 5. The feed consumption and the gains were .practically the same in the two lots; therefore there is little, if any, difference between beet and cane molasses so far as this method of feeding is concerned. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin. 259 Table 5. — Beet molasses vs. cane molasses — average of three ' -trials Cracked corn I Cracked corn Linseed meal ! Linseed meal Alf. mol. meal , Alf. mol. meal (30 Vn beet) j (30'. " r cane) Number of Iambs 75 75 Average number days 48 48 Pounds Pounds Average final weight. 87.6 88.0 Average initial weight. . '. ... ..... 66.3 ■ 66.4 Average gain 21.3 21.6 Average daily gain .444 .452 Average daily ration: Cracked corn : ... . .^. .... .1 1.40 1.41 Linseed meal _• .168 .170 Alfalfa molasses meal — beet . 1 .30 Alfalfa molasses meal— cane 1 .29 Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Cracked corn '■...."..:.. • 314 312 Linseed meal .■•.-. 38 38 Alfalfa molasses meal — beet ........ . . 292 Alfalfa molasses meal — cane 286 Death loss — per cent . .' I 1 .34 • 0 COMPARISON OF ALFALFA' MOLASSES MEALS CONTAINING 20. 30. AND 40 PER CENT BEET MOLASSES Most commercial feeders prefer a molasses meal contain - ing 30 per cent molasses instead of one containing .20 per cent or 40 per cent. While .all the. molasses meals used in these trials were remarkably uniform, the majority of these products containing 20 per cent or less of molasses are some - what variable because it is difficult to mix such a small amount of molasses uniformly with the alfalfa meal. In the opinion of many practical feeders, alfalfa molasses meal com - posed of 40 per cent or more of molasses causes the lambs to scour. In order to get information on these points, two comparisons were made of alfalfa molasses meals containing 20, 30, and 40 per cent beet molasses. The results are shown in. Table 6. Approximately the same amounts of cracked corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa molasses meal were consumed in all lots. There was no significant difference in either the rate or economy of gains. It appears, therefore, that price should determine the percentage of molasses in such feeds when they are to be used with a heavy feed of corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs Table 6. — Comparison of alfalfa molasses meals containing 20, 30, and 40 per cent beet molasses — average of two trials Cracked corn Cracked corn Cracked corn linseed meal Linseed meal Unseed meal Alt. mol. meal Alt. mol. meal All. mol. mea (20% beet) (30% beet) (40% beet) Number of lambs. 50 50 Average number of days 47 47 47 . « ■ • 1 Pounds Pounds Pounds Average final weight 84.5 83.6 84 1 Average initial weight 62.9 62.8 63 1 Average gam , 21.6 20.8 21 .0 Average daily gain .459 J442 [445 Average daily ration: ~ Cracked corn I.34 j^g 1J3 Linseed meal 1 &lt;u 1 co Tee A Haifa molasses meal— 20 per cent.'.: '.'.■.'. f.41 .. Alfalfa molasses meal — 30 per cent 1.36 Alfalfa molasses meal — 40 per cent ' "l" 40* Feed required for 100 pounds gain: Cracked corn 291 300 299 Linseed meal • 35 37 37 Alfalfa molasses meal — 20 per cent 307 Alfalfa molasses meal — 30 per cent • 308' Alfalfa molasses meal — 10 per cent ....... 314 Death loss — per cent '. 2.0 2.0 0 As a matter of fact, a careful analysis of the results obtained in these trials reveals that molasses is not needed, since lambs fed alfalfa meal made just as large and as eco - nomical gains as those fed mixtures containing varying pro - portions of molasses. It should be noted, however, that both grain and roughage were fed in bunks. A few feeders are of the opinion that the molasses is neoessary when ground roughage and cracked corn are mixed and fed in self-feed - ers because the molasses serves as a binder and prevents the corn from sifting to the bottom of the feeders, thus affording an opportunity for the greedy lambs to overeat on grain. However, no harmful results were noted when equal parts by weight of ground alfalfa and ground shelled corn were fed in self-feeders at the Illinois Station (5). DEATH LOSSES These experiments were not planned with the idea of mak - ing a study of death losses. But, since the losses were dis - tributed practically the same in each trial, a discussion of them seems warranted. The relatively small numbers of lambs used in each of the trials, however, make it unwise to attach too much significance to the exact percentages of losses in the various lots. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 259 Of the 150 lambs fed either shelled corn and alfalfa hay or shelled corn, linseed meal, and alfalfa hay, 19, or 12.7 per cent, died. Six, or 3.4 per cent, of the 175 lambs fed shelled corn, linseed meal, and either alfalfa meal or one of the alfalfa molasses meals died. But only two deaths, or 0.7 per cent, occurred among the 275 lambs fed cracked corn, lin - seed meal, and either alfalfa meal or one of the alfalfa molasses meals. The high loss in the lots fed shelled corn and whole hay may be attributed to the heavy grain feeding from the start. When a heavy ration of corn is not mixed with roughage, an excellent opportunity is afforded the greedy lamb to overeat. In every instance there was little or no evidence of sickness and the lambs were found dead in the morning. Where shelled corn was mixed with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal, the death loss was slightly above two per cent, which is considered normal by most feeders. When lambs have developed a strong tapte for corn they often pick the grain out of the meal. This may possibly explain the very low death losses where cracked corn was mixed with alfalfa meal or alfalfa molasses meal, since this method of feeding made it necessary for the lambs to eat roughage along with the grain. LITERATURE CITED 1. Savin, W. H. 1923. Winter Lamb Feeding. Nebr. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 197. 2. Fox, H. D. 1924. Fattening Western Lambs. Nebr. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 204. 3. Fox, H. D. 1926. Corn Supplements and Substitutes for .Fattening Lambs. Nebr, Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 211. 4. Newsom, I. E., and Cross, Floyd. 1926. Diseases op Colorado Feeding Lambs. Colo. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 305. 5. Kammlade, W. G. 1929. Some Comparisons of Methods of Fattening Western Lambs. 111. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 338. 6. Gramlich, H. J. 1918. Fall Lamb Feeding. Nebr. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 170. .( r»M) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>