<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00031</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of 1919-1920 The First Biennial Report of the Department of Agriculture</title>
               <date value="1920">1920</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN BIENNIAL REPORT 1919-1920 THE FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE LEO STUHR SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Hon. S. R. McKelvie, Governor Sir: The first report of the Department of Agriculture as organized under the Civil Administrative Code on August 2, 1919, is herewith sub - mitted for your consideration and approval. This report covers the period from December 1, 1918, to December 1, 1920. It has been the intent to submit this report of the facts of admin - istration of the past Biennium in a concise manner and without em - bellishment. The personnel of the Department wishes to acknowledge the courtesies received from the Executive and other Departments of State during the past two years, these having greatly aided in the administra - tive work. Respectfully submitted LEO STUHR, Secretary of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">EXECUTIVE STAFF OF THE DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Leo Stuhr Secretary of Agriculure W. T. Spencer Chief, Bureau of Animal Industry W. S. Frisbie Chief, Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil W. C. Andreas Acting Chief, Bureau of Markets and Marketing George G. Koster Chief, Division of Game and Fish J. W. Mayer Chief Clerk, Clerical and Records Division </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE POWERS AND DUTIES DEFINED The Civil Administrative Code which became effective August 2, 1919, merged a number of the various state activities formerly carried on through boards, commissions and departments, into a newly created De - partmen of Agriculture. The general powers delegated to this Depart - ment are as follows: "1. To encourage and promote, in every practicable manner, the in - terests of agriculture, including horticulture, the live stock industry, dairying, cheese making, poultry, bee keeping, forestry, fishing, the pro - duction of wool, and all other allied industries; "2. To promote methods of conducting these several industries with a view to increasing the production and facilitate the distribution there - of at the least cost; "3. To collect and publish statistics relating to crop production, marketing and farm economics, the production and marketing of beef, pork, poultry, fish, mutton, wool, butter, cheese and other agricultural products so far as such statisical information may be of value to the agricultural and allied interests of the State; to co-operate with the Fed - eral Government in the matter of collecting such statistical information. Such department shall include in its publications the reports of agricul - tural, horticultural and like societies, and of live stock associations. Such published statistics shall be the official agricultural statistics of the State; "4. To encourage the planting of trees and shrubs and the improve - ment of farm homes generally; "5. To produce and manufacture biological products to be dis - tributed to live stock producers at the actual cost thereof; "6. To inquire into causes of contagious, infectious and communic - able diseases among domestic animals, and the means for the prevention and cure of the same; "7. To take all measures necessary for the preservation, distribution, introduction and restoration of fish, game birds and other wild birds; "8 To see that live stock and stock yards, and other like places where live stock is confined, housed or fed, are properly cared for; "9. To execute and enforce all laws relating to the inspection of foods, drugs, dairy products, oils, commission merchants, cider and vinegar, oleomargarine and butterine, sanitation of premises used for manufacturing and preparation of foods, cold storage ware-houses, paints, seeds, commercial feeding stuffs, live stock remedies, hotels and inns 1 , </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE weights and measures and commercial fertilizers, and from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations and adopt such standards of food products as are necessary and proper to enforce the provisions of this title." ORGANIZATION Under this reorganization were concentrated the laws formerly en - forced by the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission, the Live Stock Sanitary Board and State Veterinarian, the Game and Fish Commission, together with a number of new laws relating to agriculture passed by the 1919 Session of the Legislature. The task of classifying or grouping this large number of subjects into bureaus or divisions according to the im - portance of the activity was then undertaken. After considerable de - liberation and conference the following sub-divisions wei» established in the Department Bureau of Animal Industry Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil Bureau of Markets and Marketing Division of Game and Fish Clerical and Records Division To the Bureau of Animal Industry were assigned the laws relating to the live stock industry and the prevention and control of live stock diseases. The Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil retained most of the activities formerly enforced by the Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission and in - cluded the laws mostly of a regulatory nature, relating to Food and Drugs, Dairy, Gasoline and Kerosene, Sanitation of Food Premises, Com - mercial Feeding Stuffs, Live Stock Remedies, Commercial Fertilizer, Paint and Linseed Oil and Hotels. To the Bureau of Markets and Marketing were assigned the laws relating to Weights and Measures, Agricultural Seeds, Potato Grading In car lot shipments. Cold Storage, Agricultural Statistics, Crop Report - ing and research and investigational work relating to production and dis - tribution of agricultural products. The Division of Game and Fish retained the activities formerly en - forced by the Game and Fish Commission including the enforcement of the Game and Fish Laws and the propagation, conservation and distribu - tion of fish from the different hatcheries and conserved from lakes, ponds, and overflows of the State. The Clerical and Records Division has charge of the clerical and record work of the Department, the issuing of the various licenses and permits, the keeping of the time and expense of the employees and the furnishing of supplies for the entire Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 7 MANNER OF FUNCTIONING The Department of Agriculture functions largely through the various bureaus and divisions which have been established under the reorganiza - tion. Many of the laws enforced are of a service or regulatory nature. There is, therefore, a similarity in the field work which is standardized in such a way as to promote efficiency and economy. To accomplish this the various field representatives or inspectors are usually held re - sponsible for a definite outlined territory or section of the State. The size of the territory depends upon the volume of work or the number of inspectors that may be available to perform this work. The inspector is required to establish headquarters at the most advantageous point in the territory if possible so that the routing can be made to the best ad - vantage and at the least traveling expense. The inspectors are required to send in a daily report of the work performed, also to give information relating to their routing for the fol - lowing two or three days, so that the person in charge at the office may get into direct communication with the inspector without delay. This is of prime imporance, in many cases, in order to investigate an emergency complaint as well as frequently to eliminate the necessity of sending an inspector from the Department when a territory man may be in the immediate vicinity from which such a complaint is made. Besides the daily report rendered by the field men they are also required to submit regular reports relating to the work assigned to them. Such reports are then carefully examined in the office and the necessary action taken. The field men are also required to keep an actual field record of work performed by them. These reports cover the work performed in a cer - tain city or county as the case may be. Such record can be demanded by the office for inspection and check and is also of considerable value whenever an inspector severs his connection with the Department and it is necessary to assign a new man to the territory. Such a record fur - nishes for the new man information as to the work performed in that territory by the previous inspector. In order that the Governor may be regularly informed of the work that is being accomplished by each activity of the Department, a weekly report is submitted to him giving data as to the nature and amount of the work performed by each branch or sub-division of the Department. It has been found, however, that for the best interests of the service, additional monthly reports be made which summarize the amount of work performed by each field man and the traveling expense incurred by him. In this way it is an easy matter to compare the different inspectors engaged in the same kind of work as well as to compare the different kinds of total work. An average of the volume of each kind of work that inspectors have accomplished is taken as a standard for that kind of work and each inspector is expected to reach this standard. Traveling expenses have been standardized in a similar manner, so that an average expense for a certain class of inspection work has now </seg>
            <seg id="p008">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 8 been established. Whenever this amount is exceeded an explanation must be made why such additional expense has been incurred. It has also been possible to compare the expense of field work performed by the use ot privately owned automobiles with the expense of the same work done by railway transportation and the hire of automobiles. This system of reporting is also of value in compiling information for a fiscal or calendar year, it being available at all times so that it is a mere matter of summarzing the monthly reports for any definite period desired. STANDARDIZATION All employees of the Department are classified in grades based upon qualifications as to education and experience for the particular service that is to be performed. An applicant upon appointment is classified within the grade. Provision is made for a specific salary for each classi - fication and for regular increases at intervals of six months 1 or one yeai. In this way there is an incentive for an employee to remain in the service for the reason that his salary is increased until the maximum is reached for that particular grade. In certain classes of work the em - ployee has the additional opportunity of being transferred or promoted to a higher grade or possibly, eventually, being placed in charge of a bureau or division. In the past there has been no incentive to train for State service and in most cases an appointee received as much salary immediately after appointment as 1 would be received at the end of a biennium. The permanency of an organization of this kind should be en - couraged through some form of civil service so that it would be an in - ducement to train for this line of work and the State in turn would be materially benefited by the training and experience of employees in the organization. It is expensive for the Department to train individuals for a particular kind of work, besides the necessity for such training is a considerable handicap in the continuity of the various activities. Espe - cially is this true when these activities are of a nature embracing a definite program extending over a period of years, as for instance, tuber - culosis eradication in cattle. Another subject that was given immediate attention under the re - organization of the Department was the standardization of the various forms used for office and field work as well as any other bulletins or printed matter published from time to time. It can readily be seen that the diversity of the work requires a very large number of different forms for the proper enforcement of laws of a regulatory and service nature requiring inspections and reports as well as forms used for permanent records in the office. To accomplish this general specifications were per - fected providing for standard size, material, type and arrangement; and. in order that these might be readily referred to, a form number was pro - vided for each form used in the Department. In this way a form can </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 9 be readily recognized and re-ordered. The date inserted at the time of issuance is a guide to the number to be re-ordered for future use. Such uniformity- of standard sized forms is a distinct advantage in the filing of this information, which constitutes the permanent records of the work performed. The field work performed in many cases is of little perma - nent value unless information to this effect is on record and available whenever needed. Before the Civil Administrative Code became effective each separate activity purchased its own supplies. Under the present plan all supplies are purchased through the State Purchasing Agent, who is in a position to investigate and receive bids and in practically all cases purchase sup - plies for less money than these could be bought for by individuals, in many cases, inexperienced in this line of work. To further safeguard against deficiencies, whenever a requisition is made for supplies the funds' available for such purpose are encumbered to the amount of the purchase, so that there is little possibility of exceeding appropriations. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Bureau of Animal Industry ORGANIZATION AND DUTIES The Bureau of Animal Industry is charged with the enforcement of all laws relating to the live stock industry and the prevention and con - trol of live stock diseases 1 . The principal division of this Bureau is that of Inspection and Control. This activity covers all field and inspection work carried on by the Bureau. The inspectors who are graduate veter - inarians are assigned according to the various live stock diseases the regulation or control of which is undertaken. Under this classification of diseases may be mentioned, Tuberculosis, Scabies, Hog Cholera, Anthrax, Glanders and Blackleg. In addition to these diseases a certain amount of sanitation and disinfection is carried on under supervision of in - spectors of the Bureau. The Bureau is also charged with the enforcement of the law relat - ing to stallion inspection. This law provides compulsory inspection of all stallions' and Jacks used for service in the State. An inspection fee is charged for this work. The Bureau co-operates with the veterinary practitioners in carry - ing on disease control work and in many cases a local practitioner is called upon to make an emergency investigation. These private veter - inarians are also authorized to make inspections of interstate shipments of live stock. It is from reports of inspections of this kind and of live stock passing through the terminal market that statistics are obtained relaing to exports and imports of live stock. The Bureau is not equipped with laboratory facilities to examine pathological specimens that are submitted from time to time by the reg - ular field force as well as practitioners; and, consequently, it is necessary to send specimens of this kind to the College of Agriculture of the Uni - versity where competent men are available and equipment maintained so that specimens can be examined and information thus derived used for disease control purposes in the field. TUBERCULOSIS ERADICATION The most important phase of live stock disease control in the past Biennium has been the tuberculosis eradication. This work is not only important from an economic standpoint on the part of the live stock interests but also as a public welfare measure. The Federal Bureau of Animal Industry co-operates with this Bureau in the work of tuberculosis eradication, each furnishing the same number of veterinarians assigned to this activity. The plan under which the </seg>
            <seg id="p011">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 11 work is carried on co-operatively is known as the Accredited Herd Plan. This means of carrying on this work on a co-operative basis was adopted by the United States Live Stock Sanitary Association at its annual meet - ing held in Chicago in December, 1917. An appropriation was then made by Congress available for carrying on this activity and also providing for an indemnity for owners of reacting cattle and who had formerly signed an agreement to operate under the Accredited Herd Plan. The 1919 Session of the Legislature apropriated $75,000.00 to meet the Federal appropriation of that amount as applied to Nebraska. Under this* agreement the same number of men are furnished by both the Fed - eral authorities and the State in carrying on tuberculosis' eradication work. It furthermore provides that an equal indemnity for reactors will be paid by both Federal and State Departments. In the past Biennium, owing to the small appropriation, the work has been limited largely to the pure bred herds of the State. The reason for this 1 being that the pure bred herds are more valuable and constitute the basis of our best breeding stock. With an increased appropriation for the next Biennium it is the intention to develop this activity so that it will be available for all dairy herds. The owners of such herds may then receive indemnity for reactors. The Dairy Law provides that milk or cream cannot be sold from cows which have not been tested by a duly authorized veterinarian and certified to be free from disease unless the product is pasteurized before it is sold. During the past Biennium the owners of dairy cattle have not been able to receive indemnity for con - demned animals. In the future with an increased appropriation any of such owners may come under the Accredited Herd Plan, or if they are unwilling to comply with such regulations as are imposed by this plan, may receive State indemnity for reactors. The Federal meat inspection service at the Omaha market has been another means of locating the source of infection of a great number of herds. Reports of animals shipped to market and found to be diseased are received daily by the Bureau from the Federal officials. In this way the disease is traced back to the farm and an effort then made to have such infected herds tested and the diseased animals disposed of. The reliability of the Tuberculin Test is no longer questioned and when performed by trained and experienced men is almost infallible. Statistics show that fifty thousand (50,000) head of cattle reacted to the test and slaughtered under Federal inspection at the Omaha plants, 96.5% per cent showing lesions of the disease visible to the naked eye. To further illustrate the importance of controlling and eradicating tuber - culosis, data relating to swine affected may be given. In the year 1920, two million five hundred eighty-two (2,000,582) hogs were slaughtered at the South Omaha packing plants under Federal inspection and of these 255,050, or 12%%, were found affected with tuberculosis. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 12 The following tables give a summary of (1) the work carried on under the Accredited Herd Plan and (2) the tests made of dairy cattle under the provisions of the Dairy Law. Scabies in cattle is a parasitic infection which has been a source of annoyance and great expense to the cattle growers of the grazing district of Nebraska for the past fifteen or twenty years. During most of this time there has been considerable work done by State and Federal gov - ernments in attempting to control and eradicate this disease. When this disease was widespread ten or twelve years ago there were about twelve or fifteen veterinarians stationed at advantageous points in assisting the State in its control and eradication. They were very successful in their work and had practically entirely eradicated all sources of infection, but funds for this work were such that it necessi - tated most of these men being taken out of Nebraska some four or five years ago and the State at that time had not sufficient funds to continue the work. For the past two years the infection has been constantly spreading until now there is a widespread infection over all of the grazing portion of the State. This demonstrates the necessity of vigilance in controlling infectious diseases of live stock and this disease should not again be permitted to gain a foothold due to lessening the effort to control the same. The men working on this project are expected to make a system - atic inspection of all cattle in a given territory assigned to each during the winter months when the cattle are bunched and on feed, in this way locating all of the infected herds and so they may arrange for the &lt;1) Dec. 1, 1918 (1) to Deo. 1. 1919 Dec. 1, 1919 In Dec. 1. 192(1 Total for Biennium Signed Application! 239 Herds Tested 197 Beat C»ttle Tested 2,612 Dairy Cattle Tested 917 Animals Tested 3,529 Animals Tested including Rrtests and Ad- ditions 7,726 Percentage of Reactors Found 5.4 Total Number Herds Accredited 9 Indemnities Paid »9,7O7.92 o;_ 26a ■Ju-j 6.72H 2.317 9,126 20,611 4.9 32 $23,600.37 502 ll'.lil 9,341 3.234 12,655 28,337 5.1 41 |M,S08.2S Dec. 1, 1918 &lt;3) '&lt;&gt; Dec. 1, 1919 Dairy Testa „ 2,148 Dairy Animals Tested 10,119 Beef Animals Tested 467 Animals Tested 10,586 Percentage of Reactors 5.6 Dec. 1, 1919 to Dec. 1, 1920 7,565 27.738 1,443 29,181 3.4 Total for Biennium 9,713 37,857 1,910 39,767 4.0 SCABIES </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FIRST BIENNIAL RKPOR 13 dipping of these cattle at a later date when weather conditions will permit. The two "dips" most commoniy used for treatment of scabby cattle are a solution of nicotine, or a combination of lime and sulphur. Owing to the fact that thes-e dipping solutions will not destroy the egg of this parasite, it is necessary that infected cattle be dipped twice at intervals of ten day periods. The following figures indicate the amount of work that has been done in the pasi Biennium in connection with this activity. There has been a notable decrease in the number of outbreaks of hog cholera during the past few years' until at the present time the control of this disease is considered well in hand and less infection exists than at any time (luring the past decade. Cooperation on the part of evrryone interested directly or indirectly in live stock con - servation has made this condition possible. The duties of State and Federal veterinarians assigned to hog cholera work have consisted in making diagnoses, advising with farmers, assisting local veterinarians', cooperating with live stock agencies and in every way endeavoring to be of benefit to the live stock interests in the matter of controlling this and other infectious swine diseases. The results obtained through this close cooperation during the past two years are evidenced by the greatly reduced losses. Prejudice against the serum treatment which formerly existed has now almost en - tirely disappeared. There is now a disposition on the part of owners to immunize their herds before any signs of sickness appear. Dec 1. 1!I1H I), &lt;•. I, 1913 Total * t.) I" for I&gt;c.-. 1. 1!U!) Dm- 1. liiin Biennium Hrrds Animalfl Hnrda Animals Herds Animal* [niperted 1.042 270,233 1,353 H4i).12r. 2,395 619.359 Freo "&gt;!»5 154.023 701 lXH.4'ir&gt; 1,356 342,515 Infected 312 81,080 4n4 119.0(17 71(&gt; 200,087 Ezpoud 135 35.130 \ha 41.027 323 7H.757 Dipped on 1st Dipping 27il 7".4:in 515 149.43ai 7!I4 i;i«».H*J&lt;l Dipprd on 2ml Dippinc 129 57.560 :174 115.12fl 5n:i 172.683 Infection nt Market Centers 105 6.6S2 105 0,dS2 * These figures for lltr ftst y*;»r inrlude Shcop :ilso. The nlmvr lwrtls passed throuffb fifty-three ("&gt;:'.) stork yards, at point of shipment. Thesi' st«(i-k yards were all disinfected. HOG CHOLERA </seg>
            <seg id="p014">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE 14 The few fundamental principles mentioned below, if followed faith - fully by breeders, would practically eliminate losses from cholera and other infectious diseases of swine. Keep only immune brood sows. Immunize pigs at weaning time Do not allow litter and filth to accumulate in barns or lots. Systematize cleaning and disinfection. Remove hogs showing signs of sickness from balance of herd im - mediately and summon a veterinarian. Hogs, dead of any cause, should be completely destroyed by burn - ing immediately. Persons from diseased premises' should be refused admission to hog lots or barns. Fence off, or drain, stagnant pools and wallows, or streams flowing from probable contaminated areas. Following is a record of the work performed under direct supervision of State and Federal veterinary inspectors: This is an acute infectious disease which may affect any of the do - mestic animals. The fact that Anthrax is also communicable to the human makes it essential that the most vigorous efforts be resorted to that it may be eradicated upon the first appearance of symptoms indi - cating its presence. The germ causing this disease multiplies very rapidly in the body of the animal. The germ is capable of remaining in the soil -for years withstanding extreme temperature changes awaiting favorable con - ditions for further growth and multiplication. This being true it can be readily understood why the hurning of the carcasses of diseased ani - mals, draining of infected areas and continued cultivation of the soil are of prime importance as direct sunlight and air greatly hinder the growth of the Anthrax germ. Persons often-times become infected with Anthrax while handling or skinning carcasses of animals which have died of the disease. A slight wound or abrasion of the skin is an ideal place for the infection to gain entrance. The method most successfully employed for immunization against Anthrax is through the use of Anthrax vaccine. This product contains many dangerous properties, hence its use should be confined to those cases only where the disease has appeared and the administra - tion of the product should be left to experienced veterinarians. The Dec. 1. 1!&gt;1X to Der. 1. 1919 H Dec. 1. 101!) to Dec. 1, 1920 Total for Biennium N'umbfr of Animals Vaccinated.... .. 49.7H7 35.699 85,496 dumber of Herds Vaccinated 1,184 1.446 2,630 Special Investigations 81 46 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">FIRST BIENNIAL RKl'OKT 15 handling of all cases of Anthrax should be immediately placed under the supervision of the veterinarian who should advise with this Bureau as only in this way can the spread of this infection be controlled and losses held at a minimum. During the summer months of the* past two years Anthrax has ap - peared in several of the northern counties of the State. Prompt vaccina - tion, isolation and proper disposal of diseased carcasses prevented a further spread of infection. Varying losses were reported from infected areas but were of such nature that no authentic data as to the actual number lost could be obtained. Most of the animals affected were cattle. Glanders is a disease which in former years when many horses and mules were used in cities and towns was of grave concern to owners of these animals. The incurable nature of the disease and its com - municability to man makes it one of the most feared diseases known to man or beast. The elimination of the public drinking trough and the advent of the Mallein Test for the detection of the disease together with stringent State laws regulating transportation have been the prin - cipal means of eradication. The tests for Glanders are similar to those employed in tuberculosis eradication work. The one most in use at the present time is the Ophtalmic or Eye Test wherein a small amount of the product Mallein is instilled in the eye and observations made at later periods. A reacting animal will show evidence through a characteristic discharge from the eye into which the Mallein was placed. Reported cases are immediately taken in charge by the State. The animals are appraised for indemnity, destroyed and the carcasses burned or deeply buried in quick lime and the premises cleaned and disinfected according to specific instructions. This disease has decreased steadily from year to year due to the vigilance and cooperation of all concerned until it has been practically eliminated from the State. Only occasionally is a case of Glanders found. The following numl ber of cases were ofl fficially invest tigated anc quarantined : Number Cases Investigated Dec. 1, 1918 In Dee. I, 1910 34 Dee. 1. l'.H!i In Doc. 1. 1920 24 Total for I! i. mi Mini 58 N'uiiiIkt Animals Lost 102 180 282 Following is a summary of the work and results for the Biennium: dumber Mallein Tests Administered l&gt;er. 1. 1918 to Dec. 1, 1919 7.338 Dec. 1. KM!) Total to for Dec. 1. 1020 Biennium 14.8M J 1,646 ■Cumber Animals Found Affected Indemnities Paid 3 $313.97 5 8 ?71.67 $3*5.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 16 BLACKLEG Stock raisers in the State having experienced extensive losses from this infection in the past have as a rule become well versed in preventive measures and, availing themselves of this advantage, the losses have been almost negligible. In previous years the loss from Blackleg in the infected districts has 1 reached as high as twenty-five percent. The loss has now been almost completely overcome by preventive vaccination. The first vaccination practiced was by the use of an attenuated virus, in different forms. This method reduced the loss to as little as one-half of one percent. By such, unfortunately, the immunity conferred was not effective for a longer period than about six months. Of recent years, by the use of a germ-free vaccine, loss has virtually been eliminated wherever vaccination has been practiced. The immunity resulting from the use of this form of vaccine too is practically perman - ent. Thus doing away with the necessity of re-vaccination. The germ-free vaccine is known as "Agressin" or "Filtrate," depending upon the method of manufacture. Blackleg is now classed as a disease little to be feared, as about the only losses occasioned by it at this time are due to the indifference of the owner to vaccination. SANITATION AND DISINFECTION Sanitation and disinfection hold a very important place in live stock disease control. It is common belief that with the removal of diseased animals all danger of a continuation of infection has been overcome. Evety effort has been made to follow up each case of infectious live stock disease with a thorough cleaning and disinfection wherever prac - tical. While a large portion of the work in this connection has been done according to instructions sent out, the work outlined below is that coming under direct supervision of veterinary inspectors of this Bureau. One veterinary inspector devotes his entire time to the supervision of this phase of the work and it is considered one of the greatest determin - ing factors in the ultimate eradication of any communicable disease such as tuberculosis and glanders. The work is carried on in a systematic manner so as to meet condi - tions in each particular case. By the removal of accumulated filth and manure from barns and lots, exposing all portions of stalls, mangers, floors, partition walls, ceilings, etc., to the application of an approval dis - infectant and in many cases whitewash in addition, it is intended that when this work is completed in each instance that the premises are in condition to receive healthy animals without fear of further infection from this source. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">P1KST BIENNIAL REPORT 17 The following inspections have been made under the direct super vision of inspectors of this Bureau: The Stallion Inspection Law requires the* before any stallion or jack is used for public service the animal must pass a. satisfactory physical examination given by a veterinarian authorized by the Bureau to make such examinations. The purpose of this inspection is to determine whether or not the animal is affected with any disease of a communic - able nature or malformation which might be transmitted to the off - spring. The law provides that every stallion and jack shall be examined between the age of two and three years and again between the age3 of five and six years. An inspection fee of three dollars ($3.00) is charged at time of first examination. For the years intervening between first and secr.nd inspections 1 a dollar fee is charged for which a renewal certificate is issued. On payment of the regular fee of three dollars ($3.00) a life certificate is granted at time of second inspection. It is required that these certificates be posted in a conspicuous place on the building in which the stallion or jack is kept. The certi - ficate contains all information relative to ownership, breeding, and the inspection report of the animal's physical condition. In compliance with the Stallion Registration Law the following in- spections have been made: The exportation of live stock is governed by the regulations of the state into wjiich the animals are to be shipped. Veterinarians ap - proved by the Federal government and by the live stock sanitary officials of the state in which they reside are authorized to make in - spections for interstate shipments. Dec. 1. 1!)1K to Dec. 1. 1U1!) l&gt;rc. I. 1D10 to Uw. 1, 1*2(1 Total for Biciini"' S'umber of Inspections ... UH 71 1 209 dumber of Duluiettions : (a) l'i.iiii~r&gt; (b) .Stock Yards 64 ■— ■ 30 -1 ■j:i 145 y.i (c) Can, 2" ■j:; 43 Fotal Dibinft&gt;-tions 114 127 241 STALLION iNSPECTIOf Dei-. 1. 101H ]),&lt;-. 1. liini Total to to for Dec. 1, 1019 Dec. 1, 1820 Biinniun 9 Pure Bred Stallions Inspected 212 ::14 526 Urade Stallions Imported 4.1 sj 07 Stallions all CUuci [nipeeted 257 :;(;(( 623 Jacks InfiM-ctod 1 :t 1 J62 393 Certificates for Public Service Issued £40 70J 1,242 Total numlxT of animals rejectid for unsoundness rtnderine thim unfit for sei ico — 6. EXPORTS </seg>
            <seg id="p018">DEPARTMENT UF AGBTCULTURE 18 Certificates of inspection are made by the veterinarian in charge. One copy is attached to the bill of lading covering the shipment whi\ a the other copies are forwarded to this Bureau for approval. One copy of the health certificate is placed on file in the office and one for - w&amp;rded to the live stock sanitary official in the state to which the cattle aro dooiiscd. in the case of tuberculin tests, one approved copy of the certificate is also forwarded to the office of the FeUeKii Bureau at Washington. D. C. Under such a plan it is possible to keep a detailed record of all shipments and thus guard against movements of diseased animals. Live stock of all classes exported during the past two year period is The live stock sanitary regulations of Nebraska provide that all ani - mals entering the State meet certain health requirements as a safeguard against the importation of stock affected with disease. As an added protection to the live stock industry an importantion regulation requires that all pure bred cattle entering the State be quarantined and subjected to a retest for tuberculosis sixty (60) days from date of entry, thereby eliminating the possibility of affected animals being placed with herds free of tuberculosis. Live stock of all clashes imported during the past two year period is as follows: Die. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total as follows: Stallions Jacks .\Il.l.'&gt; l&gt;i-.-. 1. 1!&gt;18 to I)e&lt;\ 1, 1919 136 259 3.506 nee. 1. 1919 to Dec. 1, 1920 48 149 2,828 Total for Biennium 184 4"K 6,334 Horses (all classes exrept stallions Cattle (Grazing) Cattle-Dairy and Beef j ££" 14.089 15,267 3,438 971 16,048 25.732 6.269 1,025 30,137 40,999 9,707 1,996 _ . ( Stock 8wine &lt; „ „ . | Pure Bred Sheep (All Classes) Total animals Exported 4,312 1,739 9,378 53,095 3,826 1.331 9.627 66.883 8,138 3,070 19,005 119,978 IMPORTS to Dec. 1, 1919 to Dec. 1, 1920 for It ir Tin i urn Stallions &lt; 13 64 77 Jacks Mules Horses (All Classes except Stallions). 5 382 1,830 4:t 251 2,061 633 3,891 Cattle (Grazing) 61,478 3.416 64,894 Cattle — Dairy and Beet \ r * d&lt; V ) Pure Bred ( Stock Swine &lt; ~ ■» . J Pure Bred Sbeep (All Classes) Total Animals Imported 2.646 951 82,075 1,371 114,366 265,117 1.532 832 27.037 1.005 16,594 52.835 4.178 1,783 109,112 2,376 130,960 317.952 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">FIRST BIENNIAL RKHOKT 19 SPECIMENS EXAMINED Through the agency of the Bureau 318 pathological specimens ob - tained from cases the diagnoses of which were doubtful were examined at the well equipped pathology laboratory located at the University Farm. The diagnoses furnished from these examinations enabled this Bureau to proceed intelligently along lines of control. Dec. 1. 1918 to for to De&lt;\ 1. 1919 I'. . n in mil 8 :: 1 8 oo SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS Activities under this heading are directed toward the invpstigation of cases of special importance brought to the attention of the Bureau through indirect reports and requests for assistance and advice. Veterinary Inspectors employed by the State make these investi - gations and through personal observation of the conditions at hand are in a position to advise owners 1 and take all steps necessary for the control of any infectious disease should the investigation prove it to be such. Many outbreaks of disease of highly infectious nature are sup - pressed on first appearance, thereby saving thousands of dollars to the live stock industry of the State through the ability to send inspectors immediately to the territory from which the report was received. The number of investigations of special importance for the Biennium »»•« as follows: ,,„.. , ,,.,_, ,,,,. , ,„,„ T&lt;| , . Dp.-. 1. 1919 Dm. 1. 1 Bit nnium Special Investigations Quaruntinues Issued 9 »2 SUMMARY During the coming Biennium it is hoped that legislation enacted will provide for the indemnifying of cattle owners 1 under the Dairy Laws. If this is the case particular attention will be given to develop this activity. It is intended to perfect an organization with the practicing veterinarians under which the work of testing dairy cattle for tubercu - losis will be left to the local practitioner. During the past Biennium over fifty thousand cattle were tested in the State. If indemnity is provided for dairy cattle reacting to the test the number tested during the next two years' should be greatly increased. The scabies situation, especially in the western part of the State, will receive very careful supervision. It is believed that by so doing that the disease can be kept in control and gradually eradicated. Should it become necessary, however, a quarantine will be placed over the grazing section for a definite period, and, in that case intensive means will be employed to effect eradication. Dec. 1. HUH !&gt;,r 1. 1&lt;I1(I Total </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil ORGANIZATION AND FUNCTIONS The Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil comprises the following Divis- ions : Division of Food and Drugs Inspection Dairy Division Laboratory Division. The chief of the Bureau is responsible to the Secretary of Agri - culture for the details and enforcement of the laws assigned to the Bureau, for the supervision of the inspectors and chemists, and to make recommendations to the Secretary where departmental action is deemed necessary from the report of such inspection or analysis. The Division of Food and Drugs Inspection is composed of inspectors trained for inspection of food, drug and petroleum products. These in - spectors are also employed in the inspection and regulation of sanitation on premises used tor the manufacture or sale of food. The State is divided into twelve (12) districts each in charge of an inspector re - sponsible for the details of inspection work in that district. In addi - tion there are employed special or general inspectors not assigned to a particular district whose duties are of a special nature such as in - spection of food factories 1 , flour mills and for the investigati"" ° r com - plaints involving special qualifi^"*'"" 0 d«i.ii inspector is responsible directly to the chip* "t the Bureau and is required to submit regularly .eports of all places visited and of all activities. The Dairy Division consists of inspectors with special training and fitness for the inspection of dairy establishments, creameries and other dairy manufacturing, and for the supervision and inspection of cream receiving stations. For purposes of inspection the State is divided into seven (7) districts each in charge of an inspector responsible for condi - tions in that district pertaining to the dairy industry. The inspectors in this 1 Division are responsible directly to the chief of the Bureau and are required to submit regularly reports of inspection and other activi - ties. The Laboratory Division comprises chemists and other assistants necessary in the analysis of samples submitted by inspectors to de - termine as to their freedom from adulteration or misbranding within the meaning of the law. Laboratory reports are made directly to the chief of the Bureau and on the basis of such reports recommendations are made to the Secretary of the Department when it appears that the law has been violated and legal proceedings are deemed advisable. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 K1KST B1KNNIAL KKPOKT LAWS ENFORCED The Acts of the legislature assigned to this Bureau for enforcement are as follows: Food and Drug Dairy Gasoline and Kerosene Sanitation of Food Premises Commercial Feeding Stuffs Live Stock Remedies Commercial Fertilizer Paint and Linseed Oil Hotel. These laws are enforced by means of inspection or analysis or both. These laws are all a part of the criminal statutes and offenses are punishable generally by a fine of ten dollars to one hundred dollars or by a penalty of ninety (9i&gt;) days imprisonment or both. Special methods are provided such as the issuance of orders to require compliance before prosecution is recommended. These will be noted under the laws in question. A report of the progress made under each law during the past Biennium follows: FOOD AND DRUGS The law of this State relating to food and drugs defines the adultera - tion of these substances and also defines what is construed as mis - branding. This law prohibits the adulteration of any food with sub - stances which may be injurious to health or by the substitution of any food product with an inferior or worthless article and provides regula - tions for the labeling of all foods so that the purchaser shall not be misled or deceived in any way. Drugs are also defined and are required to conform to certain official standards. Drugs not conforming to such standards are declared to be adulterated. Included with the definition of drugs are so called patent or proprietary medicines for which no official standards are fixed. These, however, are required to be labeled in such a way that they shall bear no false or misleading statements either in respect to the ingredients or to their medicinal or curative properties. The enforcement of the provisions of this Act is accomplished by the collection and examination of official samples of food and drug products manufactured or offered for sale. Inspectors are required to submit from time to time samples of all drugs and remedies which are In any way suspected of being adulterated or misbranded. These samples are examined and analyzed in the laboratory to ascertain whether they conform to the standards for official preparations and to determine whether or not they are misbranded within the meaning of the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">DEPARTMKNT OF AGRICULTURE 22 It is impossible to indicate in a report of this kind the amount of inspection work devoted exclusively to enforcement of the law relating to adulteration of food and drugs for the reason that very few inspec - tions and investigations are made for this purpose alonei but are made in connection with so called sanitary inspections. Since all establish - ments handling food comes within the provision of the law relating to sanitation, inspection is always made for that purpose and investigation as to the food sold is included in the same report. Probably the best index as to the work done along the line of food adulteration is the number of analyses completed. The laboratory reports for the Biennium follows : to to for Analyses These analyses cover all kinds of food products, drugs, commercial feeds and remedies, petroleum products and linseed oil. As a result of these analyses one hundred eighteen (118) prosecutions were filed dur - ing the Biennium charging adulteration, or misbranding and conviction and fine secured in each case. It is interesting to note that the above number of prosecutions for violation of the Food and Drugs Act com - prise seventy-five percent (75%) of all the prosecutions filed by this Bureau for violation of all the laws assigned to it. The general character of the analytical work has been about the same during the two years covering about the same class of substances with few exceptions. During the summer of 1919 a large number of samples of ice cream were analyzed owing to a comprehensive survey of the entire State regarding the quality of the ice cream being manu - factured and sold. During the summer of 1920 considerable attention was paid to bottled beverages, a total of four hundred ten (410) analyses having been made in connection with these products. As a result of this work a number of prosecutions were filed for manufacture or sale of bottled beverages containing saccharin, a coal tar sweetener, pro - hibited by law. During the winter of 1919 and 1920 there were a large number of samples of flour mill products analyzed in connection with inspection of these mills, particularly with reference to the character of the by-products manufactured and sold. At the present time the food and drugs offered for sale in Ne - braska are generally free from adulteration and misbranding. Constant attention and supervision are necessary, however, to maintain this con - dition. Owing to the character of the adulteration of food and drugs at the present time, requiring for its detection more extensive chemical analysis and research in many cases and in order that proper attention may be given to the other laws charged to this Bureau for enforce - ment, it is deemed essential that ample provision should be made for sufficient appropriation to insure sufficient laboratory help and their continuance in the service. An addition of two chemists to the labora- Deo. 1. 191S Dee. I, 1919 TnUl Dec. 1, 1919 I&gt;ec. 1. 102" Biranium 1.193 1,69 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">FIRST BIKXXIAI. KKl'OUT 23 tory force at the present time is necessary if the work is to be properly covered during the next Bienniurn and the addition of a competent bacteriologist should not long be delayed owing to the necessary work in connection with enforcement of the Dairy Law as well as certain phases of enforcement of laws relating to food and drugs. DAIRY The present Daily Law was icted at the 1919 Session of the as on the statutes before that time include all phases of dairy produc - essary standards of dairy products. Legislature. The Dairy Law which w was not sufficiently comprehensive to tion, handling, sanitation, and the nee The present law requires milk an dairy products, to be obtained under and housing of cows and provides ce cream and all ether dairy products fro manufacture until they reach the hand of the most important provisions of t id cream, the source of all other proper conditions as to the care ertain requirements for milk and •m the time of their production or is of the ultimate consumer. One this law is the one requiring all milk and cream used for consumption to be obtained from tested cows or to be pasteurized before being sold. Under this Act all cows supply - ing milk and cream for consumption must be tested at least once each year and pronounced free from disease by a duly licensed veterinarian This is designed to protect the health of the people, particularly, the babies against possible infection from tuberculous cows. A large part of the time of the dairy inspectors has been devoted to activities in connec - tion wiih the enforcement of tl'is station ot the law. In addition- to dairy establishments and dairy products this law also provides regulations as to the maintenance of cream receiving stations and station operators. Each station must be in charge of an operator who is required to be licensed by the Department and before securing a license must pass a written examination and test demonstration before one of the inspectors. Examinations are held at regular times and places throughout the State and all licenses are issued at the office in Lincoln. The law provides a penalty for testing without a license or manipulation of the Babcock Test in any way and requires that stations shall be maintained in a clean and sanitary manner. The following statistics show v.hat has been accomplished during the Biennium: NUMBER OF INSPECTIONS Dec. 1, l!)lrt to Dec. 1, l!il!i to Dec. 1. L92n Tots for Bit nn Dairy Establishments Receiving Stations dreameries tee Cream Manufacturers "heese and Condensed Milk Plantx 3rand Total 7'.i.-&gt; 1.H56 ia 1.H4L' 2.594 84 I.t 3,( 32 •&gt; ■ &gt; 1,866 n.7.J4 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 24 ANALYSES OF DAIRY PRODUCTS Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. ini« Total It will be noted that the number of analyses in connection with dairy products is rather low in proportion to the number of inspections. The main reason for this is that the dairy inspectors are trained to do considerable of this work in the field and that practically all of the tests of milk and cream for butter fat content, formerly done in the laboratory, are now made by the inspectors at the time of inspection and only samples for purposes of a check analysis or on which a prose - cution may be recommended are sent to the laboratory. A considerable increase in the number of inspections for the last year of the Biennium will be found. This is attributed to the fact that the inspection force was larger during at least a part of that year and to the fact that the inspectors were better experienced and more systematic in their work. During the Biennium fifty-seven (57) prosecutions were filed for violations of this law and included the following offenses: sale of milk and oream below standard, the sale of milk from non-tested and diseased herds, the sale of milk without a license and for the conduct of cream re - ceiving stations by unlicensed operators. While considerable progress has been made in connection with this law it is felt that the work should be even more extended during the coming Biennium. In order to accomplish results and secure compli - ance with terms of the law the inspection force devoted to this work should be increased. At least two (2) additional inspectors should be added to the force employed during the past Biennium. The additional work made necessary by some of the provisions of the Act, such as requiring cows to be tested, cannot be accomplished otherwise. As previously stated also a competent bacteriologist is deemed essential if full compliance with the provisions of this law is to be maintained at all times. GASOLINE AND KEROSENE The law relating to the inspection of gasoline and kerosene requires that these products be inspected before being offered for sale or used within the State. This applies to every shipment of either gasoline or kerosene and requires that notice be given the Department when any of these oils are received by any dealer in the State. Inspectors determine and record the specific gravity and flash point for all kerosene and the specific gravity for all gasoline and other light distillates. If a shipment is found that does not comply with the re- to Dec. 1, 1919 to Dec. 1, 1920 for Biennium dilk and Cream xe Cream iutter and Cheese... 118 16:! 281 127 &gt;l 111 (i 26 n 361 ■jt:s 52 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT quirements it is rejected by the inspector and whenever the inspector is in doubt as to the further purity of an oil an official sample is sent to the laboratory for analysis. The amount of both products inspected during the Biennium follows GASOLINE &amp; KEROSENE INSPECTIONS The Legislature at the Session in 1919 passed a law providing for the adoption of a standard for motor gasoline. This standard is based upon a fractional distillation of a measured quantity of a sample of gasoline. The object of this standard is to insure a minimum grade of gasoline that shall have a uniform range for boiling points and shall not contain any excess of so called heavy fractions. At the time this law was introduced the laboratory analyses showed very little of the gaso - line at that time offered for sale in Nebraska would comply with these requirements. The oil companies doing business in the State were notified as to the time of taking effect of the new law and the various grades of gasoline put out by these companies gradually wore found to come within these requirements. During the Biennium a number of prosecutions were filed for selling gasoline below these standards but in comparison wltto the total amount of gasoline consumed the violations have been found to be very few in number. There were no violations charged against the sale of adulterated kerosene during this period. At the present time the kerosene and gasoline in this State may be said to be generally in conformity with the standards provided by law. SANITATION OF FOOD PREMISES The statute governing sanitation of food premises is very compre - hensive and includes all places' of business in the State where food is manufactured, sold, prepared or handled in any way. Explicit provisions are set forth by law as to the maintenance and conduct of these es - tablishments and these provisions are further supported by rules and regulations of the Department. This law is enforced mainly by the inspection and actual field work of the inspectors. The law provides that where an inspection report shows conditions in any food establishment which are insanitary or not conforming to statutory provisions a written notice is to be issued by the Department. This notice sets forth in detail the conditions found and orders the necessary changes to be made within a time specified. Fail - ure to comply with the terms of any written order or the act of main - taining Insanitary conditions are offenses within the law and upon Dec 1 1U1R I&gt;&lt;c. 1, 11&gt; 1 !» roUl to »o for Dei- 1 1019 Det. 1. 1920 niennium Kerosene fiaKoline Grand Total 2R.554.45u eals. 26,619,60(1 gate. 55.174,050 cals 75.226.200 suls. 7H.72fi.4.-,i) t'als. 153.952.65H Rals [ 103,7811,6511 sals. 1(15,346,050 iraK 2H9,126,7O0 cal» </seg>
            <seg id="p026">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE 26 conviction are punishable by a fine or imprisonment. A list of the in spections for the Biennium follows: INSPECTIONS OF FOOD ESTABLISHMENTS Dec. 1. 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total Sanitary Orders Issued. Prosecutions Filed :!'J An increase in the number of inspections for each class of establish - ment is noted for the second year of the Biennium due to increased efficiency and application of the inspectors. During the summer months of 1920 a particular campaign was made on the inspection of soda fountains in drug stores and also of concessions at the State Fair and the various county fairs. These activities had received practically no atten - tion in the former year and it seemed desirable to have some supervision and regulation on these places. No complete inspections of bottling works were made in 1919 but every plant in the State was visited during 1920 and a thorough inspection made. Considerable Increase in the number of inspections of miscellaneous food factories is also noted. This includes all canning factories, the large candy manufacturers and various food factories. The number of prosecutions filed for violations of this law appears very small in comparison with the number of inspections made and orders issued. Our records show, however, that most of the written orders are complied with without further action. Requests have been made from time to time for extension of the period allowed for com - pliance with these written orders for such reasons as difficulty in secur - ing labor or unexpected sickness and in such contingencies extension of time is generally granted. Prosecutions have been filed in cases where no apparent effort or attempt has been made to comply with any part of a written order or where dealer has flatly refused to comply or where conditions have been flagrantly in violation of the law as to warrant special action. A comparison of the table will show that while the total number of written orders issued during the last year of the Biennium is greater than the number issued during the first year the percentase, however, to the number of inspections made is lower for the last year than the first year. This is an indication of an improvement in the sanitation of food establishments. Groceries Meat Markets and Slaughter Houws.. Bakeries and Confectioneries Kcstuiirnnts and Hotel Kitchens Drug Store Soda Fountains &lt;'iiin fsmns Bottling Works Miscellaneous Food Factories Flour and Feed Mills to Dec. 1, 1919 1.929 574 371 1.075 3 211 to Dec. 1, 1921) 2,188 934 540 1,964 124 2sa 48 sa 74 for Bienniuiu 4,117 1.5O8 911 3,039 124 SM 4* :\&lt;&gt; M Grand Total 3,972 6,164 10,136 Sanitarv Orders Issued 4(16 633 1,039 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 FIRST BIKNNIAL KKl'OHT The work in connection with this law is of great importance as it directly concerns the health of the people.. The program of this Bureau for the present Biennium calks for an increase in the number of inspections and a complete survey of every food handling establish - ment in the State. HOTELS The law relating to hotels- was originally assigned to a hotel com - mission for enforcement. By action of the legislature in 1917 the work in this connection was made a part of the work of the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission and since the inauguration of the Civil Administra - tive Code the details of enforcement have been assigned to this Bureau. This law provides that all hotels and restaurants in this State must secure from the Department of Agriculture a certificate of regis - tration before conducting their business. It further provides for special requirements in the way of sanitation and conveniences for guests and further provides that no hotel or restaurant shall be conducted except in «« manner consistent with the health, safety and comfort of the guests. Penalties provided are revocation of certificate of registration, clos - ing of the premises, or prosecution upon failure to comply with written notice of changes required to conform to the provisions of the law. A record of the work for the Biennium follows: The law provides that each hotel and restaurant in this State shall be inspected at least once annually. Since there are between six hundred (600) and seven hundred (700) registered hotels in this State, it will be seen that they were not all covered during the first year of the Biennium. This is explained for the reason that a large number were inspected in December 1919 which month is listed with the second year of the Biennium. The total number of inspections, however, show that each hotel was inspected at least once for each year of the Bien - nium. It will be noted from this table that the written orders issued in connection with the Hotel Law have been fewer in number than the written orders issued in connection with the so-called Sanitary Law but HOTEL INSPECTION Dec. 1, 1918 Dm. 1. l'Jlfl Total 1» t» for De&lt;-. 1. 1919 Dpc. 1, 1920 Rienninn Hotels 176 1.M25 1,201 •Restaurant! and HoM Kitchens 1,1)75 1,964 :i.ip:)'J Written Notice* Issunl 12 -7i&gt; 288 Grand Total 1.283 3,265 i.u'l* * Already included unilir summary of inspections governing sanitation of foot premises. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE the proportion of orders issued to inspections made hag been greater in the former case than ih the later. In fact there has been more than double the number of warning notices necessary in proportion to hotels inspected as there has been such warnings necessary in connection with food establishments in general. This is accounted for by the fact that up to the present Biennium no thorough and rigid inspection of hotels had been made due probably to the fact, that the Hotel Law until July 1919 did not provide an effective penalty for transgressors. Compliance has been made with practically every written notice issued and prosecu - tions' have been very few in number. Several hotels have been closed, some of them having reopened after complying with the terms of the order issued. A few in the State are closed at the present time owing to failure to comply with the provisions of the law. While this report shows progress in hotel inspection much work still remains to be done. It will be the plan of this Bureau to have at least two annual inspections of notels during the next Biennium instead of one. Much of the work in connection with registered hotels is not entirely satisfactory owing to the impossibility of more frequent inspec - tion and supervision of these establishments. This, however, would en - tail an increase in the number of inspectors' and add materially to the cost of this work. COMMERCIAL FEEDING STUFFS This law regulates the sale of all concentrated feeds used by owners of stock for feeding purposes. All concentrated feeds are required to be labeled with the name of the brand, the net weight, the per - centage of protein, fat and fiber, a list of all ingredients and the name and address of the manufacturer or agent. It is further required that all concentrated feeds, except bran and shorts, made in Nebraska shall be accompanied by tax tags which are bought at this office at the rate of ten cents per ton. Inspectors are required from time to time to submit samples of con - centrated feeds to the laboratory to see if the analysis checks with the guaranteed analysis declared on the package of feed. They are also re - quired to see that tax tags are affixed to these feeds 1 wherever required and to see that other provisions of the law are complied with. Each brand of feed offered for sale in this State is required to be registered by the manufacturer or agent with this Department, a charge being made for this registration and the registration continuing unless name of the brand or the composition of the feed is changed. The number of samples submitted during the Biennium follows: Official Samples Collected 154 Investigational Samples 315 All these samples' were analyzed and results have all been compiled Investigational samples were obtained in connection with concentrated </seg>
            <seg id="p029">FIHST BIENNIAL KKl'OUT 29 feeds manufactured in this State, chiefly those of wheat flour by-pro - ducts. A considerable number of warning letters were sent where the guarantee did not comply with the findings of the chemist. Only a few prosecutions were filed and these were for flagrant violations. The work possible in connection with the enforcement of this law is directly dependent on the laboratory force available. An analysis is necessary in connection with practically every sample submitted and this takes an appreciable amount of time, so that for effective enforcement at least one chemist should be assigned to this work full time throughout the year. Adequate provision should be made for this necessary help. LIVE STOCK REMEDIES The law relating to live stock remedies is one concerned chiefly with the branding or labeling of all products' having medicinal, curative or tonic claims for their ingredients. Each brand of live stock remedy is required to be registered with the Department before being sold and a fee of five dollars ($5.00) is charged for this registration. The law requires that each package shall be labeled to show the net weight, the name and address 1 of the manufacturer or dealer, the name and percentage of ill diluents or fillers and the name and per - centage of all poisonous or deleterious ingredients. Sixteen (16) samples of these remedies have been submitted during the Biennium and seventy - nine (79) remedies 1 were properly registered with this Department dur - ing the same period. It should be stated in this connection, however, that registration of these brands is permanent unless there is a change in the manufacture, name of the brand or composition of the remedy and that the majority of all remedies in the Department were s» regist - ered at the time the law went into effect in 1915. No prosecutions were filed during the Biennium in connection with this law. Whenever remedies were found not properly registered or misbranded within the meaning of the law, the dealer was given an op - portunity to discontinue the sale of his stock or to conform to the re - quirements of the law. Most of these remedies are manufactured outside of Nebraska and the manufacturer is beyond the reach of the Nebraska Law. In this connection it was not thought proper to recommend prosecution against a dealer in this State, who had no means of know - ing whether or not the preparation he sold was legal, without giving him an opportunity to comply with the law. A great many complaints are received in connection with live stock remedies, a great majority of which, however, arise from the purchase of remedies manufactured outside of Nebraska and sold directly to the user. It is very difficult, if not in many cases impossible, to secure any legal action against the sale of such remedies. The proper procedure </seg>
            <seg id="p030">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 30 for Nebraska residents who wish to purchase live stock remedies is to buy from the dealers within this State where they can secure protec - tion. PAINT AND LINSEED OIL This law requires that white lead in linseed oil and ready mixed paints ground in oil shall be labeled to show the list of ingredients with their percentages. The law also requires that raw linseed oil shall be pure as defined by the United States Pharmacopoeia and that boiled linseed oil shall be pure oil heated to a certain temperature before being sold. The labeling of paints is quite generally complied with and little cause for action has been found in this connection. In regard to boiled linseed oil the law is not deemed quite specific enough and a bill has been introduced seeking to modify this law and strengthen it by provid - ing certain standards for boiled linseed oil. Very few analyses were made during the Biennium for the reasons above given. In conneciion with this law it may be added that another valuable substance used in painting is turpentine for which at the present time no standards for purity exist in this state other than that sold in drug stores for medicinal purposes. Since turpentine for technical purposes is frequently subject to adulteration it seemed desirable that some pro - vision to safe guard the purity of this product should be made and a bill has, therefore, been introduced at the present session of the legislature regulating the rale of turpentine within this State and providing stand - ards of purity for gum spirits and wcod turpentine. COMMERCIAL FERTILIZER Nebraska until July 1919 had no law on the statute books in refer - ence to fertilizers. Since the introduction of this law fourteen (14) brands of fertilizers have been registered with this Department as re - quired. Only two or three analyses of fertilizers were made during the Biennium owing to the fact that fertilizers are little used so far in Ne - braska, also to the fact that laboratory force has not been adequate to assign a chemist to making fertilizer analyses. SUMMARY As may be noted from the foregoing report, the work accomplished in general during the year 1920 has 1 exceeded the work done on the same subject during 1919. As at present outlined the work of this Bureau calls for an increase during the next two years and it is be - lieved that this can be accomplished, particularly, in regard to work of inspection. In order to increase the laboratory work it will be necessary, as has been pointed out before, to materially increase the staff employed </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT there Such laws as the Food and Drugs Act, Commercial Feeding Stuffs, Live Stock Remedies, Paint and Oil and Fertilizer are primarily dependent on the chemist's analysis for their proper and effective en - forcement. Several amendments to the present laws enforced by this Bureau have been introduced during this session of the legislature. It is hoped that these will receive favorable attention as they are designed in all instances to strengthen and support the existing laws so that they may be enforced with fairness to all concerned. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Bureau of Markets and Marketing ORGANIZATION AND DUTIES In the organization of the Bureau of Markets and Marketing there was assigned to this Bureau for enforcement the laws relating to Weights and Measures, Agricultural Seeds, Potato Grading and Cold Storage. The Bureau also does a certain amount of educational and research work, such as the collecting of agricultural statistics through data obtained from the county and precinct assessors, the Federal and State cooperative crop reporting and considerable research and investigational work relating to production and distribution of agricultural products. The laws relating to Weights and Measures and which pertain par - ticularly to the inspection of weighing and measuring devices, the laws providing for the regulation and testing of, agricultural seeds and the enforcement of cold storage provisions were formerly enforced by the Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Commission. It was found advisable that these activities be assigned to the Bureau of Markets and Marketing. Potato grading in car lot shipments at point of origin was first attempted during the period of the world war as a food measure. The 1919 Session of the Legislature passed a compulsory Potato Grading Law hut for which no appropriation was made to put the same into effect. By assigning this work to this Bureau it was enforced with very little ad - ditional expense owing to the fact that regular employees could super - vise the field inspections. The agricultural statistics of the State were collected in a syste - matic manner for the first time in the year 1913. These statistics relate to agricultural production as well as census data of live stock on the farm. These statistics are collected by the precinct assessors at the time their other assessment work is done. The crop reporting service is performed cooperatively through Federal and State activities and in this way information is collected relating to the acreage, condition and yield of crops during the year. Most of this information is obtained through a corps of voluntary observers who report monthly on local conditions. The information is tabulated by counties and also summar - ized for the entire State. Both of the statistical and crop reporting services were formerly conducted by the State Board of Agriculture. Some of the investigational work carried on by the Bureau has in - cluded a comprehensive survey of the cooperative associations in the State. A bulletin has been published on this subject for the year 1919. At the present time material is being collected for the year 1920 and will be published in bulletin form in the near future. This bulletin will be more exhaustive than the previous one, for tho reason that additional </seg>
            <seg id="p033">FIRST BIENNIAL RKPORT 33 information and a more complete analysis of the material is being made. This information is proving of value in the organization of co - operative associations. Other investigations relating to the production of manufactured agricultural products such as those derived from meat production, the dairy industry, the flour milling industry, sugar beet industry, commer - cial feeding stuff and others are being made from time to time so that in - formation and statistics will be available on these subjects. In the past the statistics available relating to these industries have been very lim - ited. During the Fall of 1919 at which time prices were exceedingly high for food products a number of public hearings were held in both Omaha and Lincoln. The intent of these investigations was to determine the exact status of existing conditions with regard to the cost of production cost of distribution and cost to the consumer of different necessary articles of food. A great deal of valuable information was brought out at these hearings and a number of prosecutions were fileu but these did not terminate in convictions. Shortly after thes-e hearings Governor, Samuel R. McKelvie, called a conference of women representing the State Federation of Women's Clubs, the various local clubs and other women's organizations. The concensus of opinion of this conference was to organize a State thrift or economy campaign. Mrs. Evelyn A. Ryan of Grand Island was ap - pointed Director of the Economy Campaign. Shortly afterwards she was also appointed Federal Fair Price Commissioner for Nebraska. This work resulted In an educational campaign of price investigation and to encourage economic and conservative buying. The food inspectors of the Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil as well as the assistants of the Bureau of Markets and Marketing assisted in in - vestigating prices of foods and otherwise cooperating with the Fair Price Commissioner during the period of this campaign. This work was also carried on co-operatively with Federal representatives under the provisions of the Lever Act. Later on this activity was discontinued owing to the fact that it was virtually a war or post-war measure. WEIGHTS AND MEASURES The enforcement of the laws relating to Weights and Measures is a sub-division in the Bureau of Markets and Marketing known as the Division of Weights' and Measures. In view of the fact that this work consists mostly of the inspection of weighing and measuring devices and being of a technical nature, a separate inspection service is main - tained. The men are trained and experienced along mechanical lines and thus competent to make a thorough inspection of the different devices coming to their attention. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">DEPARTMENT OP AdRIfTI-TlRF. 34 The State is divided into a number of territories to each of which an inspector is assigned and is held responsible for the inspection in the territory. An effort is made to inspect once every year the different weighing and measuring devices over which commodities arc bought and sold. These inspections do not include railroad track scales for which the State has no equipment. The inspectors are equipped with one thousand (1000) pounds of heavy test weights consisting of twenty (20) fifty (50) pound units which have been standardized with the standard weights of the State. These are used in making the test3 of the heavier type of scales. In ad - dition to these weights they are supplied with weights of lighter denom - ination and other light equipment for the use of standardizing the lighter type of scales and measuring devices. These men are instructed not to repair scales but in cases where a slight adjustment will make a device register correctly they are authorized to make such adjustment. A table of tolerances similar to the tolerances adopted by the Federal Bureau of Standards has been adopted for the State and any weighing or measuring device not coming within these tolerance* is condemned for use, a condemned tag being placed upon the device pro - hibiting its us« until it is properly repaired. After such repair* or adjustments have been made the owner of the device must notify the Department to the effect that to the best of his knowledge the device is registering correctly upon which a release for the use of the same is granted subject to the repairs or adjustments which have been made. If the owner of a condemned device fails to notify the Department at the end of a month that the same has been repaired and adjusted, the Department sends a notice that the device remains condemned on the records unless advice is sent to the contrary. In the past few years the automobile truck has come into common use which will necessitate the installation of larger capacity scales than were formerly used. The old type of wagon scales used in the past were usually of about a four (4) ton capacity type, which when used for the weighing of heavily loaded trucks frequently exceeds the ca - pacity of the stale as well as having the tendency to throw the scale out of adjustment. To take care of the heavier loads it will be necessary to replace these wagon scales with the ten (10) ton truck type. This is being done in many sections cf the State especially where considerable grain is hauled to the elevators by truck. In order that a more reliable test may be made for truck scales as well as grain and hopper scales it is essential that the inspectors be supplied with additional test weights. Even with a maximum of five thousand (5000) pounds of test weights in many instances this would be insufficient to provide the proper load approximating the capacity of the scale. For this reason it would be advisable for the Department to secure a number of trucks capable of transporting five thousand (5000) pounds ot test weights thus reducing the expense of transporting these </seg>
            <seg id="p035">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT weights by rail as well as eliminating drayage. In addition the truck itself could be used as part of the load in testing wagon and truck scales. In the case of grain or hopper scales it is necessary to increase the load by a number of draughts of grain besides the use of the test weights. There has been an increasing demand on the part of grain elevator operators that their scales be tested twice a year. Furthermore, that the test be made in such a way that it will meet with the requirements of the Interstate Commerce Commission specifications. If this were done the weights over such scales could be used as a basis of complaints for short weights as compared with the weights at point of destination. If this service is to be rendered, it will be necessary to increase the fees charged for this line of inspection work, especially is this true, as the present fees are insufficient to make the inspection work self sustaining as it defrays only about two-thirds of the expense incurred by this ac - tivity. In most cases when weighing or measuring devices have been con - demned by inspectors, it has been a lack of knowledge on the part of the owner that the device was incorrect. There are many devices exceeding the tolerances by over weight or over volume which will bear out this statement. This condition can undoubtedly be attributed to a lack of knowledge as to the construction and sensibility of the device as well as proper care and adjustment of the instrument. The 1919 Session of the Legislature in amending the Weights and Measures Law also passed a provision requiring all dry commodities to be sold by weight or numerical count. Considerable publicity was given to this new provision of the law and at the present time is generally obsarved. Whenever violations are found it is usually due to ignorance of this provision of the statute on the part of the proprietor or his em - ployees. The following table is a summary of the weighing and measuring devices "Sealed" and "Condemned" during the past Biennium: WEIGHTS &amp; MEASURES INSPECTIONS SEALED Hopper Scales Platform Scales Wagon Scales Dormant Scales Automatic Scales Counter Scales Stock Scales Total Scalts Sealed Weights Measures Pumps Slot Weighing Machines Total Inspected and Sealed... Deo. 1, 1(118 Dec. 1, 1919 413 2,876 1,504 110 179 4.262 346 9.690 771 863 1,593 177 13,094 .'I Dec. 1, 1019 ti&gt; Doc. 1. iulm 41' 1 3,374 1,066 86 lot 5.191 519 11.665 80 471 1,038 294 13,548 Total for Bicnniun 834 6,250 3,470 196 287 9,453 865 21,355 851 1.334 2,631 471 26,642 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total AGRICULTURAL STATISTICS The statutes provide that agricultural statictisc shall be collected by county and precinct assessors at the time their regular assessments are made and this data is then sent to the Department of Agriculture to be tabulated, summarized and analyzed. In many cases this information is very incomplete and as a consequence it is necessary that estimates be made to complete this information. It is essential that more stringent legislation be passed so that these statistics will be more complete and reliable. The Department is also authorized to gather such other agricultural information as may be deemed of value for public distribution. In pur - suance with these requirements this Bureau during the short time which it has functioned has had in charge the issuance of summarized agri - cultural statistical reports, the dissemination of information pertaining to agricultural subjects in general, and the answering of inquiries re - lating to these subjects. In this connection considerable investigational work, ab applying to cooperative marketing organizations has been con - ducted and these various activities have received particular considera - tion For ready reference in the answering of inquiries pertaining to agricultural subjects, a filing system for bulletins, crop reports, books, newspapers, etc., has been established together with a corresponding card index file on these subjects. A complete mailing list of agricul - tural organizations, as well as individuals engaged in various lines of agricultural pursuit, has also been established. All of tnis reference matter together with a large amount of data relating to agricultural subjects in general has been obtained through questionnaires and per - sonal correspondence and tabulated in index form for use in future pub - licity and investigational work. The "From the Farm to the City" movement tendency continues to be one of the urgent present day agricultural problems and special emphasis has been placed on the analysis of this condition and the CONDEMNED r..\ l -&gt; i to Dec. 1, 1919 4 to Dec. 1. 1M0 18 for Biennium 23 Hopper Scales Platform Scales Wagon Scales Dormant Scales Automatic Scales Counter Scales Stock Scales Total Scales Condemned lm; 14.-, ti 120 181 ■2 SSI 126 8 6 7 1:1 4.VJ 836 T90 77 11 '.I l'.M, T98 790 1,588 Weights S3 in T2 Measures _ Pumps Total Inspected and Condemned .. B9 116 104 -,4 no 134 '♦lit 1,034 1,998 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">FIRST BIENNIAL REPOR' results obtained thereby nave received widespread publicity. Both the producer and the consumer are keenly interested in cost of production figures inasmuch as this is the basis on which the relative market prices are placed. Authentic data of this kind is continuously gathered and periodically published in order that a more complete understanding ol these problems may be obtained. Qiipstinnnaires relating to the production, manufacture and storage of various' agricultural products such as dairy products, eggs, meats and cold storage goods, etc., have proven to be a satisfactory means for se - curing authentic data which is of value to the agricultural interests of this State. Other data relating to the activities' of the Nebraska Game and Fish Commission since the time of its organization in 1879 Is also being secured and tabulated. The investigational activities conducted by this Bureau include an extensive investigation of cooperative associations. About five-hun - dred (500) complete replies in the form of questionnaires have been re - ceived, analyzed, tabulated and published in bulletin form. This bulle - tin accordingly contains information of business vulue to cooperative organizations and more extensive additional information of this kind is being gathered and compiled at the present time. The following tables show a summary of the questionnaires and an analysis of the concerns that h««; rendered this information: SUMMARY OF REPLIES RECEIVED FROM QUESTIONNAIRES SENT TO FARMERS COOPERATIVE ASSOCIATION'S .^umrwr or completed quest lonnaires 520 Number tabulated ■ iiccAvr 4H5 Number who returned profits on &gt;toek basis only ■ *r*a in Number who returned profits on patronage* baiii A AX 374 Fotal capital stock. Ill firms (nun patronage) Fotal rapital stock. )74 firms (patronage) * 886.260.00 $ 6,491,886.00 Maximum int. rest paid on (took, 4H5 firms Minimum interest paid on stock 2(1% 3% \veraKe interest paid on stock *» yr 8% ■Total iKirrowed capital. Ill firms ■Total borrowed capital. 374 firms Fotal volume of business. Ill firms o TO * 1.385.481.00 » 4,358.487.00 $25,222,665.00 ■Total volume of business. 374 firms Maximum intercut paid on loans Minimum interest paid on loans $87,147,404.00 107o 5% Vveraxre Interest paid on loans dumber who have reserve fund 7%% 389 V'umber not having reserve fund ■ «»O» 116 lowest par value per share Higfcnt par value per share UD $ 5.00 S 225 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 DKPARTMKNT OF AGRICULTl'RE COOPERATIVE CONCERNS (Separated according to commodity sion and went into effect on July 18th of that year. The Bureau of Markets and Marketing was not organized until the Civil Administra - tive Code became effective, consequently the Bureau was materially handicapped in perfecting the inspection organization for that season. This work was greatly improved during the present season, and while there is still room for further improvement, the results in general have been quite satisfactory. Twenty-six (26) inspectors are now stationed at the various prin - cipal shipping points and are supervising this work in their respective districts. The inspectors are- required to make careful examination by analyzing representative samples from each shipment. A report showing the part of the car from which each sample is taken, the percentage of undersized and otherwise defective potatoes is made, and "Certi - ficates of Inspection" based upon the analysis uinde and thus establish the grade for each car lot. It is desirable that amendments be made to the law authorizing the Department to promulgate rules and regulations for the enforcement of this measure. Such provisions would make the law more flexible and also provide for the shipment of seed potatoes or undergrades in years when the potato crop might be of an inferior quality. (Separated according to commodity handled) ing .('&lt; l T 8INESS NUMBER Elevators 250 Grain 46 Grain, Flour A Coal 34 Grain ft Coal 75 Grain, Coal &amp; Marhini-ry . 32 Grain &amp; Live Stools iSo Grain, Coal tc Live Stock 27 Grain, Machinery A Live Stock ,■■■ 2 drain &amp; Farm supplies 9 Elevators and Lumber Yards 87 Grain, Live Stock, Coal Mchy. and Bid*. Material 33 Grain, Coal and Building Material 54 Elevators and Stores 39 Grain, Live Stock, Coal, Machinery * Mdse 34 (•rain and Merchandise 5 Elovators, LiimlxT Yards and Merchandise 6 Grain, Live Stock, Coal. Mchy.. Bids. Material and Mdse 6 Implement House — Machinery 7 Creamery — Dairy Products 10 8tore — General Mdse and Machinery 85 Mill and Elevator — Flour 1 Stock Yards — Live Stock 1 LiinilH-r Yard — Building Material t Coal - 4 Miscellumttus 4 POTATOES — GRADING OF CAR LOT SHIPMENTS The Potato Grading Law was enacted by the 1919 Legislative Ses- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 F1KST B1KNNIAL REPORT • Any grades below the established United States Standards should only be permitted in case of emergency as otherwise a practice of this kind would be a direct reflection upon the quality of any potatoes for which a reputation had been established by the industry in the State. The records on file show that 905 car loads were Grade No. 1 and 812 cars were Grade No. 2 or total of 1718 inspections for the 1919 season It is estimated that approximately 3000 carload inspections will be made during me 1920 season. The following table is a record of inspection reports on file January 1, 1921 for car lot shipments made during the present season. It will be noted that up to this time u total of 2022 inspections have been made and that this classification shows 143;&gt; Grade No. 1 cars, 558 Grade No. 2 cars and 17 cars of mixed grades and that out or the total number only 12 reinspections were requested; ten (10) of the original grades were were changed as a result of these reinspection {^inspections Total Inspections, January 1, 1921 POTATOES — CAR LOT SHIPMENTS — SEASON 1920-1 192 (Record of Inspection Reports on file Jan. 1, 1921) CRADK (iRADE MIXKI) DISTHKT NO. 1 NO. 2 CARS TOTAI Alliance 99 79 1 179 Angora 2 2 Bayard 37 4 Bclmont 3 1 II Broadwatrr Bridgeport 1 ' 2 Chadnin 1 1 Clinton 44 2:1 I 71 Crawford 1 1 2 Gordon 115 HI HitrriHon '- &gt;&gt; Hay Springs 5!) :)9 98 Heniingford 162 51 3 216 Henry 69 69 Kearney 272 27 1 Kimlmll 35 9 2 300 Hi Lisco •• 1 7 Long Pino -1 111 132 Marsland 33 6 39 Miuatare 34 1 35 Horrid 171 15 Mitchell 153 31 2 Kushville 65 411 S&lt; (ittsl)luff 44 2 186 L8« 105 4'i Sidney Yockey 5 H TOTAL 1.435 558 17 13 2,010 i" ia </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 DEPARTMENT OK AGRICULTURE The term "Cold Storage" is defined by law to mean the holding of articles of food for more than sixty (60) days at a temperature of forty degrees (40°) Fahrenheit or below. The concerns conducting a business of this kind are required to obtain annual operating and inspection licenses and to make quarterly reports of cold storage holdings to this office. These statements are itemized by lot numbers, units, articles, quantity and entry dates. The law provides a limit of twelve (12) monhs for holding! food in cold storage, unless an extension of time is granted by this Department. In cases where an extension of time on any article is desired the operator is required to make a written request to that effect whereupon an examination of the food in question is made and if found in good condition a short time extension is granted; if conditions do not warrant an extension of time the immedi - ate withdrawal of such foods is demanded. Inspections of cold storage warehouses are made at three (3) months intervals. The inspector is required to make complete reports relating to sanitation of storage facilities, condition and labeling of food articles in storage and corresponding office records thereof. At the present time thirty -five (35) concerns are licensed to operate cold storage warehouses in this State. Some of the larger plants require as much as two (2) days time for each investigation and inspection. It is highly desirable that certain changes be made in the Cold Storage Law in order to enable the Department to exercise closer supervision and regulation of this industry. "Cold Storage" should be applied to mean the storing of food articles in a warehouse for over thirty (30) days, under a refrigeration temperature of forty-five (45") degrees Fahrenheit or below. All goods placed in a cold storage ware - house should be marked with entry dates and if stored for more than thirty (30) days should be marked with dates of withdrawal when released from storage and be plainly labeled "Cold Storage Goods" when placed on the market for sale. The Department should have authority to demand the withdrawal of food which is unwholesome or stored for the purpose of fictitiously increasing prices. 11 E. I .N PI 'IV Shipping Point Terminal Kearney Omaha Kearney Omaha Original Grade 1 1 Final Grade Causes 0 Scab '-lid. growth, cuts O Sritt) 2nd. growth, cuts Kearney Omaha Rushviile Omahil Ruahville Omaha Long Pine Omaha Lonj Pine Omaha Alliance Omaha Scottebluff Lincofn llinatare Lincoln Hsmingford Salem Minatare Lincoln 1 1 2 ■i 1 1 1 1 1 0 Scab 2nd. growth, cuts 2 Scab 2nd. growth, cuta 2 Orig. Insp. Sustained 0 Scab 2nd. growth, cuts 0 Scab •"•• growth, cuts 2 Scab 2nd. growth, cuts 2 Hasted in Transit 2 Scab 2nd. growth I) Scab 2nd. growth 1 Orig. Insp. Sustained COLD STOI RAGE </seg>
            <seg id="p041">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 41 The following table shows a brief summary of the extensiveness of this industry as summarized from the quarterly reports submitted to this office during the past Biennium: ARTICLES OF FOOD IN COLD STORAGE AGRICULTURAL SEEDS The Seed Law provides for the inspection and regulation of the sale of seed in the State and requires the Department of Agriculture to maintain a laboratory where tests are made free of charge for the residents of the State. The seed testing work for the past two years has been of material benefit to the farmer, inasmuch as the greater number of samples tested came from the farmers of Nebraska, and in - formation has been given them direct. In each instance farmers were particularly interested. Furthermore, it has been useful in giving a knowledge of the value of pure and gerniinable seeds and the informa - tion which should be expected from the merchant from whom seed is being purchased. The purity reports have also given farmers an idea of the weed seeds they are most apt to find in certain commercial agricultural seeds which would mature and be harvested with the crop. Other weed seeds they realize could not be so found unless it was in com - petition with the crop in the field, and a further study would give a clue to adulterated seeds. When weed seeds or other crop seeds which do not compete and mature with a particular crop are found present, it is an indication that one of three conditions exists: 1. The seeds have been mixed in the cleaning process; 2. Mixed to produce certain grades or so called "brands 3. Adulterated with some inferior seed or other material such as inert matter or seed cleanings. Date Jan. 1, 1919 Pickled Meals Pounds 2.141,06" Fresh Meats Pounds 4,746,833 Fish Pounds 44,473 Jan. 1, 1920 1,240,886 8,386,328 180,136 April 1, 1919 April 1. 1920 July 1. 1919 July 1, 1920 5.489,883 1:1.249,466 1,346,694 7,672,175 7,138.695 7,344,738 3,040,129 4.831,912 142,090 141,728 157,421 156,679 Oct. 1, 1919 14. 426. '.117 1,739,212 288.051 Oct. 1, 1920 3,268,556 2,665,219 112,284 Date Beverages Barrels KiTU's C;ims Apples Barrels Mis.-. Pounds Jan. 1, 1919 Jan. 1, 1920 April 1, 1919 April 1, 1920 416 285 386 348 1.249 34.965 4.620 7.368 32,824 60,419 3,152 17,428 6,489,555 4.483,916 9,934,344 2,171,988 July 1, 1919 July 1, 1920 Oct. 1, 1919 41(6 1.4411 1&lt;&lt;7 223,564 169,937 159,176 6(16 135 2,492 8,559,959 4.070,119 13,808,391 Oct. 1. 1920 208 148,401 246 4,178,513 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE During the early part of the Biennium bulletin No. 101 entitled "Nebraska Weeds" was published by the Department, in which thirty - six (36) of Nebraska's most common weeds and their seeds were described, illustrated by drawings and means . of eradication of such pests discussed. There are a few copies of this- publication remaining which may be secured by making request to the Department. During the past two years trade has been re-established with Europe bringing to this country a flood of such seeds as clovers and alfalfa which could not be used there for food and had accumulated in the war torn countries, especially in Italy. Great quantities of such seeds have been sold in this country, often being represented as home grown. Sometimes it has been found to be mixed with home grown seed or seed containing Russian thistle seeds to give it the appearance of being native. This is, however, a great detriment to purchasers who are so unfortunate as to secure Italian grown seed as it is not ac - climated to this country and readily winter kiHs in this latitude. There has been made 1103 purity and 2642 germination reports on 37 different kinds of seeds with a total of 3745 samples tested during the past two years. The reports sent from the Department to those who avail themselves of the privilege of the free seed tests, give the follow - ing information: 1. Percentage of pure seeds 2. Percentage of foreign seeds 3. Percentage of dirt and other inert matter found in the sample 4. Names' of weed seeds found in the sample 5. Approximate number per pound of each of the various kinds of weed seeds found in the sample 6. Approximate number per pound of other seeds found in the sample , 7. Name of the other seeds found in the sample 8. Percentage of germination of seeds 9. In Alfalfa and clover samples the percentage of hard seeds present. The following table Rives the number of analyses made during the past Biennium: Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1!)19 Total to to for Dec. 1. 1919 Dec. 1, 1020 Biennium Inspections sa 1 ■a Germination Tests Purity Analyses Identification of Plant 1.586 1.056 2.642 1,103 57 '.I 534 :il Identification of Seeds 14 11 25 Grand Total 2,233 1,623 3,856 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">FIRST BIKXNIAL RF.PORT 43 SUMMARY During the coming Biennium it is the intent to organize the most efficient service to render market reports and information to the pub - lic. If possible the arrangement will be on a cooperative basis with Federal Bureau of Markets. In this manner the service would include more general information than if limited to the State alone. Special investigations relating to marketing problems and condi - tions will be made from time to time as deemed necessary or ad - visable. Every possible assistance will be given the producer and consumer in the organization of and operation of cooperative markets and otherwise aid in reducing the cost of distribution of food products. The Division of Weights and Measures will gradually be supplied with trucks for the transportation of the equipment used by inspectors in performing this work. In this manner the testing of weighing and measuring devices should not only be performed more rapily but also more efficiently. As mentioned before in relation to this work the amount of test weights have been inadequate to give the proper test to the larger types of scales. In the potato inspection work it is the intent to perfect this service from year to year so that it will be most dependable and reliable to both grower and dealer. In this manner a reputation will be established for the Nebraska product in any of the larger terminal markets of the country. The establishing and adopting of grades and packs for vege - tables and fruits should receive attention and through conferences with growers and dealers should be adopted. In the matter of agricultural seeds the present law on this subject is not very satisfactory. It is hoped that a new measure will be passed by the legilsature which will give more information to the buyer of seeds, as to germination and purity and at the same time be fair to both farmer and dealer. It is hoped that the farmer will patronize the free seed testing service more generally than has been the case in the past. This should be done by the individual farmer or through the county agent. During the next Biennium more attention will be given to the matter of publicity, especially as relating to the different phases of agriculture and the natural resources of the Stale. As the Bureau of Markets and Marketing develops it will be the best agency in the State to collect and publish this information. For this reason producers organizations as well as dealers organization should use this bureau as a clearing house for disputes and should rely on this agency for their official information relating to production and consumption. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Division of Game and Fish ORGANIZATION AND DUTIES This activity was formerly carried on by the Fish and Game Com - mission. Under the reorganization the activity was merged with others in the Department and was designated as the Division of Game and Fish. This Division is not classed under a Bureau but the chief is directly responsible to the Secretary of the Department. In the past the game and fish work was more or less segregated. The game work consisting of the issuing of game licenses and the en - forcement of previsions of the Game and Fish Laws were in the direct charge of the Chief Game Warden. The fish culture and distribution of fish was supervised by the superintendent of the Gretna Hatchery. The principal objection to this manner of conducting these activities was that the records relating to the fish hatchery work were not available in a central office. An attempt is being made to centralize this work as much as possible in the office of this Division at the State House. From an economic standpoint it would be a distinct advantage that men trained in the enforcement of these laws should also be trained in fish culture and conservation work so that they may be interchanged from one to the other, in this manner providing permanent employment and securing more highly trained men. It is impossible to secure the serv - ices of competent men for short periods of time and if it were such men would not be familiar with the nature of the work they were called upon to perform. This feature has been very objectionable in the past Biennium. Under the present organization of the Division the following sub - divisions have been made: Division of Inspection and Control Division of Conservation and Distribution Gretna Hatchery Valentine Hatchery Benkelman Hatchery INSPECTION AND CONTROL The inspection and control of this Division consists of the enforce - ment of provisions of the Game and Fish Laws. During certain periods of the year there are many more violations than there are at other times, this being true during the Spring of the year when the flight of migra - tory game birds is northward and again for a period of several months before the open season for game birds in the Fall of the year. It is dur- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 45 ing these periods that it is necessary to materially increase the number of Deputy Game Wardens in order that proper enforcement may be obtained. The number of Wardens in the field have a direct bearing on the number of game licenses issued. For this reason ample funds should be available to thoroughly cover the various sections of the State and with this idea in view numerous attempts have been made to have the fees collected by this Division used for the enforcement and development of the game and fish work. At other seasons of the year Deputy Game Wardens are used for the investigation of applications for permit to destroy beaver. This is done to ascertain the extent of the damage done and to determine if a permit should be issued. In all cases such permits are issued for a limited period but at the same time the land owner is given an opportunity to destroy a sufficient number of animals so that further destruction may &gt;&gt;e eliminated. The following tables give the number and nature of the various violations and the special permits which were issued during the past The number of licenses for hunting and fishing privileges have steadily increased from year to year. This is especially true since a policy of more rigid law enforcement has been adopted. The following table gives the fees collected during the past Biennium. These fees are deposited in the State Treasury for the School Fund. Biennium : VIOLATIONS Dec. 1. 1918 to Deo. 1. 1919 Dec. 1. 1919 to Dec. 1, 192(1 Total for Biennium Violations of Migratory Bird Law 108 96 204 Hunting without a License 38 ■;- ?.-&gt; Fishing without a License 26 139 165 Fishing illegally 17 Illegal Trapping 8 ",4 17 71 25 Shooting after Sunset 4 4 Grand Total 197 :;17 ", 14 Arrests without Conviction 6 '.I 15 Arrests with Conviction 191 138 .".-.Ml PERMITS Dec. 1, 1918 to Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1919 to Dec. 1, 1920 Total for Biennium To Destroy Beaver 50 To Transport Beaver Hides 1 To Destroy Muskrats out of Season 9 Scientific Permits 19 Seining Permits 4 Grand Total 83 82 111 1 I ■1 Km 132 112 1" 22 6 282 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE FEES COLLECTED Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Total LICENSES to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dee. 1, 1920 Biennium Resident-Hunting k Fishing $ 48,099.00 $ 62,427.87 $110,526.8 Non-Resident-Hunting It Fishing 920.00 1.390.00 2.310.00 NouResident Fishing „ _... 872.00 1,048.0(1 1,920.00 wident Trapping 2,176.00 2,145.37 4,321.37 Non-Reaident Trapping _ 10.00 20.00 30.00 Fishing-Missouri River 235.10 205.25 440.35 Grand Total $ 52,312.10 &gt; 67,236.49 $119,548.59 CONSERVATION AND DISTRIBUTION During the new Biennium particular attention will be given to the conservation ot fish from lakes, ponds and overflows in which the water may become so low at certain periods of the year that the fish will perish unless they are removed to other lakes or streams. This is a very im- portant feature of the conservation work for the reason that large quan- tities of fish may oftimes be conserved having a material food value be- sides providing sport for the licensed angler. During the past year a condition of this kind arose but the funds available were inadequate to properly carry on the work. For this reason it became necessary to re- sort to volunteer help by way of individuals offering their services in actually seining, sorting and perparing the fish for distribution. The fish that were conserved in this way were then offered to com- munities which were interested in obtaining them in car load shipments and usually city authorities or some organization would finance the ex- pense incurred by transportation of the fish car. Under these conditions eight (8) car loads were conserved from the overflows in the lowlands north of Peru. These car lot shipments were distributed as follows : Carter Lake, Omaha 3 car loads Sand pits in vicinity of Fremont 2 car loads Stromsburg 1 car load Wayne 1 car load The fish consisted largely of bullheads and croppies. The total num- ber and species conserved and distributed in these shipments are as follows : While the conservation work was rather limited owing to funds 1 for this purpose, nevertheless, one or two men were stationed in the yicinity lock Bass 2,000 lullheads 185,500 iunflsh 13,900 'roppies 20,000 Hack Bass 3,000 ToUl 224,400 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 riRST BIENNIAL REPORT of Carter Lake near Omaha during the summer of 1920, whose duty it was by means of screens to prevent fish from escaping from Carter Lake during the period of floods and high water. As the waters receded many of the small fish in the surrounding lowlands were conserved and placed back in Carter Lake. FISH HATCHERIES There are now three (3) fish hatcheries in the State of Nebraska, In addition to the established stations at Gretna and Valentine the 1919 Session of the Legislature provided an appropriation for the purchase and maintenance of a hatchery in Dundy County. In view of the fact that a hatchery already existed near Benkelman in this County and that the same could be purchased for less money than one couid be estab - lished, this was purchased for the sum of $7,500.00. Considerable im - provements have been made at this hatchery, the capacity of the ponds has virtually been increased about one-third. The property will have to be fenced and other improvements to buildings will be necessary to place them in good condition. The permanent improvements provided for by appropriation for the Gretna and Valentine stations by the last legislature have practically been completed. Owing to the high cost of material and labor there was not as much accomplished in repairs to buildings, ponds and improve - ments to grounds as had formerly been done with similar appropriations for a two year period. At the Valentine hatchery a new pond of about ten acres in area has been constructed and will be available for the coming season. This addition to the pond area at this hatchery will materially increase the production of fish available for distribution. The distribution of fish is somewhat below the amount distributed in former biennial periods but this is largely due to the fact that the num - ber of pike in the fry stage was not so great because the supply of eggs was not available. As there has been some question as to the future returns of pike being commensurate with actual number planted, this decrease would have very little bearing on the total distribution. It is customary to plant most of the trout, black bass and pike in the fry stage, which is the period when these fish are from two to six weeks old. The results obtained in this way depend largely upon the vitality of the small fish and the conditions under which they are transplanted. Under favorable conditions the number surviving would be much greater than if the reverse were true. The kinds of fish best adapted to the waters in this State, as proven by experience, are black bass, croppies, perch and catfish. These have been produced in greater numbers than in previous bienniums. The dis - tribution of these together with the fish conserved from overflows will be of material benefit in the permanent stocking of the better lakes and abandoned sand pits which are bound to become a permanent use for fish depositories. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 48 An effort is being made to encourage communities through their councils or through some commercial or social organization to take an interest in having sand pits, from which sand has formerly been taken and which has left these ponds with a good supply of water, stocked with the kinds of fisfa best adapted for such conditions. In this way the State can stock these pits at very little expense because the fish can be sup- piled in car lot shipments. These pits make splendid depositories' as the depth provides ample protection against the angler taking out fish in great numbers and consequently they will attain greater size. This will not cnly provide sport and recreation for the public but will eventually add to the food supply which may be derived from this source. Should the funds be sufficient to extend this development work during the coming Biennium an attempt will be made whereby different communities can cooperate with the State in developing possible nurseries or lakes upon a co-operative basis. The intent would be to have a locality furnish the site and land by possibly deeding it to the State and the Department could then develop the same at a small ex- pense and afterwards stock it with the proper species of fish best adapted to the conditions. There are at this time a number of localities which would be willing to operate under a plan of this kind. The material advantage to be obtained under a plan of this kind would be that the people of the community would be much more interested in de- veloping a proposition of this 1 kind and the State would be assured that the benefits accrued would be of more general interest and the results much more satisfactory than in the past. The following table gives the distribution of the various kinds of fish from the different hatcheries during the past Biennium: GRETNA Dec. 1. 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Tout to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 192(1 Biennium Brook Trout _ 170,300 245,000 415.300 Rainbow Trout ..._ 159,500 177,900 337.400 Brown Trout _ 10,000 10.000 Black Bus (Large Mouth) — 47,400 263.400 310,801 Black Bass (Small Mouth) 6,000 125,000 131, Striped Perch 44,800 17,100 61,900 Croppies _ 65,700 75,400 141,100 Channel Catnsh _ 18,100 18,820 31,920 Sunfish 16,500 34,600 51,100 ■«** Baas 750 6,400 7,150 Tallow Bullheads — 133,800 155,050 288,850 Wall-eyad Pike _ 2,100,820 2,000,000 4,100,820 Bull Frogs . — _ _ 6,000 32,000 38,000 German Carp 22,700 22,700 Buffalo Fish _ 4,100 4,100 Sheepshead 1,000 1,000 Goldfish 3,060 930 3,990 Grand Total , 2,810,580 3,146,600 5,957.130 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT VALENTINE Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 ToUl to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Biennium Brook Trout 155,000 172,000 327 Rainbow Trout 150,000 95,000 245,1 Striped Perch 79,2n(i 66.450 145,650 Croppies 38,400 11,650 48 27,520 9,850 37,37( Black Bass (Large Mouth) Black Bass (Small Mouth) Simfish 4,700 4,300 9,0 ,gs 39,000 3 Bull Frog Kock Bai .tin 6' Grand ToUl 494,520 367.rt5i&gt; 86! BENKELMAN Dec. 1. 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Total to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Biennium Black Km- . Striped Percli Rock Bass ... 6,325 6.325 12,200 15 Sunfish Croppic 53 Grand ToUl 77:, be much more interested in fishing The public in general seems to than was the case a few years ago. This is undoubtedly caused by the general use of the automobile as the more remote hunting and fishing grounds are now more accessible to the average individual. For this reason it has become necessary that more drastic law enforcement be re - sorted to in order that the hunting and fishing may be preserved more permanently than could otherwise be done. It is for this reason that a greater number of deputy game wardens will be necessary so that violations will be held at a minimum, in this way the game and fish will be more preserved for future generations but still provide the best of sport in a limited way to the sportsmen of the present day. It may be said that this is being done as the violations, especially as applying to the migratory flight of game birds during the spring of the year, has been materially reduced. Furthermore, that the fishing laws during the summer are being more closely observed and that violations of the hunt - ing laws prior to the opening of the season in the fall of the year are not as prevalent as in the past. Public sentiment is more in favor of law enforcement as relating to the game laws and the violator or poacher is more easily prosecuted than was formerly the case. SUMMARY During the next Biennium a particular effort will be made to con - serve in as large quantities as possible, fish from overflows, ponds and streams when these dry up to such an extent, that the fish therein will perish. These fish so taken will then be redistributed to the more per- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE manent lakes and streams, thus providing sport to the fisherman and at the same time conserving a product having considerable food value. Through the co-operation of local communities it is expected to de - velop the most suitable sites for nursery ponds and other sites possible of development into permanent lakes. The plan would be for the com - munity to donate the site to the State and the State in turn to develop the same and stock it with fish. This plan has been carried out near Royal in Antelope County in establishing a trout nursery pond. A more rigid enforcement of the Game and Fish Laws must be im - posed from year to year in order that .the preservation of this natural resource may be more permanent and yet provide the best recreation for hunter and fisherman by permitting him to take game and fish at certain seasons of the year in limited quantities under certain restrictions. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Clerical and Records Division The Clerical and Records Division includes the entire clerical per - sonnel of the various Bureaus and Divisions of the Department. This does not mean that the clerical force in a Bureau is not under the direct supervision o* the chief of the bureau but general supervision is provided whereby the chief of the Clerical and Records Division can transfer help from one Bureau or Division to another and in this way take care of in - creased work in one activity when possibly some other activity has less work than usual. This method has proven very satisfactory and in cases where work is of an emergency nature it is possible to concentrate con - siderable help on one subject. While the records of the different activities are closely confined to the specific Bureaus or Divisions, nevertheless, the general bookkeeping, the time and traveling expense of both office and field forces as well as the securing and distribution of supplies is carried on by the Clerical and Records Division. In this way there is more uniformity of printed forms for the different lines of work. The system also provides for the regulating of the inspectors in the various field services as to their rout - ing and checking of the expense incurred in the performance of the field work. This has had a tendency to establish an average expense for the different activities in the field so that they can be compared monthly and this expense held at a minimum. All supplies needed in the Department are purchased through the Purchasing Agent and funds available for the purpose are encumbered at the time the requisition for supplies is made. The Clerical and Records Division is held responsible to see that these supplies are prop - erly obtained through the Purchasing Agent, that the same are correct when delivered and are also distributed to the various bureaus or indi - viduals as required by them in the performance of their duties. As for the printing, standard forms and form numbers are provided so that whenever a certain form has been exhausted it is an easy matter to know the number that should be reordered for a definite period of time. This practice eliminates waste and prevents the ordering of large quanti - ties of supplies for long periods which may become obsolete before the supply has been exhausted. This Division is also responsible for the issuing of licenses, certifi - cate of registration and the keeping of all general records of the De - partment. This work has been standardized in such a way that the forms used for this purpose are similar so that the records can all be easily filed and are thus available for ready reference. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICTJLTURE 52 The collecting of all fees for such licenses, registrations and inspec- tions' are collected and periodically deposited with the State Treasurer. The Bureaus of Food, Drugs and Oil and Markets and Marketing are self supporting and the fees collected by these Bureaus are appropriated for carrying on the work of these activities during the Biennium. The following tables include the various licenses and certificates of registration issued and the fees collected during the past Biennium: LICENSES AND PERMITS Dec. 1, 1918 Dee. 1, 1919 Total to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dee. 1, 1920 Biennium Commiuion Merchant* _ 116 132 248 Cold Storage 30 31 61 Call Storage Inspection 30 26 56 Creamery _ _ 70 79 149 Dairy 1,463 2.739 4.202 Babcock Teat _ 2,441 2,433 4,874 Retail lee Cream 64 64 128 Wholesale Ice Cream _ 58 60 118 Condensed Milk PlanU 4 5 9 Cheese Factory 112 Retail Oleomargarine 2,719 3,041 5,760 Wholesale Oleomargarine 26 37 63 Oleomargarine Manufacturers 1 1 Blot Weighing Machines 177 294 471 Grand Total 7,199 8,943 16,142 CERTIFICATES OF REGISTRATION Dec. 1, 1913 Dec. 1, 1919 Totsl to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Biennium Hotel _ 840 752 1,592 Apartment House 131 131 Rooming House 582 554 1;136 Restaurant 2,191 2,405 4,596 Lire Stock Remedy 35 44 7!&gt; Commercial Fertiliser 7 7 14 Hog Cholera Serum _ 21 17 38 8tallion Registration 614 739 1,353 Grand Total 4,421 4,518 8,930 RECEIPTS The Bureau of Food, Drugs and Oil and the Bureau of Markets and Marketing are financed on a fee basis. The legislature appropriating the fees collected or so much thereof as may be necessary for the operation and maintenance of the activities included in these Bureaus. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT 53 The following table gives the fees collected by the Department and the source from which the same are derived: FEES COLLECTED Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 ToUl to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Birnnium Babeock Test * 4,820.00 $ 4,792.00 $ 9,612.00 Cheese Factories 10.00 10.00 20.00 Cold Storage Inspections 765.00 755.00 1,520.00 Commercial Fertilizer 105.00 135.00 240.00 Condenseries ..._ 40.00 40.00 80.00 Copies of Oil Reports 300.00 456.00 756.00 Creameries 1,886.00 1,978.00 3,864.00 Dairy 1,421.00 2,391.00 3,812.00 Feed Analysis 4.00 3.00 7.00 Hotel 8,265.10 8,649.00 16.914.10 Interest on Bank Deposit 1 239.32 280.29 519.61 Live Stock Remedies 205.00 260.00 465.00 Miscellaneous 71.56 218.81 290.37 Oil Inspections ..._ 122,216.62 136,590.10 258,806.72 Retail — Ice Cream 66.00 64.00 130.00 Retail — Oleomargarine 3.49S.40 3,157.00 6,651.40 Sale of Fish 363.70 1,164.83 1,528.53 Stallion Registrations 1,721.50 1,721.50 Commercial Feeding Stuff Tax 5.921.07 4,907.03 10.828.10 Weights and Measures 8,769.01 13,071.50 21.840.51 Wholesale — Ice Cntm 292.11 300.00 592.11 Wholesale — Oleomargarine 708.32 1,075.00 1,783.32 Grand Total ....$159,961.21 $182,021.06 $341,982.27 EXPENDITURES The Bureau of Animal Industry and the Division of Game and Fish have been financed through an appropriation made by the legislature. The following tables give the salary and maintenance expense incurred in the various Bureaus and Divisions of the Department but do not in- clude the money spent for indemnity for diseased live stock or capital outlay for permanent improvements. BUREAU OF FOOD, DRUGS AND OIL Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Total to to for Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1. 1920 Biennium 1. Salaries and Wagea $ 46,558.27 $ 46,992.98 $ 93,551.25 2. Expense 31,244. U0 31,241.02 62.485,92 3. Supplies 3,847.49 3,823.13 7,670.62 4. Repairs for Upkeep 28.59 42.89 71.48 7. Equipment 1,049.48 1,574.22 2,623.70 Grand Total $ 82,728.73 $ 83,674.24 $166,402.97 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF ANIMAL INDUSTRY Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Total for Bicunium to to Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1. 192(1 1. Salaries and Wages .$ 19.944.06 * 26.8(18.74 $ 46.752. 80 2. Expense 19.174.43 16.044.95 35.219.38 3. Supplies 1.883.64 1,188.85 3,072.49 4. Repairs for Upkeep 36.80 55.2H 92.0(1 5. Fixed Charges 13,180.20 19.620.32 32.80* 6. Equipment 556.35 834.53 1,390.88 Grand Total * 54.775.48 $ 64.552.59 $119,328.07 BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total to. tu for Deo. 1, 1919 Deo. 1. 1920 Bienniutn 1. Salaries and Wage* $ ( 6.845.17 $ 20,535. 49 $ 27.38(1.66 2. Expense 7,139.24 21.417.73 28,556.97 S. Supplies 253^78 761.33 1.(115.11 4. Repairs and Upkeep 50.(10 150.00 200.00 50.00 150.00 7. Equipment 411.96 1.235.89 1,647.85 411.96 1.235.89 1,647.85 Grand Total $ f 14.700.15 f 44.100.44 9 58.800. 5» 14.700.15 $ 44.100.44 $ 58.8(1(1.5!) DIVISION OF GAME AND FISH AME AND FISH Dec. 1, 1918 Deo. 1. 1919 Total to to for Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total for to tu Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1. 1920 Biennium Dec. 1, 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Biennium $ 19.571.94 $ 18.464.51 $ 38.036.45 1. Salaries $ 19,571.94 $ 18,464.51 $ 38.036.45 2. Expense 9,555.84 10.664.33 20,220.17 9.555.84 10.664.33 20,220.17 3. Supplies 1.860.23 2.045.41 3.905.64 1.860.23 2,045.41 3.905.64 4. Repairs for Upkeep 2.532.49 2,574.22 5,106.71 532.49 574 5,106.71 5. Fixed Charges 24.00 36.00 60.00 24.00 36.00 60.00 6. Lands and Buildings. 7,014.04 10,521.05 17, 535. Oil 7,014.04 10.521.05 17, 535. Oil 7. Equipment 1.248.35 1.228.11 2,476.46 1.248.35 1.228.11 2.476.46 Grand ToUl _ 9 41,806.89 $ 45,533.63 $ 87.340.52 .$ 41.806.89 9 45.533.63 $ 87.340.52 DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE )F AGRICULTURE Deo. 1. 1918 Dec. 1. 1919 Total to to for Dec. 1. 1919 Dec. 1, 1920 Biennium Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1919 Total to to for 1. Salaries and Wage* 2. Expense .$ 92.919.44 $112,801.72 (205,721.16 .. 67,114.41 79.368.03 146,482.44 3. Supplies 7,845.14 7,818.72 15.663.86 4. Repairs for Upkeefi 5. Fixed Charges 2.647.88 2,822.31 5,470.19 13.204.20 19.656.32 32.860.52 6. Lands and Buildings. 7. Equipment .'. 7.014.04 10,521.05 17,535.09 3.266.14 4.872.75 8.138.89 Grand ToUl $194,011.24 $237,860.90 $371,872.15 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>