<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Essentials of Blackleg Prevention</title>
               <date value="1920-07">1920-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 59 July. 1920 The Essentials of Blackleg Prevention L. Van Es, M.D., V.S. Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTRE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Extension BuixjmN No. 59 2 THE ESSENTIALS OF BLACKLEG PREVENTION L. Vax Es, M. D., .V. S., It so happens that Nebraska lies within the large territory in which the disease blackleg of cattle is a more or less con - stant menace on many farms and cattle ranges. Experienced cattle men always reckon with this fact and as a rule have learned quite thoroly what preventive measures are to be taken. When, however, the disease has not appeared in their herds for a number of years they are apt to become more or less negligent in the matter and for this reason especially it may be wise to again offer a brief review of the more salient facts about the disease so far as they bear directly on its prevention. In blackleg, as in all other preventable diseases, the methods proposed have their foundation on our knowledge regarding its cause. The cause is the blackleg bacillus of which the most im - portant feature is the power of forming spores, a character - istic which it has in common with certain other disease-produc - ing germs. A spore is a small ovoid or spherical body which forms within the bacillus, when certain conditions adverse to the life and development of the bacillus are present. The spore is extremely resistant to such destructive influences as age. antiseptics, heat, etc.. and enables it to conserve the vitality as well as the virulence of the original organism. INFECTION GENERALLY FROM THE SOIL The blackleg bacillus is found in the soil of infected farms aside from the affected tissues of a diseased animal. In blackleg, which may l&gt;e regarded as a true soil disease, the transmission from animal to animal is probablv very ran*. The disease comes about more particularly from infection from the soil. In this the spores remain in a perfectly viable form for indefinite lengths of time. We do not know how long spores will retain their vitality in different types of soil, but for practical purposes it is only safe to assume that a given soil once infected must always lie looked upon with a considerable degree of suspicion. In a pasture for instance in which animnls h»ve died of blackleg the disease is apt to occur at any tim« after, even if there may be intermissions of several years be - tween outbreaks. Some authors believe that the germs can multiply them - selves in certain soils. This is not verv certain, however, in </seg>
            <seg id="p003">E88ENTIAI.S OF BLACKLEG PREVENTION 3 fact it ftfcins improbable, but there can be no doubt of the infection of the soil being constantly replenished by animals dead of the disease which are permitted to decay on the surface. AGE AND SUSCEPTIBILITY Another factor which must be given consideration when we desire to understand the principles upon which preventive measures are based is the relation of the animal's susceptibility to its age. It is a well-known fact that the heaviest blackleg losses always fall upon animals between the ages of six months and two years. It must not be thought, however, that animals younger or older than the age limit mentioned do not tako blackleg. Cases in young calves are by no means rare and outbreaks in cattle older than four years have been observed. The latter outbreaks pertain especially to cattle which have grown up in regions exempt from the disease and which at a later period are brought into infected pastures. We do not know for sure if this influence of age upon the occurrence of blackleg is dependent on a loss of suscepti - bility or on an acquisition of immunity. The influence, how - ever, cannot be denied and as a rule we are justified to cease worrying about the disease when animals have reached the age of approximately two and a half years. ELIMINATING SOURCES OF INFECTION The fact that blackleg is transmitted from the soil and the further fact that infected soil constitutes a more or lee-: permanent source of danger would make the prevention of blackleg exceedingly difficult without more specific preventive measures. Upon the latter we must place our principal reliance, while at the same time it is highly advisable to take into con - sideration such measures as are directly associated with the soil infection. In the first place, we should be active in removing the. main source of soil contamination, and this is, of course, the carcasses of blackleg animals. In the latter there are billions of blackleg germs which are apt to assume by their spore formation a particularly indestructable form. Those spores will still be alive and disease producing long after the carcass has crumbled to dust, and they are the ones which bring about the permanent infection of pasture and range. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bvixetix No. 59 All carcasses should be properly disposed of, but the ones dead of blackleg should receive special attention. Such a carcass should be completely destroyed by burning if at all possible and in case this cannot be done they should be buried deeply. Blackleg carcasses should be destroyed or buried without previous skinning or opening, as the latter manipula - tions only increase the danger of soil contamination. We know that there is a general tendency to neglect these measures and dead animals are often hauled off to an out of the way place or are permitted to decay wherever they happen to drop. This is absolutely wrong because it greatly increases the infection chances for future generations of cattle. Our knowledge of the association of blackleg with the soil also explains why a change of pasture or range is advis - able when the disease makes its appearance. VACCINATION The measures mentioned above are of great importance and when taken are bound to bring about a decline in tlu: prevalence of the disease. Yet without more specific inciiib of prevention blackleg losses would no doubt be quite extensive. The specific means referred to consists in the production of an artificial immunity to the disease. It is commonly known as vaccination. We can now choose between more than ore method of vaccination. One of those methods depends on the injection of the black - leg spores, contained in the muscle of an artificially infected animal and which by the action of heat have been deprived of their disease producing qualities. The product is known as blackleg vaccine and is procurable in the form of powder, or pellets or in the shape of short threads. It is issued, free to catttle owners, bv the IT. S. Department of Agriculture in the shape of a powder and in this form is perhaps the b?st known among preparations of this kind. The government vaccine has been in use since 1896, and in accordance with the government statistics has been used in something like twenty million animals in which the per - centage of loss from blackleg has been reduced to less than one-half of one per cent. The vaccine is issued in the shape of packages of h powder, which is mixed with water and injected in accordance with printed directions. In a publication by the IT. S. Department of Agriculture </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ESSENTIALS OF Ul.ACKI.EG PREVENTION 5 (Circular 31, Nov. 8, 191;"&gt;) the following statements are ina&lt;!t relative to the distribution and use of this vaccine: 1. Owing to the fact that a number of cattle owners have attempted to modify or have otherwise deviated from the printed directions, losses have occurred which might have been . easily avoided. It is therefore urgently recommended to follow the directions implicitly, and especially to refrain from castrating, spaying and dehorning at the time of vaccination. 2. Vaccine which for any reason is not used should be returned to this office immediately. 3. All vaccine should be used within twelve months from the date on the back of each package. After this period has elapsed the vaccine may be used to advantage, in cases of emergency, as a first vaccine, but to insure immunity it is advisable to revaccinate with fresh vaccine in the course of two weeks. 4. The only vaccine distributed by this Department is a single powder vaccine for the prevention of blackleg, and it may be injected at any season of the year. 5. Blackleg vaccine is distributed free of charge to stock owners of the United States. 6. Neither vrccine nor application Minks will be furnished to any person for distribution among others; each stock owner must apply in his own behalf. 7. The immunizing properties of the vaccine are not usually im - parted until ten or twelve days following the vaccination. 8. Deaths of animals within one or two days after vaccination should not be attributed to the vaccine, but to the fact that they were already infected with the disease before vaccination. 9. It is not advisable to vaccinate an animal after the symptoms of blackleg have developed as the vaccine is a preventive and not a curative agent. 10. Vaccination is generally followed by insignificant symptoms. In some cases there is a slight rise of temperature and a minute swelling may sometimes be noted at the point of injection. 11. Calves vaccinated before they are six months old lose the artificial immunity produced, and should be re vaccinated before the beginning of the next blackleg season. 12. Animals which have been vaccinated may be revaccinated after an interval of two weeks without any unfavorable results. 13. It is not advisable to vaccinate pregnant heifers within one month of the time for them to calve. 14. Immunity is not transmitted by the immunized parent to the offspring. 15. Do not vaccinate cattle while they are overheated. 16. Animals should be vaccinated on the side of the neck just in front of the shoulder and always on the same side. 17. The only satisfactory method of administering the vaccine dis - tributed by the Department is by the use of a hypodermic syringe. The method of soaking a cord in our vaccine solution and inserting a portion of the cord under the skin can not be recommended. 18. Anthrax is an entirely different disease from blackleg and there - fore blackleg vaccine does not act as a preventive against anthrax. Anthrax vaccine is not distributed by the Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin No. 59 Within recent years other vaccinating substances have come into use and while those have given the most encouraging re suits and no doubt can be recommended, it must not be forgot - ten that in the government vaccine we have a most efficient means for the prevention of blackleg, which has given perfect satisfaction to thousands of cattle owners during the period of nearly twenty-five years. As already stated certain new substances have come in use for the immunization against blackleg. One of these is known as blackleg aggressin. It is a germ-free, filtered, tissue juice taken directly from the affected muscles of a blackleg animal. This juice contains certain toxic substances which have a vac - cinating power, but it cannot produce disease in the abtoi'ce of the blackleg germ. There is good evidence to show that properly prepared blackleg aggressin, when injected into su - sceptible animals leave a marked degree of immunity and this product has left a large number of practical users well satis - fied. Owing to the rather high price of manufacture the aggressin immunizing agent will always be more costly than other immunizing substances. The other more recently introduced immunizing agent is known as blackleg filtrate. It is prepared from blackleg cul - tures, the fluid portion of which is rendered germ-free by a process of filtration. It is much cheaper in its preparation than the blackleg aggressin because in the process of manu - facture the use of animals is not required. It is widely used in Japan where the method originated, and results seem to be quite satisfactory. Permanent immunity is claimed to follow the use of both those substances. Inasmuch as it seems quite impossible to determine the various factors which are apt to enter into the production of immunity to blackleg, it is rather difficult to make a reliable comparison between the newer im - munizing agents and the old type of vaccine. The former have, of course, one great advantage over the latter and that is th-'t they are (at least should be) entirely germ-free. It also seems that the full immunity is established a little sooner, when the germ-free substances are u«ed than after the use of the regular vaccine. More data will however be required before anything very positive can be said in this respect. Nearly all the rather strong claims made for the tissue and culture filtrates have arisen from persons interested in their manufacture and sale, and not a few of those claims seem to originate from a desire to have them displace the older and much cheaper immunizing agents. Therefore, they should </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Essentials of Blackleg Prevention &lt; always be taken with considerable reservation. There is little doubt, however, of their immunizing value if they are properly prepared and there is nothing which should prevent their use by anyone inclined to prefer them to the old type of vaccine;. On all farms where blackleg has occurred or where it is liable to oeccur. vaccination should be an annual practice. Ordinarily it will be sufficient to vaccinate all aninnls between the ages of four months and two years. If smli animals 1k» thus treated every year there should be little chain e of infection. When the disease has broken out even calves of one month old should be treated and on farms where the disease is particularly apt to be present an additional vaccina - tion six months after the first one. while not particularly necessary, may give further assurance and security. A black - leg serum is also prepared which apparently has a certain degree of curative properties. Manufacturers recommend its use in animals already affected by the disease. Ordinarily the delay in securing the serum will render its use futile. Farmers and ranchers anticipating blackleg trouble may. how - ever, keep a supply of serum on hand, altho they should not be too greatly disappointed if the manufacturers' claims are not altogether confirmed by results. As a rule it is not necessary to vaccinate mature animals, but there are occasional outbreaks in which older cattle seem to become involved. In such cases the animals over two yenr= of age should also be included in the immunizing process. (5\n DistriHited in furtherance of cooperative agricultural extension work. Acts of May 8. 1914. and June 30, 1914. Extension Service of The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture and U. S. Department of Agriculture cooperating. W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>