<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twelfth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="1924-11-30">1924-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Twelfth Biennial Report Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 1924 ACIH PUNTING COMPAMY LINCOLN, Km. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Nebraska Public Library Commission MRS. MARGRETTA S. DIETRICH, President, Hastings, Nebraska S. AVERT Chancellor of the University of Nebraska NELLIE JANE COMPTON Acting Librarian of the University of Nebraska J. M. MATZEN State Superintendent of Public Instruction H. C. LINDSAY State Librarian NELLIE WILLIAMS, Secretary and Librarian for State Institutions MARGUERITE NESBIT Reference Librarian GRACE HOUTS Clerk for Traveling Libraries </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Hon. Chat. W. Bryan, Qovemor of Nebraska: Dbar Sb: Complying with the requirements of th« law, I herewith present the report of the Public Library Commission for the blennium ending November SO, 1924. Respectfully yours, Mabgbktta S. Ddetmoh, President. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Penonnel 5 Nebraska Public Library Commission SECRETARY'S REPORT December 1, 1922, to November SO, 1924 THE COMMISSION. The Library Commission consists of a board of five mem - bers, four ex-offlcio and one appointed by the Governor for a term of live years. The present board has been working together since the appointment of Mrs. Dietrich by Gov - ernor McKelvie in December, 1920. Also, four years ago the present state superintendent of public instruction, Mr. Matsen, assumed the duties of a member, as delegated him by law. The other members have served for longer periods of time. The state librarian, Mr. Lindsay, is the senior member. For twenty years he has been interested in the development of the work and has given generously of his time and thought. Chancellor Avery is the second in seniority, having been a member since 1909. The librarian of the University library, Mr. Malcolm G. Wyer, has been a member of the commission for eleven years. In September, 1924, Mr. Wyer severed his relations with the University of Nebraska, accepting a position as librarian of the Denver public library. We wish here to pay tribute to the service rendered the library commis - sion by Mr. Wyer. He has always felt a vital interest in its work and has given wise counsel regarding it. Not only the commission but all library interests of the state have suffered a keen loss by his change ir. fields of service. We wish him success and happiness in bis new work. Until the appointment of his successor, his assist - ant. Miss Nellie Jane Compton, is acting librarian of the University library. The board acts only in an advisory capacity, the actual duties of the commission being done by the secretary ana assistants. The secretary feels the need of help from each member of the board. She appreciates the cooperation which has been given. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The present office staff consists of the secretary. Nellie Williams, the reference librarian. Marguerite Nesblt, and the clerk for traveling libraries, Grace Houts. Miss Nesbit took: a year's leave of absence during which time Louise Wlnn of the University of Oklahoma acted as reference librarian. Miss Nesbit returned to the commission in September, 1924, Miss Wlnn going to Illinois to continue her course in library science. Previous to July, 1923, the staff numbered four. A re - duction in the salary fond necessitated a reduction in the staff. By this means a salary was released which has been used in the employment of student helpers who give hourly assistance. We have tried to meet this condition as philosophically as possible, but it must be admitted that the activities of the commission have been crippled thereby. The following pages which set forth the nature and extent of the work will disclose clearly the Inadequate slse of the staff. "The real purpose of a library commission is to promote library extension, to encourage the founding of libraries where none exist and to aid In their intelligent and economical administration." Perhaps the aim of the Ne - braska library commission has never been better expressed than in the letter of transmlttal at the close of the first blennium by the president, Mr. J. I. Wyer, to Governor Savage, when he said, "Its work is educational and con - structive and its aim to make Nebraska a better and more attractive state to live in, creates a sound economic reason for its existence." There are at present two specific measures by way of which we feel that the library commission may help to make Its aim effective. These are adult education ana illiteracy. The library world Is at present engaged In a program of adult education. The Carnegie Corporation has given funds to conduct a survey and to make a study of libraries and adult education. There is also nation-wide Interest In the problem of illiteracy. A chance to help directly in these two causes comes by way of two organisations, the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs and the Nebraska Illiteracy Commission. To Mrs. Paul C. Perryman, who is president of the Ne - braska Federation of Women's Clubs and also chairman of the Illiteracy Commission, is largely due the oppor - tunity of the libraries and library commission to engagfe actively in these educational and constructive pieces of work. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 At the Initial suggestion of the president of the library commission, Mrs. Dietrich, Mrs. Ida E. Capps of Hastings, library chairman of the State Federation, Mrs. Perry man and Miss Williams held a conference in the Interest of Nebraska club and library activities. The result was a place on the Federation calendar for Library Day. This is to be the second club meeting in January, 1925. A letter, financed by the Federation, was sent by Mrs. Capps to all club women of the state. Among other suggestions for the Library Day program is the question, "Is our library a factor in adult education?" We solicit the help of every librarian in the state In an effort to make the observance of a library day the basis of further construc - tive and cooperative work. We believe in the public library. We b?lieve in its growing usefulness. We like to think of it according to Dr. W. S. Learned as a "community intelligence center." It gives us courage to note the trend of Dr. Learned's thought in his "American Public Library and the Dif - fusion of Knowledge" where he says of the public library, "It will be a center as familiar to every inhabitant as the local post-office, and as inevitably patronised. It will constitute the central intelligence servici of the town not only for 'polite' literature, but for every commercial and vocational field of information that It may prove practicable to enter. Merchants will find there catalogues and trade lists; builders and plumbers, the technical books of their crafts; students, old or young, the orderly progress of books or materials In any important study; clergyman, the best works and periodicals dealing with religion; motorists, the latest road maps and touring guides; and artists, both technical works and comprehensive collections of pictures. "Obviously, such an institution in a small town will nci possess an extensive collection of books and materials, but it will be in close working connection with towns and cities where such collections are and where answers to questions and books on loan can be speedily secured at a trifling fee. With such connections the resources of a great part of the country may be made available for a relatively small circle." In accordance with other states Nebraska has an illit - eracy commission which Is well organised for definite work. This will include the claim of the near-illiterate as well as the illiterate. It la our hop* to be able to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Actimtie* Field Work 8 assist In bringing Nebraska to Its former high state ot literacy. The work of the Nebraska Library Commission Is or - ganized under three general divisions, field activities, a system of traveling libraries and reference loans, Un - building and supervising of libraries in the state Institu - tions under the Board of Control. When the library commission was organised in 1901. there were 24 tax-supported libraries in Nebraska. There are now 126 towns in the state which are maintaining libraries. The commission has given definite assistance In the establishment and organisation of these libraries. Field activities are not confined to help in organizing new libraries. Problems of administration, technical assistance and visits of friendly encouragement are legitimate com - mission work. Regular visits should be made to all public libraries of the stats. There Is a growing list which we call association libraries, fostered by the women's clubs. It Is from such beginnings that the greater number of our free public libraries has grown. There should be personal visits to these libraries In an early stage of their develop - ment. Some of them are strategically located and may be the possible beginnings of county library systems. All visits by the commission are made without expeMS to the community receiving help. The second activity of the library commission Is Us circulation of books to groups and individuals, upon ap - plication. The Increase In requests during the past two years Is a surprise even to ourselves. The total number of requests filled is 10,165 as against 6,213 for the pre - ceding biennium, or an Increase of 64%. There has been a phenomenal growth in the requests from individuals, the increase being 92% or 6,861 in contrast to 3,569 of the biennium preceding. While the increase in requests reaches a percentage of 64, the increase in number of volumes loaned is only 11%. As Mr. Bundy, Secretary of the Missouri commission says: "The work and expense of cir - culating books is increasing faster than the number of books circulated. Hence, if the service Is to grow, appro - priations must be Increased In order to provide more books and a larger working force." In answer to all requests of the biennium 86,230 books have been loaned, 62,287 In traveling library groups and 23,934 to individuals. It Is difficult to secure a record of circulation from the traveling library borrowers, but is the custom In this and other library commissions to </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Traveling Libraries 9 count five circulations to a volumi. This conservative estimate brings the circulation of these books to 311,4X6 volumes. Add to this the 23,943 Individual loans and the total circulation for the biennium reaches 335,378. t summary of requests and loans for the biennium closing and a table of comparative statistics is given another page of this report. We wish to say a word about the work entailed In loaning these 86,230 volumes. It is quite a different matter to send out this number of books from a library com - mission than it is to loan them from a public library. There is much more detail work In shipping by freight or sending by- post than in a hand-to-hand transfer of a book from the librarian to the borrower across the desk. Unless one has visited such a department he probably has but a vague idea of the record work which attaches to the exchange of traveling libraries or the time required to charge, wrap, weigh, stamp and get Into Uncle Sam's hands the packages which go by mall. The traveling libraries are instrumental In advancing the general purposes of the commission. Through their ■■•, people learn what a library means to a community and establish a free public library, thus providing locally what they formerly received from the commission. The traveling libraries are fixed groups of books, supplemented by books along various lines. They are loaned for a period of three months to any group of taxpayers, the borrower paying the transportation charge both ways. The travel- Ing libraries are for adults and for children. They are loaned to public libraries, schools, especially rural schools, other organisations and residential groups. During the biennium. 993 traveling libraries have been loaned to 90 counties. The three counties which have not been served are Douglas, Gosper and Loup. The counties leading with the number of traveling libraries borrowed are Lincoln 36, Lancaster 35, Thayer 32, Ouster 31. Cedar 30, Gage 26, Sawders 24, Cass 21. By careful parceling, the requests for fixed collections can be filled in a more or less reasonable time. There is one overwhelming demand which the commission can not meet. It Is for fiction to be used in the English depart - ments of the High Schools. We have a limited number of copies of Lorn a Doone, Robinson Crusoe and Tom Sawyer but hundreds of copies would not be sufficient. Nor do we feel that we should build to keep pace with </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Reference 10 this demand. These books should be provided locally la school and public libraries where It is at all possible. As high school equips its domestic science department and Its chemical laboratory, so should it consider the library as essential equipment. Expressions of appreciation come from many of our traveling library borrowers. It helps along the work of the day when the morning's mall brings letters which tell us that they were pleased with the selection of books and wish another traveling library. Of all recent letters none has cheered us more than this very spontaneous one written under date of November 10, 1924. Public Library Commission, Lincoln, Nebraska. kDear Madam: We received your books about two teks ago. I read many of them and enjoyed them ry much. I thank you very much that you let us have them. We are trying to keep them neat and clean, so other little boys and girls may enjoy them as I did. Yours very respectfully, Signed The teacher of lona, who wrote the above letter, says: "This letter was written by one of my little fifth graders, with very little help. It expresses the sentiment of the whole school." The increase In loans to Individuals seems more than the normal expansion which one might expect In any work that has not reached the height of Its usefulness. We can account in part for the increase In requests from cluB women, teachers, ministers, debaters, those taking exten - sion courses, merchants, fanners, housewives and small boys. Patrons of the commission make its service known to their friends who In turn apply for books. In addition to a normal growth of this kind is an appreciable Increase in the variety of subject matter requested. Topics for study include Americanization, boy scouts, child welfare, the church, citizenship, family budget, illiteracy, immigra - tion, laws relating to women, movie censorship, parent - teacher association and the world court Requests for* material on these subjects are many times repeated. Be - sides these are the continued calls for art, drama, modern </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Book Collection 11 a scattering request on topics of a lighter trend. Many interesting contacts are created by way of our reference loans. The individual borrower often becomes a friend who brings us her problems and her confidence. A mother giving the ages and characteristics of her three sons, the eldest of whom is going astray, appeals to us to help her "save her boys." A recent letter from, a ranch woman, who has been a steady patron, reads: "Ton have helped to make me a better woman and you have made better men of my boys." "Her boys" are the ranch - men employed upon the estate. Another cause for growth in individual loans Is attribu - table to the arrangement with the University Extension department whereby the commission supplies reference material for their courses. Registration constantly in - creases, courses are being added, until this phase of the work is by no means negligible. It is our custom to render service outside Nebraska in only exceptional cases, but with the extension registrants it seems necessary to follow their wanderings with the material needed. By this means a few books and pamphlets have been sent to each of the following states: Arkansas, California, Colorado, Idaho, Illinois, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Michigan, Missis - sippi, Missouri, Montana, New Mexico, Oregon, Pennsyl - vania, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, Wisconsin and Wyoming. Within our borders, requests for reference material have come from 535 communities, located in 92 counties. The only county not served during the biennlum is Banner. In point of towns served Lancaster leads, loans having been made to 16 communities within the county. Next in line are Cass and Custer 15, Saunders 14, Thayer IS, Cherry and Gage 12, Holt and Knox 11, and Buffalo 10. In selecting books to answer the demands, an effort Is made to keep a balance in the traveling libraries and open shelf collections. For adult traveling libraries we aim to* select such fiction as "deserves taking home to the family." For the open shelves, we buy a limited amount of fiction of literary distinction, in anticipation of use for book reviews. The juvenile traveling libraries consist of con - servative titles, the tried and easy being duplicated many times. The open shelves contain some of the beautiful editions of old and new favorites. We buy generously of boys' and girls' books because the commission Is supply- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Inatitutional Libraries 12 Ing reading zn&amp;tter for so many school children who hay© almost no other chance to know good books. It Is a pleas - ure to bay for children who neither know nor demand the latest and best seller. The open shelf collection from which the reference requests are answerd covers all classes of books. Effort is made to anticipate requests on timely topics. We continue to supplement the commission collection of 26,000 odd volumes by borrowing from the University library, the Legislative Reference Bureau and other sources of supply upon the campus. In 1912 the Library Commission was given full authority for the selection of books and supervision of libraries in the state institutions under the Board of Control. The building of these libraries presents a special problem for each type of institution and the experience of twelve years under the present system shows the advantage over the old plan. Instead of disorganised collections of books, largely donated, orderly libraries have been established of well-selected, wholesome books on all subjects and suited to each type of Inmate. The superintendents say that these libraries have exerted an Important Influence for the moral and educational work of the institutions. The following tribute from one of the superintendents is typical : "I wish to express my hearty approval of the splendid work of the library commission. The books which we have received have been a potent factor in our effort for higher standards in our management. They have been wisely selected to meet the various needs of the boys. I hope that this work so splendidly begun will be continued and enlarged." The state hospital at Ingleslde Is one to which we refer with peculiar gratification. Because the superintendent. Dr. W. S. Fast believes in books as a therapeutic agency he has made the library a sort of community center of the Institution where patients and employees go regularly tor their books. For five years it has been proving the advantage of a large, cheerful, cen - trally-located room over the crowded quarters shared with the switchboard. Dr. Fast has felt the importance of the work to such a degree that he has given us the services of a librarian. Mrs. O'Heara faithfully assists In getting the right book to the right person. In no month does the Ingleside circulation fall below 300 volumes. Some - times it reaches 400. With but two or three exceptions, books are to be found on every ward. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Another type of institution in which we feel tut the usefulness of books is proved is the penitentiary. The men read biography, travel, history, essays, poetry, ethics, religion, as well as fiction. They ask for technical books along many lines. Some of the subjects in which the men an interested are accounting, advertising and selling, blacksmithing, business employment, business letters, car - pentry, cement and concrete, dairying, engineering, draw - ing, farm management, fertilizers and crops, foundry work. fruit growing, gasoline engines, industrial chemistry, iron and steel, journalism, machine design, motor trucks, photography, plumbing, poultry, printing, road construc - tion, sheep raising, steam and hot water heating, steam power, the tinsmith, traction farming and woodwork. Not long after supplying a particularly large consignment of books covering many of the above subjects there came a letter from the librarian saying, "Thank you heartily for all the technical and mechanical books sent They are thoroughly appreciated and all in circulation." Institutions of an educational nature appreciate the books Iiished by the library commission. The following letter le recently from Mr. Booth, superintendent of the ool for the Deaf: "The books received from time to e by our school, through the generosity of the Nebraska rary Commission, are a source of much pleasure as I as profit to our pupils. They are well selected and y admirably fit our needs, especially for reading matter our younger children. Besides the books, we also sive regularly 21 periodicals, the latter for the pupils' ling room. Reading by the deaf makes to an unusual ree for education and culture, for, depending wholly n their sight for language communication, they must thought through reading if they get it at all." Along with other field work a curtailment of visits to the institutional libraries has been necessary. While this is to be regretted there seems to us less urgent need for the visits of a supervising librarian than for the service of a librarian in each institution. The books might be made much more effective could more time be given locally to their care and circulation. This statement is substan - tiated in the case of those Institutions which are putting the library on a similar footing with other departments. The secretary of the commission is a member of the Institutional Library committee of the American Library Association. This committee held a conference In Chicago in 1923 in connection with the A. L. A. midwinter meeting. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Publicity Needs 14 At this time a representative of one of the large eastern foundations was present due to an interest In the prison libraries of the country. With a heavy mall at hand, it seems that the library commission is a well-known department of the state. Then we find some one at our very doors who scarcely knows of our existence and we realise that we are not widely advertised. The commission has no regular means of pub - licity. Funds do not allow the publication of a bulletin as In the library commissions of many states. However, we believe In publicity and use available means to become known. The Associated Press and other similar agencies occasionally give us mention. An effective method of reaching the club women is by articles In the Federation Bulletin. By the courtesy of the editor, Mrs. W. E. Mlnler, the library commission has been given space In recent issues. Just among ourselves the circular letter is a medium of publicity. Another means of making the work and purposes of the commission known is by the participation of the secretary In programs of other organisations. She can give but limited time to such, but her belief in cooperation leads her to accept some invitations to speak to organized groups. Besides talks to a number of women's clubs, she has had a part In state and district meetings of the Federation, gave papers at district and state Nurses' con - ferences, talked on children's books on several occasions and will assist on Parent-Teacher Association programs. The omission of the Library Commission from Governor Bryan's budget in 1923 resulted in wide publicity for the commission. Words of approval came from many Indi - viduals from all over the state and organized support was thereby given by the Federation of Women's Clubs and the League of Women Voters. In the preceding pages, we have hinted at the needs of the state for the services of the library commission. We wish to speak specifically of those needs. The field work has been mentioned; the number of established libraries is given elsewhere. It is also stated that most of the towns in Nebraska which are large enough to maintain libraries are now taxing themselves for this purpose, though much Is to be desired to make that support adequate. From this statement it may seem that there remains no need for field work. As a matter </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 of fact it is a branch of the work which presents a press - ing need. Many of the libraries are not cataloged. Changes in librarians and library boards create conditions which call for help. Every library should be risked at least once during a biennium for friendly encouragement, if not in answer to specific call. To recently organised libraries it is often expedient to make several visits within a bien - nial period. To some libraries these visits should be of two or more weeks In duration. There is always a wait - ing list of visits to be made. Though most people seem charitably minded toward us, delay in answering sunn calls is neglect of legitimate commission activity. W* admit the neglect but we do it without apology. It la impossible In view of the cut In appropriation, which necessitated the reduction in the staff, to answer the field requests or to anticipate such needs. Nebraska is a rural state of great distances. There are stretches of country where the population Is scat - tered and the people are many miles from a library cen - ter. A survey has shown that more than three-fifths of the 1,296,000 people of Nebraska are without local library facilities. A growing number of these people Is looking to the library commission for books. In the face of a 64% increase in requests, the commission is operating on a book fund one-third less than that of the preceding bien - nium, it having been reduced by the last legislature from $6,000.00 to $4,000.00. To help meet the state need, our legislative estimate Includes a request for more money to buy books. However, to use such an increase, we feel that we need more help to take care of it. The secretary does and should do the selecting of books but she should not have to give her time to their mere mechanical preparation for circulation. One who has no acquaintance with the processes of order - ing, checking, accessioning, pocketing, carding, cataloging, replacing and preparing for rebinding has but a vague idea of the actual time necessary to get books ready for the borrower. Aside from the cataloging, which Is done by the reference librarian, most of this work could be done by clerical help. Hnvlr.r no stenographer and student help but a limited number of hours, much detail of book prep - aration falls to those whose time is needed for other branches of the work. The maintenance fund of the budget has also been re - duced. It Is possible to take care of running expenses but there Is not enough money to cover the cost of visits to </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 libraries asking and needing assistance In view of these needs, the library commission Is sub - mitting a request for an appropriation which will allow for the addition to the staff of a field agent and a stenographer. Request is being made for an increase to meet maintenance needs. We are asking for a restora - tion to the former book fund, plus an increase to cover normal expansion. An additional amount is being asked for the institutional libraries in order to supply the grow - ing inmate population with books and periodicals. The present biennial fund of $5000.00 is divided among sixteen Institutions instead of the thirteen of a few years ago. PUBLIC LIBRARIES There are 126 free public libraries in Nebraska. Four of these have been added during the past two years. They are at Gordon, Long Pine, Mitchell and Wahoo. Since Wahoo has come within the fold, there are but two towns above a population of 2,000 which do not have tax - supported libraries. These are Ord and South Sioux City, both of which have association libraries. We have worked and had reason to expect fo list Ord by this time but no levy for the support of their library has as yet been made by the town. It is necessary to report one library as withdrawn from the list. Several years ago the town - ship including Sargent made a library levy. Following this, effort was made to assist in organization, but conditions have seemed unfavorable to establishment. They now re - port a lapse of levy. Visits of organization have also been made to Shickley, Stratton, Trenton and Wauneta, in the interest of associa - tion libraries. Battle Creek has recently organised a library under the auspices of the woman's club. The list of association libraries is given on another page. The general status of the public libraries of Nebraska Is but little changed since our last report. In some towns the levy has been raised. In others we regret to say that It has been slightly lowered. Seventeen towns have reached, by tax. Incomes of $1.00 per capita which is considered by A. L. A a reasonable minimum revenue. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Building* 17 Towns having reached $1.00 per capita, by taxation: Bloomfleld Lexington Clarks* Loup City 1 Clay Center Madison Coiad Merna* Orleans eneva Guide Rock Shelton* Hartlngton Stanton Harvard Wayne Hebron Towns which have come within $100.00 of $1.00 per capita, by taxation: Arcadia* Humboldt Fairneld Sutton Falls City Table Rock Friend Gothenburg Wausa* •Those which are starred are township libraries, the population considered being that of the unit taxed. Several other towns fall but little short of the above measure. Weeping Water, from combined sources of rev - enue, has reached this mark. As for several years past there is almost no library building program in Nebraska. Two years ago we re - ported three new buildings, making 68 Carnegie libraries' and 13 from other sources. There is one new building to report for this biennial period. Arnold has nearly com - pleted a $20,000.00 library made possible by a $17,500.00 bequest of Mrs. Sarah O. Finch. The building is a memo - rial to Mrs. Finch and her husband, Ephriam S. Finch, early pioneers of Custer county. Arnold being a township library, this promises to be a center of usefulness as well as beauty. Nebraska Wesleyan University, of University Place, dedicated a beautiful new library building in June, 1924. The building cost $75,000.00. Of this amount $25,000.00 was given by Mrs. Rachel Ann Lucas, for whom the library is named. Friends of the librarian. Miss Langdon, rejoice with her in this change from the former location of the library to the attractive and workable quarters of the new building. Another building deserving mention is the new $3,500,000 Technical High School of Omaha, of which the library under the capable librarian, Miss Ingles, is an important part. Due to the vision of the principal, Mr. Dwight E. Porter, the library functions as the center of the entire system. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Gift, Legislation 18 To the list of school libraries has been added that of the Omaha north high school. Occasionally inquiry comes to this department, relative to Carnegie grants for library buildings, from a few towns which neglected the earlier opportunity and from those more recently organized. In this connection we publish here a letter of July, 1923, from Dr. W. S. Learned : "The Carnegie Corporation has definitely discontinued all ap - propriations to towns and cities for library buildings. No exceptions whatever are made to this policy and even when circumstances are most urgent it is quite useless to apply here. The Corporation has by no means abandoned its interest in library service but it feels that in so far as building* are concerned, its work has been accomplished." The reported gifts to libraries of Nebraska for 1923 are as follows: To Alliance, Arnold, Aurora, Broken Bow, David City, Falls City, North Platte, Plattsmouth. Rush - vine, Seward, Tekamah, Wakefleld. Wymore, York, Doane College and the State Historical Society was given an aggregate of 2,051 volumes, valued at $2,362.00. Gifts of money and donors are: The Kearney public library received one of his paintings by Lawton Parker, valued at Munich in 1905 at 13,000.00. The Woman's Club of Dundee gave to the library com - mission 100 volumes, most of which were recent books of fiction which had formed the basis of their study. A few of these were retained by the commission as the best source of distribution. The greater part was divided among a few newly organized libraries. In behalf of all who shared in this gift we wish here publicly to express appreciation. The only library legislation of the forty-second session of the Nebraska legislature was to repeal that part of the law in section 3188, relating to directors, making three constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. This was enacted merely to correct a previous oversight. Iroken Bow Woman's Club P. E. O. Chapter _. 10.00 tushville Eastern Star Chapter .._. 102.00 500.00 teward rork College Fred K. Babson Guy F. BuBwell 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 COUNTY LIBRARIES It again becomes our duty to report that Nebraska has no county libraries. How much failure to establish sucB Is due to general economic conditions and how much it is due to the lack of a field worker who might help the people realize the advantage of county library service. it is difficult to say. While the need of free county library service moat be felt by the residents of a county in order to bring the matter to a successful vote at a general election, we be - lieve that visits from a member of the commission staff would help to create interest looking to the establishment of a county library which we deem the eventual and ideal solution of the problem of getting books to our people who need and desire them. Many of our municipal and township libraries are not well enough financed to serve those within their taxed limits. There are many beyond those limits who are Just as eager for books, as requests coming to our depart - ment bear evidence. In a paragraph telling of our refer - once loans there are listed a few counties into all or nearly all of whose towns the commission is sending books. May these not be logical localities for mairing the county the unit of library organisation? This would allow the library commission to be so much the more available to people in other parts of the state. There are many who are far removed from library privi - leges. In 28 counties in Nebraska there are no free public libraries and 19 counties have no local library facili - ties whatever. Proposed assistance in promulgating the county library idea comes from the International Harvester Company. It Is their custom to send into certain localities representa - tives of the company who speak on various agricultural and community topics. They now suggest making the county library one of these subjects. Their cooperation in this matter is appreciated. LIBRARY ASSOCIATIONS There are two professional organisations of which our librarians may become members, the Nebraska Library Association and the American Library Association. Every librarian In the state should be affiliated with the N. L. A. because of the benefit to her and her library and for the help which she can give to the organization. We consider </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 this not only a professional privilege, bat an obligation. It is also desirable to have library boards or individual members thereof belong to the state association. The A. L. A. membership committee has for its slogan "10,000 MEMBERS BY 1926." Such a membership will enable the association to give more vital and valuable professional service to each member and to the library movement. A type of membership is provided for every type of library worker in the country. As a member of the A. L. A. membership committee, the secretary of the library commission sent a circular letter to all librarians and library boards explaining these types of membership. An increase of 17% in members followed this appeal There are others who should become members of the national organization. Please ask us or A. L. A. head - quarters for desired information. Application for member - ship may be sent to the library commission or to the A. L. A. Secretary, Mr. Carl H. Milam, 86 East Randolp* Street, Chicago. As organizations furnish an opportunity to be affiliated with other librarians, so the conferences of these associa - tions provide a chance to meet with those who have like interests. Again we urge attendance upon our annual N. L. A. meetings. Those who attend regularly feel that they cannot do without the help thereby given. It is desirable for any who can, to attend the A. L. A. meetings. Most of our librarians are unable to do so because of distances. However, it is possible for many to attend regional A. L. A. conferences. Such a meeting was held in St. Joseph, Missouri, In 1922. So manifest was the interest and so great the help that inquiries have been made regarding another regional meeting. In Octo - ber, 1924, at the N. L. A. conference, an invitation was accepted by Nebraska to Join Iowa, Kansas, Minnesota, Missouri and South Dakota at Sioux City, Iowa, in 1925. In the event of this meeting, which is advantageously located, we shall expect a large representation from Ne - braska. The 1923 N. L. A. meeting was held in Lincoln, Miss Home of the city library being president and hostess. Mr. Chalmers Hadley, then of the Denver public library, was our honored guest. He spoke to us on "Changing Fashions in Books." In 1924 the N. L. A. met in Omaha, Miss Craig, reference librarian of the University library being president. Mr. Milam, Secretary of the American Library Association, gave a splendid address on "The </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Library and Adult Education." He also talked Informally at an A. L. A. chapter meeting, providing to all who heard him an enlarged vision and a renewed courage. At the 1923 N. L. A. meeting a committee was appointed at the suggestion of the secretary of the library commis - sion, the purpose of this committee being to formulate some plan tor obtaining more comprehensive information on the status of the public libraries than is included in annual statistics sent to the commission in compliance with the law. The committee, now known as the Committee of Five, consists of Miss Tobitt, Miss Home, Miss McQuaid, Miss Jennings and Miss Williams. In February a question - naire was sent out by the committee. This included items relating to income and budget, board meetings, report to council, use of Booklist and other approved lists, sub - scription to professional periodicals, membership in and attendance upon library associations, state and national. Nothing was included which might not reasonably be met by nearly any library of the state. The results of the questionnaire were tabulated and they furnished the basis of discussion at the 1924 N. L. A. meeting, with Miss McQuaid as leader. The committee is continued for another year. It will work out some means of recognition of existing standards and will formulate some scheme for friendly competition looking to certain grades of standardization. We wish to thank the librarians for answering the ques - tionnaire so promptly and also to express appreciation for the work of the committee. Members of the Omaha staff and Miss McQuaid deserve a special word for the great amount of work done in tabulating the data re - ceived. From time to time, district library meetings have been held in different parts of the state. These one-day meet - ings are especially valuable for the librarian of the small library who feels a certain Isolation in her work in having no one in her own community with whom she can talk "shop." Also at the district meetings the attendance of trustees has been proportionately greater than at the state meetings. In May, 1924, a district meeting was held in Madison. Everyone was gracious but the weather man. In spite of him, we had a good time discussing informally a number of topics. It was a pleasure to be guests of the Madison library board and of the librarian, Mrs. Johnson, of whose work such good words may always be spoken. With a regional meeting in prospect for the fall of </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 1925, it is desirable to bold a number of district meetings in the spring. Three towns, sufficiently separated, have already extended invitations. LIBRARY INSTITUTES When places of meeting have made it possible the library commission has occasionally conducted library Institutes In connection with the N. L. A. meetings. Institutes were held in 1923 in Lincoln and in 1924 in Omaha. There were 36 librarians in attendance at the institute In Lincoln. This was an increase of 14 over any previous year. They represented 36 libraries and came from 27 counties, the distance traveled one way being 4,276 miles. Mr. Wyer, Miss McQuald and Miss Williams gave three lectures each, Including reference work, government docu - ments, statistics and reports, publicity, general problems of administration and aids to book selection. In connection with the institute the commission had a number of exhibits. One exhibit of children's books at - tracted special attention. This was an outgrowth of &amp; belief that there is urgent need to exercise care In the selection of books for boys and girls. The exhibit took the form of a house of undesirable books built upon the sand In contrast to a house of desirable books built upon firm foundation. Having visualized this contrast, approved lists of children's books were provided for distribution. That the campaign against undesirable books for children might be brought to the attention of all librarians of the state, a cut of the exhibit of book houses, printed and mimeographed lists, together with excerpts from letters by Nebraska librarians who buy books appearing only on approved lists, were mailed to all public libraries. At the institute In Omaha, 33 librarians registered. Letters came from a dozen others who wrote regretfully that they were unable to come because of distance and attending expense. Lectures on more technical subjects than have been included In any previous program were given at this institute. Hiss Taylor of the Omaha public library gave two lectures on classification and one on the shelf-list. Miss McQuald explained In full how to have a "live regis - ter." Miss Tobltt gave a talk on the business aide of the library which every librarian in the state should have heard. Topics presented by Miss Williams were book orders, accessions and withdrawals, and aids to book </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 selection. One half day was given over to book repair. We were fortunate to have this opportunity to observe the Omaha system of binding and mending. Miss Duncan also demonstrated the Toronto method of mending. Th« institute included a visit to Omaha branch libraries. We feel that exhibits are a valuable part of the Institute sessions. Several were arranged for this year, part of which were provided through the courtesy of the circula - tion and children's departments of the Omaha library. The exhibits arranged by the commission Included A. L. A. publications, a few commercial displays and printed and mimeographed lists for distribution. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 ?? seuinioA g ■3 i i "? - g sauinioA •; ■o £ paiM g s)sanb»H «; S £ s g satanioA !J Oig 5 CO pailKJ us 00 k % 1 sisdtibsH CM ecu H fr)«anl»H e»" ci 3 s »)senbaH paimoq o * samniOA 5 5 paiiu g sjsanb*a M r- 2? i ? C * II O SS P9IIW i 2 BjwnbaH R | pmnoq •• samnioA S p»tn»oq g sauiiiiOA *£ I ■ panu a I r pouvoq! § H saninioA! g g f ' LjL pawwq 5 | sisanbaH R aaraniOA " I s S •e.S sanmiOA *° s - — — I I IS? </seg>
            <seg id="p025">SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes accessioned to December 1, 1922 29,884 Volumes in library December 1, 1922 24.450 Volumes added from December 1, 1922, to November 30, 1924 1.074 Volumes withdrawn to December 1, 1922 5.4S4 Volumes withdrawn from December 1, 1922 to No - vember 30, 1924 1.M0 Volumes accessioned to November 30, 1924 12,968 Volumes In library November 30, 1924 26,4(4 EXPENDITURES DEC. 1. 1922 TO NOV. 30, 1924 From From Appropriation Appropriation 192M923 1923-1925 Books _ $1,603.26 $ 3,039.60 Maintenance _ 938.79 1,919.06 Binding 487.37 583.55 Institutional libraries 1,774.34 2,407.35 Salaries and wages 3,237.10 7,004.26 $8,040.86 $14,953.81 8,040.86 TotaL $22,994.67 Appropriation July 1, 1923 to June 30, 1925 $23,000.00 Expended July 1, 1923 to November 30, 1924 14.953.81 Balance _ _ 8,046.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 S I Si I I 1 1 I I l i l I l I l l ll 3 I I I I I I I I I | I I IS 5 ! i I I « I I I I I I I I i ll I S •Hi 2 ffl t" t*Ok0N«0*^Xi-iM«0CCQePlM NM MMrirtiOID C4 rH n»N I I I IL__ i i I S t. C oo : as n o&gt; : oo ps ■ ■» o : &lt;~i : : . 3x j io&gt;H :n«c :ioo : » o it- f H m ••» 'ih« : h'V : mtc : » • ! i ° ! ti ++ „ •»" H OONKi-uinaa isnmaOM : si! 3 = 0, SS^S'^SSg-SSSSSS : 0.BW "^~ ! ! j I MM ! ! ! M ! ! | ! I 1 lit | Jj ii l*l!pll^lf.i.lii ;2j I HiKJOjfiii! m ! szs* ifijF **m nil £,•-■ s f; « o o o^^^Sww </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 ASSOCIATION LIBRARIES Libraries In the following towns, financed other than by taxation, are under the auspices of women's clubs or other civic groups. Some of these are merely permanent travel - ing library stations. A few of these libraries will probably soon become tax-supported. Assistance in bringing the above list to date was ren - dered by the library chairman of the Federation, Mrs. Capps, in cooperation with her district chairmen. If other towns should be Included, names of such would be ap - preciated by the secretary of the library commission. Adams Elgin Ord Alexandria Elkhorn Oshkosh Angora Atkinson Avoca Battle Cre«k Elm Creek Elmwood Bus Us Fairmont Oxford Page Palmyra Polk Beaver City Beaver Crossing Farnam Grant Potter Ruskln Beemer Gresham St. Edward Belden Belgrade Boelus Hardy Hay Springs Hayes Center St. Paul Salem Scotia Bradshaw Brock Brownlee Hemingford Herman Homer Shickley Shubert South Sioux C11 Bruning Cambridge Carleton Jansen Keystone Leigh Springfield Steele City Stratton Chester Clarkson Lemoyne Lushton Sutherland Tilden Crab Orchard Crookston Lyons Mason City Trenton Valentine Culbertson Dakota City Davenport Mlnatare Monroe Mullen Valley Valparaiso Wallace Decatur Deshler Diller Dorchester Murray Nemaha Oakdale Ogallala Walthill Waterloo Western Wolbach Edgar Orchard Wynot </seg>
            <seg id="p028">2S dp xzaa 1! sisi.i .Jinn N*OO -; e^ tc o o JS r» -* o o &gt; ssss III I o 3 O US O OqpOOOt*OON^OOOO© — oe»MONiot-ocio»MSHX«ec &gt; M rt « _rt ri N«ri 00 g : ■ I t I I : I s : : i i : : : j ! j j | I ! I i [ : : j : | : a i i I r I i I i i i I It I I J •S£2Sa«-SESEB5*S.*o5c o a ja_a _b ■" o "3 13 "5 9 u o u i. « a « a c : : : : ! ! i U I I i 1 s-g • k i? f ft, o^ U § Up - ■ O 0 = 5: 1 i I ! i M U | I i I j j ! i in | i if J 1 i :?f §*§ I J I If iJllIfiPSlBli! cc e - — * bt oo ? _ a &gt;&gt; h h h « OOQOK3jZOOOOccmot(E&amp;&amp;&gt;« I 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">n go y. s. ■ 1 E &gt;i a X - ° i iSlililiyiil.Lil j « . .E5 .« . &gt;hk .2^*8 . OC4A(0NOe4OHH«At*VHVOHU3 I Oi ocQtaAnoxnTiHHt^«HvacL:n : t- UOUBinDJIO «1"l*nON««ONVt"rtNHI*OlflW : O f* iH ** rH fl r-l «O iH iH I Hoooo^noOHoevoeoMoioctooo CO © C&lt; W »H C4 rH CC SO tO O5 to C3 fH CO rH 04 ri t-l , «a r j t sinnu f ceTNcneoicoeoovoeveuMstt j I N«n«NON :«**C 00»U3MBON» jauin tet*«onu)e iwiaKuusnoOMiAt-te 1 plTB S^OOg rt»»H**rtnH«Nco*»*NM*H -h *♦ i-T a&gt; a £ SdLlBlKg caOnt0Nt*QOC^WC)Vt*OONOOlO« | oo«^oooooooeooo-*«wooooio© , OOCDOOOOOmOCDOOtOOOOlOM^t-US O1XIO3QI n n v o n &gt;a h co to o n ia n o t^ us t- o &gt;a h « . ft i! ** * a O O) U3 CO X H V (6 t^Xft H V t- Cl U) 91 V t&gt; HH Vi-iH i-T -" H M* N* N O5 N H H N H i i • : ; j j i I j ! - { ! \ j j j j I I 1 1| I Hill J J ■ i • : : • I i i i i i * : i 2 I hiiipimiJlfiii' ilj III • *- HNWTW»t»amoHf'n*iO(Ot-ooft&lt;DH iHi-irHrtlHi-lfHiHlHT-CC^M 29 5i;&gt; 53OD </seg>
            <seg id="p030">| S 1 a g 1 SUV.— JlloBl.Ul.UQdl.lJSoO'''- nonvinsJio onoe^Hnovoooi'NiaAQnbaoo *e&lt;CNt-»t-e«OB*MNnoi«io«J-E- — CO » iH rt ♦ US IO iH iH i sauiniOA O(6IO^H(CVMO^V9OO&lt;0OOVC1OOIO * « t»N M N « HC O W * NH «« t-h-fl&gt;« B •M -»d sJnoH IrtOOJOtOMOOt-OOOOO^-uTNOOOO-** a s El 9 ■»«no • t-»»«»r.t-OKOI-t-*»N»NO«* a* 10 ■*■«•-»■ n (M ■-( »&lt;O -iH«H«t.Mlll 8{K&gt;ipo(jaa Hier-t-«N«iooiifi«oBaxaeHoavo NIOM H «HH«pi1iNHeriftHVe4ia* 83y«i«s N«»oonooi-K«TT«c:&lt;s««coxoo auioani oooorHONOom»«co«&gt;oo»2 0 2£? * * H ft N f N » * * N W * t- » C W « U! N eJVr-ftH 1 MICH HrtMn US V«-*"C5f-*T-f^ 1 non*indod J|l||i I' 2 lljll ' ilbSiiil^ilflhl II II Is I </seg>
            <seg id="p031">mS 31 _£« §§!§ 11-1= S . : fl-2 u HI 'UPStatt Sip! inDt»O«OTO*«f-c-«OuJt-00O0tP5ON knoooNHoapo^t-AaoiAoniAnONNOoo iniOHt-_«OX«««!Mqb;rt»100MM»»qt- I non«inajio C4 *HHrt ri « 1H »H IO CO O 0000«0000005&lt;OMCCOOOO&gt;'*'X'0-«'MIO »u-_ot«^a«qnqrt»eau-.»q»Hq«M HNNHN»MVNHUH»rtMrt«H«« f-T souin|OA M-HtO U3vHC4t«CDte^i«C4 "V ■* 0000 »»IX) a i C-l rH &gt;— i t- ou&gt;oe9u&gt;«ui«otoi-rine«9&gt;&gt;SN«eti' CTHt-t-NMNanMt-O»»ai0fOB»lD NCCNnNHHO) 00 « U5 ■* NION tOOH siTOiponad r-&lt;" i 55 I pu« s&gt;iooa r-1 oe^ooocoooiaoooocooooeoo^oco N^N«OX3N9&gt;aSNnI-agl)xes«NK -.L1»Ma0Cn*»N«*t-HW»»M«CH ! M sap«|BS OHONMOMNOOeOOtDNOOfOOVOn OtCOafO^HONO'-5W»OX»OM«* tHUOJUI 5 I CM •t- «XNHVt»Ht"Ht*NMM^t-NOOt-MOtf uon^indoj i-? *-T GO* *4 CO rH rt fr-T t-J" C«Vrt i-&lt; 94 «H fH rH CO O a m o *- V**T*fTi.-5U:wu5WL3WCU:iO(C»»(Die i-l »1 &lt;O iv*3M 4&lt;*&lt;J SJUOH ooiaN«MHaiooMooot-a»N«oxwNa«o iH r-l i-l IN 5 o 1 IUiJm t i^J ■ ii </seg>
            <seg id="p032">a 21 32 * ! 8 i. i i o — Sags g g 5 • | 1|I|| O 1 = | I SB I I 5 • te c^ c. -t^ i- non«[noJ!0 oot-OKnooinxuaoivstoo © U3 IA U5 C4 00 t- 00 t^ CO f~l 0C_ C &lt;O o&gt; t-' r i .: l-' V oc to 'jj tc cc x L-' p-' f l-' £ — O nouBinoJio — — seniniOA I 5 pa 3 n Lt CO N N N «t^ r- « N * ii t* N naeM Jdj sanoH »— ec ?J * i^ r- c« « a H Pd c £ a. D w I £3 MXh»r-Op&gt;Ct-CXOHXCClC«MCi.": OChNCIOVCHaViTXXHOK'" W^»«0C to co us " C2 r* u? c*-i co O) w c^i re rH i-t c^i co g SI«DJpOIJ9d 3 I pn« sj|ooa v:- N W L". h aoo(0OOOO4OOOLr:c*3ooi "«• t- © o © 'X c;oo(-ot-w » l- © ic c m i 1 t n n tc c - u: ir euiODUi M »— c4"i-« »-* 4- 0 O CO V CJ O&gt; t- h* N 01 r; n « w « t- w t» uoiiPrn&lt;ioa ! rfliiiiidi! iiiiiiiii &lt; t-»«ae»o»"C«^OK — t© N ir. c a&gt; t- &lt;o c « »-i » W ri iH *-( r-t 93«XKnCCOU)OCHIAV(e«H9OC u: l: x u". « c c r: c a n » a;_i- « n v k ; N t-* ♦ tfi * H M ao V N r-*NVrtOOW«rt*r ,,„,„ ce»oc»et-c.»in«oON o»eo*»xco« </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 ifc; 3 noijBinjato o«xoi«non«uvn«s lOtouino OaoxOi^«(OT»TC4u3t-o lOHMfflO (CHH«»lflMt«Ma5W'-NO !&lt;©«©|H-^CS I noRBinaJio 04 r-&lt; iH M rH r-t c (•ononMQooaoM^aio oohuo ©OC»©COi-li~IO'V©'*e*t-C- i-H © © © © -_ « e h to u io e » q « q « o i-ioooooim eJ ef V « « «o V 1-T V «c i-T &gt;o ■• oo : i-Jef co i-f e&lt; sdtnnioA 05 -i H»»M -i^d bjiioh «S O2 s COlflt-Ht-NOIflMWiO««rt ; :t~OOO aON0OXnMU)»SN*I&gt;*« : :ulrt»C4 nqn H(&gt;u&gt;H»is&lt;g(&gt;ia« : iiaioHN =3 siwjpopiad ON :neNooa«hOfK : iohwo WO :»H^a«HN*XHr. : :mw»b hi&gt; : Hrii-iHisis unia : :nn M E- Z ' PWi 8*OOa X o o &lt;e o o o o o o o o o o o : :oooo »t-«NxoNHui«io»*o : : o o ■&lt;• » coo ih tH to t- ih to o&gt; eo co oo te : :co&lt;oeito 8*JJ«l*S i »-i o o o o t- o o co n o o t-o oo : eo o o o&gt; o ia o in o o in o t- t- o o o © rH : oo o o &lt;o o xa^n^co^toqo vtoaooo ; vnc^ino **« I-J.H «eO rHi-4tH ! t-JlH iH eaioani w ao^lAXA«IAtDNH«NM(0OOOt*«H AAHU3nHUJU3COHNCOHU30t*»QOO(0 H-.o*nooo«eaon«xs»Bfxn « aoiiBindod 1 9 a o. 1 ? til 2gS Age ++ C = •3 I*! o « o +-♦♦ t^xnoHNnfiatpt^xooHnn^iav ooooooo&gt;&lt;7&gt;a&gt;Aa&gt;a&gt;o&gt;o&gt;&lt;BAOOooooo i-&lt; iH rH iH it tH fH qc-Hiei.'5t-*qHMNr-ria ; t- 10 in oo oo ienooiooo»ooooONionr- :iono*o rim iH N« MMNHPJN I H&lt;OH« ■»1K&gt; *- 4- 4- *- ihVi-J rt«i-H cJ ce i-T cj th im' ih i-fi-f i-T i I 1 I I i I I I I I I I Xa I I I I j I ] U ' U I M I'll I </seg>
            <seg id="p034">i iithMuiihui u£ a u"&gt; 1.1.1(1. a; i. £„ i_ • o J"O a53ssoo6ssuiStt3sossB*«&lt;o-«:. non«inDan ' rt - "- **- "■ "- N - °°- *• * "- * - " *- w - "°- : - - ■ I saianiOA «HBt-«eoiMM«)Mioe^«j(i»HNN — OUJf u3t6u*.VhK '* 3 H H » O c « r. N DO J »flK) MSN^- — » OS;N.-i*in.-. »■«■ I * 2 iiritnnTia i *3nn«uivoi-u:oo»no»o oot~&lt;c E- "IBaipoiJad *u5iot.nt-cus»»«n»c»r- omis OOOr3OOOOlAOOOC4o00OOOt-^4 ..; ' 3 99«N«ceooecic&gt;')ae*n:ot- OO0&gt;A«OOOU3OOOOU3OOOMOOCO 1 — UOUBindO#T He00l«N»H»ri»HnHKO«HNa&gt;00 14 ' d 1 1 1 1 1 1 j j 1 1 i ! I j i i j i I j I \i\ i M«JJi;IJipil in I | § H|lli!lil=I?ll"l. 1 -^ l^H»H^ H^^»^iH^ !] HI </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>