<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties at the North Platte Experimental Substation</title>
               <date value="1936-03">1936-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 297 March, 1936 Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties at the North Platte Experimental Substation L. L. Zook Kalo left Early Kalo right Acre yields (bushels): Kalo, 23.8; Early Kalo Crop of 1934 on fallow, North Plane Experimental Substation! Bulletin 38 of the North Platte Experimental Substation L. L. Zook, Superintendent ■■. ■ The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties L. L. ZOOK » This bulletin reports results with miscellaneous sorghum varieties on dry land at the North Platte Experimental Substation for varying numbers of years during the 14-year period 1921-35. Comparisons are made between the yields of grain sorghums and corn. Differences m response of grain sorghums and corn to seasonal conditions and differences m their effects upon succeeding crops are shown. Two years of preliminary trials of Atlas sorgo and corn for ensilage under irrigation are also reported. 2 The drouth-enduring qualities of the sorghum crops have given them particular interest m regions of limited and uncertain I rainfall. In the Plains areas south of Nebraska, the superiority of sorghums over corn for grain production has long been recognized. In Nebraska and the Plains areas further north, with lower mean temperatures and shorter growing seasons, the grain sorghums have not furnished as successful competition for corn, and the Nebraska-Kansas line has come to be regarded m a general way as the dividing line between the two crops. The recent years of severe drouth and low corn yields have stimulated interest m the sorghums. The development of improved and earlier-ma - turing sorghum varieties also gives promise of extending successful pro - duction further north and west m Nebraska. GRAIN SORGHUMS Annual yields of Substation White corn and grain sorghums grown m varietal tests during 11 years (1924-35), with 1927 omitted, are shown m Table 1. These yields are averaged m periods varying from 2 to 11 years, to accommodate different groups of varieties, and the average yields are shown m Table 2. Average yields for the same periods m percentages relative to corn and the average estimated percentages of maturity as judged by observation of performance at North Platte are shown m Table 3. The varietal plats varied somewhat m size from year to year, but were usually of six rows, eight rods long, or approximately 0.06 acre m size, and usually duplicated. The soil was prepared by early tillage and kept free of weeds until planting time, which ranged from about May 20 to June 10. Surface . planting with a corn planter or grain drill m 40- or 42 - --inch rows was practiced m all years except 1934, when on account of the dry condition of the surface soil at planting time, a lister was used for planting. 1 Agronomist, North Platte Experimental Substation, and Associate Agronomist, Division of Dry Land Agriculture; Bureau of Plant Industry, L\ S. Department of Agriculture. J For the years 1924-33 the sorghum variety tests were a part of the crop improvement project carried on cooperatively by the Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. Department of Agriculture, and the North Platte Experimental Substation. For these years the data herein used are taken from the annual reports compiled by G. F. Sprague (1924-29) and N. E. Jodon (1930-33), Junior Agronomists, m charge. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties Table 1. — Comparative annual grain yields jor grain sorghum varieties and corn jor all or part 'of the years 1924-35, with 1927 omitted— North Platte Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska. Acre yields (bulhelsl C. I. No. Variety j j j j j " j 1924J 19251 1926J 1928, 1929| 1930 1931, 19321 1933 1934 1935 lIIi I . 1 [ ... Corn— Substation White.. 36.3 26.9 0.0 48.5 15.4 35.1 20.8 15.9 30 7 8 1 21 9 182-1 Fetenta 17.5 44.5 7.6 9.4 20.1 30.9 22.6 1(17 331 63 371 *I J??*" .*»* 3.9 18.8 4.6 11.1 18.6 31.2 29.7 21.5 45^ i.\ l\.\ 901 Club kafir 194 s OJ nr&gt; }T g j J7 &#132;„- - 22 _ _J 23A 35.9 23.5 39.6 44:3 12.2 34.4 «n J, °, sV"J ,„A I8 ' 7 3l ' 9 38 -7 27.3 41.9 10.3 31.7 620 Dwarf Hcgari 18.0 41.5 9.8 10.1 312 432 Pink kafir 10.9 34.8 4.3 12.8 8.7 ... 971 Dwarf Freed . ... H. 3 20.9 32.6 14.8 29.3 919 Custer milo 15.2 32.1 27 9 24 7 965 Dwarf feteriu x(MxK) 2d!2 25.3 20J 33 5 917 Sooner milo ll.fi 179 .' ig^ 325 '°99 &amp;gy Kal ° '.. 50.0 17.7 35.2 918 Wheatland"".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'. ..'. ..'. ".'. 39-; 3=o °'° 8A FC9170 Cheyenne -.. .' |." ' Jfifi "• ,g 5 £ o&lt;:s , 7.7 27.6 Greeley 443 2 4 .8 Each variety is briefly described, and its favorable and unfavorable characteristics are discussed m the following paragraphs. Much of the information on origin of varieties has been taken from Kansas Bulletin 266, Varieties of Sorghum m Kansas, by A. F. Swanson and H. H. Laude. Feterita has dry, not very leafy stalks, that grow to a height of 5 or 6 feet. Its forage value is low. The large white seeds are soft and palatable. The average grain yield for the 11-year period 1924-35 at North Platte Table 2. — Average grain yields of grain sorghum varieties and corn for varying terms during the 11 years 1924-35, with 1927 omitted— North Platte Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska. 1 Average acre yields (buihels)— l927 omitted C I. No. Variety j ~ 11 yri. 7 yrs. 4 yrs. 4 yrs. 3 yrs. 2 yr*. 2 yrs. 1924-35 1929-35 1924-28 1930-33 1933-35 1932-33 1934-35 Corn— Substation White... 23.6 21.9 27.9 25.6 20 2 23 3 15 0 182-1 Feterita 21.8 22.9 19.8 28.7 25.5 219 21~7 904 Dawn kafir 21.3 27.5 9.6 32.0 28.2 33.5 196 901 Club kafir 33.6 . . . 39.8 34 9 43 1 28 2 902 Kalo 30.5 ... 35.8 30.3 42.0 23 3 905 Modoc 28.6 ... 35.0 28.0 34.5 210 620 Dwarf Hegari ... 19.9 432 Pink kafir ... 15.9 971 Dwarf Freed ... ... ... ... ... 22.1 919 Custer milo . . 25.0 ... 26.5 965 Dwarf feterita *(MxX) ... ... 26.3 ... 26.9 917 Sooner milo ... ... 25 5 1009 Early Kalo ... 3V.3 265 899 Atlai ... 134 918 Wheatland ... ..'. 37 i Co" .'. 17.7 Greeley ... ... ... ... 34.6 * Data from Table 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 297 was 21.8 bushels per acre, in comparison with 23.6 for corn. Low yields frequently are the result of poor stands, as the soft seed rots quickly if cool, wet weather occurs after planting. It usually matures safely at North Platte, is too tall for combine harvesting, but is satisfactory for binding, shocking, and topping. Table 3. — Percentage yields of grain sorghum varieties relative to corn for varying terms during the 11 years 1924-35, with 1927 omitted, and average percentage maturity of grain sorghum varieties. 1 Average yield, percentage of corn — 1927 omitted C. I. No. Vanrty , Av. pct B . 1 1 yrs. 7 yrs. -4 yrs. 4 yr$. 3 yrs. 2 yrs. 2 yrs. mature 1924-35 1929-35 1924-28 1930-33 1933-35 1932-33 1934-35 Corn— Substation White 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 100 182-1 Fcterita 92 105 71 112 126 94 1-45 95 904 Dawn kafir 90 126 34 125 HO 144 131 70 901 Club kafir.. 153 ... 155 173 185 188 75 902 Kalo 139 ... HO 150 180 155 85 905 Modoc 131 ... 137 139 148 140 85 620 Dwarf Hegari 71 80 432 Pink kafir 57 65 971 Dwarf Freed ... 95 ... 100 919 Custcr milo 103 ... 114 ... 65 965 Dwarf fctcrit.i x(MxK) 103 ... 115 ... 90 917 Sooner milo 109 ... 65 1009 Early Kalo 170 ... 177 100 899 Atlas 66 40 918 Whcatland 159 ... 70 FC 9170 Cheyenne ... 100 . Cocs 118 100 Greelcy 148 ... 100 1 Data from Table 1. Dawn kafir has a moderately sweet, fairly leafy stalk, usually about six inches shorter in height than feterita. The forage value is fair. The seed is palatable, smaller, and somewhat harder than feterita. For the 11-year period 1924-35, the average yield was 21.3 bushels for Dawn kafir and 23.6 ' for corn. Dawn kafir matures safely at North Platte only in years of above normal temperatures and length of growing season. It is too tall for com - bine harvesting, but satisfactory for binding and topping. It has some promise as an ensilage crop in western Nebraska, where later varieties such as Atlas and Pink kafir do not mature well enough for good quality. Club kafir is a selection from Dawn made at the Fort Hays (Kansas) Branch Station. The stalks are slightly sweet, somewhat more leafy and six to twelve inches shorter than those of Dawn. As indicated by the name, the heads are shorter and more globular than are the ordinary kafirs. The seed is palatable and the yield high. For the 7-year period 1929-35, the yield of Club kafir was 33.6 bushels per acre and. for corn 21.9 bushels. Its yield was substantially above corn in all years but one. Except for its doubtful maturity, Club would be among the most promis - ing of the varieties grown. It is somewhat beyond its safe range of maturity at North Platte, and is not recommended further north and west except possibly for ensilage where full maturity is not important. It grows too tall for combine harvesting. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties Pink kafir has a moderately sweet, fairly leafy stalk, that grows to a height of five to six feet at North Platte. It has a fair forage value and palatable, non-bitter seed. It was discontinued after a five-year trial (1924 - 2.9) both on account of poor yield and late maturity. Modoc is a selection developed at the Fort Hays (Kansas) Branch Station from a cross of Pink kafir and Freed sorgo. The stalks are fairly leafy and sweeter than most of the kafirs. The seed is palatable, non - bitter, and the yield relatively high. Yields were above corn in six of the seven years 1929-35, and the averages 28.6 for Modoc and 21.9 for corn. Although Modoc does not always mature fully at North Platte, it has a sufficient margin in maturity over Club kafir to make up for a part at least of its lower yield and to make it of about equal value with Club in most sections of Nebraska where either may have promise. Modoc giows too tall for combine harvesting, but has a suitable height for handling with a corn binder and the uniform height and long extension of stalk above the upper leaf make machine topping unusually easy. Kalo was first grown under the name of Yellow kafir. It was developed at the Fort Hays (Kansas) Branch Station from a natural cross of Pink kafir and Dwarf Yellow milo. The stalks are only slightly juicy, some - what less leafy than Modoc, and grow to a height of about four feet. The seed is non-bitter and palatable, but the yellowish-brown color makes it somewhat less attractive than the lighter-colored seeds of Modoc and Club kafir. Kalo outyielded corn each year of the 7-year period 1929-35, and the average yields were 30.5 for Kalo and 21.9 for corn. Kalo is only slightly below the line of safe maturity at North Platte, and its high yield places it near the top of varieties that are promising for grain production in central and southern Nebraska. Early Kalo is, as the name indicates, an early selection of Kalo. The two strains have similar stalk characters, except that the early strain is V/z to 2 feet shorter. (See cover page.) It matures ten days to two weeks earlier than the original strain, and for the time tested has produced somewhat more. For the three years 1933-35, Early Kalo outyielded corn and all other sorghum varieties except Club kafir in 1935. The 3-year average yields were 34.3 for Early Kalo, 34.9 for Club kafir, and 20.2 for corn. Early Kalo has not been grown for a sufficient length of time to secure full proof of its value, but its safe maturity and high yield in the preliminary tests indicate that it may be an adapted and profitable crop for a considerable extension beyond the limits of many other grain sorghums in Nebraska. No extended trials have been made of Early Kalo for combine harvesting, but its height at North Platte indicates its suit - ability for this method of handling, except that it lodges rather easily after maturity. Dwarf Freed has slender, somewhat sweet stalks, that grow to a height of about 4'/2 feet. It is a selection made at the Fort Hays (Kansas) Branch Station from the taller standard Freed. It is somewhat superior in forage value to the grain sorghums having heavier, dry stalks. The grain is palat- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 297 able and non-bitter, but does not thresh off clean in damp weather In four of the five years 1929-33, its yield was less than that of corn and the averages were Freed 21.8, corn 23.6. Dwarf Freed is sufficiently early to mature safely in most sections of Nebraska, but its poor yielding ability will doubtless prevent its replacing very much corn acreage for cram pro - duction. Dwarf Hegari is a selection made at Chillicothe, Texas, about 25 years ago, from a lot of seed originally introduced from Khartum, Sudan, Africa, under the native name of Hegari. Dwarf Hegari has stout, medium juicy, slightly sweet stalks, that grow 4 to 5 feet tall. The seed is white with red marking, non-bitter and palatable. Dwarf Hegari has produced well under irrigation. On dry land at North Platte and in tests throughout the plains, its performance has been erratic, both as to yield and maturity For the 5 years it was carried in the North Platte tests, its average grain yield was 75 per cent of the yield of corn. In two of these years its grain yield was substantially higher than corn and in two other years less than half the yield of corn. In yield and quality of forage, it ranked among the better gram sorghums. In 1935 a large amount of Dwarf Hegari seed from the irrigated sections of the southwest was sold for emergency planting in Nebraska. in tnese plantings its reputation for erratic behavior was well borne out in some cases it compared well with other crops for forage. In other cases the results were disappointing. Many of the plantings were made late and in most cases seed did not mature. At the North Platte Substation, com - mercial Dwarf Hegari in 1935 showed a large amount of varietal mixture. I he gram yield was 13.8 bushels per acre in comparison with 21.9 bushels !vt?' ■ ?u rag^ yidd Was 81 P er cent of Atlas sor g°- p^nted June 10, this Dwarf Hegari was estimated 40 per cent mature on September 27 Sooner milo was developed at the Woodward (Oklahoma) Field Sta - tion from a cross of Dwarf Yellow and Early White milos. It has a heavy dry leafy stalk and at North Platte grew to a height of about 3'/ 2 feet, sooner outyielded corn in two of the four years 1929-30, 1932-33 and the A^rK" Wer , C S °° ner 20&gt;1 ' C ° m 243 - S ° me ° f the heads g— neck. At North Platte, Sooner matured slightly later than Dwarf Yellow milo and was discarded chiefly on account of poor yield. Sooner has shown some tendency in Kansas to lodge. frnm U 5 er "^ Was de , ve !°P5 d at the F°« Hays (Kansas) Branch Station from the cross of Pink kafir and milo, recrossed with milo. At North Flatte its growth and performance have been similar to Sooner In the four years 1930-33, Custer outyielded corn twice and the average yield! were Custer 2..0, corn 25.6. It was discontinued on account o( uSe maturity and no gain in yield over corn. fouHwf Th^ X , mil °: ka , fir haS dr ? stalks that g™ to a height of about four feet. The seed is similar to feterita. It outyielded corn somewhat in three of the four years 1930-33, and the average yields were Dwarf feterita </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties x milo 26.3, corn 25.6. It reached fair maturity but was discontinued on account of its slight gain over corn. Wheatland milo is from a cross of milo and kafir produced at the Woodward (Oklahoma) Field Station. It has a sturdy stalk that grows to a height of about three feet. It has been grown at North Platte only two years, 1932 and 1935. In 1932 its yield was more than twice that of corn and in 1935, five bushels per acre above corn. The two-year averages were Wheatland 37.1 and corn 23.3. Although this two-year test indicates that Wheatland may approach the better sorghum varieties in ability to yield and, has the advantage of suitable height for combine harvesting, its adapta - tion is limited by unsafe maturity to comparatively small areas in Nebraska. Cheyenne Sweet Stalk kafir is an early maturing variety developed in northwestern Kansas. It has slender stalks, somewhat variable in sweet - ness, that grow to a height of about six feet. The seed is white, non - bitter, and palatable. Grown at North Platte in 1933 and 1935, its two-year average yield was 27.6 bushels per acre, and the average yield of corn for the same years 26.3 bushels. Cheyenne makes an unusually rapid early growth. It also matures quickly after heading with less delay as a result of unfavorable weather than is the case with most sorghums. It will mature safely in a wide area in western Nebraska, and should have more value than corn as a combined grain, forage and ensilage crop. It should be cut as soon as mature to prevent shattering and lodging. Coes is a very early variety developed at the U. S. Dry Land Field Station, Akron, Colorado. It has a slender, slightly sweet stalk that grows to a height of about V/ 2 to 4 feet. The seed is white, non-bitter, and palat - able. It has been grown in the North Platte tests only two years, 1934 and 1935, producing an average yield of 17.7 bushels. Corn for these years averaged 15.0 bushels. The outstanding characteristic of Coes is its extreme earliness. Under average conditions, it should mature safely in those sections of Nebraska having the shortest growing season. It is some - what tall for combine harvesting, but probably can be handled in that way. Coes may be expected to produce less than the later-maturing varieties where the latter can be successfully grown. Greeley (Tribune No. 12) is another selection from the same Pink kafir-Freed sorgo cross from which Modoc was selected. Greeley was selected at the Tribune (Kansas) Branch Station. It has slender, slightly sweet stalks that grow to a height of about 4 feet. The seed is white and palatable. In the North Platte tests in 1933 and 1935, its average yield of 34.6 was 149 per cent of the yield of corn and practically the same as the average yield of Modoc for the same years. Greeley is early-maturing and can probably be grown safely some distance west of North Platte. Grohoma was produced in Oklahoma probably from a natural cross of unknown varieties. It has heavy dry stalks that grow to a height of about 4 Vz feet. The seed is mostly brown and unattractive in appearance. It Avas groAvn m the North Platte tests m 1933 and 1935. The first year </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 297 yield was the highest of the 17 varieties grown in the test. In the second year Grohoma was one of the four grain sorghums that produced less grain than corn. On account of uncertain maturity, poor seed quality, and un - even stalk growth, Grohoma is not regarded as a promising grain sorghum variety for Nebraska. Dwarf Yellow milo has a heavy, dry, rather leafy stalk that normally grows to a height of 3 to 4 feet. The heavy thick stalks make the tonnage of forage relatively high and its feed value low. The seed is large and palatable. In the 14-year comparison 1921-34 in the crop rotation fields at North Platte, its average yield was 23.8 bushels per acre and that of corn 23.0 bushels (Table 4). The higher yield is not considered sufficient to offset the higher cost of harvesting and lower feed value in comparison with corn. The tendency of the heads to "gooseneck" makes topping of bundles difficult, and poor emergence of heads, heavy stalks, and some - times excessive height makes it unsatisfactory for combine harvesting It does not always mature fully at North Platte, and is not recommended tor areas further north and west. Dwarf Yellow milo is also susceptible to chinch bug injury and should not be grown in sections where such injury is likely to occur. DIFFERENCES IN RESPONSE OF GRAIN SORGHUMS AND CORN TO SEASONAL VARIATIONS The differences between the grain sorghums and corn in growth habits heat requirements, and heat and drouth resistance result in a difference in their response to varying seasonal conditions. Combinations of weather conditions more favorable to one may occur in one season and those more favorable to the other in other sea - sons. In the varietal tests, the corn Table 4. — Comparative annual and yields in 1924 and 1928 were more average gra/'n yields of corn and than double the grain - sorghum Dwarf Yellow milo in six crop yields (Table 1). In 1932 and 1935, rotations— 1921-34. much higher yields were made by ~ Acre yid.h (»,„*,/,) the grain sorghums than by corn. ' ~T j — Dwarf ov™?*!,") Dwarf Yellow milo and corn rn I Y '»™ """ were grown in four crop rotations i"h 30.7 30.9 o'l under comparable conditions, for !&lt;$ \\* s - 6 - 51 the fourteen years 1921-34. The "*" i° 5 n.s lj annual and average yields and the iwr -ir.'.n ,,j;i —is'l annual gain or loss of milo in com- \™ u'j i°1 ~ j^ parison with corn are shown in J™' *&amp; 4S.fi 13.3 Table 4. In the thirteen years that 1932 -;- 3 9.5 'J| recoverable yields were produced, [^ 2 ™ - ju Dwarf Yellow milo made the higher ii 2ilo im 0 ;jj yield seven times, in amounts rang- * Mim; &gt; 'ten indicates im*. ing from 0.2 to 18.5 bushels per acre. Corn produced the higher yield six times, in amounts ranging from 0.1 to 15.8 bushels per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties THE EFFECTS OF THE GRAIN SORGHUMS AND CORN ON SUCCEEDING CROPS In comparing the total values of grain sorghums and corn, considera - tion should be given not only to relative yields and to feeding values which ( finally determine prices, but also to residual effects on the land that influence the yields of the crops which follow. Corn is recognized as having a high value in dry-land crop rotations on account of not ex - hausting soil moisture as thoroughly as the small grains, and allowing a greater carry-over for the benefit of the crops that follow. In the dry-land crop rotations at North Platte, average yields of all crops following corn have been higher than those following small grains except where rigid after-harvest weed control was practiced on the latter (see Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bulletin 279). Grain sorghums have not shown a like beneficial effect upon succeeding crops. The crop rotations from which the yields of corn and Dwarf Yellow milo are shown in Table 4 may also be used to show the relative effects of the two crops upon each other and upon crops of barley which follow. The 14-year average yields are arranged according to rotations in Table 5. The six rotations make three pairs. In two of Table 5. — Average yields of corn, milo, and barley from six crop rotations, 1921-34. 14-ycar average acre yields Rotations ■ Corn Milo , Barlc l r Barley after corn after milo No, Bu. Hit. Bit. Bu. 60 — 2-yr., corn-barley 23.9 ... 17.9 601— 2-yr., milo-barlcy 23.6 . . . 14.4 410 — 3-yr., corn-barley-wintcr wheat 23.9 ... 23.9 413 — 3-yr.. milo-barlcy-winter wheat ... 23.1 16.4 409—1-yr., milo-corn-harlcy-ryc 21.1 23.3 17.1 408 — l-yr., corn-milo-barlcy-ryc 23.2 25.0 ... 16.5 Average 23.0 23.8 19.6 15.8 Increase in milo over ccirn ... 0.8 ... ... Decrease in barley after milo from barley after corn ... ... ... 3.8 these pairs, corn is used in one and milo in the other. In the third pair, both corn and milo are used in each rotation, but the order is changed so that in one case corn follows milo and in the other milo follows corn. In all cases corn or milo is followed by barley. In the two-year rotations Nos. 60 and 601, the average acre yields of corn and milo alternating with barley are about equal, i.e., 23.9 and 23.6 bushels, respectively. The barley yield after corn exceeded that after milo 3.5 bushels per acre. In the three-year rotations Nos. 410 and 413, the corn and milo yields are also about equal, i.e., 23.9 and 23.1 bushels, respectively. Barley after corn exceeded barley after milo 7.5 bushels per acre. In the four-year rotations Nos. 409 and 408, corn yields after milo and rye were 21.1 and 23.2 bushels per acre respectively, with 2.1 bushels more </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 297 where rye was the preceding crop. Milo yields after corn and rye were 25.0 and 23.3 bushels per acre respectively, with a yield 1.7 bushels higher where corn was the preceding crop. The yields of barley after corn and milo were 17.1 and 16.5 bushels respectively, i.e., a yield 0.6 bushel higher where corn was the preceding crop. In the six rotations, the average yields of corn and milo from 56 plat - years each were 23.0 and 23.8 bushels per acre respectively — a higher yield of 0.8 bushel in favor of milo. The average acre yields of barley from 42 plat-years each after corn and milo were 19.6 and 15.8 bushels respectively — a higher yield of 3.8 bushels where corn was the preceding crop. In order to be rated superior to corn, a grain sorghum should not only yield enough to more than make up any comparative lack of feed value, but, on the basis of these tests, should produce several additional bushels to compensate for possible losses in yield of the succeeding crop. FORAGE SORGHUMS ) Only a few varieties of sorgo (forage sorghum) have been grown at the North Platte Experimental Substation. These are described and com - pared as follows: Amber sorghums in Nebraska vary in height from .5 to 9 feet and in time of maturing as much as 30 days. The seed colors are either black or red. They have in common the characteristics of sweet, juicy stalks, hard, bitter seed, and ability to germinate and produce good stands under less favorable conditions than many other sorghums. Much of the seed used is produced locally and its regional adaptation preserved. It is grown both in close drills and in cultivated rows, with about equal yields of forage. In I ;. . tj. '"*■"•.'• Xll ' ' ' •' id'"'**'"''" ' \ "' '' J JI.^1 "^ '' t^i^lm^^* * ' m ''~ ~ w ■ - -. ' g^^i^ V - '^^X-a^ Fie. 1. — Atlas sorgo left, Cocs sorgo right. Yields (1934) of cured forage on fallowed land: Atlas 5.6 tons, Coes 1.0 ton per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Grain and Forage Sorghum Varieties more favorable localities, close drill seeding is preferred for forage and cultivated rows for seed production. In drier sections wide-row seeding is used for both forage and seed. At the North Platte station, Red Amber, which is sometimes erron - eously called Orange, has been grown in close drills on dry land for many years. Its average yield is about 3 54 tons per acre. Yields above five tons per acre were made in some of the better years, and yields below two tons occurred on the average in only one year out of seven. In the 1935 varietal test, Red Amber sorghum in cultivated rows produced 4.5 tons of field-cured forage exclusive of. seed, and 36.3 bushels per acre of seed. Early sumac is an early selection of standard Sumac made at the Fort Hays (Kansas) Branch Station. It has very juicy, sweet leafy stalks that grow to a height of about six feet. The seed is bitter, dark red in color, much smaller, and threshes freer of the glumes than Amber. In the 1935 tests at North Platte, Early sumac produced 5.5 tons of high-quality field - cured forage and 26.9 bushels of seed per acre. Early sumac is highly prized for forage in western Kansas. It seems probable that a large portion of the Amber acreage in southern and southwestern Nebraska could be profitably replaced by Early sumac. Atlas is a selection from a cross between Sourless sorgo and Blackhull kafir that possesses the good qualities of both. It was developed by the Kansas Agricultural Experiment Station, Manhattan, and first distributed from there to farmers in 1928. The variety has sturdy, leafy, abundantly sweet, juicy stalks that grow to a height of 7 to 10 feet. The seed is white with red markings, not bitter, palatable, and attractive in appearance. It requires 120 to 130 days to mature. In eastern and central Nebraska, it has been received with enthusiasm on account of the high yields of foiagc and ensilage produced. The limits to which the profitable production can be extended north and west in the state have not been determined. The trials at North Platte indicate that it may have promise for forage and ensilage in territory considerably beyond the range of mature seed pro - duction. Atlas has been grown at North Platte for only three years, 1933 to 1935. On dry land, the three-year average yield of seed was 13.4 bushels per acre. For the same year the average yield of corn was 20.2 bushels, of Early Kalo 343 bushels, and of Club kafir 34.9 bushels. The Atlas seed pro - duced was immature, and could be made suitable for planting only by careful drying before freezing weather. Forage yields of Atlas were secured only in 1934 and 1935. In 1934, the yield on dry land cropped the previous year was 2.7 tons per acre, and on land fallowed the previous year 5.6 tons per acre (Fig. 1). Amber sorghum yields with these preparations were respectively 0.6 and 1.1 tons. In 1935 on dry land cropped the previous year, the yield of Atlas was 6.7, of Sumac 5.5 tons, and of Amber 4.7 tons. All weights are of field-cured forage. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 297- ATLAS SORGO VS. CORN FOR ENSILAGE UNDER IRRIGATION Atlas sorgo and corn have been grown on commercial fields for ensil me for the two years 1934 and 1935. The previous treatment and amount of water used per acre were not the same on all fields, and the comparisons are not as exact as though the two crops had been grown experimentally n the same field. However, the results show the reactions of the two cops to different seasonal conditions, and may be considered as general indicators ot the relative values of the two crops on fertile soil under irrigation In the hot. dry season of 1934, corn was permanently injured by burn - ing between irngations, and Atlas was much less severely affected The average ensilage yields were Atlas 15.2 tons and corn 5.9 tons per acre In 193d with temperature conditions more nearly normal, corn made about the usual response to irrigation, and the growth of Atlas was less than that of the previous year. The average ensilage yields were Atlas 11 3 tons, corn 14.0 tons per acre. The two-year average ensilage yields were Atlas li.5 tons, corn 10 tons. &lt;5M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>