<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  SILO CONSTRUCTION IN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXV, Article VIII. SILO CONSTRUCTION IN NEBRASKA. Bt L. W. Chase. June, 1913. Homemade concrete block silos on R. B. Schneider's farm, Fremont. Nebr. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA D. S. A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. &gt;THf REGENTS OF THE UMIVEREITv) HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Lincoln. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE PRANK L. HALI.ER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL A VERY, Ph. D., I.L. D., Chancellor, ex officio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. B DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF, EIeab Wu-cox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. .1. Ai.way, Ph. D.. Agricultural Chemistry. 7. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. '.. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. EGain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. PttAvnSEX, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. ence Bki'ner, B. Sc., Entomology. Kiesrelbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. C. W. Pugblev, B. Sc, Farm Management and Agricultural Extension. W. J. Morrtix, M. For., Forestry. Erwtx H. Barbour, Ph D.. Geology. KChatbur?!, A. M., Hiahway Engineering. Emerson, D. Sc, Bortteuttmre. O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. G. A. Lovelaxd, A. M., Meteorology. ■ P. Snt^eh. M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation. North Platte. IW. Burr, B. Sc.. Associate in Soils and Crops. North Platte; Assist - ant Agriculturist, Op.cc Dry Land Agriculture. U. 8. Department of Agriculture. M. H. Swexk. A. M.. Associate in Entomology. (E K. K. Link, A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Botany. . TbUIUUIX, A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. R. McDor.E. A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. on O. Rost, A. M., ' "r'xtnnt iti Agricultural Chemistry. I Hopt, B Sr., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). RATn.tFF, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). s Rail, B. S. A., Assistant in Animal Husbandry. Lee, B. St.. Assistant in Animal Husbandry H. J. Grami.ich, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Stttrdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant tn Animal Pathology. G. C. White, A. M., Assistant in Dairying. T. R. Cooptr. B Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. James Cowan. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation Valentine. Fritz Knorh, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. 8. W. Pebtn, Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nti, Foreman Demonstration Farm. Culbertgon. • Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">I .NTRODUC TION j, Abbreviations t Location of silo 5 Amount to be fed 6 Size of the silo 5 Essentials of a well-designed silo ,. M g Types of silos 9 Wood Silos 10 Stave silos 10 Silo woods 11 Ordering stave silos — The manufactured silo 1L The homemade tongued and grooved stave silo 11 Bill of materials for a silo 16 feet by 30 feet 12 Foundation IS Constructing the foundation 13 Erecting stave silos 14 Silo doors 17 Homemade doors 18 Silo roofs 18 Laying out and constructing the roof 19 Anchoring the silo 19 Chute and ladder 2u Painting 20 Care of wood silos 21 Inspection of wood stave silos 22 Tables of materials for wood stave silos 22 Pit Silos, ob Sn.os in the Grocxd 27 Gas in pit silos 28 Types of pit silos 23 Constructing pit silos 28 Removing the earth from pit silos 30 Plastering the walls 3S Cost of pit silos 32 Inspection of pit silos 35 Concrete Block Silos 36 Kinds of blocks 36 Size of blocks 88 Concrete block machine 39 Making concrete blocks 41 Mixtures for concrete blocks 44 Curing the blocks 4 1 Foundations 41 Mortar 45 Reinforcing 4o Door frames and doors h Intermittent door frames 4 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Concrete Block Silos — Comluded. page Continuous door frames 49 Doors 52 Scaffold 52 Hoisting the material 65 Laying the walls 56 The roof 56 Cornice blocks 57 Cost of concrete block silos 61 Inspection of concrete block silos 84 Clay Block, or Hollow Bkiik Sii.os 68 Foundations 67 Doors 67 Scaffold M 68 ■• The silo walls 68 Reinforcing the walls 69 Roofs 69 Bill of material used in Iowa silo on I'niversity Farm 69 Cost of clay block silos 71 Solid Concrete Silos 73 Style of concrete silo 74 Forms 7 J Constructing homemade forms 74 Foundations 78 The walls 78 Sand, stone, and gravel 79 Cement 79 Proportions of cement and sand 79 Mixing the concrete 79 The reinforcing 80 Doors 82 Staging 82 Hoisting the concrete 83 Erecting the walls 83 The roof 84 Making and placing cornice blocks 85 Reinforcing the roof 86 Placing the concrete on the roof 87 Cost of concrete silos 88 Other Sii.oh 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">BY L. \V. CHASK. INTRODUCTION. To the people of Nebraska, silos are a new part of the farm equipment. Tn southern Europe they have been used for ages, but not for storing Indian corn. Historians tell us that the leaves from grapevines were placed in pits in the ground and these pits then covered with earth. In the winter this forage was removed and fed to the stock. Silos were first introduced into America about 1875. These early silos were not of the same style as those we now see, but were more in the form of pits walled with stone, some of them reaching above the ground and some of them only coming to the surface. In the discussion of the pit silo in this bulletin, it should be remembered that this is the oldest and original form of silo construction, and, while this type has largely been abandoned in order to secure the benefits of greater height and larger ca - pacity, the peculiar soil conditions in western, central, and many parts of eastern Nebraska make this type of silo worthy of con - sideration. ABBREVIATIONS. ' = foot. *bd. = board. " = inches. r^jcu. yd., cu. yds. = cubic yard, d.=penny (8d.=eightpenny). i^- cubic yards. pc, pcs. = piece, pieces. c^c = cents (50c, 50 cents) rd.=round. LOCATION OF SILO. Silos may be located within the barn, but only in a few instances has it been found economical to do so. Many men hare learned that if their silos had been within the barn they would not have been wrecked by the wind. However, silos should be of such construction that they can withstand the weather without the protection of barn walls. When silos are built BUL. 188. AQR. EXP. STATION OF XEBK. VOL. XXV, ABT. VIII. LIMITED (5) </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 the silage while the barn holds and protects the silo. B5y placing the silo adjacent to the barn and in close prox - y to the feed-way, the silage can be handled as conveniently io the silo were within the barn. i[t is preferable to have the silo at the north end or side of barn. When in this position it retards the force of the north ds in the winter and docs not interfere with the sun's rays does it break the southern summer breezes. A wood silo n placed in the shadow of the barn is not as susceptible to ing out during the summer months as when more exposed to sun. I A. silo built into the bank adjoining a hank ltarn is without bt the nioRt economical type of construction and location, cutter used for filling such a silo is set on the hank. thereby airing u shorter elevator and a correspondingly smaller engine. • silage can be removed from the base of the chute and put i the mangers without being elevated. AMOUNT TO BE FED. I As soon as the air comes in contact with silage, fermentation omes active and the silage soon spoils. After the silo is once ■ned it is essential that a certain amount of silage be removed tn the top daily or the surface will soon mold. The amount this daily removal will vary with the kind of silage, the &lt;le - e of ripeness, and the firmness with which it is packed when t into the silo. Since cold weather retards the action of bac - ia. it is not necessary that the silage be removed as fast in winter as in the summer. Silage made from green corn ■ks so much better than from over-ripe corn that it excludes 1 air more perfectly; consequently it will stand longer without It is considered good practice to remove between two and three inches daily from the entire surface of the silo during the summer months, and during the winter months this amount is reduced to about one-half that required in summer. SI7.K OF THE SILO. The first step in deciding the size of the silo is to determine the kind of live stock and the number to be fed. The number of days which the stock are to be fed determines the capacity re - quired and from this we get the diameter and height of the silo. If it is anticipated that at any time of the year more stock than the minimum number are to be fed. the capacity of the silo should be increased by increasing the height rather than by in creasing the diameter. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 ing table as an approximate guide for the amount of silage to be fed daily under average conditions to the various ages and kinds of stock : Table 1. — Approximate daily ration of silage. Stock sheep I Fattening sheep t Table 1 shows that if each dairy cow requires 40 |M&gt;unds per . 27 cows would require 1,060 jkhiikIs daily and for a 180-day ling season thev would require 1114.400 ftounds. which is prac - illy !&gt;7 tons of good feed. Since there is always some spoiled lm- the silo should hold at least 100 tons. If the feeding sea - is to be extended, the capacity of the silo must be increased. I In Table 2 it is found that a silo should be about 14 feet in meter to furnish the proper amount of feed for 27 cows. It 1 be seen from Table li that a silo 14 feet in diameter and feet deep will hold 100 tons. Tabu 2. — ftmte &lt;&gt;f feeding from tito* of different diameters. Approximate •Approximate number of the different kin.ls of lu-T .orKf st °^ to keep the siu * e f rom spoiiing in 8umm " r * If the silo is to be used for winter feeding only, it will require only one-half as many of each kind of stock to keep the silage in good condi - tion as where it is used for summer feeding. kiml of stock Weight eig Fed per d? perd lay I Stock horses Work horses Pounds .500 1,200 1,300 Pounds 5 if 10 I Calves Stock cattle Beef cows Dairy cows Fattening cuttle 500 1,000 1,300 1.000 1,200 I 40 25 *,,,,,- - Summer Winter Ho- «£ Stock cattle Beef cattle Dairy C0W8 .V25 755 1,030 1,340 1,700 2,100 263 378 515 670 850 1,050 48 44 69 63 94 86 122 112 155 142 191 175 26 38 52 67 85 105 21 30 41 54 68 84 13 19 26 34 42 53 I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 (n parity of round silos in (From King's Tables.) I Io«de Inside diameter of silo, in feet hei K of , in feet 10 12 14 16 18 20 126 38 51 67 85 105 34 49 66 87 110 135 37 55 75 98 123 154 42 61 83 108 136 169 47 67 92 119 151 186 51 74 100 131 166 205 56 80 109 143 181 -'24 87 119 155 196 242 94 128 169 213 261 101 138 180 229 282 172 208 264 I Where a large number of stork are to be fed from a silo it is rays better to build two silos of a smaller diameter than one an extremely large diameter. This is especially true of stave ». The shell of a large stave silo is no thicker than the shell a small silo but its sides are much nearer flat, hence it will : resist the wind pressure nearly so well as a small silo. ESSENTIALS OF A WELL-DESIGNED SILO. The essential features a well-designed silo can be summed np briefly as follows : 1. The walls should be practically air-tight. 2. The inner surfaces of the walls should be smooth and per- pendicular. 3. The inner surfaces of the walls should be free from corner*. Bound silos are more efficient and economical than other types. 4. The walls should be sufficiently non-conducting to prevent excessive freezing. — especially so when the silage is to be fed during cold weather. 5. The waJls should be sufficiently firm or sufficiently well anchored to prevent cracking due to settling or racking due to 6. The doors should be so designed that a minimum amount of silage has to be removed before they can be opened. 7. A good ladder should be provided with steps from II inches to 18 inches apart and at least 34 inches away from the silo or walls of the chute. 8. The foundation should be heavy, well made, and reach be- low the frost line. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Silo Construction in Nebraska. 9 9. A good roof makes the silo more durable, adds greatly to its appearance, and if tight assists materially in keeping the silage from freezing. Silos which have the above features will be found convenient, cause little trouble, and when properly filled will keep the silage in perfect condition. TYPES OF SILOS. There are two general types of silos — 1. Pit silos, or silos built partially or wholly below ground; 2. Silos above ground, built of wood or of masonry. The stave silo is the most common of the wood type in Ne- braska. The masonry silo is commonly built of — Concrete hollow blocks; Clay block or hollow brick; Solid concrete, built by pouring concrete into form; some - times called the "monolithic silo." Concrete plastered on metal lath. All masonry silos should be reinforced with steel, and when so reinforced are the most durable form of above-ground con - struction </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 WOOD SILOS. EVood silos in various forms are used thruout the Kast, but in rask.-t the wood stave silo seems more popular, altho during past year the wood silo known as the crib silo has been in- I'ccd and is receivin«; considerable attention. Single-piece fir stave silo, at Beef Cattle Barn, University Farm Lincoln, Nebr. K Since a consideration cannot be made here of all the wood k. the discussion will be confined to the wooden stave silos. § There are three general types of these silos, the homemade in stave, the homemade tongued and {grooved, and the maim tured tongued and grooved. The first type mentioned is somewhat cheaper than the other types, but it does, not seem possible to hold in sha|»e silos made STAVK SILOS. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 when the silos are empty the air gets on all sides of the staves and causes them to dry out faster than if tongued and grooved. BThe second tyjie of silo is ms strong as any stave silo and as ily cared for. hut is more trouble to order than the third e. which also is likely to have more convenient doors. sir.o woods. I ; il«s have not bm in Mr long enough in Nebraska to warrant drawing of any definite conclusion as to lasting qualities of ■rent kinds of wood. Two white pine homemade plain stave &lt; MOT Omaha, examined after having been used eight years, t found vei-v badly decayed at the lower ends of the staves. heap white pine silo on the I'niversity Farm was practically ed out at the end of five years' use. while a better grade of te pine silo, hnilt in 100 1. which has been in use about eight one-half years, lias just commenced to decay at the lower &lt; of the staves and is apparently in perfect condition above first foot. t Bulletin No. 100, Iowa Experiment Station, places the merits voods for silo use as follows: 11. Redwood; 'J. Cypress: S, Oregon Fir; 4. Tamarack; 5, ite Pine; fi. Long Leaf Yellow Pine. OKDKRIN(i STAVE SILOS. The Mmmmfmttmioi sik&gt;. — In ordering a silo it must be borne I mind that the custom of silo manufacturers is to sell only silo proper, or outside wall, with the necessary anchor rods 1 also the rafters for the roofs. In order to complete the silo, the following materials are needed The Homemade Tongue/] and Grooved Stave Silo. — This silo needs all the material just mentioned under ordering "The Manu - factured Silo" and in addition needs the material for the silo proper with the anchors and rafters. The bill of materials should be made up about as follows, and should be ordered at least ninetv davs before needed: *ilo floor Table 4. page 22 foundation wall Table 5. page 22 Sheathing Table 8. page 25 hoofing Table 8. page 25 Table 7. page 23 Jfcate. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Silo Construction in Nebraxku. BILL OF MATERIALS FOR A SILO 16 FEET BY 30 FEET. Port Table 4. Floor, 16.4 sacks cement, 2.88 eu. yds. sand. . $10.16 Table B. Foundation. 3 ft. deep, 36.9 sacks cement. 6.48 cu. vds. sand 22 . 90 Table 6. Door materials, 4 I"x4"xl2', 1 2"x4"xl2', 7 T hinges, 2 lbs. 12d. nails, 1 lb. 8d. nails, 7 2" screws 1 . 12 Table 7. Staves. 117, 30' long (3,510 bd. ft.) 17.^ M Table 7. Hoops, 27 pcs. 4"xl8' rd. steel, 15 pcs. J"xl8' rd. steel. 3 pos. 3"xl8' rd. steel. Total weight 687 lbs 22:50 Table 7. Hoop lugs, 27 I", 15 f". 3 3'' 4 . :»0 Table 10. Guy wires, 150' of 7 strand No. 9 wire cable. . 3.16 Table 10. Bolts, 4 *"x2J" 20 Table 10. Loop bolts, 4 i"x36" 1 .25 Table 10. Eye bolts, 4 |"xl2" 80 Table 10. Bods, 4 £"x about 4' M Table 10. Bottom anchors. 4 i"s24". with eve and bend. .M Table 8. Batters, 18 2"x4"xlO' 1" .' 3.14 Table 8. Sheathing, 38 l"x8"x!0' 10" 9.48 Table 8. Shingles. 11} bunches 12.00 Table 9. Headers. 2 2"x4"xl2' 40 Table 9. Nails. 10 lbs. 4d.. 12 lbs. 10(1.. 2 lbs. 20d 1.20 Total $269.31 FOUNDATION Stone, brick, hollow brick, concrete blocks, or concrete may lie used for the foundation, but because of the ease of handling and the inexperienced help required concrete is preferable. The most common style of found:ition is shown in figure 5. but there is this objection to it, that in order to keep the stave* from slipping off the foundation a ledge of at least five inches must be left on the inside, and this ledge prevents the silage from settling projierl.v, tlms causing it to spoil just above and below t lit' junction of the silo :ind foundation. A preferable foundation is shown in figure 1. This consists of a floor of concrete, upon which the staves are set. but this necessarily makes the silo more expensive per ton capacity than the silo foundation first mentioned, since the cheapest part of the silo is that part made by throwing the dirt out from Pig. L inside t 1 &lt;&gt; foundation. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Silo Construction in Xebruxka. 13 Concrete should never be plastered on the outside of the silo to make a tight joint at the ends of the staves, and neither should it be put on the inside. In the former case the staves will soon shrink away and then a pocket be formed which will gather dirt and water and hasten the decay of the staves, while in the latter case the concrete will hold the staves out so that they cannot I tightened and as a consequence the silo will leak and rack. •bably the best material to put in this corner is well-worked f. It will make a tight joint and yet when the staves are itened will let them draw together. The clay should prob - y be replaced every year. CONSTRUCTING THE FOUNDATION tlf the ground is not level where the silo is to be located, ghly locate the outside of the foundation and level the ground, n set a stake where the center of the silo should be, and, by ins of another stake and a string, scratch on the ground the h for the inside and outside of the foundation (fig. 2\. If a Fig. 2. Laying out the lines for the foundation. Fig. 3. The trench dug, ready for the founda - tion. stave silo is to be set on the foundation, the inside diameter of the foundation should be about 10 inches less than the diameter of the silo. Theoretically the' two should be the same, but be - cause the staves of the silo shrink and because it is hard to get the inside of the silo round there must be a wide surface for the silo to rest upon, even at the expense of some spoiled silage at this place. When the foundation is marked out. then dig out the trench as shown in figure 3. using care to get the inside smooth and keeping it firm. The sides of the trench are the forms for the concrete. In making the forms for the foundation above the ground, use almost any kind of scrap material for the stakes. Use care, however, to keep the insides straight and vertical and true to the edge of the excavation. If the edge of the trench caves badly when driving the stakes, the concrete can be put into the trench l»efore the stakes are driven; but before the re - maining concrete is put in, the surface of the set concrete should </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 be swept and washed clean and covered with a coat of pure cement and water. Be sure to set the anchor lugs AAAA (fig. 1 1 before the concrete is filled too high in the forms. Do not leave the forms out of level expecting 1o level the con - crete in the forms. Tt is much easier to level the tops of the forms hv raining and lowering the stakes than to level the sur - face of the concrete within the form*. Before throwing the dirt out of the inside of the foundation, scratch a line on top of the foun - dation hy means of a cord an.1 staves are to be set. This line Ki,j. 4. Illustrating the form and foundation. nail, which will tell where thf is shown by BBBB in figure 4 and by A A A in figure 5. I One-half inch lumber or common weather boards can be used the forms above ground, but they should be left ont in the i or be soaked before using. EHECTINf; STAVE SILOS. The most practical method of erecting stave silos is by means of the single post staging. I This method consists (fig. 5) of erecting a six. seven, or eight - mJ staging around the foundation of the silo. When the stag - is completed it forms a cage the sides of which brace each pr. The planks which are used for walks and are placed at erent elevations in the staging assist also in bracing the tern - ary structure. tTo erect the staging, first consider how high the planks which to be used should be placed to make them convenient for idling the hoops. If the foundation is two feet from the nnd. the first and second hoops should be put on by standing the ground, while the third can be put on from the first walk the staging, and then continue on up to the top of the silo, th this plan in mind, the first walk of the staging should be &gt;nt ten feet from the ground and the remaining walks should about nine feet apart. Lay ont and build up, on the ground, sections BBB (fig. 5). using 2x4's 16 feet long for posts and 1x6 fencing boards 16 feet long for the cross braces. Raise two of the sections in place and temporarily brace them with some fencing boards. Place the lower cross-tie fC), which is a 2x6 of any length over 12 feet. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 and nail it. then raise the other sections into place and nail up the remaining two lower cross-ties (CC). Place the planks DDD in position and nail them to the cross-ties. Place the planks EEE in position on the ends of the other planks, but do not Fig. 5. The single post stage method of erecting stave silos. nail them. Then using some of the temporary braces put on the cross-braces and continue with the remaining walks. Material to be used in staging for all silos 10 feet and leas in diameter and from 28 to 30 feet high : Posts, 12 2xl's, 16 ft. long. Cross-braces. 24 Ix6's, 16 ft. long. Cross-ties. 9 2x6's. 12 ft. long or longer Planks, 18 2xl2's. 12 ft. long or longer. To erect the homemade silo, first select a straight stave. Lay out the points for the top and bottom of the doors and saw part </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 way thru one of them as shown at A, figure 6. [ These saw kerfs are made so that the saw mav enter when it is time to saw out before the hoops are all on. k Measure across the top of the silo in several places and see he silo is round. Tf it is. the roof can he put on right away t can be left until the silo is filled. The latter method is the ier way. I Should the silo not happen to be round, it can be trued by 'ing timbers of the proper length in between the staves on ©site sides across the narrow diameter. I If the silo is not round both at the top and bottom and is not mb. it will settle out of shape and cause a great deal of I doors, i Nail another stave temporarily to this one to stiffen Set these two staves in place where the door should come. I plumb and stay them in at least three different places. Set staves up on either side of this stave and nail them to- her by means of water-soaked lath or barrel staves. Plumb staves occasionally and stay them to the staging. A row of soaked cleats should be nailed on at the top, the middle, and bottom. Keep every stave exactly on the line scratched on . the foundation. 1 £} ' If the silo is a manufactured ■j-y .-=Lc = "]~~U -4 tl stave silo, set the door frame I tl first and proceed in the same ■*~1 r = °rC^p^T~' -f-H nianner as described above. The staves can be conven- k I -'I iently slipped thru the staging I at almost any point (O, flg. 5). ! t -r-r; ( I i Often it is easy for the man on i~K "" 1 I 1 the top staging to handle the top of the stave with a piece of The last sta\e .an be put in hi | - |l I place by spreadiiis the adjacent I staves out from the true circle 4 s -i— I and after the stav has been in- •I — it~ ' * T ' wi'ted crowding them hack into s - line. Another method of pat- Fig. 6. Door details. tin S the last 8tavp into »' laoe is to snread the stavet? at the top only and lifting up the last Rtave crowd it down into place. The first method is preferable. Place the top and bottom hoops in position and tighten them first. They lessen the danger of having the silo wrecked by wind ! i only a The fin JF- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 trouble in the future. Never fill a new silo until it is Imth round and plumb. ■Every stave should be stapled or nailed to the hoops in ;it st two places and preferably in three. SILO DOOES. t?he silo door is not as vital a part of the silo as many people wont to make it. However, it is operated more times than any other part and should tx- conveniem and yet durable and tight The opening should be large and easy of access. The most convenient opening inspected was 22 inches wide and 42 inches high. Such an opening, however, is feasible only in masonry silos. The hoops of a stave sil« should never be over three feet apart hence the door opening must l&gt;e less than three feet high. Generally they are about 20x30 inches. The doors should be easily opened and easily closed. The design should be such that as little silage will have to be removed from in front of them as possible before they can be opened. They should be so designe* that it is not necessary tc have mon than one door open at a time. In e&gt; tremely cold climates it is well to have . door which can be opened and close* culi time silage is taken out. A close( door in a silo will do very much towan keeping the silage from freezing aloni the walls. The inside of the doors should be smooth iind the doors should fit against the silo wall so tight that there is no opportunity for the entrance of air. It is well to nail felt or some type of Pig. 7. Section of silo gasket material around Ihe doors where &amp; owing doors and plac - s, of hoops. they rest on the silo, as this will make the joint tighter. When the doors have become wiped, it is often well to smear a layer of thick clay around on the door frame so that when tho door is put in place it settles into the clay and makes a tight joint. emptying a silo, always put the doors back in place as : as the silage is used down below them, and keep them in </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 much abuse when in place and they prevent the formation of air currents thru the silo which tend to dry out the staves. HOMEMADE DOORS. Tlio doors should be about four staves wide (fig. •&gt;». By means of the square, lay off the top and bottom lines (if each door, being careful to have the lines pass thru the saw kerfs that were made in the first stave set up. Saw out the door pieces, nail them together with the % 2"x'2" cleats, put the button on the lower end and the T hinge on the upj&gt;er end, then put the door in place and by means of a claw hammer bend the upper end of the hinge so it will hook over the hoop. When the I"x4" strips have l»een nailed to the staves adjoining the doors, the silo is ready for the roof. To ojten the doors, turn the button and by means of the fork handle spring down the hoop over which the hinge is fastened and the latter will unhook and the door fall in. Because of patents which cover the bracing and reinforcing about continuous doors in stave silos it is practically impossible to make them without infringing on these patents. SILO ROOFS. Many silos are built and used without roofs, but this is no doubt false economy. The roof serves three purposes. It strengthens the silo, keeps out storms, and when built tight, as it should be. assists very materially in keeping the silage from freezing. The conical roof presents a much more pleasing ap]&gt;earance than either the pyramidal or gable roof and is fully as easily jnvmu m twmlm- 3 Fig. S. Showing construction and details of roof. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 :uicl &lt;-hc;i|ih i ■oiisTi-iii-tcd. Where two silos are constructed to - gether, they are sometimes connected with one roof. Such a plan makes it much more convenient to handle the upper end of the blower, but the roof does not present as neat an appearance and when built tight over both silos, to keep out the cold, is much more expensive than two conical roofs. LAYING OUT AND CONSTRUCTING THE HOOF. I 'ut a piece of post or log large enough for the peak of the '. or build up a block for this purpose, made of 2"xl2" planks to a circle and nailed together so that the grains cross. Nail upper ends of the rafters to this block. Any pitch will do the rafters, but the bill of material for the roof in Table 8 iade up for one-third pitch. The rafters can be laid out the e as the rafters of any building, remembering, of course, that ridge is twelve inches wide. I The rafters should all be placed in position and then spaced eqml distance apart before the length of the header is meas - i. Place the header far enough below the center of the rafters :ive a bearing for the upper end of the short piece of sheathing. Table !• will be found the radius of a circle which should be d for cutting the outside of the header. All the headers can cut at once except the last one. and its length should l&gt;e left il it is time to place it; then it should be cut to fit the dis - et bi 'tween the last two rafters. ANCHORING THE S1I.O. The anchors are almost if not quite as important as the lumps Pig. 9. One method of anchoring Fig. 10. Details of anchor shown in figure 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 the toji ;ind the bottom Manx silos are erected with no anchors at the bottom, but they nearly always give trouble by blowing in. Manufac - tured silos are nearly always equipped with sufficient anchors and cables. Icanies. There are two methods of an - choring the homemade silos. One is ■ shown in figure 9 with the details in figure 10. The cable ctauapi around the rod D and into the eve - bolt B which in turn passes thru the tank lag. The loop bolt A can be fastened to a post or a deadman as shown. Figure 11 shows how to anchor the top by looping the wires around the rod D at one end and with a post at the other, theu twisting them up with a stick. »11. A simple method of anchoring silos. CHt-TE AND LADDER, t.\ chute for conveying the silage from the top of the silo to ground should be constructed on all silos. They save feed. i to keep storms out of the silo when the doors are open, and greatly to the appearance of the building if neatly made. A venient size is about three feet square, but the chute make* cttcr npj toara nee if it is at least four feet square. I If the ladder is a part of the door frame, it saves the trouble constructing one. altho it is a question whether a good ladder ilt onto the side of the chute and at right angles to the door not more convenient. The runjjs of I lie ladder should be from lfi inches to 18 inches apart and at least four inches from the walls of the silo or the chute. They can l&gt;e made of I"x2" pieces nailed to 2"x4" pieces sitting edgewise up and down the sides of the silo or chute, or a better way is to nail them onto the studding of the chute. PAINTING Silos have not been in use long enough in Nebraska to de - termine whether it pays to paint the staves on the inside with some form of pitch or tar. It is quite true that when the st;iv»-s </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Silo &lt; onxtnution in Xebraska. 21 •ire painted on the inside the silage does not settle quite as well, neither do the walls of the silo clean as well. There is no doubt but that the silo, like all other farm buildings, should be kept well painted on the outside. It no doubt will add to the life of the building and also add very much to the appearance of the place. CARE OF WOOD SILOS, The silo is one part of the farm building equipment whicl must have attention just at the proper time. A great many silos have been either blown down or badly wrecked because the farmer put off tightening the hoops or fastening the anchors If a strong wind comes up when the hoops are loose or an anchor is not fastened, either the staves will be blown in at the bottom or at the top, or the silo will be blown down. It is almos impossible to put sufficient emphasis on the necessity of keepinj the hoops at the proper adjustment when the silo is empty am of always having the anchors fastened. It is impossible to give any definite rule for the amount of attention which should be given the hoops, but they should never become so loose that they sag. They probably should be tight - ened two or three times during the summer, and then in the fall loosened when the silo is being filled. If the hoops are tightened too much when the silo is dry, there is great danger of the staves swelling sufficiently to cause them to buckle during a rainy spell. If the door frame is flat, the buckling will take place at that point first; hence the necessity of selecting a well-constructed door frame in a silo. If the hoops are too tight and the staves are dry, when the silo is filled the staves will absorb so much moisture from the silage that it will cause them to expand and unless the hoops are very strong and united with heavy lugs there is danger o: the Ings or the hoops breaking. Even tho the silo is very well anchored and the hoops are kept properly adjusted, sometimes it will get out of plumb, that is, it will lean or rack to one side. It is never best to fill a silo when it is not standing perfectly straight, and the best time to straighten a silo is during the summer when the staves are dry and free to slip past each other. The silo can be straightened by using the anchor rods to wrap around the top, then hitching a traction engine to the other end of the rods and very slowly pulling the silo hack to an erect position. If it is not possible to get a traction engine, a block and tackle with a good team of horses will often be sufficient. Sometimes the silo can be straightened by the use of a heavy woven wire fence stretcher to pull it back to' a perpendicular. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Silo Construction in yebraxka. INgPBCTION OF WOOD STAVE SILOS. The observation of a large number of stave silos leads to the recommendation of careful and frequent inspection of the condition of the anchors and hoops on this type of silo to prevent, in so far as possible, their Ihmiijj wrecked or injured by the wind when standing empty in summer. A number of such silos were entirely wrecked liefore they had been built twelve months, while others were not wrecked until they had been used about five years and one had stood eight years l&gt;efore it was blown down; while others, tho not wrecked, were Mown out of plumb and re - quired considerable labor and expense to put them in condition for use. T.USI.KS OF MATERIALS FOR WOOD BTAVE SII.ns. Tabu 4. — Materials for foiirinrh eomentf floor. Table a. — "Materials for a I irelre ineh eomrete foundation wall. one foot in height. Mixture 1:2:4 Mixture 1:5 Dian Her of Sacks Cu. yds. Cu. yds. Sacks Cu. yds. jilo, in feet cement sand stone cement san.l stone cement san.l * If the silo foundation is to be more than one foot high, multiply the above quantities by the denth of the foundation in feet. Mixture 1:2:4 Mixture 1:5 tieter of in feet BMki Cu. yds. cement sand Cu. yds. ■tow Sacks Cu. .se- cernent sand 110 12 14 16 18 20 ti .45 8.75 Ii2 12 n:&lt; 15.fi 1 W 19.75 IJ8 24.4 1.71 .90 1.24 l.l&gt;4 2. is 2.74 3.42 7 1 ■-' '.•25 i.a 12.5 2 1(1 16.4 2.88 »J 3.65 35.65 4.50 10 12 14 16 18 20 7.30 8.85 10.82 11.88 1330 14.63 M AV2 .72 M .93 1.03 1.03 1.24 1.44 1.65 1.86 2.06 7.7 9.3 10.75 12.30 13.82 15.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Table (&gt;. — Door materials for silos of various heights. ■ 1 1 j rf J I j j 5 i a s j§ K x -5 X ■ i J H i 3 3 I 55 TABU t. Mult rial hill for stair xilos. SILO 10 FEET IN DIAMKTKH H.-i K lit ! lb is 20 22 24 26 30 Number of slaves* 73 7:5 73 73 73 73 73 Number of staves* 73 7* 7» 73 73 73 73 Board feet in staves I, His Board feet in staves l.ltiK 1,314 1,460 1,606 1,763 1,898 2,190 9 10 11 12 13 15 1,314 1,460 l,60ti 1,763 1,898 2,190 Number of hoops I (J" steell . . t Kber of hoops f (.[" steel) . R her of pieces 24 !) 10 11 12 13 15 s Number of pieces 24 Number of pieces 27 30 33 36 39 45 27 30 33 36 39 45 Length of pieces, in feet 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 12 Length of pieces, in feet 12 Pounds of steel in hoops IU Pounds of steel in hoops j IU 216 240 264 288 312 360 216 240 264 288 312 360 Number of j " hoop lugs ! 24 Gallons of paint (3 coats outside) 2.2") Number of \" hoop lugs 24 27 :«) :« :J6 39 45 27 30 33 36 39 45 Gallons of p:iint 2 coats outside) 2.2") 2.60 2!K) 3.20 3.50 3.75 4.00 2.60 2.90 3.20 3.50 3.75 4.00 SILO 12 FEET SILO 12 FEET IN DIAMETKR. II 21) ■ 24 26 30 IN" DIAMETER Height It) IS 20 22 24 26 30 Number of staves* 88 Number of staves* 88 N N H 88 i 88 88 N H v&gt; 88 88 88 Board feet in staves 1,408 Board feet in staves ■ 1,408 1,584 1,760 1,936 2,112 2,288 2,640 I 10 11 12 13 15 1,584 1,760 1,936 2,112 2,288 2,640 Number of hoops + (\" steel) ... 8 Number of hoops + ( 1 " steel) ... 8 I 10 11 12 13 15 Number of pieces 24 Number of pieces i 24 27 30 33 36 39 45 27 30 33 36 39 45 Length of pieces, in feet 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 14 Length of pieces, in feet 14 Pounds of steel in hoops 224 Pounds of steel in hoops 224 252 280 308 336 364 420 252 280 308 336 364 420 Number et \" hoop lugs 24 Number of i " hoop lugs ] 24 27! 30 1 33 36 39 45 27 30 33 36 39 45 Gallons of paint (2 coats outsidei 2.75 Gallons of paint (2 coats outsidei: 2.75 3.10 3.50 3.80 4.15 4.50 5.25 3.10 1 3.50 3.80 4.15! 4.50 5.25 * Staves to be IS" with tongues and grooves i" deep t Hoops to lap 8" at each lug. Kotb. — One or two extra staves should be ordered to replace those h are defective. ll I I : J I t 1 |j o ] I 1 ] I I J I 8 2 1x4 13 1 2x4 tj 4 1 I 4 0 2 1x4 14 1 2x4 So 1) 1 5 .' I 1x4 14 1 2x4 S | 1| 1 5 4 3 1x4 12 1 2x4 I • It 1 6 ii :i 1x4 12 1 2x4 • I l) 1 6 30 4 1x4 12 1 2x4 12 7 2 17 11 [' 1x1 u I 1 - x4 14 ; 9 v I x 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Tabu 1.— Material bill for stave nilot—Continu,;!. SILO 14 FEET IN DIAMETER. Height 18 Height 18 20 22 24 26 30 | 36 20 22 24 26 30 36 Number of staves* 103 Number of staves* 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 103 Board feet in staves 1,854 Board feet in staves 1,854 2,060 : 2,266 2,472 2,67.8 3,090 3,708 2.060 2,266 2,472 2,67.8 3,090 3,708 10 11 12 ft 15 18 Number of hoops t (*" steel) 9 Number of hoopst U/' steel) . . 9 10 ! ' 11 12 IS 15 18 Number of pieces 27 Number of pieces j 27 30 33 36 39 45 54 30 33 36 39 45 54 Length of pieces, in feet 16 Length of pieces, in feet 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 16 Pounds of steel in hoops i 288 Pounds of steel in hoops 288 320 352 384 416 479 576 320 352 384 416 479 576 Number of } " hoop lugs 27 Gallons of paint (2 coats outside) 3.60 Number of i " hoop lugs 27 30 33 36 39 45 54 30 33 36 39 45 54 Gallons of paint (2 coats outside; 3.60 4.00 4 40 4.80 5.20 6.00 7.20 4.00 4.40 4.80 5.20 6.00 7.20 MLO 6 FEET IN DIAMETER. Heigh, 20 22 24 26 30 36 Number of staves* Board feet in staves Number of hoops + 117 117 117 117 117 117 2,340 2,574 2,808 3,022 3,510 4,212 10 11 12 13 15 18 18 21 21 24 27 30 Rof I" pieces in hoops of I" pieces in hoops of I" pieces in hoops of pieces, in feet . ... 9 9 12 12 15 21 3 3 3 3 3 3 18 18 18 18 18 18 Bds of steel in hoops . ber of X" hoop lugs her of ':" hoop lugs l&gt;er of ; " hoop hips 466 502 558 594 687 835 18 21 21 24 27 30 9 9 12 12 15 21 3 3 3 3 3 3 (l:illcms of paint 2 coats outside «J0 5.00 5.50 6.00 6.80 8.25 Ml.o 18 FEE I IN DIAMETER H. K ht 3) B 24 26 30 36 Number of staves" 132 132 132 132 132 132 Board feet in staves 2,640 2,904 3,168 3,432 3,960 4,753 Number of hoopst 10 11 U 13 15 18 Number of I" pieces in hooj&gt;s Number of ~" pieces in hoops Number of {" pieces in hoo|&gt;s IS 21 21 24 27 30 11 • 12 12 15 21 3 3 3 3 3 3 Lenirth of pieces, in fi-et -&gt;() 20 20 20 20 20 Pounds of steel in hoops 518 5M 620 660 763 928 Number of \" hoop lugs 18 21 21 24 27 30 Number of i" hoop lugs !• !t 12 12 15 21 Number of ,".' hoop lugs. ••• I &gt; 3 3 3 3 Eisof paint (2 coats outside) . •"&gt; 10^ 5.60 6.10 6.70 7.20 9.25 Staves to be IS" with tongues and grooves |" deep. Hoops to lap 8" at each lug. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 SILO 20 FEET IN DIAMETER. Height 22 24 26 30 36 Number of staves* 147 147 147 147 147 Board feet in staves 3,234 3,528 3,822 4,410 .5,292 Number of hoopet 11 12! 13 15 18 Number of k" pieces in hoope 24 28 28 36 44 Number of \" pieces in hoops 12 12 16 16 20 Number of \" pieces in hoops 8, 8 8 8 8 Length of pieces, in feet 17 17 17 17 ; 17 Pounds of steel in hoops 689 734 805 K96 1,059 Number of &lt;" hoop lugs 24 28 28 36 44 Number of \" hoop lugs 12 12 16 16 20 Number of |" hoop lugs 8 8 8 S 8 Gallons of paint 1 2 coats outside ) 6.25, 6.75 7.40 | 8.50 I 10.00 * Staves to be If" with tongues and grooves \" deep. t Hoops to lap 8" at each lug. able 8. - 01 //in ena or roo. r .v. I I Hameter of silo, in feet Rafters Sheathing Bunches Patent roofing of Size Length No. Sixe Length | ■hingles ££• Length No. 16 16 16 18 20 20 i 1 x4 6 61 25 1x8 7 If 5 7 7 6 2 x4 7 Hi 29 1 x* 8 4* 7 8 8 8 2 x4 9 34 1x8 9 7f 9 9 10 2x4 10 23 38 1x8 10 10 Hi 10 113 2x4 11 5* 42 1x8 12 J 14 11 12 6 2x4 12 8i 46 1x8 13 31 17* 12 13 8 e 9. — Bill of materials for roofs — Concluded. abl: hameter of silo, in feet No . Sixe Headers j Length7 in feet Radius of circle Nails i i Lbs. 4d. Lbs. lOd. Lbs. 20d. 16 2 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 2 x4 10 12 1 10* 16 ( 14 f 16 16 18 5 3 6 2 7 7 10 8 9 9 8 4 5 1 e , , 8 9 1 10 12 2 12 14 2 15 17 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Silo Constitution in Xebraska. If the system of anchoring as illustrated in figure 9 is used. ' • material necessary for the silos of various heights is given in Table 10. Table 10. — Anchor materials where cable is used. Height of silo, in feet . 16 IS 20 22 21 26 30 I 36 Feet of 7 -strand N'o. 9 win 1 cable 70 80 , 100 110 120 130 150 170 For silos of all sizes ;ind diameters, four each of A. B, C, and D, and eight of E in figure 10. also four i"x2£" bolts for fasten ing E. figure 9. to the lower ends of the staves will be needed. Should it be desirable to use the system of anchoring shown in figure 11, which is simply eight stVands of wire twisted to - gether, the material given in Table 11 should be used. Table 11. — Anchor materials where wire is used. For each silo, four each of B and D. figure 10. I eight of silo, -n feet . . 10 18 20 22 24 26 30 36 "eet of No. 9 wire 600 675 875 925 1000 1100 1250 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 PIT SILOS, OR SILOS IN THK liHOIXl). I Pit silos arc cheap, durable, cost practically nothing for r - p, and silage does not freeze in them. Further, thev require ?«s expensive cutter and a small engine for fill in jr. since i!i" ge need not be elevated in filling. ■Their greatest disadvantage is the inconvenience in removing silage. Tn large areas of Nebraska the soil is peculiarly Semi-pit silo on Chase farm. Pawnee City, Xebr. Eted to pit silos. Wherever water cisterns can be made by ering onto the earth, pit silos can be made in a similar man- Such silos should not enter water-bearing soil, and when - a stratum of soil is passed thru which is apt to rolleot </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 water the walls of the silo should be built much heavier or the top of the silo kept so tight that the water in such stratum will not freeze and force the plaster off. GAS IN PIT SILOS. The claim is made that carbon dioxide gas collects in the bottom of the pit silos and makes it dangerous to enter them. In conversation with several owners of pit silos they stated that nothing of the kind had ever occurred in their silos. The temperature of a pit silo is much higher in winter than the surrounding air. and because of this higher temperature in the silo, air currents are formed that carry off all dangerous gases. If the top of these silos be left open, the currents of air set up by the wind are sufficient to keep the air circulating so that gases will be removed. Greater quantities of gas form within a day or so after the filling begins; hence, if the silo is partially filled and then per - mitted to stand for a few days, it is best to run the cutter a few minutes before the silo is entered. The falling silage will force all dangerous gases from the silo. If one desires to test the con - dition of the air in a partially filled pit silo, he may do so by lowering a lighted lantern to the bottom. If the lantern con - tinues to burn, there is no danger to a man entering the silo. If I he light is extinguished by the gas. the silo should not be entered. TYPES OF PIT SII.OS. There are three types of pit silos: Plain holes in the ground, where the walls are plastered and the silage is cropped in and lifted out at the top; Holes in the ground, but with the silo extended above the ground from 4 to 12 feet, the roof placed above this, and the silage removed thru the side of the upper part ; Silos built similar to either of the other two, but set in the bank so that retaining walls which act as a chute are placed np and down beside a line of doors. If there is a bank barn and the retaining walls connect the silo to the barn, the conditions are ideal. Of the three types of pit silos mentioned above, the last is the most convenient, also the most expensive. The first is the cheapest and likewise the least convenient. CONSTRUCTING PIT SILOS. Most silos are constructed by commencing at the bottom and building up. but a pit silo can be constructed by commencing at the top and building down. By building a silo in this manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 the ground acts as a staging and no lumber or labor is required for that purpose. Build all of that part of the silo which stands above the ground before very much excavating is done. The roof can be put on at this time or after the silo is filled. First dig out a trench, similar to the one showu in figure 12. Fill this with con crete and let it set. The ring of concrete formed in this manner will serve as a border to protect the rim of the plain pit silo or as a foundation for that part of the silo above the ground. The plain pit silo will then be dug down about six feet, which Fig. 12. An illustration of the is :1 convenient depth for easy border of the pit silo; also one plastering. This section will be type of frame tor hoisting the earth. plastered, another section dug down and plastered and so on until the pro|MT depth is reached If it is desired to build part of the silo above the ground, it can be done in several ways. Staves may be purchased and a short stave silo lx&gt; erected, or one may use solid concrete, con - crete blocks, clay blocks, or concrete plastered onto metal lath. If solid concrete is to be used, forms can be made by building up wooden hoops and lining them with 1x6 boards standing verti - cally. Tf forms are used in this way. they will necessarily be six inches apart to provide space for working the concrete and holding the reinforcing in place. The handiest reinforcing for such a silo probably is heavy woven wire fencing. A form of metal lath known as ''Hy-Rib" can be purchased on the market which will come bent to any diameter desired. This form of metal lath can be set up on the foundation and plastered with a sufficient number of coats of cement plaster to make a wall of concrete about three inches thick. Another method of building the part of the silo above the ground is to set up two-inch by four-inch studding about every two feet and nail metal lath to the inside of these. The lath should not be so firmly nailed but that the studding can be re - moved. Plaster several coats on the inside of the lath, then remove the studding and reinforce with heavy galvanized fence wire wound around the outside of the metal lath. Then put a few coats of cement plaster on the outside. It is fully as easy to hoist the dirt out of the top of a bank silo as to remove it thru the doorway; so build the silo proper </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 900 Construction in Xrbraska. in the same manner as the other pit silos excepting that the earth be dug away as shown by figure 13. By digging out in this manner. There is opportunity for building a heavy wall where the doors are and furnishing the supports as figure 14 for the retaining walls to rest against. In concreting this silo. Fig. 15. The form in place for holding the concrete for the heavy section about the doors of a bank silo. Fig. 13. Showing how to cut away the earth to support a door frame and re - taining walls for a bank silo. Fig. 14. Showing how to build the door supports and retaining walls for a bank silo. (rin must lie used at the doors. This can be built as shown in re 1"). To use this form when the walls are concreted from top down, the form must be dropped sufficiently far below concrete of the previous setting to permit throwing the con - e into place. The gap thus formed between the two settings len plastered full with a dry mixture of concrete. REMOVING THE EARTH FROM PIT SILOS. The most common method of hoisting the earth from the silo pit is to arrange a track support for a hay carrier car. The hoisting frame I fig. 12) as used by M. C. Anderson and his brothers of Gushing, Nebr.. consisted of a tripod made of poles set up at one side of the silo and a scissor frame made of similar material at the other. The latter was set sufficiently far away so that a wagon could pass between it and the silo. A 2x12 was fastened between these supports, and an ordinary hayfork car at - tached to this which would elevate and carry the dirt. As a means of carrying the dirt these men used barrels (fig. 18) which were two-thirds size and were made into buckets by boring a If" hole thru the staves below the center. A 1£" pipe was put thru these holes and a chain fastened to each end of this to act as a bail. To hold the barrels from tipping while ascending, a wagon rod was put thru the upper part of the staves parallel with the pipe and one chain put on one side of this rod and the other chain </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 l&gt;ut mi the other side. When the barrel was dumped, the rod was pulled out far enough to free the chain on one side, and the barrel tipj&gt;ed itself. With this equipment Mr. Anderson says they arranged to fill a wagon in eight minutes. This would be about a cubic yard every five minutes. While removing the dirt Fig. 16. Showing a semi - pit silo ready for exca- vation. Ki~. 17. Illustrating the va - rious stages of excavation of a semi-pit silo. Fig. 18. Barrel used for hoisting earth from silo pit. frnin the pit, neighbors exchanged work so that a gang of seven men with two teams on the wagons and one on the hoist worked at once. Three men filled the barrels, one looked after the hoist - ing and returning of the barrels, and one drove the hoisting team. W. P. Bennett of Cambridge and the men on the Chase Farm :it Pawnee City used similar devices except that they used boxes instead of barrels for carrying the dirt. The bottoms of these boxes were hinged on one side and fastened with a catch at the other, which could be tripped, thereby letting the bottom drop down so that the dirt would fall out. These boxes were 20 inches wide, 20 inches deep, and 30 inches long. Mr. Bennett states that with five men digging in the pit he would take out four boxes every five minutes. This would be about a cubic yard everv five minutes. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 PLASTERING THE WALLS. The plaster for the walls should be not less than one part Portland cement and two and one-half parts screened sand. The walls should be thorolv wet just before applying the plaster. The first cent should be left rough and then followed with a second coat before the first coat has had time to set. Silos with about three-eighths inch of plaster were inspected and were found in good shape, but it is believed advisable to put on a sufficient number of coats of plaster to make the walls at least three-fourths of an inch thick. For proportions of cement, sand, and lime, see page 15. COST OF PIT SILOS. At Gushing, Nebraska, five pit silos were built by one farmer and his four sons. A silo was dug on the farm of each of the sons and one on the father's farm. The digging for these silos was done during the coldest part of the winter and the plaster put on when the weather became warm enough to avoid freezing. To make the border of the silo, the men, by the use of a post hole nuger, bored a series of holes adjacent to each other in a circle of the proper diameter, then trimmed the edges of the trench thus formed. The trench was then filled with concrete. These men dug one silo without hauling the dirt away, but Mr. Anderson thought it took longer than to haul the dirt, as it took so much time to move the frame which supported the hoisting apparatus. Hecause of the cold weather they did not plaster their silos as they dug them. To support the men while plastering, they built a platform out of seven planks and supported these planks with four ropes, which were in turn fastened to planks lying across the top of the silo. These ropes were wrapped around the platform so that the men would untie the ropes and let them - selves with the platform down as needed. Mr. M. C. Anderson furnishes the following table of labor and material for the first silo and states that they made the others in less time : </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 14'x27'. full pit without roof. Border MATERIAL 2 loads sand, at 9tc each $0.40 11' sacks cement, at -4.V net 5.40 Plaster for wall and floor: 20 sacks cement, at 45e net 9.00 21 loads sand, at 20c each 50 I a hoi:. Border: Bnarattag, placing ttaacto, and hauling two loads sand: ."&gt; men and 1 team, fi hours. f7.50 t proper: Excavating — ."&gt; men. 27 Ins. each, at 20c 27.00 1 team. 27 hrs.. at lie 4.05 Hauling sand. 2.1 loads 1.50 Plastering. 24 hrs.. at 20c 4. SO Total cost of silo 160.15 This work was all done with unskilled labor and at a time of year when little else could l&gt;e done. Hovs who had never touched a trowel liefore did a large part of the plastering. The above figures do not include the roof nor the hoisting apparatus. The latter would not amount to verv much, as it would be divided among five men and nearly all of it used on (lie hayforks after- COST OF SILO ON W. P. BENNETT'S FARM. CAMBRIDGE. NEBR. l(i' by :tn' full pit. with roof and hoisting apparatus Lal&gt;or f•&gt;- •sr &gt; Hoard 18. (Ml -jo sacks cement 20. (M» S loads Rand 4.00 Km ft. V wire cable 2.50 lm ft. r *f * 4 -°° t 'arrier for cable 4 . 00 Rope and post to erect cable l.M i"xl2" bolts, top wall 1.00 Hoxes to lift dirt 5.00 l.umU'r for roof 20 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 COST OF SILO ON CHASE FARM. PAWNEE CITY. NEBR 12 feet in diameter. 13| feet above ground, and 2(1 feet in the ground; walls 3i inches thick below ground and 5 inches thick above ground. Labor, True cost, labor $2 per day $1 50 per day EU $0.30 $0.30 ks cement for walls 1 ks cement for wall plaster at 40e 46.80 i 4iix I ks bottom J ■days digging and hauling 63.00 47. J."&gt; ay's team hauling 9.00 6.00 9.00 6.00 6 days elevating dirt 9.00 6.00 17 days constructing silo and hauling sand. 74.00 55.M 9.00 6.00 37 days constructing silo and hauling sand. 3 days, team hauling sand 4.50 3.00 5 days heluing plaster 10.00 7.50 lij days plasterer, at $5 8.50 MO 3 days on roof 600 4.50 Reinforcing. $3 3 00 3.00 3 00 3.00 220 feet of lumber in roof. . . \ . .„- an . an . 128 feet of lumber in rafters i at ** aUo 9 °° 10 pounds nails ! .35 .35 Total j $243.5&lt;) 1300.75 Mixture of concrete for walls: 1 part cement to 5 parts bank run sand. Mixture for plaster on walls 1 part cement to 2 parts screened wind. Capacity 78 tons Cost per ton capacity $ 2 . 68 rT OF lb ISO' FULL PIT SILO. USING THE COST OF M. C. ANDERSON'S U'x27 SILO AS A BASIS OF COMPUTATION. MATERIAL. Border : Sand, 2.25 loads, at 20c each |0.45 Cement, 14 sacks, at 4."&gt;c each 6.30 Plaster for wall and floor : Cement, 25.6 sacks 11 . 52 Sand, 3.14 loads, at 20c 63 I A BOB. Border: Excavating, placing concrete, and hauling 8) </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 &lt; i rand total INSPECTION OF PIT SILOS. A number of pit silos have been inspected which have been used, some one year, some two years, some six years, and one for eighteen years. This inspection demonstrates the success of the pit silo, so far as the principle involved is concerned. These silos are giving universal satisfaction. Because, however, of the method of construction, one was being remodeled. One which was built with square corners required considerable time and expense in tramping the silage in the corners and around the rough stone wall while filling. The pit silo which had been used 18 years was made by plas - tering the lower earth with natural cement and protecting the upper walls with brick. The cement had peeled from the walls in places, but the owner did not consider this sufficiently detri - mental to make repairs necessary. Another pit silo, which had been used six years, was made by building the upper walls of brick and leaving the earth bare below the brick. This silo was in a perfect state of preservation and giving excellent satisfaction. As a result of this inspection, the following recommendations are offered : All pit silos should be built round, with the wall perpen - dicular and smooth. The wall should extend at least three feet above the surface of the ground. The concrete wall or border should extend at least three feet below the surface. Below this point the walls should be plastered with not less than three coats of rich cement mortar, and in loose sandy soil more coats should be added, giving a thicker and stronger surface. Tn the silos visited, where the plaster was from five-eighths of an inch to one inch thick, of Portland cement mortar, the walls were in perfect condition, regardless of the length of time the silo had been in use. Note. — A bulletin dealing with the subject of handling silage will be issued later. This bulletin will discuss hoisting devices for pit silos. 5 men, 39i hrs. each, at 20c $39.5(1 2 teams. 39} hrs. each, at 15c 11.85 Plastering, 30.fi hrs.. at 20c 6 . 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 fOXORETE ItMM'K SII.OS. I There in many instances where the roar re to Mock silo will more advisable than other types. In ■ comnmuity where y one man expects to liuild a silo probably such a silo will be a|'« r .uiil easier to ereel than a solid concrete or a clav block Concrete block silos, Priesland Farms, Omaha. N'ebr. silo. If properly constructed they arc as Bjaod as any silo and no doubt have a more pleasing architectural effect than am other type.. It is a sini]ilc matter In make the Mocks, and a mason can make the Mocks, and a mason can learn bow to lav The Mocks and follow specifications after a little practice. There are three ireneral types of blocks which can be used for silo construction. The solid Mock, the hollow block, and the two-piece block. These blocks may have rough or smooth out - sides and may l&gt;e either curved or straight. The straight blocks. KINDS (IF ]',[.(&gt;&lt; KS. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 snKHiiii mrface to the silo. iA'heu cement blocks arc made very fast, it is essential thai mixture of which the lwwly of the block is made be quite dry. erete when used in this way is quite porous. If the face of blocks can either lx- of a much richer mixture than the body he Mock or he made of very wet concrete and troweled, a h better block for silo construction can be made. It is pref - »le that the face of the block Ik' both richer and wetter than body of the Mock; also, if the face of the block be troweled inkes a block which will not absorb moisture. Whenever it nt possible to make or obtain blocks of this nature, the inside of the silo should be plastered after the walls are laid. If the expense of plastering is ton imt the walls can l&gt;e washed or (Minted with ■ mixture of one part cement and one part tine screened aaiid. This will take the plan of jdasterinir as far as *Ral - inj; the pores in the blocks N concerned, but does not leave the wall as smooth as plaster. The solid block, such ;is is shown h\ "a." figure 10. is advisable only when &gt; machine has to Ik- made and one cannot lie const ructed which will make the hollow Fig. 19. Type of con- Mocks. This solid block is more quirk h orete block which utiuh- than the others, but requires ntOIT cSn a trucUo^ * S "° ■"•"** ! * *•*» i "" 1 *»**" t() lli "" lle and conducts heat and cold more readily. The department of Agricultural Engineering has devised a machine which can lie made in any rar pester shop and by any - one handy with tools, whereby two piece blocks such as shown by ( 'b," figure 10. can he made. These blocks are laid up in the silo wall so that the leg of one in the inside wall will overlap the leg of one in the outside wall but in the course above it. tit will be noticed by studying figure 20 that these blocks ■n laid on a silo wall make nearly a |ierfect dead-air space. mac of this feature the silage is less apt to freeze, as heat not be transferred back and forth thru the walls as readily. cks made in the above manner can have a wetter and richer .ture in the face than in the back, and the face can also be R-eled. Two silos built of these blocks near Fremont gave the most pleasing appearance of any silos visited. RmMt of impurities </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 (commonly iron) in the sand and water of which the blocks were made, colors form on the blocks which are sufficient to break up the monotonous sameness of most cement block buildings. I Because of the successful performance of the machines de - ipd to make the two-piece block, the department has designed Machine which will make the single-piece hollow block as wn in "c." figure 19. This block cannot be nitide ns fast as Fig. 20. Showing how the two-piece cement block was laid in the wall and the door frame of R. B. Schneider's Bilos the two-piece block, but is much easier to lay. It does not give the troweled outside face to the silo, and neither does it give as perfect a dead-air space, but does give the troweled inside sur - face. Commercial blocks, "d." figure 19. may be purchased in nearly every town in the state. These may be either straight or curved to fit the curvature of the silo. They make a good silo and one which has an attractive appearance. Since these blocks are generally very porous, they should be plastered on the inside after being put into the wall. If curved blocks can be obtained, less plaster will be used ; but since it is essential that plaster be used on this type of block, a straight block will make a good silo pro - vided the blocks are not over 16 inches long. SIZE OF BLOCKS. All but three of the concrete block si log which were inspected in Nebraska were made with 12-inch walls. This seems unneoes- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 sary, for silos visited in the East, made of 8-inch walls, were found to be sufficiently stroug. Twelve-inch blocks are unneces - sarily heavy and require more material. If a four-inch clay block wall or a six-inch concrete monolithic wall is strong enough to make a permanent and serviceable silo, an eight-inch concrete block wall should be strong enough, and such a wall is much cheaj&gt;er than a twelve-inch wall. CONCRETE BLOCK MACHINE To make the form figure 21, cut two pieces 8 inches long from an eight-inch plank and two pieces 24 inches long from the same Fig. 21. A homemade two-piece cement block Fig. 22. Iron parts for joint between foot lever and plunger in cement block form. machine. plank. Nail these pieces together in the form of a box, with the short pieces 16 inches apart. This makes the outside of the form, which is supported by the four legs cut from pieces of 2x4. The legs should be of such a length that the top of the box is not less than 36 inches from the ground. Stay each pair of legs with a 2x4 crosspiece which is about 10 inches above the ground. Before nailing the legs to the box. make from a piece of hard wood the rocker "b" which 8up]H&gt;rts the foot lever "c" and place it in position. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Ill IIOIII III* I »trlll( 11 ",' eiglll-lllt II I I4UIK IWU JMtrvco are the pnacr length to reach from the top of the form to the lower side of tin- stay pieces. Nail these in place as shown by The plunger is made by nailing a block 2"x8"x10" onto the end of a piece of i'"xS"xir&gt;". and across this block are nailed the iwii pieces "dd" which support the pieces "ee." The upper end of the plunger is made open, so that all loose sand will fall thru, while the lower end is notched out to receive the strap eves and links shown by figure 82, which make the joint between the plunger and the lever. The ends of pieces "dd" and "ee" act as upper guides, while the lower guide "f" is made by cutting a slot in a plank which just tits between the pieces "aa." The slot should be just a trifle larger than the plunger or there will be too much friction be - tween the two. t Strips of wood should 1*' nailed around the top of the box live it a convex form and these should l&gt;e covered with band 1 to prevent excessive wear. If the centers of the strips are mil thicker than the ends, the blocks will have the projter vature for a Ki-foot silo. Figure 23 details the templets. Sufficient of these should l»e Fig. 23. Templet details for a two - piece cement block machine. made for a half-day's work, unless the work is rushing; then there should be sufficient for a full dav's work. When the blocks for the outside layer of the wall have been made, the strips should l&gt;e removed from the top of the form and concave strips lie put in their place. The blocks should also ha made shorter for the inside layer of the wall, and to do this u small block is placed on top of the templet at the end of the </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 ffor ■ 111 foot silo. 14 •" for a lU foot silo. U\" for a 14 foot 14j" for :i 1&lt;t-foot silo. 14i" for an IN foot silo, and 15" for foot si!o. {The concrete for lilorks sliould be about as damp as good How earth. It slionld be thrown into tin- forms and well aped, then the surface removed with the tool shown In figure and the space then tilled with a richer and moister mixture ich is well troweled down. The Mocks can he any height, Imt an tight-inch block is standard, and tliis is a g 1 depth for silo use. so it should he adopted. Hlocks Hi and M inches long can lie used if curved. • nit the former is much more easily handled and is generally ad - visable. MAKING ioNcKKTK BLOCKS. Kl'eineiit blocks have been made in forms chmi|&gt;ed together i hand clamps. Imt this process is very slow and doubtful of ing results when labor is considered. 7 Fit. 24. Scraper for removi njc concrete from far*- of blorka. Fig. 2o. Cross-section of homemade two-piece cement block machine. Figures SI and 23 illustrate the machines used in making the blocks for two silos near Fremont. By the use of this simple homemade machine two men could make :{(»() blocks 8"xl6" each day. But since it takes two of these blocks to lay as much wall space as one single-piece block. 300 blocks is the equivalent o" IM common blocks. One hundred and fifty common blocks ar ■ '■oiisidered an average day's work for two men with small com - mercial machines. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 The machine works on the principle of a box with the toj&gt; gone and a bottom which will work up and down inside. On this movable bottom rests a templet which forms the back side of the block. The face of the block is up and by placing strips on the top of the box which are either convex or concave the face of the block can be made either convex or concave. The blocks are set to one side on the templet and allowed to remain there for at least 24 hours. At the end of that time the templets are carefully tipped up on one side and the blocks :i8 carefully set up onto their sides and allowed to remain for two or three days, when they can be ricked up to finish curing. ■The machine for making the one-piece hollow block (fig. 26) rks on the same principle as the two-piece machine, but the Fig. 26. Homemade single-piece concrete block machine. tr is iron instead of wood, and stands at the end of the ma - ie so it can be worked by hand. The machine haa a loose om which is curved to fit the outside of the silo. The top of machine is concave and is covered with strap iron to protect Pieces "aa." figure 27, are placed in the ends of the machine to make the inside of the block shorter than the outside, and the pieces "bb," figure 26, are inserted into the machine to make the blocks hollow. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 curved false bottom the pieces "aa." figure 27. Sufficient con &lt;rete is then thrown in and tamped down to reach up to the holes, which will then receive the pieces "bb," figure 26, flfter which more concrete is added and tamped until the form is full. About one-half inch of the top is then scraped off with the tool shown in figure 24. and this space is filled with the wet, rich mix - ture for the surface. This surface is smoothed off with a few strokes of the trowel, which makes it waterproof after it has thoroly set Pig. 27. Longitudinal cross-sec- Fig. 28. Iron de - tails fora single - piece homemade concrete block machine. tion of homemade concrete block machine showing the lever, the Joint, the plunger, and the curved templet. When the form is filled, the cores are removed and the lever is pushed out, which forces the block out of the machine. As the lower edge of the false bottom reaches the top of the ma - chine, it is swung around and permitted to rest while the helper places the templets against the side of the block and at the same time turns the block and false bottom over onto the templet and carefully sets the block and the templets to one side. The false bottom is then dropped back into place and another block is made. It is always well to make several half blocks, as this will obviate the necessity of cutting whole blocks. Half blocks can be made in the machine described above by making a box which will drop into the form and fill one-half of the space. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 siln Construction in \&lt;hru*h&lt;i. The black machines described above can lie used for straight blocks as well as curved and for that reason are convenient about any farm. MIXTTUKS FUR CON'CRETK BLOCKS. Irhe body of concrete blocks can lie made of one ]&gt;art cement ive or six parts sand. If the sand is tine, five parts should sed : if it is coarse, six will do. The sand and cement Rhonld horoly mixed dry. then wet and mixed. The mixture should ust as wet as will stand after the block is removed from the 1. Generally it should be about as wet as good mellow earth. BThe face of the block should he one part cement and two and -half parts screened sand and quite wet. I If a good &lt;|iialitv of cement is used, the blocks should not be mitted to dry very quickly. They should be kept in the de for several days after brtag made, and should be thoroly : at least twice a day at first and once a day after about two »ks. When the blocks have set three or four days, they can ricked up outside but should be covered with clean straw or imvas. and the whole mass thoroly soaked with water. For N PATIO. VS. The footings for the foundations of concrete block silos should be heavier than for the clay block or wooden silos. They should not lie less than 28 inches wide at the bottom and two feet deep. With a good foundation and plenty of reinforcing in the walls a Mock silo can crack from top to ltottom and vet serve its purpose. t\. mixture of one part cement, three parts sand, and six s broken stone or coarse gravel will make a mixture for the ings and foundation walls. If the crushed stone cannot be had. one part cement and six parts coarse sand will make the mixture. By making the sand and cement mortar very wet and ]&gt;ouring it over cobblestone which has been thrown into the trench for the footing, a good foundation can lie built. To excavate for the foundation, lay out a circle which has a diameter equal to the inside diameter of the silo plus twice the thickness of the walls. Tf the location of the silo is such that i he outside of the foundation walls should be plastered to keep •yater out. make the diameter of the circle about eight inches rreater. Throw out the dirt within this circle down to a depth CTRIXi; THE ISUM'KS. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">which lacks two feet of Ikmiij; as ttef as the foundation should be made. On this bare earth lay out another circle which in about two indies farther across than the inside diameter of the silo. then excavate for The footing as shown by fijjnre 2!). Fill this Fig. 29. Illustrating how FU. 30. Two types of founda - tion for cement block silos. to excavate for a con- crete b'.ork silo founda- tion. trench with concrete and when it has set throw out the dirt inside of it down to the bottom. The inside of the footing should he plastered until it is smooth. It is then ready for the founda - tion walls. They can be of blocks, or a form can be built inside and thev can be made of concrete. MORTAR. Since cement mortar is not suflicientlv plastic to adhere easily to the blocks, it is ncci ssary that some lime be added. Hydrated lime is generally used for this, as it comes in paper sacks and can be mixed with the Rand and cement in the dry state. The proportions can l&gt;e varied to suit the individual. However, the minimum amount of lime should be one part cement, one-third part hydrated lime, and two parts screened sand. The maximum amount of lime may be one part cement. two parts hydrated lime, and four parts screened sand. The mortar should not be dried out too quickly, and since- the blocks absorb moisture verv readily thev should be thorolv wet </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 just before laving. Pippin;; them into tanks of water is to be preferred to all other methods, but this is rather slow, so if they are thoroly sprayed both before and after they go onto the scaf - fold they will lay very well. . BEINFORCING. Concrete block silos are reinforced by phu-ing iron rods in the mortar joints between the layers of blocks. The most conven - ient size of reinforcing is No. 3 wire, but, since this must be ordered from the mill. \" rods can be welded together or several strands of No. 9 wire substituted. Wherever possible it is con - sidered advisable to order at least a month beforehand and get the No. 3 wire. This should be high carbon, as it is much easier handled than the soft wire. Wherever the No. 3 wire is not used, the substituted material must have an equivalent cross-section I No. 3 high carbon wire will come in coils and must be lightened to fit the curve of the silo walls. To do this a simple ice. such as is shown by figure 31, should be rigged up. The 3£ Fig. 31. Device for straightening reinforc - ing wire. (From Iowa Bulletin No. 117.) Ei is drawn thru the bent pipe as it comes from the reel, and ie same time is measured and cut. The pipe can be bent so the wire will conform to the oxact circle of the silo. The forcing is not as thick as the moi-tar joints, hence will lay iem. DOOB FRAMES AND DOOBS. The doors can be either intermittent or continuous. Prob - ably the ease of making and the cheapness of erection of the intermittent door will equalize the more convenient use of the continuous door. This leaves the matter of a choice in the type of door with the desire of the individual who is to own the silo. Continuous doors were used in the Schneider silos near Fre - mont (flg. 32). They had frames made of \"s&amp;" steel laid next to the blocks and held there by the reinforcing wire. Onto the door side of this steel plate was bolted a 2"x2" angle iron and against this angle the doors rested. About every three feet </seg>
            <seg id="p047">800 Construction in Xebraxku. 47 finch round bars were bolted between the steel plates. Those bars hold the silo together and they also furnish a convenient ladder. Fig. 32. Detail of steel door Fig. 33. Showing the reinforcing and how to make a simple type of dooi frame for a concrete block frame used In R. B. Schneider's silos. INTERMITTENT DOOR FRAMES. Two types of intermittent doors are offered for use. The ty|«&gt; shown in figxire 33. which consists of a plank frame two inches narrower than the thickness of the walls of the silo, it the simpler by far hut not as durable. This door frame is built so it will just sit in between the layers of stone and is held in place by spikes which have their heads in the mortar joints. The door rests in the recess formed bv the door frame and blocks. Reinforcing about this door is placed in the holes of the cement blocks and in the mortar joints above and below the doors. The vertical rods should he about f inch in diameter and the horizontal rods should be f inch or 7-16 inch in diameter. Mortar should be filled into the openings in the blocks where the vertical reinforcing is placed, as fast as the blocks and reinforcing are put in position. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Silo Vonxt nation in \ibninka. &gt;A more durable type of door frame and one which give* ■ ter appearance is shown in figure 34. It consists of a con - e frame and eMtag which forms a recess for receiving the Fig. 34. Illustrating a concrete door frame and casing for an intermittent door in concrete block silos. Eand also it conceals the reinforcing which is placed alMiut door. The forms for making such a door frame, flgnre :{."&gt;. ist of an inside form, an outside form, and two pairs of ips. The inside part of the form "a" is made of a frame Fig. 35. Forms for a concrete intermittent door frame. which is abotit 24 inches si|iiare and has a depth of about 1 inch greater than the thickness of the wall. This frame is made slightly hopjier-shaped so it can be easily drawn from the con- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Siio ( 'onxf met ion in A t'bnt*k(t. 49 ile. Nailed to the wide face of this frame is a l".\0" rasing. which will rest against llie inside of the silo wall. In the ner formed by the frame and the casing are nailed some '!" strips ••&lt;■("" which have the outside tapered the same as main frame so that they will draw from the concrete. These i|&gt;s are for the recess in the concrete for the doors. Mlockg I." to act as guides for Ihe outside part of the forms, should nailed in each one of the corners of the main frame. tThe oulside part of the form "e" is made of a l"x:t" frame ilar to the casing for the inside form but with inside diuien - is such that it will just fit over the guide Mocks. \"\i" strips I l&gt;e nailed along the outer edges of the two sides and bottom he inside of this frame, which will rest against the outside of silo liiocks and form the casing for the door frame. The p along the top of the frame is left off so that concrete ran Hit in after the silo Mocks have lieen set shore the door frame. BTo hold the two parts of the form in place, two pairs of ups made of L ( x4"s and 7-1(5" l»olts are used. I Reinforcing for this door is illustrated in tiirnres 34 and .'?fi. eli also illustrate the forms in position readv for continuing laving of the wall. Two C inch ban are set vertically at icr side of the door, and the horizontal reinforcing bars are ked around these Two !-inch bars are tilaced in the concrete li below and above the doorwav and hooked around the vcrti - bars. CONTIMOIS DOOR FRAMKS. iTIie cont inuoiis door frame I fig. 37) consists of two concrete ts at each side of the door, which hold the vertical reinforc - rods and receive the ends of the horizontal rods. Between «e posts and extending across the doorway at intervals of ut every 10 inches are concrete beams that contain the heavy iforcing rods which tie the walls of the silo. Tn the inside of vertical concrete posts are recesses which receive the ends he doors. I The forms which are made to mold the doorposts and cross - ims are made in two parts — one part which stands on the ide of the silo and one part which stands on the outside, and two are held together, when in use. with bolts. The cro«» - iiii is molded at the same time the posts are by means of a box trough which extends between the two legs of the main form. p outside and bottom of this trough an' attached to the out - e part of the main form and the inside part of it. The following detailed directions for making continuous door frames pertain to forms fourteen feet long, but they can be built ten feet loner in one section or six feet loner in two sections ' </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Silo Construction m Nebraska Lay our and cut l"xlO" boards (EE) as shown by figure 38. The uncut edge of one of these hoards should have 1-16-inch Fig. 36. Show - ing the form for the inter - mittent con - crete door frame in place and where the reinforc - ing ia set. frame bevel one way, and the other board should have the same bevel in the opposite way. These bevels give the boards flare, so that they will release from the concrete. The two boards AA, figure 37. are now nailed to the four pieces BBBB. two of which are [» — Mi w tC \* « a *\ •' \* Fig. 38. Showing how to cut the boards "EE" In </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 not shown, the boards being 24 inches apart and the pieces B being 8 inches from each end of the boards and an equal dis - tance apart. Nail the pieces EE and CC to AA as shown by figure 37. and after cutting the pieces DDDD nail them in place. The pieces FFFF are cut 22 inches long at one side and 23 inches long at the other and nailed to EE and DDDD. Except for boring the holes in the pieces BBBB which receive the bolts that clamp the two parts of the form together, this finishes the out - side part. The inside form is made by first beveling the edges of two I"x8" boards (GG^ so that the concrete blocks will rest against them. Rip a 2x4 down the center, holding the saw at an angle so it will make a bevel. Dress the cut surfaces and the pieces HH will be made. This part of the form is now ready to be nailed to the pieces TUT. which correspond to the pieces BBBB. Tn nailing the boards "(US'" to the pieces ITU care must be taken to keep them such a distance apart that HH will just fit inside of EE. Cut from the pieces which have been taken from the boards EE eight blocks KK and nail them to HH just behind JJ.TJ; then cut the latter and nail them to KKKK. but not to FFFF. When the holes have been bored in II II which correspond to those in BBBB, the form is ready to bolt together and set in place. Bolts i"xl6" are required for this. fare should be exercised to get the form perfectly plumb the first time it is set; after that it should plumb itself, altho it is well to test it each time it is raised. The reinforcing about this door form should be two V' verti - cal reinforcing rods in each concrete post, and in the concrete beam should be placed two i" rods which hook around the verti - cal rods which regularly come in the corresponding mortar joint, and in addition to this if the silo is over 14 feet in diameter a f" rod should run thru the concrete beam and extend three feet into the mortar joints on each side. rE 12— Bill of materials for a 1-ifoot door form for silos of any diameter and height. 4 pcs. I"x8"xl4' 2 pcs. I"xl2"xl4' 4 pcs. 2"x4"xl4' 1 pc. I"xl2"x8' 8 rxlfi" bolts. 1 pc. I"x8"xl6' </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 sila Construction in Nebrmakm. IKMIItS. ti'on veil ient doors can he made from two layers of flooring rds with building paper be twees them. One layer of HH rds should 1h' sorisontal and the other vertical. Moors for the fontimioiis frames can be made the MUM 1 as those illustrated in Ignc '■'-. tA conveiiient scaffold aids materially in saving time while Iding the walls. Those in charge of em-ting the experimental s in Iowa tried three types of scaffolding and found the one eh is described in the following quotations from Iowa Bulle - \'o. 117 to 1h' the most convenient. This type of scaffold was d in building tin- two cement block silos at Fremont and was nd satisfactory. Reference is made to figure IV.). "This scaffold differs from most building scaffolds in that the platform is movable. The platform itself consists essentially of a square framework of 2x8's of reasonably clear, still' lumber. These are shown by the dotted lines at "A." also in the corner elevation. Their length for a US- foot silo is approximately lit feet 0 inches. At the ends of these and flush with the bottom of each are securely nailed 2-inch pieces, "H." of convenient length. Thus the bevel at the end extends through three 2-inch pieces instead of one, and fur - nishes ample bearing u|K&gt;n the supporting pins. "NY There should l&gt;e at least J inch of clearance all around the post. "M." This framework is held together at the corners by an eye-hoH and a 2x8x4 l&gt;eneath shown by dotted lines at 'C and the outer foot plank above. The eye liolts, '¥!.' which secure these corners should be made of 2-inch metal with washer at each end. The length should lie from 11 to 12 inches between the washci-s. Diameter of eye should lie 1 inch inside and four are required. A 2x8. 11 feet long, shown at 'F,' bolted at each end to blocks which are in turn nailed to the middle of the two opposite mem- Ikm-s "A." T'pon this framework is placed a 2x10. 15 feet 10 inches long, indicated by 'G.' lying flat across the center of "F." and the two members 'A.' Extending at right angles from ■&lt;;.' and lengthwise upon 'F.' are two Milliters. 2x10. 7 feet f&gt; inches long, indicated by 'H.' Beneath and nailed to the inner end of these timbers 'H' are blocks which extend two inches under 'O." By placing these blocks on each side of 'F.' it is no* necessary to nail 'II' to 'F.' It is highly desirable in a scaffold which must be used repeatedly that no nails need be drawn when knocking it down. Wood soon becomes so broken and split that SCAFFOLD. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Silo Count ruction in Xcbranka. 53 it will not hold nails. I'pon the comers of and diagonally to this frame are laid, inside of TV two widths of plank 2x12. 8 feet long, lettered T." and. connecting the ends of these and resting ujMin the ends of •('•' and "II. " are three boards 1x12 METHOO Of" LAPPHC WALL REINFOfKX^CNT VEW THROUGH VKkU. AT CORNCR OF 5CAFTOU3 Fig. 39. feet long, lettered 'J,' beveled at the corners to fit the circle, also five boards 1x12. 5 feet long, lettered 'K,' which are not beveled. The four boards 1x12, 6 feet long, lettered 'R,' com - plete the upper part of the platform. Beneath the platform, for reasons seen later, are suspended by several strands of No. 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Silo Construction in Xebratfka. wir»\ two 2x12. 14 feet long, lettered 'L.' These should be about 4 feet below the top of the platform. The wire hangers should be at the ends and in the middle. If strong 1-ineh hard lumber is at hand, it may be substituted for the 2-inch upper foot planks shown in drawing. In fact this plan may often be changed to suit materials at hand, but in case all new materials are to be bought, the plan shown will be found to give general satisfaction and all parts having been used rej&gt;eatedly are known to be sufli - i-icntly strong. Four upright ]&gt;osts. lettered 'M,' secured to the wall at points approximately equally spaced, support the scaffold platform by MMM of J-inch round steel pins 16 Inches long. 'NY extending through 1 inch holes in the uprights. Eight of these are required, as one set should not be removed from a lower hole nntil the other pins are placed to support the scaffold in case any of the hoisting device should break. "Each upright consists at first of 2x6, 8 feet long, and 2xt;. ]C, feet long, screwed together with three 2^-inch No. 14 or No. 16 flatheaded wood screws. Tt is necessary to use the flatheaded screws in order that the head will countersink itself into the wood, thus not interfering with the raising of the scaffold plat forti!. One of the bottom members of the upright is 8 feet long and the other is 10 feet long in order that the post may be added to as needed by simply screwing 16 foot length. 2x6 on alternate sides. These upright posts are secured to the wall by means of light wires lettered '1*' which are placed about 3 feet apart vertically. Every alternate time the scaffold is moved two-inch blocks lettered •O' should be placed snugly between the post and the wall and nailed to the wall. This places the post about three inches from the wall. Then it should be toe-nailed to the blocks, and the wires passing through the wall drawn tight. This holds the scaffold support rigid in all directions and enables the builder to keep them plumb. Tt is better to block two of these upright posts each time the scaffold is raised rather than to block them all each alternate time. The distance between the holes in the upright will depend upon the kind of hoisting apparatus used. In the past wire stretchers have been used for this purpose. One type of lever wire stretcher was attached to a clevis secured to each post at a convenient distance above the platform and an eye bolt in the corner of the platform. * * * By the use of these stretchers, it was possible to raise only one foot at a time. There - fore the holes were necessarily one foot apart and three raises were made consecutively, thus the masons found it necessary to build only three feet of wall from each position of the scaffold wiiich was a great convenience and permitted more rapid and better work. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">■ "The common double pulley block wire stretcher has been used very successfully. It has several advantages over other kinds. With the ordinary length of rope, the platform may be lifted 18 inches each time, thus accomplishing a three-foot lift by only two changes or with longer rope, the three-foot lift can be accomplished at one pull. An advantage in the hoisting may be obtained by standing upon the wall instead of upon the scaffold, thus reducing the weight to be lifted, very materially. A bit of plank lying upon the wall behind the post is convenient to stand upon. Anyone preparing to build several silos could well afford Kivest in hoisting apparatus consisting of triple blocks and inch ropes. In any kind of hoisting apparatus, light cast - crimped chains, and unwelded eyes should be carefully avoided."' HOISTING THE MATERIAL. The derrick, figure 40, is used for hoisting the material ma- Fig. 41. Swinging derrick for holst- Fir 40. Derrick for hoisting terial Into silos. ing material into silo. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Tins sjuiit' type was used on the masonry silo :it the I "nivcrsitv F.-irin. also on the concrete block silos at Fremont. The dimen - siciis of flie derrick, however, were the same M those used in Iowa, but kmni of the extreme danger of the derrick buck - ling and breaking while l&gt;eing raised it is considered bettor to reinforce it with a Xo. !» wire truss as shown at "a." tThe derrick post is a buitt up I-beaat, the stem is a S'x&lt;&gt;". I the crossbars are 2"x&lt;&gt;" pieces. The arm "I5" is supported the brace "&lt;'." To su]i|&gt;orl the derrick, two No. !( (piv wires fastened on the outer end of "H" and one in the inner end. ■ pulleys tram a hayfork can be used to run the ropes over. If a concrete roof is pnt on the silo the derrick should be made so it will swing. To do this, a one-inch pin is placed in the lower end and is dropped into a plank which is staked down. The guv wires are fastened to a one-inch pin at the top and a sweep for turning is bolted to the post I fig. 41 I. LATINO THE WALLS. Lav a row of blocks around on the foundation, leaving a space of altout I inch l&gt;etween blocks. If when the circle is nearly complete it is found that a block must be cut to fit the space left l&gt;et\veen the end blocks, crowd the circle out or in so that half a block may 1*&gt; inserted in the space. Uy so iotaf, the necessity of cutting a block in every tier is obviated. A little time spent on this course will save much time later. When laving up the walls, care must l&gt;e exercised to make |K*rfect joints, especially those which are vertical. If the out- side joints are pointed with a concave pointing tool, the walls will have a better ap|&gt;earance. and the added labor will not be inu.-h. The inside joints should be left perfectly smooth and this can not l»e done if a mason's trowel is used. A plas- ■42. Paddle Imct'i trowtl or a bluntedfjed paddle such as is ■ rnakinn , ... , .t . . .,, . ... . smooth mortar shown by figure 42 is preferable for this work. To keep the walls plumb and the circle true. iical lines made with a car|K-uter's pcaei] should U' put onto courses of stone on the outside aln&gt;ut four foot apart, '"aaa." re :?4. These lines should 1m&gt; kept vertical as the silo in - ses in bright. This can lie done by the use of a mason's nb. The mason should plumb his walls on these lines. This not only keep the walls vertical, but will keep the circle true. THE ROOF. ■The roof may he made of plain boards, or it may be sheathed I covered with patent rootiny: or shingles, or it may be made </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 inanent and fireproof material, the roof should he the game, and it has been found that, where the roof form can lc used for several silos, a concrete roof is cheaper than a well-made shingle roof. A J -pitch roof is easier to make tli.in iiiiv other, but it does not give sufficient head room to permit the man to tramp the last layers of silage. A J-pitch roof "jives sufficient head r«Kini. but it is hard to hold the concrete in Fig. 43. Illustrating how place while building it. Probably the to build cornice for con- '.pitch roof is the must satisfactory crete roof on a concrete .,„. _ „„_„„„+„ „„„* for a concrete roof. block silo. Figure 4.'5 illustrates a simple method of construct ing ;i concrete roof. The two upper courses of blocks are each laid out alMHit 1A inches; then the course of cornice blocks is laid on top of these and the concrete put in as explained under roofs for concrete silos I page 87). In the concrete block Kilo, wooden blocks are placed on the top of the second course of blocks, which will support the ends of the rafters, which in turn rapport file roof forms. CORNH E BLOCKS. The cornice blocks should blocks. They will then have strong. 1m- made while making the wall ample time to cure and become Itlocks for the cornice may block machine by making two Ik* made in the two-piece cement blocks and dropping them into the machine on top of the templet as shown by "a" and "b," Fig. 45. Showing how Fig. 44. Showing how to make cornice block in two-piece concrete to make templet ana concretecornice blocks in a one-piece concrete block machine. block machine. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 the wall block and one inch shorter the other. To make cornice blocks in the one-piece block machine, cut two pieces of tin or sheet-iron which will drop down over the core holes on the inside of the machine, then make three or four templets as illustrated in figure 45. The block is made by drop - ping the templet into the machine as any templet, then filling the mold in the same manner as for wall blocks and removing it in a similar way. The curve in the mold will not show suffi - ciently to bother any. By making as many blocks each day as there are templets it will take only a few days to make sufficient cornice blocks. Tf commercial blocks are used for the walls, cornice blocks can be made cheaper as shown on page 85 under "Making ;ind Placing Cornice Blocks" than to Mike machines as above illus - trated. If intermittent doors are used, sufficient additional blocks must be made to fill the wall between the doors. The exact number of blocks required is given in the table. Extras should be made to replace broken ones. This table is computed on the basis that a sack of cement will make 13 blocks and that a cubic yard of sand will make 77. If the blocks are to be 8"x8"xlfi". about 7 per cent of material should be added. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 16" long, with approximate amount of material required in their construction, for silos of various sizes, using contin - uous doors up to the fourth layer of stone from the top of the silo. r Sacks cement 84 92 100 Cu. yd*, sand 14.2 15.5 16.9 Cement for mortar. 36 39 43 Sand for mortar... 2.3 25 2.8 Whole blocks 1,195 1,314 1,432 Half blocks 26 29 32 Sacks cement.. Cu. yds. sand.. Cement for mortal! 40 44 48 Sand for mortar .... 2.5 2S 3.1 Wholeblocks 1,345 1.479 1,813 Half blocka ' 26 29 32 » Sacks cement.. Cu. yds. sand.. Cement for mortarl 45 49 64 Sand for mortar... 3.0 3.2 3.4 rE 14. — Materials for footings of concrete block or solid concrete silos. Diameter of silo 10 12 Sacks cement 12 14 16.5 19 21 I 23.5 26 | 28 1,395 il.501 1,808 1,714 1,821 1,927 2.1. 35 | 38 41 44 47 50 5» 63 108 117 126 134 142 150 167 183 ISJ l'.t.7 21.1 22.6 24.0 25.4 2S.2 31.0 ■0 54 57 61 64 71 78 3.0 3.3 3.4 3.6 3.9 4.1 4.6 5.0 ,195 1.314 1.432 1,551 1.689 1.788 1.906 2.025 2.143 2.3XO -'M7 M 29 32 35 38 41 44 47 50 56 82 93 1"-' 112 121 131 14' 149 158 167 185 303 12.7 17.3 1H.S 2 .4 21.9 23.5 25.0 26.6 28.2 31 .1 XI 40 44 48 52 56 60 64 67 71 7» 87 2.5 2 8 3.1 3.4 3.5 3.8 4.1 4.3 4.6 5.1 5.6 .345 1.479 1,612 1,748 ,1,879 2.013 2,146 2.2K0 2.413 2,680 2.947 M 29 32 35 38 41 44 47 SO 56 62 Ml 115 125 135 147 157 167 177 188 ; 208 239 17.6 19 4 21.2 22.9 24.6 26.4 28.2 30.0 31.7 35.2 38.7 45 49 54 ■ 63 67 71 76 80 88 9* 3.0 3.2 3.4 3.7 4.0 4.3 4.6 ! 4.9 5.2 5.8 6.3 14 I 16 I 18 I 20 ! 22 I 24 v^u. yu. 1 *. saiiu I -.•&gt; | -. t o •&gt;.«. | •&gt;. i &lt;*.i •s.o o o.o B Height of silo, in feet 2022 24 262H303234364O44 ■ Wh..l.- blocks 645 720 784 849 1 913 978 1.042 1,107 1.171 1.300 1,429 Half Works 26 29 32 35 38 41 44 47 SO 56 62 Sucks cement 52 57 62 67 73 78 82 87 92 102 112 Cm. yds. sand h.7 9.5 10.4 11.3 12.1 13.0 13.8 14.7 15.5 ! 17.3 19.0 Cement for mortar 22 24 26 28 30 33 35 37 39 Sand for mortar 15 1.6 1.7 1.9 2.1 2.1 2.2 2.4 2.5 Whole blocks 775 852 928 1.005 1.0K1 1,158 1.234 1,311 1,387 1.840 1.69a Half blocks. 26 29 ■ M .18 41 44 47 50 56 62 Sacks cement.. 61 67 73 79 85 91 97 103 109 121 133 Cu. yds. sand 10.3 11.3 12.3 13.3 14.3 15.3 16.3 17.3 18.3 111 .'-• 4 Cement for mortar 26 28 31 33 36 39 41 44 46 51 56 Sand for mortar 1.7 1.9 2.0 2.1 2.3 2.5 2.6 2.8 3.0 3.3 3.6 Whole blocks 925 1.017 1.108 1.200 1,291 1.383 1,474 1,566 1,657 1,840 2.023 Half blocks 26 29 32 35 38 41 44 47 50 I 56 62 Sacks cement 72 79 85 93 101 108 116 122 129 144 158 Cu. yds. sand 12.2 13.4 14.B 15.8 17.0 18.2 19.4 20.6 21.8 24-' M&lt; Cement for mortar 31 34 37 40 43 4fi 49 52 55 I 61 67 Sand for mortar 2.} 2.2 2.4 2.6 2.8 3.0 3.2 3.4 3.5 3.9 4.3 Whole blocks 1,075 1.182 1,288 1,395 il,501 1,608 1,714 1,821 1,927 244 Half blocks.. 26 29 32 35 j 38 41 44 47 50 56 62 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 ment in worttir joints. Diameter of silo, in feet _k 111 12 II M l&gt; 20 1 ■ r hi. H } f 1 ; it i.l a z - 2 ii R *j e; «i «' -i «• «; *j _ 5 * = * 1 3 g 5 » • 3 a a I * i a a a 'i i .... i .... i .... i .... i .... i X / 1 , ii 1 1 ., I I 0 .... 0 O .... 0 ... (I .... () II II u .... o 1 } 2 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 1 1 .... 1 1 i 3 0 .... 0 .... (I ... I) .... U ... (I :) II ll u .... o i 4 1 ... 1 ... I ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 4 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 4 ? 5 0 .... 0 .... 0 ... () .... U .... II I 6 1 .... 1 ... 1 ■ ■ 1 .... 1 ... 1 I .-&gt; II II II 0 0 .... 0 I 1 1 1 1 1 .... , [ 7 0 .... 0 ... 0 0 .... 0 .... 0 II 7 II II II II (i I j 8 1 .... 1 ... 1 ... 1 .... 1 ... 1 li s 1 1 1 1 1 .... 1 (9 0 .... 0 .... O ... (&gt; .... I) ... 0 '.I II II II O .... I) , 10 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 III 1 I 1 1 8 ] 11 II .... 0 ■.•■ I) .... 0 .... () ... I) ' 12 1 39 1 45 1 Xt 1 Hi 1 m 1 74 s II II o II » .... n U i » i 4.-. 1 .53 t «o i M i i It I I ... 0 .... (I ... 0 ... 0 .... 1 la (i n ii it o .... i 10 J 14 1 ... 1 .... 1 ... 1 0 ' 15 II 41 H (I M 0 ■ 1 S."&gt; 1 in u i l l i ii 15 I il 44 II IK) 0 68 1 S.1 I i M 1 ... l l I .. o .... I) 1 II .... I) 12 ] 17 II o ... I) .... I) .... 1 ... 1 12 II ' IS 1 .".5 1 H 1 7.". 1 8.i 1 1(15 1 115 I i HI II ... 0 ... 0 ... 1 .... 1 ... 1 1 14 ' 211 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... I) .... II .... II ' tl n HI II 72 II ■ I 1112 1 124 II IM , 11 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... II .... I) 1 14 II 0 n n ii no i o "-' ii 83 1 1112 1 124 ll 22 1 II l 1 1 II Hi '23 II .... 0 ... I) .... 1 . . 1 ... 1 Mi 23 II n II 1 ( H 1 72 1 85 1 &lt;»7 1 ll'.l 1 143 1 Mi 24 1 72 1 So 1 97 1 in i 14:) i i 25 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... 1 25 1 1 I 1 ... 1 is I Hi n .... .... 0 ... 1 .... 1 .... I ' .'7 1 S2 1 97 1 IH II IM » 1«2 1 K'&lt; II ... 0 ■••• 0 .... 1 .... 1 1 H I -2 1 113 ll ■ ii n -II } 2!&gt; 1 .. .. 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... 1 211. . . ■-".I 1 1 1 I .XI il ni 1 1111 1 127 1 1112 1 1WI 1 m 30 I) m( 1 11(1 1 127 1 , :tl ! .... l ... l .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 :)1 1 1 1 .... 1 22 \ .i-2 ■■ .... 0 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 22 J 32 ,. .... 0 .... 1 .... 1 ... 1 .... 1 Ma 1 99 1 12:t 0 143 I) 179 1 219 1 Ml 33 1 99 ; I 123 0 143 II IT'.l 1 219 1 ! M 0 .... II .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... 2 34 0 .... I (I .... 1 .... I 1 .... 1 .... I 24 ) :« 1 ... 1 ... 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 24 ) :« 1 1 ... 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 ' :«i II \tU i 1 IM 1 Mi 1 204 1 247 2 Ml ' Mi II im 1 Oi IM 2114 117 1 .11.-. 21; \ ;!h (' : ;; : 1 ...'. \ .'." 2 . : ; ; I I m 1 US 0 149 II 180 1 Ml 1 285 1 C7 , 41) 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 2 .... 2 :!7 1 .... 1 3H II .... 1 1 1 1 I 2li . , ,. 1 .... I ... 2H &gt; 41 II ... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... 1 I 42 1 126 1 1«9 1 202 2 M4 -' 332 I 410 | 4.S 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 ... 1 .... 2 30 &gt; 44 I) .... 1 I .... 1 .... 2 ... 2 .... 1 '4r. 1 137 1 188 t 225 1 298 1 370 2 Ml , 4B 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 32 ) 47 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... I .... 1 I 153 1 | 208 1 247 | 340 2 418 2 . )!l 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 1 .... 2 34 ? ■ 1 .... 1 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 I 2 1 51 1 17 1 ' 228 1 277 1 Hi 1 456 1 ■ M 1 1 ... 2 .... 2 ... 2 .... I 36 \ S3 1 .... 1 .... 1 ... 1 .... 1 .... 2 '54 1 186 1 246 2 315 2 417 2 504 (Mil ... 1 1 .. I ... 2 .-• I 1 1 I .... I II I „.. 2 31". 417 2 504 1 ... I ... I .... 2 .... 38 } 56 1 .... 1 ... 2 .... 2 .... 1 ... 2 I 57 1 207 1 2B6 1 345 1 451 2 551 . i 58 1 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 .... 2 40 \\ 50 1 .... 1 .... 1 1 ... 1 .... 2 ' IWI 2 225 2 300 2 382 2 494 2 59S I TM I 1 300 2 382 I 2 ' 494 2 ' 59S I T'd Ungthl., cul Belweradoon.. 34' 6" 40' 9" ' 47' W •" 59' s </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 T.uii.k Hi. — Xtimber nf i-orniec blocks 8" wide and 10" long and material require/I in their manufacture for silo roofs tcith carious iliu meters. i ON&lt; HFTF. lir.(« K S1I.O ON THE KARM OF A. AKMANN, MAMTKL, NEIfR. UiniiK'tci- Hi ft.. lici";liT '-i'2 ft., VI" wall, concrete block, without Capaoitr 130 tons. *.-)!'. Ill) 56. M ti.Olt 34.00 ■.'4.1T. S4.IKI 248 sacks cenient. at 40c 99. 20 Blacksmith bill 8.55 Total cost 1415. If Cost less home labor f24L.8o Coet per ton •! . 19 roof and clintc IT. .lavs, at *2.00 28 .lays, at 2.imi 3 days, at 2.00 I'." .lavs, at 1. -J.V.' 19 J davs. at 1.28 121 days, at S.M iinasmi Material — 2 cars sand 37.50 1209.75 (3,000 ll.s. left I 2(1(1 ll)s. No. 14 jpilv. wire, at «c 12. 00 Doom ltJ0 -"•"' :?r&gt; Diameter of silo, Number of blocks .Sacks cement in feet required required Cu. yds. sand required — 10 4'.) 1.43 U M 1 7ii 14 ■ 2.00 M 7n !&gt;.:«) 15 2..i&lt;) 20 97 COST OF CONCRETE BLOCK SILOS. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Silo ' (»intruction in Xebraska. !i II \ EIDER'S FIRST CONCRETE BLOCK SILO, FREMONT, KEBR l)i;i meter. 16 feet; height, 374 feet. Capacity. 167 tons. Two - piece concrete block, with concrete roof, but without chute. Foundation and floor — 54* sacks cement, at 35c 119.08 12 on. yds. sand, at |1.41 16.92 Labor 9.27 $45.27 Blocks— 243.5 sacks cement, at 35c 85.22 40 cu. yds. sand, at $1 .41 56.40 Labor on blocks 101 . 12 Hauling blocks to silo 12.00 254.74 Doors and frames — Cornice blocks — 75 sacks cement, at 36c 2.71 1 cu. yd. sand, at f 1.41 1 .41 Labor 3.46 7.58 1.41 Labor Erecting silo walls — 62 sacks cement, at 35c 21 .70 0 bbls. lime, at $1.25 7.50 t cu. vds. sand, at $1.41 5.64 500 lbs. No. 3 wire, at .027c 13 . 50 50 lbs. No. 9 wire, at .03c 1.50 Total cost $658 78 Cost less home labor $444.16 Cost per ton capacity 3 .94 Cost per ton capacity, less home labor 2.66 Steel 34.00 Lumber Tar paper Xails Bolts Carpenter 6.25 .50 .25 .25 3.50 Mason's labor 1 Common labor .oof— 30 sq. yds. metal lath, at Me 24 sacks cement, at 3"&gt;c 2J cu. yds. sand, at $1.41 1 barn sash Labor 156. on 75.79 3.00 8.40 3.18 .75 9.48 : </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 R. B. SCHNEIDER S SECOND CONCRETE BLOCK SILO. Same specifications as first silo Foundation and floor $45 27 Blocks 254 . 74 Doors and frames 44 . 75 Cornice blocks 7 . 58 Erecting walls — 644 sacks cement. itKc 122.58 6 bbls lime, at *1.25 7.50 4 cu. yds. sand, at $ 1.41 5.64 500 lbs. Xo. I wire, at $0.027 13.50 50 lbs. No. 9 wire, at ?0.03 1 . 50 Mason's labor 128.40 Common labor 44 . 84 223 . 96 Roof — 30 sq. yds. metal lath, at lOr 3.00 2fi sacks cement, at 3r&gt;c 9.10 2} cu. yds. sand, at $1.41 3.18 1 barn sash , 75 Labor 8.03 24.06 Total cost $600 .36 Cost less home labor $416 . 69 Cost per ton capacity 3 . 59 Cost per ton capacity, less home labor 2.49 The cost of the two homemade concrete block machines was $2.89 for material and $5.06 for labor. Labor on 300 templets was $8.36. and the material $22.88. Material in the scaffold cost $30.00. and the labor for erecting and removing in both silos was $9.48. Forms for the foundation contained material to the value of $3.92. CONCRETE BLOCK SILO OF E. M. LITTLE, SILVER CREEK, NEBB. Foundation — Excavating. A day $1 . 50 28 sacks cement, at 424c 11.90 Concrete work — 3 men one day 4 . 50 Reinforcing — old iron and wire 1.00 $18.90 • Copy of statement furnished by E. M. Little. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">118 sacks cement. ;il 42ic IK.16 Labor — 3 men. 7i davs. at flJM 33.7.~&gt; 4.200 anchors, at tS.76 16.75 16.78 Rent — mold iind pallets ]0.(H&gt; fill!).*;.* Construction — Mason. ,xj days, at $4.00 34.00 L' helpers. S.I davs. at 91.60 2"). ."ill ."&gt; sacks cement, at 42.1c 8.13 :: lil. Is. lime, at Sl.&lt;&gt;."&gt; 4.9.") 200 !hs. No. 4 wire, at ?1.40 2.80 3 iii. iron rod for doors 3.00 |x4J in. Indts 30 Ti'.tig Hoards and roofing for doors B.SI Dimension of silo — 14J l&gt;v ."52 feet inside; 1.0M Mocks. 24 to cniii-se. IVnilde walled. frost, air. and moisture jiroof. IVmianent. Grand total without roof. iota] without roof. hnltaft and Ixwml. ... $2h»;.4S (^ost less home labor f172.48 it- labor f17'J.4S Capacitjr of above silo. 107 tons hove silo. 107 tons Cost |H-r ton fprity fi .03 fprity $1 .93 Cost \n'v ton capacit.v. lens home lalwtr f 1 .fil rapacity, less home lalx&gt;r f 1 .fil I'ON CRETE BIJK K SIl.O OK A. S. CI.EARY, NORTH LOIP, NKKIS. :te block silo ok a. s. ci.eabt, north loit, nkki:. Size. lfi'x.W; foncrele blocks made on the farm. Ifl'x.W; tamtrtie blocks made on the farm. Cost of labor and material making the blocks $180.00 and material tiinkiii&lt;r the blocks $180.00 Labor of mason 95.00 M 95.00 Wire for rein forcing 6.00 ifoi-cin&lt;r 6.00 Roof 30.00 Doors 20 . 00 Total 1331.00 Total 1331.00 Cost jter ton capacity $2.78 capacity $2.78 Cost of concrete block machine 32.00 i'te block machine 32.00 built with the barn. iR a table compiled from a statement furnished bv finite was built with the barn The altove is a table compiled from a statement furnished by Mr. Clear?. INSI'Kl TKl.V OK CONCRKTK Itl.OCK SII.OS. The concrete block silos which were inspected had been used from one to six Tears. One of these had a short crack near the </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Wit Construction in Nebraska. 65 foundation ; another had a small crack caused by using green blocks ; and another was leaning about two inches out of perpen - dicular. This was due to its being partially undermined by the river during a severe flood. None of these silos had defects which would impair their usefulness in the least or require any repairs. One stone silo was visited in Wisconsin which had been used 15 years, and the cement plaster on the inside still showed the trowel marks. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 clay block, ok hollow brick silos. r-'or the jiast ten or fifteen years clay Mock silos have been in in Ohio, and in IM8 the Agricultural Engineering section of Inwsi State College |iro]&gt;osed a type of this silo which did Clay block silo at the steer feeding plant, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. not require special blocks. This type of silo, known as "the Iowa silo."' has become quite popular in Iowa and other states where </seg>
            <seg id="p067">ajWO (. OTlitt 't'ltt't tOtl tt% -N €0t'(lxfCQ. 67 Silos built of this material are durable, not more expensive than other tyjHHs of above-ground silos, present a good appear - ance, and are less apt to freeze than some of the other types of silos. In their construction, however, it is essential that an en - gineer supervise the erection of the first silo or that a mason who has previously worked upon one be employed. In 1910 a silo of this type was built on the University Farm and during the three years it has been used has given excellent satisfaction. The clay block silo consists essentially of either a concrete or a clay block foundation, upon which is built the walls of the silo. These walls are made of clay blocks 4 inches thick, 8 inches high and IS im-hes long or 5 inches thick by 8 inches high aud 12 inches long. The blocks are set on edge and the reinforcing rods are laid in the mortar joints. The door frame consists of reinforced concrete door jambs tied together with two clay blocks about every 42 inches, which in turn are heavily reinforced. The roof should be of concrete. FOt.'NIMTIOXS, In constructing the silo there are i wo good types of foundation which can lie used. 1. Concrete footing with blocks atn&gt;ve. (Fig. -Hi. i 2. Concrete footing and founda tion to a foot or so above the ground. Probably the concrete footing with clay blocks for a foundation wall will be found easier to erect than the concrete footing and con - crete foundation wall. And if care is exercised to keep the water from accumulating within the cavities in &gt;-wir— H Fig. 46. Clay block silo foundation. the blocks during freezing weather, such a foundation will be permanent. DOORS. The same tyj&gt;e8 of doors are applicable to this silo that are applicable to the cement block silo, and the only change neces - sary in making the doors is to reduce the thickness of the forms. The boards marked EE, figure 37, in the continuous forms should be three inches narrower for 4-inch clay blocks than for the 7-inch concrete blocks. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Silo Construction in Nebraska. SCAFFOLD. Since the erection of this silo is identical with the concrete blocks, the same type of scaffold is used. THE SILO WALLS. The walls of the silo are made of clay blocks and left bare or plastered or washed with cement. Since this type of silo is classed among the durable silos, it is essential that the walls be of good material. Whenever possible to obtain them, the blocks should be hard burned and curved, but since there are no manu - facturers in Nebraska of clay blocks especially for silos, it is necessary to send out of the state for the hard burned and curved blocks. This of course will make increased freight charges and it will often be cheaper to use the local yard run blocks and plaster, thorn inside and out with cement plaster. The silo at the University Farm was built of yard run blocks, then plastered in - side and out with cement plaster. The plaster not only seals up the soft brick so they do not take moisture, but makes a smooth wall on the inside and out and adds very much to the strength of the walls. Tf the walls are not to be plastered, considerable time must be used in making a perfect joint, and there is a question whether it is not as cheap to build the wall, paying very little attention to the vertical joints, and then plaster the silo, thus filling all the joints perfectly. If the walls are to be washed with cement, it should be done either as they are being laid or as the scaffold is being lowered. The cement wash for this use should be one part cement and one part fine screened sand, wet and mixed to the consistency of cream and applied with a whitewash brush. There are several types of clay blocks which can be used, but the 4"x8"xl2" is no doubt the cheapest and easiest to handle. Fig. 47. Five types of clay blocks which can be used for silo con - struction. "A" is 5"x8"x24"; "B" is 5"x8"xl6"; "C" is 4"x8"xl6"; "D" is 5"x5"xl6 w and "E" Is Fig 8. Silo c.r - nice for c lay block silo. 4"x5"xl6". </seg>
            <seg id="p069">■ is less apt to freeze, but is more expensive and more troublesome to lav. The former size has been found sufficiently strong, so its in* is recommended. Figure 47 illustrates good clay blocks for REINFORCING THE WALLS. Altho the walls of a clay block silo are not as thick as those of the cement block silo, there is such a small difference in the amount of reinforcing required that the same table of reinforc- ing and the game manner of placing it are applicable to this silo. ROOFS. The roof can be made of any material, but since the concrete roof costs no more than a good shingle roof it should without question be used. There are three general ways to build the cornice of the roof. Oin- is the same as is shown under concrete silos, the other is to build cornice blocks of concrete and lay them in place, while the third one is to lay the top row of tile on its side. Cornice blocks are made by splitting tiles lengthwise, making the pieces L- 'shuped and laying them on their backs on the wall as shown by figure 4S. and then filling them with concrete. The remainder of the roof can be built the same as for concrete silos. To facilitate the construction of the silo, the derrick, the door forms, and the scaffold should be made ready for assem- bling before the masons arrive. The foundation can also be put in and likewise the floor. BILL OF MATERIAL USED IN IOWA SILO ON UNIVERSITY FARM. 16 feet in diameter and 31 J feet high. 100 sacks Portland cement, at 52ic 152.50 27 sacks hydra ted lime, at 35c 9.45 11 cu. yds sand, at $1.40 15.40 24 cu. yds. chips, at $2.75 6.88 4.030 pcs. 4"x8"xl2" hollow tile, at $2.25 per 100. ...... 90.68 DOORS. 150 sq. ft. W. ]\ flooring, at $45 per M 6.75 1 sq. 1-ply roofing 2.00 RIINFOBCTNG. \" reinforcing steel I 2g 45 f" reinforcing steel I </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 silo Conn! ruction in Xebraska -~&gt; Mix. :" rods, mild steel, at $2.40 j&gt;er cwt ft.ft 10 lbs. }" rods. Norway iron, at $4 per cwt .40 10 lbs. i"xl" rods. Norway iron, at $ 4 per cwt .40 STAGING. 630 ft. 2" Y. P. lumber, at $30 per M 18.M 64 ft. l"x!2" lumber 2.00 8 Y's.1" machine bolts .in H V'x15" machine bolts DOOR FORMS. 20 ft. W. P. lumber 3 . SO Total material $2.'!7 M LABOR. ExeavatinfE- Men. 40 hrs.. at 25c $8.00 Team. 10 hrs.. at 18f 1 .50 Placing foundation. 10 hrs.. at 2.V 2 ."0 Making cornice blocks. 21 hrs.. at 20c 4 .20 i Cornice blocks discarded later. 1 ) Laying floor. 12 hrs.. at 20o 2 40 Masons laying wall. 01 hrs.. at 70c 03.70 Helping masons. 25 hrs.. at 20c 5.00 Helping masons. 105 hrs.. at 2.~&gt;c 26.25 Masons plastering inside, fil hrs.. at 70c 42.70 Helpers plastering inside. 70 hrs.. at 25c 10.00 Superintending, making scaffold and erecting it. 128 hrs.. at 30e 38.40 Total labor $213 . 05 Total material 2'M M Grand total $451.45 In erecting the walls, the staging slipped and pushed the wall out about two inches, and it was thought best to plaster the de- pression until the wall was straight on the inside. Later it was found that this was unnecessary, and about $25 could have been saved on the silo, which would make the silo cost $426.20 up to the roof, but not plastered on the outside. This includes all hauling, the staging, and the board for the men. but does not include the roof and the chute, which were built by the con- tractor who built the barn. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 COST OF CLAY BLOCK SILOS CLAY BLOCK 8II.0 OF F. P. TIPTOX, 8EWAHD, NEBH. Size. If feet li.v :55 feet Foundation — Excavating. 1:2 lira., at 20c Placing concrete. 8 hrs., at 2flc 20 sackR cement, at 4Se 4 yds. sand, at $1.50 Foundation — Excavating, ll' lu-s.. at 20c |2.40 Placing concrete. 8 hrs., at 2flo 1 .60 20 sacks cement, at 4.V ft. 00 t yds. sand, at $1..~0 6.00 $19.00 Walls— Walls— Rrick and steel, f. o. b.. Reward Cement. 38 sacks, at 45c Sand. 5 yds., at $1.50 Rrick and steel, f. o. t&gt;.. Seward 123.50 Cement. 38 sacks, at 45c 17.10 Sand. 5 yds., at f 1.50 7.50 Hardware 4.55 Blacksmith 2.50 Hardware Blacksmith Labor — Masons. 130 hrs.. at 60c Helpers. 100 hrs.. at 30c Labor — Masons. 130 hrs.. at 60c 78.00 Helpers. 100 hrs.. at 30c 30.00 263.15 Door forms — l&gt;ooi- forms — Carpenter. 11 hrs.. at 40c Lumber Carpenter. 11 hrs.. at +0c 4.40 Lumber 5.08 9.48 Scaffold- Labor. 28 hrs.. at 40c Material, lumber, stretchers, etc Scaffold- Labor. 28 hrs.. at 40o 11.20 Material, lumber, stretchers, etc 36.72 47.92 Roof form — Labor. 7 hrs.. at 40c Material Total This includes all forms and staging, bu Roof form — Labor. 7 hrs.. at tOc 2.80 Material 12.33 15.13 Total $354.68 This includes all forms and staging, bnt does not include in side plaster, roof, or chute. Since Mr. Tipton built three silos with t side plaster, roof, or chute. Since Mr. Tipton built three silos with the forms for this silo. their cost should be divided among the tli their cost should be divided among the three, making this silo cost ?330.50. Cost less home labor f278. 10 Cost per ton capacity 2 . 21 Cost per ton capacity, lees home labor 1.88 Note. — A more complete description of the erection of this silo will be found in Towa Experiment Station Bulletin No. 117, Ames. Iowa, and Farmers' Bulletin No. 430, U. 8. Department of Agriculture. Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 CLAT BLOCK SILO OF W. K. MANSFIELD, WISPIER, NERR. Sire, 2O'x47'. walls of 4 and 5-inch blocks 2,000 5" blocks fill .50 1.700 4" blocks 72 50 Hauling blocks, at ?2.50 per day. man and team 16.25 170 sacks cement, foundation, mortar, and plaster 85.00 Hauling cement 5 . 00 16 loads of sand 16 . 00 Hauling sand and steel 10 . 00 Wire reinforcing and hardware 47 . 00 Door material and labor in construction 12.06 Labor of two masons and one tender 145 . 00 Board of masons and tender 15 . 00 Farm labor, 36 days, at f 1.65 per day 59.40 Excavating 13 . 20 Total $607.85 Without roof or chute. Capacity, 356 tons. Cost per ton capacity f 1 . 70 Cost, less home labor 489 . 00 Cost per ton. less home labor 1 .37 The above is a table compiled from information which wag furnished bv Mr. Mansfield. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 SOLID CONCRETE SILOS. There are as yet very few solid concrete ailos in Nebraska, hut because of the moderate cost of these siloe, their durability, and their ease of construction, it is believed that there is a great field in Nebraska for them. Wherever sand, gravel, and atone Solid concrete silo, on Bert Mapes' farm. Norfolk, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 »^ I / O * f)Tt X( I If 1 I If AJJ | // .&gt; €0t (tffrCfJt can be obtained without too great expense or the cement oMaiaeal at a reasonable price, such silos should be found feasible and practical. I If a contractor who understands the erection of concrete silos available, there is no doubt but that it would be advisable to ure his services to put up the silo. It is possible to build a concrete silo in which only the founda - tion and walls will be of concrete. But the appearance of I coa&gt; crete chute as compared to the common, cheap, vertical board chute, which is so commonly used, adds so much to a silo that whenever possible it should l&gt;e erected. tA shingle roof presents a good apjtearance on a stave silo. Imt a masonry silo only when constructed at a great 1 1 |W — f mi experiences in the erection of concrete roofs, it lias beea •ned that they are uot materially more expensive than shingle fs and on masonry silos they produce a more pleasing ett rt cannot help but be more durable. FORMS. I There are several fypes of commercial forms on the market. &lt;if which cost approximately in proportion to their eonven - ■e of operation. A silo contractor would probably do well to •chase a set of these forms in preference to working our a ign of his own. as the details of operation are all worked out I there will be no expensive delays caused by failures and in imenting. Even where a great many farmers will work m - her and build several silos, there is no doubt but that the lmercial form will be more satisfactory. If an individual farmer or a few farmers combine to erect silos, a homemade form will probably be found the more practi - cal. In Wisconsin such forms are being used by many fanners and the University of Missouri is encouraging their use. It is not convenient to build a concrete chute with such forms at the same time the silo is being constructed. But if a concrete chute is to be added it can be built afterwards with a special form. CONSTRUCTING HOMEMADE FORMS. The form as used in the construction of a silo on the farm of W. A. Stacy, at Davenport, Xebr., during the past summer con - sisted of an outside band of galvanized iron and an inside band of wood covered with similar material. Each band was 4 feet STYLE OF CONCRETE SII-O. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 1 1 1 1 1 . I 111 ■ OU THICK* OflP n 38 lit 1Q TOjJPi IiC* D t \ II \(**\ US OT OOI 18 «1 DO strap irons, while the inside one was built onto a frame of two wooden ribs. The supports for the form also supported the stag - ing and all work was done from the inside with no outside franie- rtefore starting the construction of the form, a sweep for lay - out circles should be made (fig. 49). Make this from a straight strip of board which is about a foot longer than half the diameter of the silo. On one corner staple a wagon rod which will be inserted into the ground and act as a pivot. At a point in the same side of the straight edge as the wagon rod Fip. 49. A sweep (or laying out silos and silo forms. tune inch less tlian half the inside diameter of the silo away i the rod. staple a spike. This spike will scratch a line for outside of the rib of the form. A string should not be used this purpose, as it will stretch sufficiently to make the form Iiilar. iU'hen the sweep is ready for laying out the circles, cleaa off 'vel patch of ground and tamp it down smooth where the forms will come, then by means of the sweep lay off a circle eh is two inches less in diameter than the inside diameter of silo. The thickness of the vertical boards which will be led to these ribs makes the form the proper diameter. Place lank, which is to be used for making the ribs of the form, on i circle as shown bj figure 4!&gt; and lay off one section of the tn for the si/.e of silo, which is to be built with the dimen - is shown in Table 17. Oat out the piece and then very care - y lay it around on the circle, marking each place the piece Table 17. — Size of section for ribs to solid concrete silo form. «T igure 5i Diameter of silo, in feet A. Length of section B. Width Of swvtion - s 10 1 r o" 3' 9" V II" 5' 34" 6' \" 6' 10" 7' 71" 8" 8" 10" 10' 10" </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 Silo Const ruction in Sebraxka. km lain on the circle. If. when the circle is complete, the first and last marks lack only an inch or two of coming together or lap over a similar amount, the piece should be marked as a Fig. 50. Fig. 61. Showing how to place rib pattern on board to avoid waste. pattern and the remaining pieces cut, but if the marks are off more than mentioned above, the pattern should be made longi r or shorter an amount equal to one-eighth of the diacfcpMey. Figure 51 shows how to place the pattern on the boards so they will cut and make the least waste. If the splice pieces ("A." fijr. 52) at each joint are curved to fit the walls of the form, the Fig. 52. Showing section of ribs which support the frame for the inside form. latter will be much more rigid. The holes for bolting the splice pieces to the main ribs may be bored before or after the form is assembled. Cut the boards for the wall of the form and then assemble, using care to keep the wall square with the ribs; otherwise the form will be twisted. If the form is to be used for more than one silo, it should be lined with No. 28 galvanized iron. The iron comes in sheets which are of convenient size to nail to the form. At four opposite joints of the forms, seats should be cut for wedges as shown by •'It," figure 52. At these joints slots should be made in the ribs so the bolts will slip when releasing the form from the silo. To prevent the edges of the wedge from burring they are covered with band iron or old tire. The seats </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 figure 53. The wedges force the form out against the wall after each raising. When the form is complete, level it up on blocks and see that it has the same circumference at both top and bottom and also see that the sides are plumb. After this is done, measure the width of gap at both joints, top and bottom, and see that these are kept the same when building the silo. Fig. 53. Showing inside forms with wire loops and lever in place for drawing the form together; also a cross-section of the form showing the wedge in place. The outside form should be made of No. IS or 20 galvanized iron and if possible of one continuous piece. This of course necessitates the ordering of the iron three or four weeks before needing it. On opposite sides the form is cut and held together </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 v iiii ikmih (iiid sipjij^s «is siio" u i}\ iigiirc o*r. i ii*tw^ iMiiTs snouiQ be i"x20" and the straps made of Y'xli" irons to keep the forms from buckling. At Hm splices. 2"x4" pieces are nailed onto the iron. Fig. 54. Outside form for concrete silo. Handles for raising are riveted to these forms a distance from the ends of each form equal to one-fourth the length of that part of the form. FOUNDATIONS. The foundations for concrete silos should have the same size footings as the cement block silos, but the foundation wall should be of concrete and slightly heavier than the wall for that part of the silo which is above ground. §The mixture in the footings can have less cement in it than walls require. The foundation wall, however, should have same proportion as the wall above ground. THE WALLS. Many concrete silos have been built with walls 12 inches thick, but several were inspected in Wisconsin which had been up three or four years which were only six inches thick and found to be sufficiently strong. During the summer of 1912 several were built in Nebraska with six-inch walls and so far have proved to be sufficiently strong. By the use of sufficient reinforcing and a good mixture of concrete, a six-inch wall is heavy enough for a silo that is not over 36 feet high. One inch in thickness should be added for each 8 feet of depth over 36 feet </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 If the silo is to be erected near a crushing plant or a gravel pit where such materials are cheap, they should be used in erecting the silo. The proportion of sand, cement, and stone in such instances should comply with the usual customs of the neighborhood for good concrete. Because there are very few places in the state where it will pay to use gravel or stone, sand alone will lie used more for con - crete. The coarser the sand the better, but fine sand will do. Coarse sand does not require as much cement as fine sand. Dirty sand should be avoided, but wherever it is not possible to get clean sand the dirt can be removed by washing. A test to determine whether sand is clean is to fill a twi» - quart glass jar with clear water and then slowly let a fair sample of the sand drop into the jar. Let enough sand in to make it about one-half inch deep after settling, then let the jar stand for a few hours, at the end of which time if there is consider - able scum on the sand it will indicate too much dirt. CEMENT. The cement should always l&gt;e clean, smooth, free from lumps. and so far as possible fresh from the mills. PROPORTIONS OF CEMENT AND SANK. The proportions of cement and sand will vary with the kind of sand. It is the duty of the cement to fill all pores in the sand, and. altho the pores between the particles of coarse sand are larger than between the particles of tine sand, they do not occupy as much space in the body of the Mai, as there are no pores in each individual particle of sand. This reasoning shows why more cement is required for line sand than for coarse. There is very little sand which will require a mixture of less than one part cement and four parts sand, while some sand in the state is coarse enough so one part cement and six parts sand will make a good mixture. MIXING THE CONCRETE. In order to save labor in mixing and handling the coinrete. careful judgment must l&gt;e exercised in planning the layout. Probably the best lay-out is shown by figure on. If a mixer is used it will stand in place of the board. The sand is first thrown onto the board, then the cement is placed on top of this and the two thoroly mixed. The water is </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 Hilo Construction in Nebraska. The sand should be placed well toward the end of the board then leveled, and the cement thrown on top of it. To mix the sand and cement, one man should stand on each side of the pile and with short-handled, square-nosed shovels turn it to the empty end of the board. Until the men have turned a few batches, the sand and cement should be turned four times before wetting and three after. As the men become more used to handling the mixture, the number of times required for Fig. 55. The lay-out for handling turning can be reduced. sand, cement, and water while Plenty of water should be building a concrete silo. used in the concrete, hut not sufficient to make it too sloppy. It should be sufficiently plastic to run around the reinforcing. THE REINFORCING. I From a theoretical standpoint, the concrete walls have suffl - lt strength to hold the pressure of the silage; but, due to &gt;r foundations and the contraction and expansion of eon - te because of difference in temperatures, the walls will crack ess well reinforced. Where concrete silos have not been snc - sful it will generally be found that they were not properly lforeed. The reinforcing should be uniform, free from kinks, I kept near the outer surface of the walls, but should never exposed. I The same table of reinforcing can be used for concrete silos is given for concrete block silos (Table 15). with the addi - 1 of the vertical reinforcing which is given in Table 18. §New woven wire fencing which has an equivalent cross-see - i area of the horizontal wires can be used, and often to good antage. when the other wire is not available. KThe reinforcing is held in position by inserting the short tical rods in the concrete beneath before it has set, then wir - the horizontal rods to these so they will be held in place. If intermittent doors are used, V' reinforcing rods should be placed above and below each door and bent around the nearest vertical rods. This is illustrated in figure 56. Where contin - uous doors are used, two i-inch rods should be placed between the doors. One of these rods should extend to the second verti- </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 Fi( S9. Door form for continuous door. Pig. 57. Illustrating the placing of reinforcing in a continuous door ?«lo. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 (Fig. 57.1 DOORS. The intermittent doors are much easier to make than the continuous, but. as in all other silos, they are not as convenient after once in place. Figure 58 shows how the form is built for the door. It simply drops in between the silo forms and after the forms are raised it is removed and dropped into the form above. Forms for continuous doors are made in a similar manner, but with a projection in the upper part so that the second form drops onto the urst. The piece (•) in this form, figure 59. &lt;lr&lt;&gt;|is back so that the concrete between the doors is held away from the door boards. Hinge doors can be purchased which will fit into nmtutt silos as well as into stave silos. Such doors are more conveu ient during extended cold 8|&gt;ell8. as they are easy to keep closi &lt;1. and hence keep the heat of the silage within the silo. STAGING. Staging such as was &lt;leseril&gt;ed for concrete block and clay block silos i page ."&gt;2 I can be used for the concrete silos, but the Fig. 60. Showing the form, staging, and hoisting de vice in place while erecting a concrete eilo. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 posts should he set farther from the wall so the form can slide between the posts and the walls. In the block Hilos. wires were placed lietween the blocks for tying the posts to the walls. Similar wires should be placed in the concrete, but they are slipped up beneath the form and the top of the concrete after the form has been raised. If the reinforcing has a tendency to stand out against the form, either inside or out. strips of boards should be inserted bttwtci the reinforcing and the form, and as the concrete is heinjr put in place these boards should be raised. HOISTIXO THE rONCKKTK. f Several devices can lie arranged for hoisting the concrete, can be hoisted in half barrels, dumped onto the platform, and shoveled into place, or hoisted in pails and carried to the form, or hoisted in wheel harrows and wheeled across the i&gt;latforin. or a series of platforms can he erected so that a man can stand on each and pass the concrete from one platform to the other with shovels. Probably the most convenient method is to use the derrick shown in figure 11 and raise the concrete in pails. ERECTINO THE WALLS. The order of procedure in erecting the walls should be about {follows: First build the silo forms (the excavation can be ie at the same time or afterwards) ; fill the footing, and re the inside form on this and fill to the ground line. One two horizontal rods should be placed in the concrete near ground line, and the vertical rods, which should be placed nt two and one-half feet apart, should be pushed into the crete. KTn placing the concrete it should be kept at a uniform depth lie form. Tf it is deeper in one place than another the water s into the low place and carries the cement with it. ■ While the concrete is setting, the staging should be made and in place. I After the concrete has set about twelve hours, the inside h can be raised, the horizontal rods placed and fastened r&gt; the vertical ones, the outside form raised, and the concrete i put in place. The concrete can be thrown into the first sections with shovels. If the staging is not complete before ng this section, it can be completed while the concrete is At this time the derrick should be made and the device for hoisting prepared. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Mb Construction in Sebraska. 84 When the height of the silo has become such that it is im - possible to work from the ground on the outside, the outside form should be raised first, the reinforcing then put in place, and the inside form raised. THE ROOF. ITwo methods of building roofs have been used. One is to Id a framework of rafters and cover them with Hy-Rib, a type metal lath which has a rib that strengthens it; then cover i with concrete to a thickness of about three and one-half hes at the bottom and two and one-half at the top of the I The other method is to build a form which in reality is the ters and the sheathing for a shingle roof. Place rod reinforc - on this and cover it with concrete. The latter method is more simple, and is fully as cheap if more than one silo be built from the forms. In order to make rafter supports for the forms, tapered blocks 2"x2i" are placed in the concrete 6 or 8 inches down from the top of the last section, figure 61. These blocks are driven out after the form is removed, and J"x2"xl2" irons are put in their places. These irons support the rafters and also the cornice forms. Fig. 62. Showing; how to cut pieces for cornice forms. Fig. 61. Illustrating how to set Irons and blocks for holding roof form rafters, also cornice forms. The form for the roof can be built the same as the fi-ume and sheathing for a wooden silo, except that it should be re - membered that the form must be removed from beneath. The sheathing should not be nailed and all other nails should be «et so they may be easily drawn from beneath. If several silos an- to he built with the same form, the roof </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Silo Construction in Nebraska. 85 form &gt; should be made in sections, so they can be removed in unitR. To do this the rafters should be doubled. i'he cornice form can be made by cutting curves from 2"x8" ;s as shown by figure 62. These pieces are then laid in ? on the iron supports shown in figure 61, and held in place he galvanized iron band which also makes the outside of form. This band can be held together by iron straps aa n in figure 61 or by blocks as shown in figure 63. Fig. 64. Illustration of forms for making concrete cornice blocks. Fig. 63. Showing how cornice band is held together with blocks. Another method of making the cornice is to make concrete cornice blocks as shown in figure 04. MAKING AND PLACING CORNICE HI.OCKS. Lumber for the form can be of any standard length, as this will avoid the necessity of cutting and the necessity of wasting the material. Nail one-inch by six-inch boards to the edges of a 12" plank and then nail a board across one end. In order to produce a flange on the inner edge of the block a one-inch by nine inch board is nailed on top of the plank midway between the sides. The edges of this board should be beveled a trifle so that it will not interfere with the removal of the blocks. Two parting strips such as is shown at "A," figure 64, should be made to hold the concrete in place while troweling it into shape. The space cut from the lower side of this strip should be just </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Silo Construvtion in \cbraska. In mak i n&lt;r the blocks, first lay m the edges of the form the width of the blocks. The outside end of the blocks should be a trifle wider than the inside. A block 10" wide is convenient To make and handle. The blocks should be placed in the form riii- nrxa so that they will remain true. ■Tack the parting strips in place temporarily and after the r two Matin are made remove and place them up two spares. I The concrete for this work should be the same proportion :is other work, hut it muRt be dry and when being placed l&gt;e 1 tamped and then troweled into shape. After the blocks have been in the form about 24 hours they can l&gt;e removed and others put in their places. tWhen building the roof with these blocks, place the roof in in position, also the reinforcing; then set a block, and le holding it in place put the concrete in position for the f. The concrete will hold the cornice. When men are work - on the roof near the cornice or on the cornice they should held to the peak by means of straps. These are not incon - ient and might save a serious fall. ■The same conditions for building roofs apply to concrete is that apply to concrete block and clay block silos. REINFORCING THE ROOF. tThe reinforcing in a silo roof must resist two forces. — an ward pressure due to the arch of the roof, and a downward ssure due to the weight of the concrete. To resist the out - •d pressure, rods are placed horizontally. A good heavy rod ced in the concrete at the base of the roof is sufficient to hold outward pressure of the silo, but by placing other horizontal Fig. 65. Illustrating the placing of reinforc- ing and concrete on the torm for concrete roofs. The sweep for keeping the concrete at a uniform depth is in position. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 trouble to place the concrete. These rods hold the fresh con - crete up in place so that the work can be hastened; and more - over, the rods add strength to the roof. The radial rods prevent the roof collapsing, due to weight, and it is essential that they extend over the silo walls. These rods should not be over two feet apart at the base of the roof nor at any place up the side of the roof. Ene-fourth inch rods are heavy enough for all silos mp to ?n feet in diameter, and silos larger than that should have J-inch horizontal rods or one j}-inch rod close to the base e roof. Figure (55 illustrates the method of placing rod reinforcing. One-inch blocks should be placed under the rods at various places to hold the reinforcing up in the concrete. These blocks may be removed as the concreting progresses. PLACING THE CONCRETE ON THE ROOF, Before starting the concreting of the roof, set a J-inch or ■finch pin into the peak of the cone, then make and pivot on this pin a sweep, as shown by figure 65. which conforms to the fin - ished shape of the roof. TTave the concrete of just such a con - sistency that it will not crowd down the roof. The crowding will be noticed by the concrete becoming thicker at the hori - zontal rods and thinner just below them. Start placing the con crete at the cornice and fill up along the roof a distance of about three feet, finish a band around the roof to where the men re - • civc the concrete from the hoist, then finish another band in a similar manner, and finally finish the peak, and as the man moves down the peak, he concretes the strip left where the hoist is located. To finish the last point near the cornice a man tie* himself onto the hoisting rope and works from the hoist. If a ball or shaft of concrete can be made before the roof work is started, set it in the peak. — it adds to the appearance of the silo. The concrete ball can be made by making a ball of stiff clay about three inches in diameter on the eye of an iron pin which is about ten inches long. Tie a wire around the straight end of the pin to hang the ball by. Dip the ball into thin concrete every three or four hours and hang it up to dry. Continue the process of dipping and drying until the ball is about 9 inches in diameter; then when ready stick the iron pin of the hall into the peak of the roof and the ball will stay. A shaft should l&gt;e made in a form of wood or steel or clay. When the roof is complete the silo is completed, excepting </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 the cement wash. With a whitewash brush, this is put on the inside as the staging is lowered and on the outside from a ladder. It adds to the strength of the walls if they are wet every day for a couple of weeks. This is an easy task if a small force pump is purchased and used as a spray pump. The outside appearance of the silo is improved if it is plas- tered, but this will increase the expense $40 to $50 and im- proves the silo only in appearance. COST OF CONCRETE SILOS 1 ON &lt; BETE SILO OF GEOKGE HALL, ALTO, NKBK. 16'x42' — 6" solid concrete walls, with foundation, chute, and roof. Built in June, 1912. Excavating, 40 hrs., at 18c |7.20 Excavating, team, 3 hrs., at 15c .45 Building wall, 344 hrs., at 18c 61.92 Making scaffold and raising, 39 hrs., at 18c 7.02 61.92 Framing roof form, 6 hrs., at 18c 2.52 Placing concrete on roof, 30 hrs., at 18c .... 5 . 40 Removing roof forms and scaffold, 24£ hrs., at 18c 4.41 Washing walls with cement, 32 hrs., at 18c o.Tti 194 68 Superintendent's time 52 . 50 Total labor *147 . 18 Material cost — 330 sacks cement, at 35c $115.50 Hauling cement 7 .87 168.510 lbs. sand, at Uc 75.83 Lumber in scaffold 6.51 Window 80 Total material |314 . 14 for 6 men, 14 days 42.00 ling form 10.00 366.14 Total cost of silo complete, with roof, chute, foundation, erection, board, and hauling 1513.32 lauling sand iteel Voven wire, 56 rods, at 35c liscellaneous expenses )oors 40.25 37.40 19.60 4.78 5.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Silo Const ruction in Nebraska. 89 Capacity of silo 194 tons Total cost per ton capacity |2 . 65 Cost per ton capacity, less home labor and board 1.64 CONCRETE SILO AT VALENTIN! SUBSTATION, VALENTINE, NEBR. 16'x30' — fi" solid concrete walls, with foundation, roof, and chute, Foundation and floor — Labor. 60 hrs., at 224c 113.50 37 sacks cement, at 30c 11.10 6 yds sand, at |1.14 6.84 Superintendent labor, 15 hrs.. at 35c 5.25 $36.69 Wall- 10 hrs. labor at 25c 2.50 18.80 Placing forms, 10 hrs.. at 224c 2.25 Placing reinforcing. 10 hrs.. at 22ic 2.25 Placing concrete. 30 hrs., at 224c 6.75 Cement, 21 sacks, at 30c 6.30 Sand, 2$ yds., at $1.14 2.85 Reinforcing. 75 lbs., at 4c 3.00 Superintendent. 15 hrs.. at 35c 5.25 28.65 Removing roof form and scaffold 10 hrs.. at 22}c 2 1 25 Loading forms, 5 hrs., at 22Jc. 13 Drav 3.00 Superintendent. 20 hrs., at 35c 7.00 13.38 Hardware 7 . 60 Scaffold 41.00 Reinforcing Cement, 219 sacks, at 30c Sand, 34 yds., at $1.14 Raising forms and placing reinforcing. 258 hrs., at 224c Placing concrete. 171£ hrs., at 22ic Cement washing. 19 hrs.. at 224c Removing forms. 20 hrs., at 22Ac Cleaning forms. 10 hrs., at 22^c Superintendent. 90 hrs.. at 35c 51.08 65.70 38.76 58.05 38.59 4.28 4.50 2.25 31.50 &gt;oors- Flooring Tar paper Xails Hinges 5.80 2.00 .50 8.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 1124 hra 24.80 Removing forms. IS lirs S.M Filling forms. 105 hrs 33.00 Cement. 200 sacks, at 51.Se 102.60 O ravel. M yds., at *2.47 84.00 Reinforcing 34.39 Frt. on mixer, forms, imil reinforcing 28.60 Painting with cement. 12 hrs 2.40 Cutting reinforcement. 0 hrs 1 .20 1 sash 85 Placing forms. 11 hrs 2.20 Placing reinforcing. 6 hrs 1 .20 Placing concrete, 20 hrs 4 . 00 Reinforcing 2 . 00 Cement. 24 sacks, at 51.3c 12.30 Oravel. 3 yds., at |2.47 7.41 Removing forms. 3 hrs -60 1 sash 85 : r Labor. 8 hrs 1.60 Material 7.40 Hinges 12.00 Nails 25 „ Rent on mixer 5.00 Horse labor 5.50 $ 114.73 Total cost of silo complete with roof, chute. foundation, erection, board, and hauling $."&gt;0fi.86 Post per ton capacity 4 . 25 CONCRBTl SILO OF BERT MAPE8, NORFOLK, NEBR. Ifi'x34' solid concrete walls, with foundation, roof and chute. tndation and floor, including 4 ft. of Rilo wall — ■ Dipping. 41 hrs.. at 20c *8.20 Placing forms. 4 hrs.. at 20c .80 Leveling. 10 hrs.. at 20c 2.00 Filling. 25 hrs.. at 20c ." . 00 .i Cement. 55 sacks, at 51 .3c 28.22 Gravel. 8 yds., at 12.47 lfl.7fi $63.98 Wall— Cleaning forms. 22 hrs 4.40 Raising forms and placing reinforcing. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 Hardware |6 . 00 Superintendent 52 . 50 Board for 6 men. 14 days, at *3.00 42.00 $1041. 5&lt;i Scaffold— Labor. 16 hrs.. at Me $3.20 Material 35.75 Ladders 4 . 15 43 . 10 Total cost of silo complete with roof, chute, foundation, erection, board, and hauling $.579.24 Cost less home labor and board ; hauling being paid for, $439.84 Total cost per ton 4 .09 Cost jwr ton. less home labor and board 3.09 ro\citrr« sito of w. a. stacey, davekport, xerh. 14'x38'— 6" solid concrete walls Homemade form* — Labor 17.55 Material 03.63 $71.18 Foundation and floor — Labor 21 .05 Material 44.65 65.70 Walls- Labor 84.50 Material 157.87 $42.87 Scaffold- Labor 5 . 10 Material 39 .87 Freight on mixer (2 ways) 6.46 51 4.T Chute forms — Labor 6.40 Material 9-56 15.96 (L^bor Material 25.05 28.60 Material 28.60 53.6.1 Roof form — f form — Labor 510 Labor 5.16 Material 10.86 Material 10-86 15.96 rs — Labor 4.00 Material 8.25 12.26 • Mr. Stacey expects to build a water tank on top of this silo, bo the walls of the Bllo were built only up to the tank and the forms for the roof of the tank prepared. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 5 men, 12 days, at f 2.5(1 per day $30.00 Total 1558 .50 ■ this. $154.53 is for forms and scaffold, which can be used at least ten times, hence only $15.45 of it should be charged to this silo, making the cost of the silo, less the roof, but with the chute $418 . 42 Assuming that the roof should cost the same in propor - tion that the roof for the Valentine silo cost, it would be 22 . 25 Making the silo complete, roof, chute, erecting, founda - tion, hauling and board for men $440.67 Cost less home labor and board of men $301 . 90 Total cost per ton capacity $3.48 Cost per ton less home labor and board $2 . 36 It will be noticed from the above figures that the silo proper and one-tenth of the scaffold and forms cost only $2. r &gt;4 .•;:■,. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Silo Construction in Xebraska. 93 F18. — Vertical reinforcing required in silos of various sizex. to be 3 feet apart and either round or square and S feet long. Diameter of silo, in feet Heifcht MO *12 14 t Pounds required Pounds required Pounds required Round Square pC8 ' Round Square No. PCS. No. pcs Round Square &gt; Diameter of silo, in feet Height of 16 IS 20 rilo, fee, Pounds required Pounds required ! Pounds required No. ___ Round Square P 08 ' Round Square No. pcs. No. pcs. Round Square 40 61 255 340 .57 61 255 340 57 51 255 340 57 M 340 452 76 M 340 452 76 as 340 452 76 ,H.-, 425 567 95 U 425 567 N 88 425 567 M u 425 567 &lt;)5 102 510 680 I 114 Kloe 10 and 12 feet in diameter do not need vertical reinforcing rods ting at the doors unless they are more than 30 feet deep. 12 60 80 12 13 60 80 12 12 60 80 12 16 SO 103 16 If. 80 103 16 16 80 103 16 55 275 356 65 55 275 356 M Si 275 356 65 275 356 65 66 330 440 I 78 60 60 60 SO 80 80 325 325 325 325 390 80 80 80 103 103 103 433 433 433 433 510 45 45 45 60 60 60 75 75 75 75 90 225 225 225 300 300 300 375 375 375 375 450 I 85 85 180 180 (80 175 175 175 175 170 380 380 506 506 506 633 633 633 633 760 63 63 84 84 84 105 105 105 105 126 315 315 420 420 420 525 525 525 525 630 I </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 Tablk 10. — Cement mid siuiil required for icaite of monolithic silos. Walls 6" thick. Proportion: one part cement and five parts sand. Diameter of silo, in feet i in 12 14 Hi IN JO II 11 11 1 1 11 ■a 1 I I I 3 I 1 8 i I ! I I I 8 I z a ill fl 2 g 4 % 4 * 4 = - l - I I S I _S I J5 I I iiaiJ'cSllidllaJI^ 14.2 96 16.9 111 19.5 127 23J 14:i 25.0 157 J7.7 15.6 15.6 Ift5 18.6 123 21.5 130 24.5 157 26.6 173 30.5 17.0 115 20.3 137 23.5 152 2ti.S 171 30.1 ISO 33 2 18.5 125 21.9 145 25.4 Iti5 2&gt;).O 1S5 32.0 206 19.9 134 23.6 156 27.4 177 31.2 liKt 35.1 220 19.9 21.3 144 25.3 107 29.4 190 33.4 214 37.0 236 41.5 153 27.0 178 31.3 203 35.6 228 40.1 252 44 4 22.7 24.1 163 28.7 1S9 33.3 216 37.it 242 42.0 288 47 0 173 30.4 200 35.2 22* 40.0 256 45.1 2K3 50.0 25.5 27.0 27.0 182 32.1 212 37.2 241 42.3 270 47.0 290 B2J 28.4 192 33.8 223 39.1 253 44 .0 286 50.1 315 WJ </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Silo Construction in Nekrmtkm. 95 OTHER SILOS. In addition to the above-men tinned types there are three new tyjx's of silos now being erected in Nebraska which seem to be worthy of consideration in this bulletin. but none of them have bem in use sufficiently long to prove their merits. The silo commonly known as the "crib silo" is easy to erect and seemingly will require little or no attention. The silo made by erecting a temporary framework of stud - ding to which light metal lath is nailed and the latter then covered with cement plaster, seems to be reasonable in price and verv durable. The silo made by plastering cement plaster onto Hy-Rib ap - parently makes an exceptionally strong, serviceable, and j:ood looking building. Concrete silo built from cement plaster on Hy-Rib metal lath, at University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">THE BANK 8II.O OF PETER BERGQUIST. ATLANTA, NEIIR. Doors are provided up and down the side of the silo opposite the passage, so the silage can be thrown from the bilo into the common litter carrier which runs out over the feed bunks, as shown in the cut. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>