<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE State Inspector of Oils TO THE Governor of the State of Nebraska FOR THE YEAR January 1 to December 31, 1912</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">ANNUAL REPORT OF THE State Inspector of Oils TO THE Governor of the State of Nebraska FOR THE YEAR January 1 to December 31, 1912 WM. HUSENETTER, Sute Inspector of Oil. Hammond Printing Co. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Lincoln, Nebr., Dec. 30, 1912 I the Honorable Chester A. Aldrich, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Dear Sir: In conformity with the provisions of section 4554 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for the year of 1909, I have honor to transmit herewith a detailed statement of the affairs of the Oil Inspector Department for the year of 1912, beginning January 1st and ending December 31st of the said year. I am much gratified that I am able to furnish you a complete re - port for the 1912 year's business. While this has not been customary. a little extra work has made it possible. These reports should go to the public at the end of each year. Tours respectfully, WM. HUSENETTER. State Inspector of Oils. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Win. Husenetter State Inspector of Oils. W. 8. Jay Deputy, First District, Lincoln L. A. Donahoe Deputy, Second District, Omaha 8. I. Nies Deputy, Thirl District, Neligh Jas. Schoonover Deputy, Fourth District, Neligh U. O. Etherton Deputy, Fifth District, Bartley F. A. Wlsner Deputy, Sixth District. Lexington C. B. Speidell Stenographer, Lincoln Mr. P. W. McDermott appointed Stenographer Sept. 1, 1911, re- signing April 15, 1912. Mr. Roy Armstrong appointed April 16th resigning August 1st. Mr. C. B. Speidell appointed August 1. 1*11 / </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Year 1912 It will be noticed by the numerous requests made to the Legal De - partment and opinions received, that there has been considerable confusion and difficulty in the administration of this department the past two years caused largely by the rigid requirements of our present Oil Law to reject all Petroleum Products which do not pass the test required for Illuminating Oils, however, temporary relief has been procured by the combined efforts of the users and sellers of the class of machinery that use the low grade and cheap oils for power purposes. An action was brought by these interests in the Washington County District Court presided over by Judge Leslie of Omaha, whogranted, on the showing made by these interests a restraining order against any hindrance of these lower grade of petroleum products being used for power purposes. Various other interests such as clothes cleaners, painters, cookerage concerns and many other require a large amount of low grade gasoline which is commonly called Naptha are unable to purchase it now, unless doing so unlawfully. Nebraska at this time is the only state which prohibits the sale of Low grade gasoline. In my judgment, the coming Legis - lature should be asked to remodel our Oil Statute, at least that portion prohibiting the lower grade petroleum products from being used for power and heating purposes and it is my opinion that the oil statutes should be so constructed as to permit the sale of all grades of gasoline to anyone desiring it, with each grade carrying an inspection showing just what it is, that parties may pur - chase what they want and know what they are getting and at the ?ame time, a very severe penalty should be enacted to this end so that the sellers of these oils will feel it necessary to brand these goods carefully. We of this department are considerably gratified after paying all the expenses of every kind, we are able to turn over to the State Treasury for the years of 1911 and 1912, something over $76,000.00. Yours most respectfully, Wm. Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">RULINGS Hon. William Husenetter State Inspector of Oils Lincoln, Neb. I Your letter of the 8th instant, addressed to the attorney general ■ been referred to me for answer. 1 note that you inquire: "Is there any reason why the state inspector of oils can not per mit the use of a lower gravity than 62 degrees on gasoline for pui poses other than illuminating, heating and power?" In answer to your question I will say that in 1909 the legislature of this state passed an act regulating the sale and use of oils. This act provides, among other things, that gasoline shall be inspected by the state inspector of oils, or his deputies, before being offered for sale or use for consumption for illuminating, heating or power pur - poses in this state. (Cobbey's Annotated Statutes of 1911. sec. 6325.) The act further provides that it shall be unlawful for any manu - facturer, dealer or vendor to sell, or offer for sale, gasoline that has a specific gravity of less than 62 degrees, as measured by the Beaurne hydrometer, at a temperature of 60 degrees Fahrenheit. (Cobbey's Annotated Statutes of 1911, sec. 6334.) No punishment is provided, however, for those violating this provision of statute. Neither is there any provision of statute, so far as I know, which makes unlawful the use of such gasoline for purposes other than heating, lighting and power. There is. however, a provision of sta - tute making it unlawful to sell, or offer for sale, or knowingly use adulterated gasoline, and providing that such unlawful act shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $500. I am, therefore, of the opinion that adulterated gasoline, no mat - ter what its specific gravity may be, can not lawfully be used or sold in this state, but that gasoline which is not adulterated may lawfully be used, so long as it is not used for illuminating, heating, or power purposes, even though it has a specific gravity of less than In response to your oral request for an opinion as to whether or not the law requires low grade oils, which are used in this state but which are not used for illuminating, heating, or power purposes, to be Inspected. I will say that, in my judgment. It is the safer plan to have such oils Inspected. Sections 11 and 12 of the original act (Cobbey's Annotated Stat - utes of 1911. sec. 6335, 6336) provide: "It shall be the duty of all persons, firms, partnerships and corporations transacting business In this state to Immediately notify the state Inspector of oils when any oils mentioned in </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Eion one of this act are received by them, which oils have not 1 stamped and inspected as provided in this act. Any persons, s, partnerships of corporations violating the provisions of this section shall be fined fifty dollars ($50) for each offense." "Any pei son or persons whether vendor, manufacturer or dealer, who shall sell or attempt to sell to any person in this state any of the oils mentioned in section one of this act (6325) ui'ioie nating the same inspected as provided in this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be subject to a Pnalty in any sum not exceeding three hundred dollars ($300." above quoted provisions of statute, when considered in con- ttion with the fact that the law does not permit any oil fluid i.-h is a product of petroleum, or into which petroleum enters, to be used for illuminating, heating, or power purposes in this state, unless it conforms to certain prescribed tests, and the obvious dif - ficulty, not to say impossibility, of determining, without inspection, whether or not it conforms to such tests, lead me to the conclusion that the legislature intended that all oils derived from petroleum or into which petroleum enters, if they are to be sold or used in this state, should be inspected. I think this intent is expressed in lan - guage sufficiently definite to make it effective. In answer to your oral request for an opinion as to the specific gravity required by statute in all illuminating oils offered for sale, Kused in this state. 1 will say that the law seems to be quite plain that point. It expressly provides: "The specific gravity shall not be less than forty-six degrees measured by the Beaume hydrometer at a temperature of sixty degrees Fahrenheit. * * * Provided, however, that in the case of illuminating oils made from the petroleum produced from wells in Kansas, Oklahoma, and Colorado, when properly la - beled as hereinafter provided, such illuminting oils may be sold' and offered for sale in this state for illuminating pur - poses where the specific gravity shall not be less than forty - two (42) degrees as measured by the Beaume hydrometer at a temperature of sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit, and the residue contained therein shall not be more than seven per cent by weight after being distilled at a temperature of not more than five hundred seventy (570) degrees Fahrenheit. Provided, further, that every reservoir, tank, barrel, cask, package, or receptacle containing illuminating oils produced from Kansas, Oklahoma, and Colorado oil fields shall be truly, plainly and conspicuously labeled in large letters 'Kansas Oil,' 'Oklahoma Oil. 1 'Colorado Oil,' or words of similar import." From this, it appears that no illuminating oil should be approved by you. or offered for sale or used in this state, unless it ha* a specific gravity of at least 46 degrees Fahrenheit, except such illuminating oils as are made from the petroleum produced from wells in Kansas, Oklahoma and Colorado which may. when prop- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 erl&gt; labeled and when they have a specific gravity of at least 42 degrees and conform to the other conditions mentioned in the pro - vision of statute last above quoted, be sold tor illuminating pur- Tours very truly, Grant G. Martin, Attorney General By Geo. W. Ayres, Deputy Attorney General. January 27, 1912. Hon. William Husenetter State Inspector of Oils, Lincoln, Neb. Dear Sir In answer to your oral request for an opinion of the attorney general's office as to whether or not gasoline, having a specific grav - ity of leas than 62 degrees Fahrenheit, may lawfully be sold in this state, provided it is not sold for heating, lighting or power pur - poses, I will say that section 10. of the act providing for the inspec - tion of oils and establishing the office of state inspector, expressly declares such sales to be unlawful: "It shall be unlawful for any manufacturer, dealer or vendor Isell or offer for sale, any petroleum product known as gas - ie, that has a specific gravity of less than sixty-two degrees Mas measured by the Beau me hydrometer, at a temperature of sixty degrees (60) Fahrenheit." Fu will see that the above quoted provision of statute makes all without exception, of gasoline having a specific gravity of than 62 degrees, unlawful, but, by reason of an oversight doubtless upon the part of the legislature, the section does not contain any provision for the punishment of those making such sales. Hence, so far as any criminal prosecutions are concerned, If other conditions required by law are complied with, one selling gasoline having a specific gravity of less than 62 degrees, provided he makes such sales for purposes other than heating, lighting and power, is not subject to punishment. ■ I do not think, however, that you should countenance such sales long as the avowed policy of the state, as declared by the legis - lature, is to making them unlawful. In order that my views upon this question may be fully understood, it may not be amiss perhaps to refer to some of tbe various sections of statute in which the law V listing the sale of gasoline, and other oils of like character. Is forth. The first section of the act in question reads as follows: "All mineral or petroleum, kerosene, gasoline, or beniine. tiny oil fluid or substance which is a product of petroleum, into which petroleum or any product of petroleum enters or is found as a constituent element, whether manufactured </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 9 in this state or not, shall be inspected as provided in this act, before being offered for sale or used for consumption for Il - luminating, heating, or power purposes in this state." (Com- plied Statutes of 1911, ch. 64, art. 1. sec. 1.) The second section merely creates the office of state inspector of oils, and provides for the appointment of a deputy inspector to carry out the provisions of the act. The third section makes it the duty of the state inspector of oil* and his assistants to examine and test all the oils referred to In the first section, among which you will note gasoline is included, and to issue his certificate certifying that said oil has been duly inspected. In case the oils inspected are approved by the person making the inspection, this section of the statute also provides that he shall mark upon the cask or package containing the oil, the word "approved," and shall affix his brand and also state the actual test as provided for in this act, with the date of inspection and his official signature. If the oils so examined and tested do not meet the test provided for in the act, the person inspecting the same is required to reject said oils and mark upon the tank, reservoir, barrels, cask or package containing same, the word "rejected," and affix thereto his brand, giving the actual test as provided In the act, with the date of the inspection and his official signature. Section 10 of the act provides that one of the tests prescribed for gasoline shall be that it have a specific gravity of at least (2 degrees, as hereinbefore set forth. Section 11 of the act makes it the duty of all persons, firms, partnerships, and corporations transacting business in the state, to Immediately notify the said inspector of oils when any oils men - tioned in section 1 of the act, which you will observe includes gaso - line, are received by them. It provides for the punishment of any person, firm, partnership, or corporation violating the provisions of the section. In other words, this section of statute expressly provides that any one who receives any of the oils mentioned in the first section of the act, hereinbefore quoted, if he fails to give due notice to the inspector shall be punished by a fine. Section 12 of said act makes it unlawful, and punishable by a penalty not exceeding $300 and not less than $100, for any person, whether vendor, manufacturer, or dealer, to sell or attempt to sell to any person In this state any of the oils mentioned in section 1 of the act, before having the same inspector as provided In the act This section does not provide, however, as some of the sections do, that the oil must be not only inspected but approved. Section 15 of the act in question provides, as I have already pointed out in a previous letter to you, that the sale of adulterated gasoline Is a misdemeanor and punishable by a fine not exceeding Construing together the several sections of the act In question. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 AXMAL REPORT ciflc gravity and whatever the purpose for which it is intended, must be inspected in order to comply with the laws of this state; that any person, who receives any uninspected gasoline and fails to notify the state inspector, or his deputies, of its receipt, is liable to punishment; that any person who sells, or attempts to sell, any such gasoline for any purpose whatever, before it has been inspect - ed, is liable to punishment; that any person who sells adulter - ated gasoline for any purpose whatever, Is liable to punishment; that no gasoline having a specific gravity of less than 62 degrees Fahrenheit should be marked "approved" by you; that the intent of the legislature was to make unlawful the sale of gasoline for any purpose whatever, having a specific gravity of less than 62 degree*, but that by mistake and inadvertence the law was left in such a condition that if unadulterated gasoline having a specific gravity of less than 62 degrees Fahrenheit is inspected in the way and manner provided by law, and is afterwards sold for some purpose other than heating, lighting, or power, the seller can not be prosecuted crim - inally for such sale. Yours very truly, Geo. W. Ayers, Deputy Attorney General. Office of the State Inspector of Oils Lincoln, Nebraska, January 30, 1912. riving been conscious for some months that a great injustice being done to those who desired to use low grade kerosene and gasoline for heating and power purposes, I have appealed to the Attorney General's office for some construction of certain sections of the oil laws whereby it would be possible for me to approve of the use of lower grade oils for the above purposes. But in a lengthy opinion just received from the legal department I find they hare been unable to furnish the relief I sought. I am obliged, therefore, to submit the following rulings: I -It is unlawful for any person, whether vendor, manufac - sr, or dealer to sell or attempt to sell to any person or per - i in this state any of the oils mentioned in section 1 of the laws of the State of Nebraska, before having the same in - :ted. subject to a fine of $300. Consequently all gaso - or kerosene must be inspected and either marked "ap - red" or "rejected." — All kerosene shall have a specific gravity teat of 46 de - i and a flash test of 112 degrees. All gasoline shall hare ecific gravity test of not less than 62 degrees, provided, sver that the illuminating oils from, Kansas. Oklahoma, and rado may be admitted with a gravity test of 62 degree* for line and a gravity test of 42 degrees for kerosene. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 11 Third — Having received numerous requests from different parties desiring to offer for sale a preparation called "Distillate," I have submitted a sample to the State Chemist who finds that this preparation carries a gravity test of 36 to 38 degrees and a flash test of 140 degrees which is simply a low grade kero - sene and is, therefore, prohibited by our oil laws. Ih — While the 1909 Legislature which created the present laws neglected to provide a penalty for using low grade gas - le called Naptha for purposes other than illuminating, heat - and power. Section one of the oil laws makes its use or I unlawful, consequently I would be obliged to withhold my roval of Its use or sale. I— Believing that these rulings will work a serious hardship those demanding the cheaper oils for heating and power par - es and where there is absolutely no reason why they should be available the 1909 Legislature has certainly made a seri - error. I have suggested to several heavy consumers of aper oils that possibly there might be brought some friendly t whereby the courts might be able to furnish some relief. ;re appears to be no discretion with oil Inspector but to ob - ve the law as he finds it. (Signed) Wm. Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils. Lincoln, Nebraska. February 29, 1912. To All Deputies — E erring to the matter of carrying samples of uninspected oil one town to another, discussed at our recent meeting, I de - i make the following ruling: EA11 inspections of oil shall be made in the town where the oil ocated and inspection slip either handed to party or put in the t Office before Inspector leaves town." This rule may be dispensed with when it occasions a very un - reasonable delay and when other work suffers from such delay, but in no case Is the matter of expense to be taken into consideration. When an exception is made to this rule I will ask you In your first report thereafter to mention the same and its cause. The law anticipates that the inspections should be made on the ground or as near as practical. The State and Public are entitled to our faithful observance of the spirit of the law. Yours truly, (Signed) Wm. Husenetter. State Inspector of Oils. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ANNUAL REPORT Lincoln, Nebr., May 18, 1912. 1 am extremely gratified at this time to state to those users of low grade oils for power purposes that at last the conditions that have made it impossible to use low grade oil for power purposes have been overcome through a friendly suit brought by various in - terests assisted by the state inspector of oils in the district court of Washington County presided over by Judge Leslie, of Omaha where a decision has been rendered where In it is held that low grade oils for power purposes do not have to test up to the legal requirements for illuminating purposes. The oil law passed by the 1909 legislature required all of these lower grade oils to pass under the illuminating test which has made this department endless trouble in administering the inspection pro - position. While the oil law as it now stands requires the inspection of all petroleum products, it will not be the policy of this department from this time on to inspect these lower grade oils to be used for strictly power purposes excepting in such cases where it is neces - sary to safeguard the public from a class of oils not readily discerned from illuminating oils and at all times this department reserves the right to inspect or not inspect as the interest of the public may appear. Wm. Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils. The following is the finding of Judge Leslie in the District Court of Washington County: — IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF WASHINGTON COUNTY, NE- BRASKA IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLI- , CATION OF HARRY RUBENSTEIN '- JUDGMENT AND ORDER FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS. \ On the 16th day of March, 1912, came Alfred E. Compton, Sheriff of Washington County, Nebraska, and produced the body of Harry Rubensteln, petitioner herein, and also made return an an - swer to the writ of habeas corpus Issued in this case, and after ex - amining the petition of the plaintiff, the return and answer of •aid sheriff, the warrant of arrest and commitment and the complaint on which said warrant was based, and hearing the proofs, and after hearing the argument of counsel, the court desiring to take the same under advisement, the said court permitted the said petitioner to enter into a recognisance for his appearance at such time as the court might order, and the petitioner having entered Into proper recognizance and thereafter the attorneys representing the parties </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 having produced to the court briefs on the questions of law involved, and the court being now fully advised in the premises, finds as fol- 1. The court finds that on March 16, 1912, the petitioner, Harry Rubenstein, was arrested and taken into custody, and unlaw - fully held in custody and deprived of his liberty by Alfred E. Comp - ton, Sheriff of Washington County, Nebraska; that said sheriff arrested and detains said Harry Rubenstein by virtue of a warrant of arrest issued by the County Judge of Washington County, Ne - braska, and placed in the hands of the said sheriff for service. Said warrant was based upon a complaint filed by the County Attorney of Washington County, Nebraska, copies of which warrant and com - £t are attached to the petition in this case, and the court finds said petitioner was held solely and alone on account of said laint and warrant. Ee court finds that the said complaint and warrant do not s any lawful ground for the arrest and detention of said •. 3. And the court being requested to make specific findings with respect to the law involved, in that respect finds as follows: The complaint is insufficient in that the law does not prohibit the sale or use for power purposes of petroleum oils containing more than a trace of sulphur compound or which contains tar-like matter, or which has a specific gravity of less than forty-six degrees meas - ured by the Beaume hydrometer at a temperature of sixty degree* Fahrenheit, or the color of which is not water white nor of bluish opalescence. 4. That the complaint is insufficient to state an offense against the law. since the said complaint charges that the petitioner nsed said oil for power purposes, and said law does not prohibit the use for power purposes of petroleum oil or the product of petroleum oil, although the same does not meet with the requirements of the law for oil to be used for illuminating purposes. IT IS THEREFORE CONSIDERED. ORDERED AND ADJUDGED BY THE COVRT: That the said Harry Rubenstein be discharged from the custody of Alfred E. Compton, sheriff of Washington County. Nebraska, and from said unlawful detention. BY THE COURT, Charles Leslie. Judge. Lincoln, Nebraska, June 1st, 1912. To Whom It May Concern: Owing to the fact that there has been made recently a decision by the Hon. Judge Leslie, in the Washington County District Court, wherein it is held that the low grades of petroleum oils such aa distillate, gas oils, fuel oils, etc.. may be used for power purposes. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">ANNUAL REPORT 14 Some confusion might possibly arise from this decision in regard to other oils and gasoline. While our Nebraska Oil Law explicitly provides for the inspection of all petroleum products, I shall hold that the inspection on the above mentioned low grade oils for power purposes is not necessary and will not inspect them. Kerosene oil and gasoline will be inspected as heretofore, no matter for what purpose used. Naptha or other low grades of gasoline being prohibited by oil statute, the use of this will still be prohibited. Yours most respectfully, (Signed) Wm. Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils. Lincoln, Nebraska, June 14th, 1912. To Whom It May Concern: To those Oil Inspectors doing business in the City of Omaha, it will be my policy from this date not to accept any samples offered in bottles for Inspection. All inspections must be made from cars before being unloaded. This the inspector will be able to do without infringing on the time limit for unloading cars. I will thank you for your assistance in this matter. I have had numerous complaints from various sections of the State where barrel oil has been shipped, that stenciling has been so poorly made, (and some times not made at all), that the gravity or flash is not discernable. My inspectors will be authorized from this time on to condemn all such cases. Yours most respectfully, (Signed) Wm. Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils. June 16. 1911. Hon. William Husenetter, State Inspector of Oils, Lincoln, Nebr. Dear Sir II have your letter of the 12th instant, In which you propound I following questions: K'Can any of the products of petroleum named in section 1, the Nebraska oil laws, vlx., kerosene, gasoline and naptha, sold or uced for other than illuminating purposes, which r e a lower test than that required by law?" f'Do these low grade products of petroleum, which are vir - lly low grade gasoline, escape the regulation contemplated our oil laws by being called other names than gasoline?" </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 15 I will say that the law forbids any person knowingly using for illuminating, or heating, or power purposes, either gasoline or kero - sene, or any other oil which is a product of petroleum, before the same has been legally inspected and approved; that is to say, It la made unlawful to use for any of the purposes above mentioned any oil product of petroleum unless it meets the test required by law. The penalty prescribed for an unlawful use of any oil product of petroleum for heating, lighting, or power purposes is a fine not exceeding $100 nor less than $20. (Compiled Statues of 1909, ch. 6,, art. 1, sec. 14.) You will observe that it is the use of the products of petroleum for certain purposes, and not the sale of same, that is made un - lawful and punishable by this section. Section 10, of the same chapter and article, declares it to be unlawful to sell or offer for sale any gasoline that has a specific gravity less than Is prescribed by said section, but as no penalty is fixed by this section for a viola - tion of its provisions, it is practically unenforceable. Section 16, of said chapter and article, makes it unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale, or knowingly use for illuminating purposes, any adulterated kerosene, which, by reason of being adulterated, will not comply with the tests required by law, and makes it unlawful for any person to sell or offer to sell, or knowingly use, any adul - terated gasoline. The penalty prescribed by law for a violation of the provisions of this section is a fine of not to exceed $600. Your second question I will answer by saying that low grades of gasoline do not escape the regulations provided by law for gaso - line, merely because of the fact that their venders may choose to call them by some other name. Very respectfully, Grant G. Martin, Attorney General, By George W. Ayers, Deputy Attorney General. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ANNL AL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Comparative statement of inspections and receipts of the department for the years 1906 to 1912 inclusive: Barrels Barrels Total Fees Approved Rejected Inspected 1906 222,712 None 222,712 $22,271.«0 1907 261,735 760 262.495 26, 330. SO 1908 263.597 186 263,782 25,825.00 1909 331,983 562 332,546 33,307.26 1910 411,991 762 412,753 41,344.20 1911 501,261 411 601,251 50.242.60 1912 580,645 2657 583,302 58,362.90 Total 7 years 2,573,924 5,337 2.578.840 $267,683.45 COMPARATIVE STATEMENT OF THE AMOUNTS PAID TO THE STATE TREASURER FOR THE YEARS 1906 TO 1912, INCLUSIVE. 1906 $ 9,228.78 1907 13,845.34 1908 13,599.15 1909 17,425.60 l»10 24,742.99 1911 35,134.55 1912 41,783.87 Total $156,760.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 17 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Barrels Approved and Rejected and Amount of Fees for the Year Beginning January 1, 1912, and Ending December 31, 1912. Barrels Barrels Barrels Fees Months Approved Rejected Inspected Collected January 28,793 28,793 $2,879.30 February 38,267 322 38,589 3,860.20 March 35,100 363 35,463 3,546.30 41,653 617 42,270 4,229.76 45,688 325 46,013 4.604.96 55.711 331 56,042 5,608.35 July 54,100 155 54,256 5.428 50 August 69,013 363 69,376 6.938.65 September 62.075 174 62,249 6,227.05 October 50.638 50,638 6,072.75 November 60,175 7 50,182 5.020.7S December 49.432 49,432 4,945.95 Totals 680,645 2,657 683,302 $58,362.90 rICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Statement of Mileage Used and Received for the Year Ending December 31, 1912. Received Used Balance W. S. Jay 13,196 12,768 418 L. A. Donahoe 12.892 11,797 1.096 S. I. Nies 26,092 25,674 518 J. Schoonover 18,938 17,214 1.7J4 U. G. Etherton 23.788 22,692 1,196 F. A. Wisner 28,496 26,211 2.285 Wm. Husenetter 22.006 21,219 787 Total* 146.408 137,376 8,033 J </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN NEBRASKA Invoice of Office Furniture and Equipment of the State Inspector Oils. December 31. 1912 Two roll-top desks. Sectional filing case, two sections. One sectional filing case and bookcase combined. One letter press. One check protector. One Remington Typwriter No 240452 One typewriter table. One typewriter chair. One office chair. One Burroughs adding machine No. 27796 One electric fan. One Cram's atlas. One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1907 One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1909 One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1911. One Compiled Statutes. 1907. Two waste baskets. One cuspidor. Office books, records, supplies and desk furnishings. Two IXL office knives. Postal scales. One dictionary One wardrobe cabinet One mirror. One brush One comb Two pair office shears One riveting punch. Three new Foster cups complete Four sets of stencils. One Coal-Oil Manual. One clock. All the foregoing property is in the office </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Statement Showing Division of State Into Districts for Convenience in Handling Inspections for Year 1912. First District — W. S Jay, Deputy, Lincoln. Ashland. Auburn. Bennett. Cortland. Douglas. Emerson. Falls City. Havelock. Homer. Lincoln. Talmage. Valparaiso. Wakefield. Wayne. Louisville. Neb. City. Plattsmoutb. Ponca. Walthill. Wahoo. Pawnee City. Sioux City. Weeping Water. Tecumseh Second District — L. A. Donahoe, Deputy. Omaha. Blair. Millard. Omaha. Council Bluffs. North Bend. Schuyler. Herman. Fremont. Oakland. Ft. Calhoun. 3o. Omaha. Missouri Valley. Lyons. Third District — S. 1 Nies, Deputy, Neligh Ainsworth. Albion. Norfolk. Laurel. Rushville. Scribner. Spencer. Stuart. Bloomfield. Chadron. O'Neill. Oakdale. Orchard. Neligh. Plainview Randolph Howells. Pilger. Humphrey. Hartington Niobrara. Gordon. Valentine. West Point. Fourth District — Jag. Schoonover, Deputy. Aurora. Aurora, David City. Fullerton. Genoa. Seward. Beatrice. Crete. Spalding. Stromsburg. Surprise. Columbus. Geneva Central City. Greeley Center. York </seg>
            <seg id="p020">ANNUAL REPORT Fifth District — U. G. Etherton, Deputy, Bartley. Alma. Pairbury. Nora. Blue Hill Grant. Red Cloud. Beaver City. Hebron. Stratton. Bloomington. Holdrege. Sutton. Curtis. Hastings. Kenesaw. Minden. Wauneta. McCook. Superior. Swanton Upland. Cambridge. Edison. Elwood. Edgar. Sixth District— F. A. Wisner, Deputy, Lexington Alliance Ansley. Bridgeport. Sumn°r. Sargent. St. Paul. Broken Bow Callaway. Loup City. Mason City. North Platte. Gothenburg. Grand Island Kearney. Ord. Sidney. Wood River. Scotts Bluff. Kimball. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Year Beginning January 1912, and Ending December 31, 1912 RECEIPTS I Inspection fees J58.150.76 Copies of Reports 125.00 Sale of Hydrometer 2.50 ,4.9V. I O 125.00 158,278.26 ce on hand 1,200.00 ICMTS.M DISBURSEMENTS o. I Salary Chief Inspector $2,000.00 Expense of Chief Inspector 331.68 Salaries of Deputies 7,200.00 Expenses of Deputies 2,434.80 Milfeage Books 2,680.00 E. R. Sizer 102.00 Express 9.40 Telephone, Rent ft Tolls ISO. 80 Western Trunk Line 13.30 New Typewriter, (240452) 63.15 Office Assistance 18.80 Stenographer 842.80 Tagllabue Mfg. Co. Supplies 61.08 Messages 3.36 Supplies, Printing. Miscellaneous 443.23 IU6.4I4.39 Paid t State Treasurer 41,783.87 Balance on Hand 1,200.00 1,2 0. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of January, 1912 RECEIPTS Cash on hand Jan. m $1,200.00 Ind. Co-op Oil Co., January fees $2.90 Pen. Consumers Oil Co., January fees. . 5.70 St. Joe Oil Co., January fees 5.80 Three Star Oil Co., January fe«» 6.40 Hugh Elliott, January fees 7.20 James Taylor, January fees 7.20 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., January fees. . . . 12.50 City of Hartington, January fees 12.10 City of Oakland, January fees 16.70 Omaha Oil Co.. January fees 18.60 National Refining Co., January fee*.. 25.10 Manhattan Oil Co.. January fees 48.60 State Oil Co., January fees 59.20 Mutual Oil Co.. January fees 128.80 tat'l. Refining Co., Omaha, January fees 194.70 tandard Oil Co., January fees 2,281.20 $2,832.70 C. St. P. M. * O. Ry., November fees. . .50 C. St. P. M. &amp; O. Ry., December fees. . .80 C. B. &amp; Q. Ry.. November fees 20.20 C. B. it Q. Ry.. December fees 36.50 C. * N. W. Ry., November fees 26.00 Omaha Oil Co., December fees 41.90 I'nion Pacific Ry., December fees 127.90 Standard Oil Co., Copy of Jan. Report 5.00 Nati. Refining Co., Copy of Jan. Report 5.00 Nati. Refining Co., Copy of Dec. Report 5.00 268.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of January 1912 DISBURSEMENTS Cr. American Express Co $1.26 Paynes Printery, printing 2.00 E. R. Sizer, post cards 3.00 Nebraska Typewriter Co., ribbons 3.50 Miller &amp; Payne, sample case 5.00 Lincoln Traction Co., tickets 5.00 Auto. Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Bell Telephone Co., rent and tolls y.25 State Journal, record book 12.50 Geo. Bros. Griffiths, stencils (16) 80.00 C. &amp; N. W. Ry., mileage 160.00 P. W. McDermott, Stenographer, salary 70.00 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and Expenses 136.20 J. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expenses 130.40 U. G. Etherton. Deputy, salary and expenses 120.50 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expenses 132.01 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expenses 122.25 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expenses 111.30 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expenses 183.66 Star Publishing Co., space 17.00 *1,32«.»2 Paid to W. A. George. State Treasurer 1,776.18 Balance 1, 200.00 $4,301.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month Ending February, 1912 RECEIPTS Ca»h on hand February 1 $1,200.00 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., February fees. . . . $9.35 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., February fees. . . . 7.25 St. Joe Oil Co., February fees 9.3 5 Nat'l. Refining Co., February fees.... 15.00 C. B. £ Q. Ry., February fees 25.20 Manhattan Oil Co., February fees. ... 38.30 Marshall Oil Co., February fees 107.30 Mutual Oil Co., February fees 329.20 Nat'l. Refining Co.. Omaha, Feb. fees 396.10 Standard Oil Co., February fees 2,681.50 $3,611.60 I'nion Pacific Ry., back fees 70.70 C. * N. W. Ry.. back fees 60.90 Marshall Oil Co., back fees 60.20 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 5.00 Nat'l. Refining Co., copy of report. . . . 6.00 201.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statement (or the Month Ending February, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS American Express Co $.23 American Express Co .35 George Bros., printing .90 Western Union .67 Western Trunk Line, circulars 5.60 George Bros., printing 14.26 C. &amp; N. W. Ry., mileage 140.00 P. W. McDennott, Stenographer, salary 70.00 EA. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expenses 125.55 . S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expenses 122.05 G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and exp. 133.49 Schoonover, Deputy, salary and exp. 144.00 A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and exp. 113.60 m. Husenetter, Chief, salary and exp. 207.46 Jl.216.74 Paid to W. A. George. State Treasurer 2,596.(6 Balance 1,100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of March, 1912 RECEIPTS Cash on hand March 1 $1,200.00 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., March fees $2.00 Pen. Con. Oil Co., March fees 2.:,0 Fanners Oil Co., March fees 6.40 Wilhelm Oil Co., March fees 4.80 St. Joe Oil Co., March fees 6.60 James Taylor, March fee* 12.20 Jansen Milling Co., March fees 12.90 Omaha Oil Co.. March fees 16.30 H. E. Elliott, March fees 14.60 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., March fees 16.50 State Oil Co.. March fees 32.00 Marshall Oil Co.. March fees 48.40 Manhattan Oil Co., March fees 78.80 Mutual Oil Co., March fees 113.40 National Oil Co., March fees 467.60 Standard Oil Co., March fees 2.527.20 3.362 20 C. St. P. M. ft O. Ry., back fees 1.00 Cudahy Packing Co., back fees 16.20 Union Pacific Ry., back fees 33.51 C. B. ft. Q. Ry. Co., back fees 40.90 Union Pacific Ry., back fees 52.42 Standard Oil Co., copy of report • 5.00 National Oil Co.. copy of report 5.00 154 03 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 27 OFFICE OF THE STATK INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of March, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Adams Express Co .19 Kostka Glass Co., supplies .65 American Express Co 2.90 Auto Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Bell Telephone Co., rent 4.00 E. R. Sizer, stamps 12.00 Bell Telephone Co., tolls 10.40 C J. Tagliabue, supplies 34.26 C. &amp;. N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 260.00 P. W. McDermott, Stenographer, salary 70.00 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and exp. 131.80 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and exp 138.00 D. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and exp. 134.60 J. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and exp. 154.18 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and exp 128.70 tA. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and exp.. 108.75 m. Husenetter, Chief, salary and exp.. 181.51 $1,375.84 Paid to W. A. George, State Treasurer $2,140.39 Balance 1,200.00 I4.7H.2J </seg>
            <seg id="p028">ANNUAL REPORT 28 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of April, 1912 RECEIPTS on hand April 1 $1,200. on St. Joe Oil Co., April fees .60 Pen. Con. Oil Co., April fees 2.90 St. Joe Oil Co., April fees 7.00 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., April fees 4.80 Cudahy Packing Co., April fee* 12.20 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., April fees 13.10 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., April fees 13.65 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., April fees 16.30 Omaha Oil Co., April fees 32.60 State Oil Co., April fees 46.80 Marshall Oil Co., April fees 147.20 Manhattan Oil Co., April fees 167.20 Mutual Oil Co., April fees 254.20 National Refining Co., April fee*. ... 278.20 Standard Oil Co., April fees 3,009.70 $4,006.35 C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., back fee* 26.10 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., back fee* 35.00 Union Pacific Ry. Co., back fees S5.C2 C B £ Q. Ry. Co., back fees 40.80 137.62 $6,348.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 29 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of April, 1812. DISBURSEMENTS Adams Express 2 3 Western Union Telegraph 6- Automatic Telephone Co., rent 4.0ft Bell Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Bell Telephone Co., tolls 9. IB George Bros, supplies 36.00 C. &amp; N. W. Ry. mileage 280.00 P. W. McDermott, Stenographer, salary 35.00 Roy Armstrong, Stenographer, salary 37.80 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expenses 182.66 J. Scboonover, Deputy, salary and expenses 129.94 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expenses 124.96 U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expenses 140.63 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expenses 127.32 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expenses 139.73 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expenses 112.60 $1,364.33 Paid to W. A. George, State Treasurer 2,779.64 Balance 1,200.00 $5,343.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA r'inan; ial Statement lor me Month of May, 1912. RECEIPTS 4'ash on hand May 1, $1,200.00 Dr. Farmers Oil Co.. May fees 4.40 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., May fees 6.40 St. Joe Oil Co., May fees 6.60 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., May fees 10.30 Red Seal Oil Co., May fees 12.55 Nat'l. Refining Co.. May fees 26.20 Omaha Oil Co., May fees 26.60 Marshall Oil Co., May fees 34.90 State Oil Co., May fee* 41.10 Manhattan Oil Co.. May fees 129.80 Mutual Oil Co., May fees 280.40 Nat 1. Refining Co., Omaha, May fees. . 651.50 Standard Oil Co.. May fees 3,207.80 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 5.00 $4,443.55 C. St. P. M. ft O. Ry. Co., April fees 1.40 Nat 1. Refining Co., April fees 16.20 C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co., April fees 28.50 C. B. A. Q. Ry. Co., April fee* 41.00 C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co., April fee* 54.50 I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., April fees 59.79 201.39 $6,844.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of . May, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Nebraska Typewriter Co., repairs .50 Western L uion Telegraph Co., tolls .65 E. R. Sizer, stamps 10.00 Automatic Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Paynes Printery, supplies 12.50 B. A. George, supplies 36.80 C. &amp; N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 160.00 Roy Armstrong, Stenographer, salary 70.00 F. A. Wlsner, Deputy, salary and expenses 135.79 I'. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expenses 152.23 \V. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expenses 130.20 J. Sohoonover, Deputy, salary and expenses 148.80 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expenses 114.76 S. I. Nies. Deputy, salary and expenses 148.35 Win. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expenses 196.41 $1,320.98 Paid to W. A. George, State Treasurer 3,323.96 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of June, Itl2. RECEIPTS I ish on hand June 1 Dr. $1,200 St. Joe Oil Co., June fees 1.26 St Joe Oil Co., June fees 4.36 Pen. Con. Oil Co., June fees 6.20 Superior Oil Co., June fees 5.20 Superior Oil Co., June fees 5.26 Corn Planter Oil Co., June fees 5.26 St. Joe Oil Co., June fees 6.15 Superior Oil Co., June fees 6.16 Superior Oil Co., June fees 10.60 Jansen Milling Co., June fees 13.90 Cudahy Packing Co., June fees 13.40 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., June fees 14.00 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., June fees 16.20 Blair Gag Co., June fees 26.50 State Oil Co., June fees 39.90 Omaha Oil Co., June fees 64.90 Marshall Oil Co., June fees 126.50 Manhattan Oil Co., June fees 201.20 Mutual Oil Co., June fees 206.10 Nat'l. Refining Co., June fees 655.30 Standard Oil Co., June fees 4,220.30 Union Pacific Ry. Co., April fees 18.75 C. &amp; N. W. Ry. Co., May fees 16.20 Union Pacific Ry. Co., May fees 39.94 C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co., May fees 78.10 $5,694 59 S6 894 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE INSPECTOR OP OIL8 33 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of June, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS American Express Co .80 Sanitary Laundry, towels 3.00 Harry Porter, supplies S.03 C. &amp; N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 200.00 Roy Armstrong, Stenographer, salary 70.00 U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expenses 157.28 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expenses 133.30 J. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expenses 146.05 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expenses 134.70 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expenses 146.70 L. A. Donahoe. Deputy, salary and expenses 113.70 Win. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expenses 197.16 $1,306.72 Paid to W. A. George, State Treasurer 4,387.87 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of July, 1912. RECEIPTS Cash on hand July 1 $1,200.00 Pen. Consumers Co., July fees 2.30 Corn Planters Co., July fees 3.60 Dewitt Light Co., July fees S.60 St. Joe Oil Co., July fees 9.05 James Taylor, July foes 13.20 Farmers lnd. Oil Co., July fees 16.30 Superior Oil Co., July fees 17.65 lnd. Co-op. Oil Co 19.40 Nat. Refining Co., July fees 25.70 Marshall Oil Co., July fees 39.50 Omaha Oil Co.. July fees 59.10 State Oil Co., July fees 105.20 Manhattan Oil Co., July fees 214.80 Mutual Oil Co., July fees 238.80 Nat. Refining Co., July fees 383.70 Standard Oil Co., July fees 4,160.20 $5,307.00 C. R. I. ft P. Ry. Co., June fees Nat. Refining Co., June fees . 12.20 31.50 C. B. ft Q. Ry., June fees 13.00 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., June fees C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co.. June fees . 13.00 14.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Financial Statement (or the Month of July, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Bell Telephone, rent $ 4.00 Auto Telephone, tolls, July 8.10 Auto Telephone, rent, July and August 8.00 George Bros., printing 11.30 Bell Telephone, tolls, May, June, July 52.15 State Journal, printing and supplies 76.50 State Journal, annual reports 162.50 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 280.00 Roy Armstrong, steno., salary 70.00 S. I. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses 166.40 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses 142.80 F. A. Wisner, deputy, salary and expense* 134.82 U. G. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses 152.55 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses 131.40 L. A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses 112.00 Wm. Huaenetter, chief, salary and expenses 187.66 $1,699.68 Paid to W. A. George, state treasurer 3,691.32 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of August, 1912. RECEIPTS Cash on hand August 1st $1,200.00 Superior Oil Co., August fees $ 5.40 St. Joe Oil Co., August fees 5.50 S. M. Bousall, August fees 6.90 Superior Oil Co., August fees 7.70 Superior Oil Co., August fees 9.30 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., August fees .... 12.30 Richey Sand Co., August fees 16.30 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., August fees .... 16.30 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., August fees 21.40 Omaha Oil Co., August fees 32.40 State Oil Co., August fees 61.60 Marshall Oil Co., August fees 122.40 Manhattan Oil Co., August fees 221.50 Mutual Oil Co., August fees 272.60 Nat. Refining Co., August fees 458.60 Standard Oil Co., August fees 5,620.80 6,891.00 C. St. P. M. ft O. Ry., April fees .50 Union Pacific Ry., June fees 42.62 C. St. P. M. ft O. Ry., June and July . .70 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., July fees 21.90 *8.15«.7» </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8 37 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement (or the Month of August, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Western Union Tel $ .30 American Express Co .50 Auto Tel. Co., rent and tolls 5.30 Bell Tel. Co., rent and tolls 9.60 George Bros., printing 15.50 E. R. Sizer, stamps 47.00 Remington Tpr. Co., typewriter 63.15 C. &amp; N. \V. Ry., mileage 200.00 C. B. Speidell, stenographer, salary 70.00 U. O. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses 148.25 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses 159.70 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses 138.40 S. I. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses 149.65 L. A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses 112.05 F. A. Wisner, deputy, salary and expenses 133.20 Wm. Husenetter, chief, salary and expenses 197.16 $1,449.76 Paid to W. A. George, state treasurer 5,506.96 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ANNTAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of September, 1912. RECEIPTS Cash on hand September 1st $1,200.00 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., September fees . ..| 1.95 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., September fees . . 6.30 Superior Oil Co.. September fees 6.90 Superior Oil Co., September fees 7.34 St. Joe Oil Co., September fees 7.00 Blair Gas Company, September fees . . 34.30 Omaha Oil Company, September fees . 46.10 Manhattan Oil Co., September fees . . 145.50 Marshall Oil Co., September fees 159.20 Mutual Oil Company, September fees. 287.00 National Refining Co., September fees 368.70 Standard Oil Co.. September fees .... 5,004.26 6,074.35 Nat'l Refining Co., August fees 24.30 C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., August fees 32,20 C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., July fees 38.70 Union Pacific Ry. Co., July fees 48. 8« 144 06 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8 39 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Financial Statement (or the Month of September, 1912 DISBURSEMENTS Adams Express Co $ .42 Auto. Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Bell Telephone Co., rent and tolls 7.35 Office assistance 10.40 Tagliabue Mfg. Co., hydros 26.82 C. B. Speidell, stenographer, salary 70.00 Win. Husenetter, chief, salary and expenses 191.86 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses 142.50 L. A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses 114.46 S. I. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses 146.10 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses 129.55 D. G. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses 141.70 F. A. Wisner. deputy, salary and expenses 129.42 C. &amp; N. W. Ry., mileage 320.00 .$1,434.37 Paid to W. A. George, state treasurer 4,784.04 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">ANNUAL REPORT 40 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of October, 1912. RECEIPTS Cash on hand October 1st $1,200.00 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., October fees $ 1.80 St. Joseph Oil Co., October fees 2.70 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., October fees .... 2.25 Superior Oil Co., October fees 3.45 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., October fees 4.90 Superior Oil Co., October fees 4.95 St. Joseph Oil Co., October fees 6.10 Superior Oil Co., October fees 5.40 St. Joseph Oil Co., October fees 7.20 Beatrice Oil Co., October fees 7.20 Jansen Milling Co, October fees . . . : 12.20 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., October fees . . . 12.30 James Taylor, October fees 13.50 Peoples Oil Co., October fees 26.70 Omaha Oil Co., October fees 46.30 Marshall Oil Co., October fees 68.50 Bute Oil Co., October fees 139.70 Manhattan Oil Co., October fees 175.40 Mutual Oil Co.. October fees 218.90 Nat. Refining Co., October fees 280.20 Standard Oil Co., October fees 3,887.10 4,926.75 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., August fees 6.30 Union Pacific Ry., August fees 57.23 Missouri Pacific Ry., September fees . 6.45 Union Pacific Ry., September fees .... 27.27 C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co., September fees . . . 57.80 166 05 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">STATE INSPECTOR OP OILS 41 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, Financial Statement for the Month of October, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Western Union Tel. Co $ .29 Harry Porter, supplies 1.50 Adams Express Co 1.35 Auto. Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Western Trunk Line, circulars 7.70 E. R. Sizer, stamps 10.00 George Bros., printing 16.05 Bell Telephone Co., rent and tolls 12.40 C. tc N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 200.00 C. B. Speidell, steno., salary 70.00 U. G. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses 145.76 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses 130.35 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses 153.50 F. A. Wisner. deputy, salary and expenses 137.63 8. I. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses 147.10 L. A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses 115.01 Win. Husenetter, chief, salary and expenses 200.41 $1,353.04 Paid to W. A. George, state treasurer 3,728.76 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of November, 1912. RECEIPTS. Cash on hand November 1st $1,200.00 Dr. lnd. Co-op. Oil Co., November fees . . . .f 2.70 S. P. Doyle Company, November fees . 2.40 St. Joseph Oil Co., November fees .... 5.80 Corn Planter Co., November fees .... 5.55 St. Joseph Oil Co.. November fees .... 7.50 Farmers lnd. Oil Co.. November fees . it.M Farmers lnd. Oil Co.. November fees . 12.40 Meridian Oil Co., November fees 13.00 Rlchey Sand Company. November fees. 16.30 Jansen Milling Co.. November fees . . . lfi.20 Blair Gas Company, November fees . . . 2«.2n State Oil Company, November fees . . . 48.30 Marshall Oil Co .. November fees 86.40 Manhattan Oil Co.. November fees .... 97.10 Mutual Oil Company, November fees . . 257.60 National Refining Co.. November fees. . 492.80 Standard Oil Company. November fees. 3,652.80 4,753.26 C. B. &amp; Q. Ry Co., October fees 8.40 C. B. * Q. Ry. Co.. October fees 12.20 C. B. « Q. Ry. Co., October fe«« 20.20 C. St. P. M. &amp; O. Ry.. August fees .... .30 C. St. P. M. &amp; O. Ry., September fees . . .40 State Oil Co., one hydrometer 2.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 OFFICE OF THE STA1 E INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of November, 1912. DISBURSEMENTS Adams Express Co $ .23 Auto. Telephone Co., rent 4.00 Bell Telephone Co., rent and tolls 15.10 C. £ N. W. Ry. Co.. mileage 280.00 C. B. speidell, steno.. salary 70.00 U. G. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses 141.50 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses 133.20 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses 142.50 F. A. Wisner, deputy, salary and expenses 128.10 L. A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses 114.20 S. I. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses 131.90 Wm. Husenetter, chief, salary and expenses 203.71 Paid to W. A. George, state treasurer 3,432.81 Balance 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of December, 1912 RECEIPTS. Cash on hand December 1, 1912 $1,200.00 S. P. Doyle Co., December fees S 3.00 St. Joe Oil Co., December fees 6.30 Missouri Pacific Ry., November fees . . 5.26 Rock Island Ry. Co., November fees . . 13.00 National Refining Co., October fees . . 20.60 C. B. ft Q. Ry. Co., November fees ... 12.20 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., November fees . . 49.10 Peoples Oil Co., December fees 16.30 Farmers Ind. Oil Co., December fees . . 16.30 Marshall Oil Co., December fees 61.70 State Oil Co., December fees 64.70 Omaha Oil Co., December fees 32.20 Meridian Oil Co.. December fees 32.20 Manhattan Oil Co., December fees .... 175.60 Mutual Oil Co., December fees 209.60 National Refining Co.. December fees. 513.80 Standard Oil Co., December fees 3,676.70 National Refining Co., copy of Decem - ber report 5.00 Standard Oil Co., copy of December re- port 5.00 4,918.56 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA Financial Statement for the Month of December, 1911. DISBURSEMENTS Western Union Tel., messages % .95 AdaniB Express Co., express 1.18 Sanitary Laundry, towels 3.00 George Bros., printing 4. 00 Auto. Tel. Co., rent 4.00 E. R. Sizer, stamps 20.00 Postal Tel. Co., message .49 Office assistance 8.40 C. * N. W. Ry., mileage 200.00 U. G. Etherton, deputy, salary and expenses, Dec.. . 137.60 W. S. Jay, deputy, salary and expenses, December. . 126.35 J. Schoonover, deputy, salary and expenses, Dec.. . 125.35 II. Nies, deputy, salary and expenses, December. . 141.10 A. Donahoe, deputy, salary and expenses, Dec. . 112.65 A. Wisner, deputy, salary and expenses, Dec.. . . 124.88 Wm. Husenetter, chief, salary and expenses, Dec.. . 202.22 C. B. Speidell, steno., salary. December 70.00 $1,282.17 Paid to W. A. George, treasurer 3,636.38 Balance 1.J00.0O </seg>
            <seg id="p046">;isnooomb &lt;y. icoct-cjoox I 1 *— lO 3 •— 2 i I 8 "* b- 00 rH O M « 2» Jiicuscc^u: a t i£ * a w t- -r u: EJE,coaekOt~to^ao I I aaxenen I I a 9 lit - a S ■ •O ■ XI Ei (S oS •&lt; . e* o w s&gt; — -we* &gt;t~30t-t-O&gt;»00 2««&lt;e»gtieo , « e « c - e x ■►'ooio.-i^t-t-m Uxri«t-XKC ■ «-H CO l£ IO i-l ■» Oft ■Sec N««ae&lt;« ■ r* o « fH oe to ip »tO W OU3M t* : &lt;«.:»cnoa «~© Me«nial 4, HNUNNSM = — ONt-0&gt;00 .^ »7. ■&lt;&gt;i~ooxaot0 ~ r o~e voncio — -rr?. xnoon £ J«_NiPfc </seg>
            <seg id="p047">I booooooooooiooioooo lO^teNX^MWt-OiONt-HNX O^NAeAHAX«OHNOO«N gooohownoon ih&lt;n CO *O OJ iH iM pj i lfi^!CN00*M»t-Ot-N»HNQ0 oooor-o^weo^eoN ca JvnAHioVNMV • • ■ ■* tc • • tt&gt;HOet-(Dne)H • • • «-h ■ ■ ■lieuiN h p&lt; . . . . . w ..... I I ■ oo « « * h w •ifit-Hioeaott • • &gt; r- r- t- &lt;o t- oo • oo oo oa oo eo o n - - O * ae i. 1 : « a&gt; ♦ • eg ao rH t-i • • : rt : : I jNioaoooiCAWor* • - • e* cm o» • 5 00 N M *4 w4 ,-,... eo .... - i to » u * -rai ■ ■ . «4 ■ £»«*)-« . «■ • . ■ .&lt;ts«Tuis«no«« -taceo ■ 3 i-i io r- so m ■♦ n eq 10 ■ nn ■ « &lt;■ n -&lt; m , u» • ■ __» ; _jj :ii-3CiaMNMt-ao« - • 00 00 &lt;* • M g*t-W»HO(»WON • • i-« w - A i^ - ?J Ni — • • » «~eo~^H 4O n"« aooeo - e* us e* • 3 &amp;iaov«Ha«non ■ =m t- e© co * fl *-9 C^ IO Pi i-l C*J • e 11 8Olfl«MN*N«i)6H • • i-H - - ; C* W C* iH • • ■ • * •__. -__^ 5 Jt-^NN oToO &lt;© © © 0* ~ * O to ' ~ "5 U^'A^t't-tON^HO • • t- O - ■ X a3»lfi^X*MNt-N • • •*• • ■ X I *"^i&lt;©«t-aO • -(OMifl - -00«O • ■ ® 00 Oft M (© CO - -«hm • • • ■ A«eon&lt;-i ■• — •• • • ( gj - . • . . . . m t- oo • to c* «d - '■* os "^ • »i" C&lt;-)-^ao ■ ao as ac • o« • 'toe* ■ r- itf ao«M • ■*■ — ■ r- ■ • — • Inhh • • • ■ ■ J3 ■••••••• • • q • « ■ M»*«105M«t-» • • to US ■• •n»h»1-mh»OH • • N -.1 e* ... I </seg>
            <seg id="p048">o ■* « ih •* ia rtnao n h « » «e rtt.«ri«&lt;e««H«Ou«NOt-ONCNM «ecnri«ioan»u:«MH««nt-«ioo i-t »-!•*• U3 1H 00 CO rH « -OOTM iMiyiUlHililii! 83 ! .......... .t- M ...... .«O« o : : : : : :S : :"S :S : : : : : M 2S Q 5 a sf a o o S °T • •« « « • t . .«• . .* ■• •a m o t- t- « • -oo : «0 IN KMICt- • • « a •-■ »h .-i t« • • &lt;e 5_: ::::::::::: : :S &lt;::::::.:::: :~ :::::: is 03 &lt; ft 6 * « ♦ • 10 ic &gt;.« m-« 40 a- ••••;••• ; « t LL _L^.'-J_L : ::::::: LS • O&gt; • • IB &gt;O M |::::::5::*j::::::::;j * * * * • * * * * ■• 0- O "•••■»•• rH ...... &amp;•••••»•••»« 5 z as o |::::s:: s :: ::::::: :::s r&lt; : : : : : : ::::::::::: :5 ,•«•■■ ■•• •» Jj « • • • • •« &lt;e 23 imjFJijjiim-nmi | = §£ . « t- ♦rt . • ■ m ci-»eei ■■■■■» f!*ilijiliilll!liiii 3 00 :::::::::: :5 ::::::::: «j : 'dg^ '-6% • ; :3 : 6« : : : : ' 5 § m £ &gt;.« 5 !| if-o E -2 &amp; -&lt; _• *x I - p-' •= 1 </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>