<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 31st Session Nebraska Legislature 1909</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">V ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE 31st Session Nebraska Legislature 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">first session of the Nebraska legislature : I congratulate you up - on being called to serve in your legislative capacity at a time when the state is enjoying general prosperity. Nature has been kind and her yield bountiful. Our people are industrious and the demand and prices for their products satisfactory. Our population is not dense, probably less than one and one - half millions dwell within our borders. A study of the records of our bureau of statistics will show how marvelous have been the achievements of these later years. So rich our soil, so matchless our climate, so wonderful the industry of our people that here upon Nebraska's fertile prairies, American civiliza - tion in its highest development piles up each year a larger surplus of useful products than a like number of people can produce upon any other spot on earth. With a clearness of vision and understanding as to the purposes and possibilities of legislative enactment, a steadfast and successful people will not expect of you impossible things or unreasonable laws. Having wrung year after year, great riches from a generous soil, they now know that they can com - pd prosperity to abide with them always. They will, however, expect of the party, whose members now control this senate and the house, the specific legislation pledged in the platform upon which you were elected. To stamp those promises upon the statute books of our state as written law, should be the purpose, the constant purpose and 1 . the accomplished purpose of this legisla - ture. Mandate of the People. I wish to impress upon both houses the strength and direct - ness with which this mandate for certain legislation comes from the people. After a long period of continued and complete control of state affairs by one party, the citizenship of this com - monwealth has placed another political organization in power in the legislative and executive branches of our government. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 in this change. It is rather a triumph of ideas; a verdict in favor of better laws, a condemnation of certain unsatisfactory methods, a demand for amendments to legislation already enact - ed and against which the | &gt;mplain. The basis for this opinion lies in the significant fact that while the executive branch of the party placed in power received a very modest plurality the legislative majority of the same party is overwhelming. The electorate of Xebraska is certainly as intelligent and independent as that of any other state in the republic. They know that the executive can but enfora edicts, the legislature must make the laws. Understanding this they gave emphatic endorsement to the law-making de - partment of the party now responsible with power. The party whose platform promised the legislation which I shall urge and the people gave their approval with a force that can neither be misunderstood or denied. ■vernor Sheldon has detailed to you the result of his ad - ministration of state affairs, and you have listened to his rec - ommendation. I urge that you give earnest and careful con - sideration to all that he has said. I shall not go further into a discussion as to the needs of the different state institutions and deparments. but refer you to the reports and recommenda - ions made to the governor by the sujierintendents and heads of departments for your information and guidai 1 shall briefly call your attention to legislation, the prospect and hope of which, in my opinion, has brought about this change in the control of the executive and legislative depart - ments of state government. It is first to be noted that no new or radical legislation is asked for. Ew] ion is but to amend, correct, or improve some existing law. As a general rule, we already have too many laws encum - bering our statute books. Many are good, some imperfect, a few bad. The good should be let alone, the imperfections </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 an honest and fearless enforcement of the laws that we now have, rather than a constant cry for new laws, and new laws as an excuse for inaction and delay. While upon this subject I would raeommend the appointment of a qualified commission to revise and improve our present code of laws, so that justice may be more easily and rapidly obtained in our courts. That this is sorely needed is a point upon which all of our best legal authorities agree, and I recommend it to your careful consider- tThe matters to which I wish to call your especial attention not numerous, but I believe them to be important. I shall present them to you under separate heads. Suggestions as to Improvements in Our Banking Laws. I Andrew Carnegie has said, "America has the worst bank - ; system in the world." I scarcely think the facts warrant h a statement, but will venture the opinion that we have not -I em that it is possible for us to obtain and nothing : the best should be good enough for the people of Nebraska, r present law is very much in advance in all that pertains safe and proper banking to the law which preceded it. No ; will venture to maintain that the one now in force is perfect, srefore, we are warranted in asking for still further improve - nt. The primary purpose for the establishment of banks far as the public is concerned, is first that the people shall ve a safe place to deposit their money, and second that those o need it may conveniently obtain funds upon proper secur - after the money shall have been gathered together by the iking corporation. I The ideal system of banking will guarantee to depositors absolute certainty of the return of every dollar deposited, this will insure the greatest possible volume of loanable ds in banks for the needs of business. The state and nation </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 security of the depositor since they permit and authorize the receiving of deposits under the sanction of a charter granted by the state. Recognizing this implied obligation the state has aln provided in many ways by useful laws for the insurance and guaranty of the funds of dej who place their money in banks operating under its laws. From time to time, these guaranties have been increased until losses to d« are rare indeed. The report of the comptroller of the currency for 11*08 shows that a tax of one twenty-sixth of one percent levied upon the deposits in national banks during the forty-fh that that system has been in nee would have raised a sufficient sum m that no p. who had trusted his money to a national bank, would Inr a cent. A study of the figures of our own state banking depart - ment shows even a more satisfactory condition. Only during the last eight yea' he law provided for a complete n from receivers of failed banks. During this period a tax of ban one-thirtieth of one percent levied upon the deposits in our state banks would have raised a sum sufficient to have insured even, r against any possible loss. With these facts before us, T do not hesitate to say that :t reflection upon our American civilization and bu - ds to longer fail to provide an insurance guaranty fund and banking law, which will make every dollar deposited in a Nebraska bank, absolutely sure of being returned to its lawful owner, upon demand. Certain deposits are now secured in 6tate and national banks by safeguards in addition to the guar - anties which the law exacts of the banker to protect his indi - vidual depositor. The county, the state and the nation having found by experience that the securities which the law provides for the ordinary depositor are at times insufficient and there- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 There can be no rule of business ethics which ate and the nation and den to whether or not additional guaranty fund can be I with the , unfair burden and res itv upon the I 1 bat the desir rity can be obtained by ]. light tax upon the capital stock of each bank trans, - bnainen under our laws, thus providing a guaranty fund to pay • -t I v any possible 1&lt; ; &lt;&gt;r by reason of the failure of a state bank. The amount of such tax to be a certain rs as shown by the reports of the : banking and payment to be n: -tated pe - and for a fixed amount. The volume &lt;&gt;f money supposed to be in circulation in the United States on October 1, 1908, according to the latest report of the national banking department, was $3,378,800,000. Less than one half of this enormous sum is accounted for by report - er i ing banks of every description or as on deposit in the national rv. Xot Dae tenth of that portion which u unaccounted - serving any useful purpose in the economy of modern Methods. If one-half of it were returned to the banks, it would enormously expand the business and wealth of the state and nation and raise the banking power of the United - until it would exceed that of the rest of the civilized world. Tobringthis great idle fund into active channels of trade, is the problem for the bankers and legislators to solve. If loss of bank deposits is made a thing of the past, I believe a great step in this direction will have been accomplished. The reports of the comptroller of the currency and of on to the individual depositor. Tin thai it will pro? ihe dep </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 show that the cost of an adequate insurance fund would be a -mall cli of the bank al of 409 national banks hi' it during the forty-five that the national system has l&gt;een it banks $17 71. in iaims have been all Four hundred nal banks have been liqui - and th&lt; ,. Therehaslx'en$1^2,lS-2.3in, collected from the assets and stockholders liability of failed institutions, or more than 100 per cent of depositors' claims. The ex]&gt;enses of liquidations and the payment of claims, other than those of depositors has reduced the amount collected until only about 75 per cent of the amount due d trs has actually been returned to them. In later years ui * ter conditions this percentage of loss has been greatly red Four: 1 banks insolvent during 1908 have been liqi &gt;t their deposits have been returned to their creditors. department of banking has a complete re for tl. It of receiversl.! banks. TL \vs that since 1900 I r of $515,264.24 hai been placed in jeopardy by rea - the failure of state banks. From th&lt; of these ins titutioi aims have been liquidated until the e unpaid for the entire period of eigb.1 3 or an aver t ■boot $86,000 to depot Creditable as this rtain that with a number of impr&lt; which can be made in our pt law, the percentage of loss can still be materially reduced. The minimum capital required for the incorporation of a bank should be increased to at least $15,000. Bank examina - should be made twice a year instead of once as now re - quired. Examiners should be assigned to a certain territory and thus eventually would become familiar with conditions and se - curities in that locality and would acquire the necessary 1: </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 would examine, which is the essential thi ining solvency of any banking corporation. Under a guaranty plan which would make the hanks The possibilities of profit to be made in taking other &lt; money on deposit, loaning if to the public and keepii luring that at I le numb re rapidly than the t busineei with consequent overloaning, hazardous r lding and ex It that in lean years fail' ean be in a great measure overcome 1 require: •ccur and inno &gt;ple suffer. The over-issuance of ch:: an the losses of the -houhl »■ share in the control of the department. The pi kiii£ board, which 1 of three office an entirely different purpose, should 1 and a in lx)ar&lt;] established to be eon by the governor if its members to have 1: i banking and at lea- of them to be actively engaged in that business at the tir appointment. A bank • ioner should Ik? app' by thf irovernor with the approval of the banking board, who I ba&lt;l an experience in ti ■ that required b '" the board, Bd of the boa* be bank' n at Linocln at stated periods and 1m - 'ministration of the bank- I by critics of the 2fuar;r plan that it would lead to the i . This would 1 lie re- Id gre;r ur bank if the banking boanl m iwered t bank charti </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 me. The ainount required in each i; Id bear a proper proportion to the popula - wn or city in which the bank is to be establ As an example, ihowing the manner in which requirenu •■ to capital affect the number of bank charters issued, 3,042 na - banks i .zed since 1900 when the require - - redaesd to $2."&gt;,000 as the minimum. Thi.- nks than the entire number in When the law was changed in this respect. The reduction of the minimum capital stock requirement to $85,000 has doubled the numlier of national banks in eight A substantial in - crease in the amount required as a minimum capital for the establishment of state banks would have a salutary eff - he number of banks within a satisfactory limit and also provide g t-curity to the depositor. Tt 1 that in the state of Oklahoma the guar - ds law has led to the issuance of an excess of bank charters and the establishment of too many banks with the minimum of capital. I have examined the last report of the comptroller of the currency a3 to the organization of national banks in that state to ascertain if there might not be general causes which have led to a rapid increase in the issuance of bank charters in Oklahoma, such as are incident to the settlement and development of a new state, and having no relation to this guaranty law. I find by way of comparison that whereas since there have been 85 national banks chartered in Xebraska, 84 in Kansas, 43 in Colorado, 24 in Washington and 26 in •n, in Oklahoma during the same time there have been established 312 national banks, 253 of which have the smallest capital which the law permits. I to the amount of assessment to be levied in order to pro - vide an adequate fund for the prompt payment of depositors of insolvent banks, I would suggest that one-fourth of one per cent be levied upon the deposits as shown at the last statement </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 law and this to l&gt;e followed with additional levies in like amount at periods of six, twelve and eighteen m thereafter. After the accumulation of a guaranty fund i to 1 per cent of the aver. in the guaranteed banks, an annual tax of one-tenth of one per cent should be k under a proper system of insurant -hould pile up a surplus fund to pr for the inevitable demands of less fortunate ti Ys an additional security against any possjh], oh as rdinary demands upon the fund the board should be ed to levy m I per cent of the average deposits in any one year. While this asses - might never be levied, the power to DM it would have a su - in times of possible panics. Such provisii in aocnmulating in eighteen months with the i ining in state banks as at pi guaranty fund 51. This would be $127,097 more than the entire if deposits involved in the bank failures in thi - in the last nil It is three times the amount that • been necessary to have paid upon demand all the : -itors in failed banks during the year with the he; failures of any in the pact decade. 1 n times as much i i Id have been required to pay immediately all of the ied up in state hanks daring any one of the last . With the additional amount that would be eontri h a guaranty fund during the years when no failures &lt; oeeur and added to this the power to raise in any one year by ordinary much as has been placed in jeopardy during the worst year that we have experi aw was established. It is my judgment that such i ild Ik' a rook of refuge for the banks and for ■ in the fiercest financial storm that may come, comparisons you will observe, are based upon the experience ■peil under our present law. With the additional safe- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 upon a guaranty fund should be still lighter. Indeed your first purpose should be to so surround the banking business with safeguards and practical regulations as to make our r the safest and best in the republic aside from any sustaining force of a guaranty fund, and thus you will make the demands upon your guarai. m so light that it cannot fail. At this time, I want to congratulate and commend the management of our present banking department for the splendid results it has secured under the present law. It is the showing of exceedingly small losses sustained under our present management and sys - tem which gives us confidence to believe that with improve - ments in our laws as to capitalization, management and control a still better showing can be accomplished. The proposed guar - anty fund under such a system as has been suggested should be deposited with the state banks under regulations similar to our present state depository law or with such additional security as the legislature may require. The proposed law should pro - vide that national banks may avail themselves of the advantage and protection of the guaranty fund under suitable provisions and satisfactory showing as to the condition of such banks to the banking board. The banking board should be empowered to fix the rate of interest to be paid depositors by banking corporations oper - ating under the guaranty of deposits law, or if this be thought too great a power to confer upon them, the rate should be fixed in the statute by the legislature. I have gone into the matter of these proposed changes in our banking law somewhat fully, because the legislation asked for is new in part and therefore has met with some opposition. As a last word upon this subject, I want to impose upon you to the utmost the responsibility placed upon you in dealing with this question, and to urge you to remember that in whatever you may do you must be fair alike to the banker and the depositor, and the law enacted must stand the severest tests of business experience. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Our present revenue law should be amended in so far i necessary to restore to the ]&gt;eople the right to elect the pi' •aaeesors and to limit in part, at least, the arbitrary powers which the present law givet to the state board of equals and assessment, so that the people shall haw ■one voice in determining the amount of taxes they shall be rapport the state government Tt aj great a gift of power to give to the state and county l"&gt;ard the right to determine the amount of the levy which shall •I upon the proj&gt;erty of the citizens and at the same the state board to determine through its mandates to the county i and his deputies the valuation that shall l&gt;e placed upon the property of the taxpayers. When w&gt; bat the member! of this all-]M&gt;werful board of MeeM _ in their official capacity as the heads of different are authorized to spend the money taken from the ■ pie by the force of this same revenue law, the r lurking in thi- of power becomes more apparent. 8 remarked that different state departments have mended the present law because it provides much mont their use. li rally to be noted that those who pay out \ which others must pay in, view the magnitude of the amount to be expended with greater equanimity than those who have to provide it. The cost of our state government hf ■ 1 enormously in recent years. I wish to impress up&lt;&gt;: that funds should be provided to meet every legitimate demand of the government, our different state institutions and our schools, but every dollar that comes out of the treasury must l»een paid in by some taxpayer and the great bulk of the - income is dug out of the soil by the unremitting labor &gt;se who can ill-afford to pay for extravagance or unneoes - t-ary expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 The railroad commission should be authorized and em - powered to appraise the physical value of the public service corporations of the state, and to control their debt-making power. If they have that power now, as some maintain, the legislature should provide the means with which to pay the cost of such t appraisement. A determination of the actual value of the perty of these corjiorations must be the starting point of fTective attempt at rate regulation. I believe that adequate funds can be provided for this purpose by requiring all corpor - ations doing business within the state, to pay a small annual license fee into the state treasury. The right to incorporate and operate under our laws is a valuable consideration and the power and protection given entitles the state to a proper report as to the conditions of such corporations together with a fee commensurate with the privileges granted. Such a law in other states brings a sufficient revenue to warrant its enactment fthis legislature and the devotion of so much of the fund provided to the purpose of obtaining a proper appraisement public service corporations, would be entirely proper, because any event corporations should be required to pay for the ex - pense of examination and valuation just as a bank or insurance company is now required to do. Home Rule for Both Omahas LThe cities of Omaha and South Omaha should be given plete local self-government under charters satisfactory to them and to you. First, because it is un-American to deny them the right to rule and govern themselves in all matters pertaining to municipal affairs. Second, it is to the best interests of their citizenship that they should have placed upon themselves the responsibility of the proper conduct and admin - istration of their own affairs. It is inconceivable that these two metropolitan cities, whose progress and development, is the pride of the state, are the only communities within our common- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 wealth that must be ruled in some of their principal depart - ments of municipal government by an absentee overlord. I am satisfied that you will carry out the will of the people of two great cities as expressed through their representativ this legislature. Our present primary law is unsatisfactory and unfair in many of its provisions. The expense to the state in holding a state wide primary is enormous, and unless the election re - sults in registering the will of the party majority of those voting and placing better candidates before the people than the con - vention method, the benefits of the law cannot be sai&lt;l to warrant its cost. Under the present law, the accidental alpha - betical position of the candidates named upon the ballot, times more potent in obtaining nominations than merit or abil - ity. The number of names required upon the petition of a candidate for a state office, is grossly insufficient. The cost of elections both to the candidates and the state is greatly in - creased. It is doubtful if the average elector will ever have the required acquaintance with the long list of candidates for the different offices upon the ballot in a state wide primary to insure intelligent selection. I would suggest to you a county primary to nominate county officers and delegates to a convention. The state convention to select two or more names for each office to go upon the primary ballot and to make the party platform, which ought to be issued in advance of the primary, instead of. subsequent to it, as at present. The plan of the present law for organizing the party machinery, is not particularly calculated to produce good results nor is it fair in its provisions to the different counties. In the last analysis, no law can be considered satisfactory unless it accomplishes the things which it was framed to do, and I cannot believe the present primary law has public approval judged by this standard. It should either be amended materially in its pro - visions or repealed. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 I would suggest that the constitution be so amended that u non-partisan board of control could be created to be appointed by the governor and have conferred upon it the entire manage - of our various state institutions. The state institutions -houl.l be removed from politics as far as may be done and merit alone should determine the right of any person to serve ate in the different departments made subject to the board :itrol. This board, in my opinion, should consist of three •era and have at its command the state accountant and a qualified purchasing or business agent, who should have a al knowledge as to machinery, material and construction contracts and of all matters of business coming before the lx»ard. »This board of control should purchase all supplies for all ' state institutions by open competition among those desiring sell to the state. The practice of maintaining a cash fund at irious state institutions should be abolished and the busi - ness of the state so far as it applies to the general conduct tl administration of the different state institutions should be lematized. For the first time in a number of tlie state institutions and departments for which the gov - ernor appoints the officers and employes have passed into the luui'l- of an executive of another party than that of a number t preceding executives, who have been responsible for them, making what changes I contemplate, I have urged upon those, whom I have self "tain salient things. First, that they shall accept their ]&gt;ositions with the understanding that they hold them only upon the condition that they render to the satisfactory service. That no salaries are to be increased, nor new offices created, unless authorized by the legislature, uploy no one not actually needed and to exact full time, cheerful and effective service from every person in the employ - ment of the state. The clerk of the supreme court and all other officers of the state and county governments who now receive </seg>
            <seg id="p019">npoa a i and all fees and m nl Kv them should be converted into the county treasury. TL. harped in every instance ■houM ifficient, m that no Ion would l&gt;o sustained by the Btate or county by reason a£ litigation upon the part uf private parties. I would rhat a proper ap - propriation Ik? made to n the worthy and patriotic purpose of erecting a suitable monument in this city to the memory of the martyred president, Abraham Lincoln. Both the time and the place seem especially appropriate, as the one is the coiitciinary of his birth, and the other boars his honored name. In tlie matter of appropriations, I urge you to proceed with cau - tion and to act upon your very beat judgment. The exj of tlie state must be kept within its income. Those responsible to you for estimates of expenditures for the biennium for which you must provide tlie necessary funds, ask for more money than the cx]&gt;e&lt;-tod total income of the Do not forget that the men, who have sent you here, have to pay the bills of expense and expenditures, which you shall allow. lie generous to our schools, but not extravagant. Large appropriate iiicre; arely if ever, bring better service. There are doubtless other matters which this legislature can take up with lienetit and profit to the people who have sent you here, but I fed confident that if yon provide satisfactory !■ relating to the question to which I have referred, you &lt;■. home with the certainty that you will tin istied &lt;•■ ueiicy. With a firm reliance upon the wisdom and ju&lt;L of this legislature and a hope that with your assistance may together in some fair measure fulfill the hopes and meet the expectations* of the citizens uf Nebraska, who have tr us with power, I submit these qt gentleon the b </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>