<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Rural Clubs for Women</title>
               <date value="1915-12-15">1915-12-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 3«. BULLETIN OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE. RURAL CLUBS FOR WOMEN. By Emma Reed Davisson. Distributed December 15, 1915 UTH ASHLAND COUNTRY WOMEN'S CLUB LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purposes of the Cooperative Agricul - tural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8, 1914. University of Nebraska Agricultural Extension Service and the United States Department of Agriculture, Cooperating. C. W. PUGSLEY, Director of Extension Service. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE. THE EXTENSION SERVICE. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the regents HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, President, Valley HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey. HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Dean, College of Agriculture; Director, E Station. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF C. W. PUGSLBY, B. Sc., Director. A. E. Anderson, A. B., Farm Demonstration Work. Maud Mathes Wilson, B. Sc., Home Economics. HULDAR PETERSON, Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Emma Reed Davisson, Women's Clubs. Frank C. Dean, A. B., Agricultural Editor THE EXTENSION COUNCIL (HMDS OF OCMHTKiait.) E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. UPSON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandben, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomology. T. A. KIES8ELBACH, A. M., Experimental Agronomy H. C. Filley, A. M., Farm Management. ALICE M. Looms, A. M., Home Economics. R. F. HOWARD, A. M., Horticulture. 'P. B. Barker, A. M., Instructional Agronomy. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. H. E. Bradford, A. B., Principal, School of Agriculture ■Resigned </seg>
            <seg id="p003">RURAL CLUBS FOR WOMEN. By Emma Reed Davisson. "Not what we give, but what we share, For the gift without the giver is bare; Who gives himself with his alms feeds three, - Himself, his hungering neighbor, and Me." Jambs Russell Lowell. This bulletin is addressed to the many women living on Ne - braska farms who are interested in the social and economic advancement of their homes and communities. The object is to explain how to organize and conduct a home economics club and to suggest club activities and opportunities for home and community work. Dotted here and there over the broad prairies of Nebraska where just a few years ago the first sturdy settlers came, we find many homes. Most of the sod houses have been replaced by substantial modern dwellings. But these monuments of years of labor and hardship are no dearer to the dwellers than the first homes, where together the families bravely met the bitter storms of winter and the hot destroying winds of summer, each season in its turn bringing hard conditions to face. The women in these homes not only bravely did their part of the actual work, but gave to the world sturdy sons and daughters. With the successful conquering of the hard early surroundings has come a keen insight into economic conditions. The woman on the farm looks to the future when the work in her home can be carried on by means of labor-saving devices, run by artificial power just as in a city dwelling, when her kitchen will be built and equipped to meet her demands in the saving of time and labor just as is her sister's who dwells in the most modern apartment in the city. There also has come a desire for a better understanding of all household problems, because she realizes that by sane living the health of her family can be greatly controlled. She realizes that she must understand the composition of foods and their uses by the body and be able to balance a meal, in order to furnish proper food for the growing child as well as the adult. In this era of high prices it is neces - sary for every woman to be able to detect the adulteration in tex - tiles, and to depend on her own knowledge when selecting cotton, linen, wool, or silk. It is the desire of the housewife, because of </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin J6, College of Agriculture. expending so large a percentage of her husband's income, to understand how to carry on wisely the duties of her household. These and many other perplexing problems are confronting her. Very few women have had the opportunity to study home economics and perhaps would not enter school now if they could. But by means of clubs for women they are obtaining this knowl - edge they so much desire, and while so doing are learning to know their neighbors. The club spirit- the spirit of real help - fulness — may be seen more plainly in the rural club than in any other. In the thinly settled districts, the club is often the center of the community life. The social side is emphasized, and this is as it should be. The club members plan for entertainments, social diversions of many kinds, and to all come the husbands, families, and neighbors. Young people need amusement in every rural community, and they will have it at any cost. See that it ■ of the right kind. Help them to plan it and let the children of the club realize that it is their club too. SOME SUCCESSFUL RURAL CLUBS Women used to think that because they lived on farms it was impossible for them to take part in anything outside of their homes. This is a mistaken idea. Many of the rural clubs in Xebraska have proved by their acts that there are many helpful Fig. 1.— The Simeon Club. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Rural Clubs for Women. 5 things for farm women to do. Only a few of the many rural clubs doing splendid work are mentioned here. The Simeon Club in Cherry County, for instance, is the center of a remarkable community life. Simeon is more than twenty miles from a railroad. The organization of the club was sug - gested by the husband of one of its members. The men met at round-ups and dehornings and in this way learned to know each other. The women had no way of meeting and were very lonely. The club is unique in its organization, having no officers, con - stitution, nor dues. Any woman in the community is eligible to membership by simply promising to be neighborly. This promise has been kept by all and as a result has come a community life that is almost ideal in many respects. They meet for an all - day session, and the time is spent in sewing or in otherwise assist - ing the hostess. Their programs have been quite varied, but are always well planned and executed. The South Ashland Country Women's Club is one of the older clubs in the State, having recently issued its tenth annual announcement. These women have been very helpful to their community in many different ways. Perhaps the most lasting thing accomplished by them is the splendid library of several hundred volumes purchased and owned by them. Their program work has been very good, much time having been given to the study of home problems. FIG. 2. -Pleasant Hour Club, Minatare. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin 36, College of Agriculture. The Pleasant Hour Club is a rural club, the members living in the vicinity of Minatare. This club holds its meetings in the afternoon. The work done has been exceptionally good. The programs are carefully planned a year in advance, the year - book being unusually attractive. The members have added much to the social life of the community by their entertainments and picnics. Thru their efforts, a pleasant rest room has been established in Minatare, where all women and children are welcome when in town. Near Ansley are five rural clubs "The Farm Kensington". "Needle Craft Club", "Sewing Circle", "Busy Bees", and "Algernon Club". Each club has in its own way been doing excellent work for the home and community. The clubs have all been studying home economics — have all assisted in promot - ing the social life of their respective neighborhoods and have taken a keen interest in all community problems. One of them, altho its membership represents many religious beliefs, assisted in obtaining a minister for Sunday services. Realizing that they can be very helpful to each other by keeping in close touch, a general organization of the five clubs has been perfected so that meetings may be held where topics of mutual interest will be discussed. They are planning to meet twice each year, the winter meeting to be held in Ansley and the summer meeting in a grove. It is not surprising that this whole community reflects this spirit of helpfulness. OPPORTUNITY FOR STUDY AND COMMUNITY WORK The old idea that a woman is neglecting her family if she takes an interest outside of her home is fortunately not credited by the thinking people of to-day. The fact has been conclusively proved many times that women are better home keepers when something causes them to be interested in community affairs. They return home with an added zest for its many duties, and are able to accomplish more because they have something of added interest to think about as they work. The woman on the farm has more need for recreation than the average woman living in town. Her working hours are longer, her duties more strenuous, and there is much less to attract her attention outside, so that it is very necessary for her to plan diversion. Her interest in the community is only natural. Who better can see the need of proper schooling for the children or the need of what the commun - ity church stands for? Someone has said, "Society to-day demands service of each individual. Somewhat of oneself one must contribute to the social machinery or be a clog in the wheel. " </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Rural Clubs for Women. 7 The mother in the home is, or should be, a great power for all that is essential in the betterment of the community life. The rural club has been successful in some districts, not only in pro - viding social life, but in improving the schools, in providing the children with good books, and in giving them the right kind of amusements. Can anyone doubt that the planning and carrying out of these helpful ideas has not also helped the mother as she worked about her home? Fig. S. The Farm Kensington near Ansley. Several clubs are giving special attention to the study of children. Women find it necessary to understand how to care properly for children, so that much sickness and resulting un - happiness may be prevented. It used to be thought that certain diseases were unavoidable, and mothers let the children be exposed to them, desiring to "have it over with." A large per - centage of deaths of children are caused by so-called preventable diseases, and many persons have suffered for years because of the after-effects of some disease in childhood. Children have been thought stupid in some cases, when the only trouble was a lack of proper food. By sane living, plenty of sunshine, fresh air, and proper play, much can be accomplished. It is not strange that mothers find themselves benefited by meeting together to </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Extension Bulletin 36, College of Agriculture. ■&gt; study and discuss these problems. What better thing could be accomplished by a rural club than to see that the children have hot lunches at school thru the winters? The success of a club should not depend upon the efforts of any one individual but upon the whole membership. If one member assumes all of the responsibility the others cannot help but lack interest. With a share of responsibility comes a stronger feeling of possession. The average club passes thru periods of apathy when it seems that nothing can arouse enthus - iasm. This can in a great measure be overcome by doing some - thing worth while. Have a definite object in view. Plan to do something that is of vital interest to your community. Establish a rest room, obtain a library, and have a story hour for children. Assist the school by beautifying its grounds or hanging pictures on the walls. The day of the purely cultural club is past. Its place has been taken by the club that reads and studies just as the old club did, but also takes an active interest in the com - munity and does helpful things as only women can do them. The result will be surprising. By helping others the danger of stagnation is passed, and you will find a living, active club again. In like manner the church will be benefited, for when you work for the good of all the community your church must feel the effect of the strength and harmony of its members. In the club all meet on common ground, and in this way an understand - ing comes — a more tolerant spirit of each others ideas and be - liefs. Strength must come with understanding and unity. HOW TO ORGANIZE AND CONDUCT A CLUB If you are interested in organizing a rural club, talk the matter over with your neighbors. A few women who are interested can create a desire for a neighborhood club by explaining the bene - fits to be derived from such an organization. All women are feeling the need of mental growth and social contact. They realize keenly that to be good wives and mothers they must take an interest in all community affairs. How better can this understanding come about than thru neighborhood clubs, where all members have the same interests at heart? An invitation may be extended over the telephone to inter - ested women to meet at some home or convenient place to organ - ize a club, or if a more general invitation is desired the announce - ment can be made at the church and schoolhouse. When the appointed hour arrives, any woman can call the meeting to order. Then someone moves that Mrs act as temporary chairman. The temporary chairman will call on </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Rural Clubs for Women. 9 Mrs to act as secretary. She will also explain the object of the meeting or request someone else to do it. After the subject has been thoroly discussed, someone will move "that a club be organized." This will be seconded and put to a vote. Now that a permanent organization is started, it is well to elect regular officers, consisting of president, vice president, secretary, and treasurer. These officers may be elected by ballot if desired, but a much more informal way is to proceed as in the case of the election of the temporary chairman, electing first the president, then vice president, followed by the secretary and treasurer. It will then be necessary to adopt a constitution. A simple form follows which may be adopted, if desired. The articles are read one at a time by the secretary, the president asking after each reading if there are any suggested alterations. After all have been read, the constitution is adopted as a whole. SUGGESTED FORM FOR CLUB CONSTITUTIONS. ARTICLE I. I. This club shall be known as the Club ARTICLE II. Sec. I. The object of this club shall be to encourage sociability while working for the betterment of the home and the community. ARTICLE III. Sec. I. The officers shall be a president, vice president, secretary, and reasurer. Sec. II. The duty o f the president shall be to preside at all meetings. Sec. III. The duty of the vice president shall be to act for the president n the absence of the latter or when requested by the president to do so. Sec. IV. The duty of the secretary shall be to keep the minutes of the meetings and give notice of extra meetings. Sec. V. The duty of the treasurer shall be to care for the finances of the club. ARTICLE IV. Sec. I. The majority of the members present at a meeting shall con - .stituteja 'quorum. ARTICLE V Sec. I. The officers of the club shall constitute an executive committee which shall determine the time and place of holding the meetings and arrange the program for the same, also settle any special business which may arise at any club meeting. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Extension Bulletin 36, College of Agriculture. SUGGESTED FORM FOR A CLUB MEETING ORDER OF BUSINESS Call to order. Music (if desired). Roll call. Reading of the minutes of last meeting. Reports of committees. Unfinished business. Miscellaneous business. Program. Discussion. Adjournment. SUGGESTIONS FOR THE MANAGEMENT The meeting is made more interesting and helpful by answer - ing to the roll call with quotations, current events, children's sayings, or favorite recipes. Roberts' Rules of Order or Parliamentary Usage for Women's Clubs by Emma A. Fox are both good authorities for parliamentary usage. It is best to have regular annual dues, the amount to be determined by the club. If refreshments are to be served, have them as simple as possible. Limit the dishes served to two or three, unless the club holds all-day meetings. Then never let the meal become a cooking contest. Usually it is well to have a program committee to be respon - sible for all club programs. This lightens the burdens of the president and secretary and gives more people an active interest in the work. The club programs should be carefully prepared so that each meeting will be looked forward to. They will necessarily vary because of the individual tastes of the members preparing them. But it will be found that all women are keenly interested in the questions of the day and that anything that betters the home will find instant response from them. When it is possible, it is a good plan to outline the program one year in advance. In this way a more constructive outline is possible, each meeting correlating with the other. This makes it possible also to know just when each member is on duty, thus giving her plenty of time for preparation. The Extension Service, College of Agriculture, University of Nebraska, has outlines prepared and will be glad to send copies free on application. With these outlines, the State Traveling </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Rural Clubs for Women. 11 Library, State House, Lincoln, will loan all books needed for reference, if desired— the only expense being the freight from Lincoln to your nearest railway station. CLUB COURTESY. Avoid confusion. Justice and courtesy to all. Always be prepared for roll call. Stand when addressing the chair. Do not talk when someone else has the floor. Do not wait until the last moment to prepare your paper. The successful club must have perfect harmony. Remember the rule of the majority and rights of the minority. OPPORTUNITIES FOR RURAL CLUB WORK. See that hot lunches are served at school. Encourage the teaching of home economics in your district school, even if only one period a week can be given. Beautify the school building and grounds. Take an interest in the social life of the children. Establish a story hour for children. See that good books are circulated in your neighborhood. Include the families in your community when you give enter - tainments. Further the good roads movement by giving your hearty cooperation. Make your neighborhood more healthful by encouraging sanitary sewerage disposal and by working toward fly extermin - ation. Establish a rest room in the town where you do your shopping. This has wisely been called an age of prevention. By sane living, disease may be to a great extent eliminated. Give especial attention to the study of food, shelter, and clothing, so that the health and happiness of your families may be promoted. EXTENSION WORK OF SPECIAL INTEREST TO NEBRASKA. FARMERS' INSTITUTES. Farmers' institutes are one-day meetings held for the dis - cussion of farm and home problems. Lecturers from the Agri - cultural College assist in these meetings. SHORT COURSES. A short course is a week's school of home economics. Often the work is given in connection with a course in agriculture for </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extension Bulletin 36, College of Agriculture. men. The women's work consists of lectures and demonstrations in cookery, textiles, and household management. All of the work given is of practical value to the home keeper. Lectures and demonstrations are furnished by the College of Agriculture. BOYS' AND GIRLS' WORK The purpose of this work is to interest boys and girls in agri - culture and home economics. The work is developed by the boys and girls in the home, the school, or on the farm. Plans and instructions for the work are sent to them from the College of Agriculture. Another feature of the Boys' and Girls' Work is the junior short course. This is a one-week school of instruction conducted on plans similar to those of the senior short course. WOMEN'S CLUBS In many of the rural communities over the State, women have organized clubs. In several places the farmers' institute auxiliaries have changed their organizations into clubs. These clubs prove very helpful to all who belong to them. Great benefit is derived from social contact, and when a group of home keepers discuss the needs of the home and community life they find ways and means to assist in bettering conditions. The Agricultural Extension Service, University Farm, will be glad to assist in organizing clubs, and will assist any club or group of women to plan home economics programs. A lecturer or demonstrator may often be secured to assist at a meeting. the only expense being the entertainment of the woman while the guest of the organization. For further information concern - ing any of this work, address Extension Service, College of Agri - culture, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. OUTLINES TO BE USED AS COURSES OF STUDY BY HOME ECONOMICS CLUBS. 1. How to Organize and Conduct a Club. 2. Food Outlines No. I. 3. Food Outlines No. II. 4. Textiles. 5. Civics. 6. Care and Feeding of Children. 7. Miscellaneous Readings. 8. Geography and History of Nebraska. /\ n A 5 T* 11 »• &lt;■ ■» f • 11 9. Extension Bulletin 15 (a miscellaneous course of study </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Rural Clubs for Women 13 10. Mother and Baby. 11. Miscellaneous Material on Food, Household Management, etc. 12. Lessons in Bird Study. 13. Extension Bulletin No. 32. Lunches for the Rural School 14. The Home. (In Press.) 15. The Achievements of Women. (In Press.) HELPFUL MATERIAL FOR HOME ECONOMICS CLUB TALKS. 1. Vegetables. 2. Meat. 3. Invalid Cookery. 4. Quick Breads. 5. Cookery. 6. Balanced Meals. Directions for Simple Home Serving. 8. Bulletins for Reference in Study of Foods. 9. Nebraska Girls' Canning Club Recipes. 10. Time Table for Canning Clubs. 11. Classification of Foods. 12. Preservation of Eggs by Means of Water Glass. 13. Care of Clothing and Cleaning. 14. Comparison of Textile Fabrics. 15. Chemical Testing of Materials. The above material will be sent free upon application to the Extension Service, University Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. AVAILABLE EXTENSION BULLETINS. The following bulletins and junior circulars may be had free of cost by residents of Nebraska upon application to the Agricultural Extension Service, University Farm, Lincoln. BULLETINS. Alfalfa Management. 1911. 13. Agricultural Extension Short Courses. 1913. Cost of Growing Crops in Ne - braska. 1911. 14. Tha Climate of Nebraska. 1913. 15. A Course of Study for Home Economics Clubs. 1913. 16. Twelve Lessons in Sewing. 1913. ■i. Testing Seed Corn. 1912. 4. Cooking and Sewing. 1912 Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. 1912. Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. 1914. 17. Twelve Lessons on Foods and Their Preparation. 1913. 12. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. Growing Potatoes, i 1913. 18. Simple Water Systems for the Farm. 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Extension Bulletin 36, College of Agriculture. 20. Saving the Corn Crop. 1913. 29. Pruning Trees, Vines, and Shrubs. 1915. 21. Filling the Silo. 1913. 30. Neglected Orchards and Their Care. 1915. 22. Sweet Clover in Nebraska. 1914 23. What is a Farm Demonstrator? 1914. 31. Cooperation. 1915. 32. Lunches for the Rural School. 1915. 24. Spraying Fruit in Nebraska. 1914. 33. Use of Hog Cholera Serum. 1915. 25. The Babcock Test and Its Use in Herd Improvement. 1914. 34. Second Annual Report of County- Cooperative Farm Demonstra - tion Work. 1914. 1915. 26. Directory of Nebraska Dairy- Cattle Breeders and Dealers. 1915. 35. Woodworking Exercises for Home and School. 1915. 28. Feeding Alfalfa to Horses. 1914 36. Rural Clubs for Women. 1915. JUNIOR CIRCULARS. CORN Soil in Relation to the^Growth of Crops. The Planting of Corn. Cultivation of Corn. The Insect Pests of Corn. The Growing Corn Plant. Selection and Preparation of the Corn Plat. Seed Corn Testing. The Selection and Care of Seed Corr AND CANNING. GARDENINC The Garden Plan. Insects. First Garden Operations and Tools. Planting. Preparing Vegetables for Market Canning. Cultivation and Thinning. Transplanting. Planting Second Crop. Fall Garden Work. TOMATC ( l.Tl'RK Hotbeds. Pruning and Training. Tomato Diseases. Varieties and Planting. Transplanting and Spraying. Field Planting and Cultivation Harvesting and Marketing Cooking. COUMB 1. COURS£ 11 Purpose of the Study of Foods Starch and Its Use in the Diet. Starch and Sugar Vegetables. Cereals. Legumes and Nuts Bread. Fish and Poultry Invalid Cookery. Salads. Milk and Milk Products. Meat and Its Use in the Diet. Quick Breads. School Lunches. Cake. Gelatin and Frozen Desserts. Balanced Meals. Preparation of a Meal SEWING. Shirt Waist and Outline on Cotton. Draft for Nightgown and Outline Couwb ■. Extension Bulletin No. 16. on Silk. Covtm ii. Making a Nightgown. Making a Kensington Bag. Making an Embroidered Collar. Clothes and Their Effect. Dtm Skirt and Outline on Wool O-28-M&amp;-10M. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>