<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00048">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00048</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  STUDIES ON THE RELATION OF THE NON-AVAILABLE WATER OF THE SOIL TO THE HYGROSCOPIC COEFFICIENT.</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">RESEARCH BULLETIN NO The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. STUDIES ON THE RELATION OF THE NON - AVAILABLE WATER OF THE SOIL TO THE HYGROSCOPIC COEFFICIENT. By F. J. Ai way ACCEPTED FOR PlBLICATlllN NOVEMBER. 1912 Districted Jine 25. 1913. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD (tmi .to. NT. or MM up.ivcn.irr) HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Liucoln. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlclo. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. • F. J. Alway, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. R. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Fra.ndsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bbuneb, B. Sc, Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Farm Management and Agricultural Extension. W. J. Mobrill, M. Fob., Forestry. Erwix H. Barboub, Ph. D., Oeology. G. R. Chatbubs, A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, D. Sc, Horticulture. — O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. G. A. Lovkland, A. M., Meteorology. I. P. Snydeb, M. S., Superintendent of Experimental Substation, North Platte. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Associate in Soils and Crops, North Platte; Assist - ant Agriculturist. Office Dry Land Agriculture, V. 8. Department of Agriculture. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. * R. S. Tbumbui.i., A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. * Guy R. MrDoi.E, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry Clayton O. Rost, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistrti. Ebwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). P. B. Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). J. A. Ratclijt, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). * Eli is Rail, B. S. A., Assistant in Animal Husbandry. C. B. Lee, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry. H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathninuu G. ('. White, A. M., Assistant in Dairying. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. James Cowa.n, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz Knorb, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. S. W. Pebin, Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nte, Foreman Demonstration Farm. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. Introduction 5 Review of previous work — Older view of the importance of the hygroscopicity of soils 8 Recognition of the falsity of the older view 10 Studies of the hygroscopie coefficient by Hilgard and Loughridge. . 12 Later studies on the nonavailable water and on the relative hygroscopicity of soils 14 Previous studies by the writer IS Recent studies by Briggs and Shantz IS General description of the experiments 21 Soils used 21 Plants grown 21 Greenhouse used 21 Determination of the soil moisture 28 Free water 30 Wilting coefficient 31 Determination of the dry matter of the crops 32 Preliminary experiment 32 Growth of wheat on semi-arid soil compared with that on humid soil. Experiment of 1909 33 Summary of experiment 44 Growth of crop plants with different amounts of water in the sab - soil. Experiment of 1910 45 Pilling the cylinders 48 Separation of roots from the subsoil 49 Cylinders without plants 51 Red Fife wheat 52 Cylinder with no free water in the subsoil 58 Cylinders with 4 per cent free water in the subsoil 60 Cylinder with 7 per cent free water in the subsoil 61 Cylinder with 12 per cent free water in the subsoil 61 Two cylinders with moister soil near the surface 61 Kubanka wheat 62 Cylinder with no free water in the subsoil 65 Cylinder with 4 per cent free water in the subsoil 65 Cylinder with 8 per cent free water in the subsoil 65 Cylinder with 12 per cent free water in the subsoil 67 Two cylinders with moister soil near the surface 68 Milo 68 Cylinder with no free water in the subsoil 69 Cylinder with 4 per cent free water in the subsoil 69 Cylinder with 8 per cent free water in the subsoil 69 Cylinder with 12 per cent free water in the subsoil 70 Two cylinders with moister soil near the surface 71 Mexican beans 74 Summary of experiment of 1910 It- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 region. Experiment of 1911 78 Red Fife wheat 83 Milo 90 Mexican beans 99 Summary of experiment of 1911 10*5 Experiments with perennial desert legumes 10* Experiment 1 108 Experiment 2 110 Experiment I 11 1 Summary of experiments 114 The hygroscopic coefficient versus the wilting coefficient In compari - sons of the available moisture of soils 115 Summary and conclusions 119 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE HYGROSCOPIC COEFFICIENT. BY F. J. AI.WAY. INTRODUCTION. tit is generally recognized that a mere statement of the total isture content of a soil gives little or no information as to the amount of water which is available to plants growing upon that soil. To obtain such information it is necessary to first ascer - tain the nonavai table portion of the soil water. Sachs in 1859 introduced the direct method for the determination of this — al - lowing plants to grow in flowerpots filled with the soil until they permanently wilted and then determining the amount of moisture remaining. At practically the same time Hilgard developed an indirect method — the determination of the hygroscopic coefltcimt of the soil, which consists in exposing a very thin layer of air - dry soil to an atmosphere saturated with water vapor and kept at a practically constant temperature until the maximum amount of hygroscopic moisture has been absorbed, after which the water content is determined. Notwithstanding the fact that the descriptions of both these methods were published over fifty years ago, almost all investi - gators who have occasion to make soil moisture determinations still publish their data in the form of percentages of total water. Tn field studies where the soil is exceptionally uniform such data may possess definite significance to the individual investigator well acquainted with the particular soil, but usually the dat;i are meaningless to others and often are entirely misleading even to him who has made the moisture determinations. Such data do not permit of the recognition of a particular soil as either rela - tively moist or relatively dry : yet practically any farmer can rec - ognize a soil as either moist or dry by merely looking at it and feel - ing it. That nio«t soil investigators have so long continued to follow a method which does not give as much useful information RESEARCH BUL. 3. A(iR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Research Bulletin Xo. S 6 regarding the amounts of available soil moisture as can be se - cured by an ordinary farmer using only his eyes, his hands, and a spade or auger, is uot so remarkable as it may at first appear. On the one hand, the direct determination of the nonavailable soil moisture is so tedious that in field studies, where a separate de - termination for every sample might be necessary, the amount of labor involved appears prohibitive. 1 On the other hand, experi - mental data on the relation of the nonavailable water to the hygroscopic coefficient are very scanty and there has never been a general recognition of the latter as equivalent to the nonavail - able moisture. The general failure to recognize that differences in moisture content which are very apparent while the samples are being collected are not to be detected from the tabulated percent - ages of total water is probably due to the general practice of having assistants or laborers attend to the collecting of the sam - ples. The lack of a general recognition of the importance of the de - termination of the hygroscopic coefficient is probably, however, due chiefly to the reaction from the old view of the practical im - portance to be attributed to the relative amounts of moisture which different soils, when dry, are able to absorb from the at - mosphere, a view which originated with Sir Humphrey Davy early in the nineteenth century and was fully accepted by the foremost investigators until 1875. The long acceptance of this erroneous view of the value of the hygroscopicity of soils was due to the prevailing opinion that the amount of water lost by trans - piration from a unit area of land was far in excess of the amount of water falling, as rain and snow, upon the same area. This loss had been calculated from pot experiments in which plants had at all times been kept supplied with an abundance of 1 A good illustration of the variability of the soil of individual samples from foot to foot and from boring to boring is indicated in the following, which gives the hygroscopic coefficients of soil samples taken from dif - ferent fields at the game time or from the same field at different times on the H O Ranch, near Madrid, Nebraska: Depth No. 1 No. 2 No. 3 No. 4 No. 5 &lt;No. 6 No. 7 No. 8 No. 9 No. 10 No 11 Feet 1 * o oo 2 10 4 9.8 3 10 2 9.8 « 7 0 83 5 7 0 6.9 6 7.8 7.4 7 6.9 __• i ■ 9.8 10 5 lu a 92 7.7 69 ; 6.4 6 6 6.3 69 5.9 4.0 5.1 s» ! 1 10 4 1 8 0 6.7 6 3 6.0 4 1 3 9 I 9 7 4 6.1 7.0 7 2 7.1 9 1 9.1 9 1 7.7 5.9 8 5 6 3 10 2 6.4 12 4 7.1 13. 1 7.7 12 2 9 3 9 0 11 5 9.4 • 9 9.2 90 9 2 7.0 ! 7.8 9.3 13. 0 14 2 12 8 « 33 3.0 3.0 ; j; is i </seg>
            <seg id="p007">rate per unit area of surface. The transpired water, thus calcu - lated, exceeded the precipitation and to account for the difference it seemed necessary to assume that the soil could have absorbed and rendered available to vegetation the ever-present water vapor of the atmosphere. Later it was found that the loss of water by transpiration depended upon the degree of moistness of the soil Ed that, hence, there was no evidence of any such deficit. Ex - :iments by Mayer and by Heinrich indicated that plants were able to make any use of the hygroscopic moisture and that none of the moisture of the air was rendered available to the plant thru the absorbent power of the soil, and Mayer discouraged era indicating the hygroscopicity of soils on the ground that it would cause confusion if very hygroscopic soils were marked with a defect in regard to the water supply when this was not of much practical significance for the reason that these soils were the very ones that had the highest water capacity. Following this proof of the falsity of the old conception of the significance of the hygroscopicity of soil* came the view, carried to the opposite extreme, that a knowledge of the hygro - scopic power of different soils is practically valueless, the ques - tion of the usefulness of a knowledge of the relative hygrosco- Kty of soils being apparently confused with the distinct ques - i of the usefulness to plants of the hygroscopic moisture of the soil. Loughridge was the first in connection with field studies o soil moisture to determine the hygroscopic coefficients of all the Inples dried and to tabulate the free icatrr as well as the tota ter. Loughridge's work first suggested to the writer the de mination of the hygroscopic coefficients of the different soi nples, taken in connection with a field study of soil moisture 1904-1905, after he had found that there was little agreement ween the data on the total soil moisture and his field notes. e data on the free water, on the contrary, agreed with the field lervations. The results of this field study suggested the pot teriments reported in the following pages. These experiments re carried out in connection with and subordinate to various 1 investigations, the object being to determine the relation of i final water content of the soil to the hygroscopic coefficient 1 to determine to what extent the moisture was removed from different portions of the subsoil not i&gt;enetrated by plant roots. For assistance in the experiments the writer is indebted to Dr. W. D. Bonner. Dr. R. A. Coitner. Mr. G. R. McDole. Prof. R &lt; TVnmhull and tin- l-itc Mr \V \ \\'iill«chlpj&gt;-pp ' </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 KEVIEW OF PREVIOUS WORK. OI.HKK VIEW OK TI1K I M 1'IIUT AM K OP THE H YGROSI Ol"l&lt; ITY OF SOUS. Dmry roaaMorcd that the hygroscopic power of soils enabled tlieni to render the water of the atmosphere available to |&gt;l;iiits and that the relative hygrosopicity of a soil served as an index of the product iveness of land. "The power of soils to absorb water from air is much connected with fertility. When this power is great the ] da nt is supplied with moisture in dry seasons, and the effect of evaporation in the day is counteracted by the absorption of aqueous vapor from the atmosphere, by the interior parti of the soil during the day. and by both the exterior and interior during the night." 1 "I have compared the absorbent power of many soils with res|&gt;ect to atmospheric moisture, and I have always found it greatest in the most fertile soils so that it affords one method of judging of the productiveness of land."' Schiihler." wtio was the first to determine the maximum amount of moisture absorbed by various soils when exposed to an atmosphere almost saturated with water vapor, agreed in the main with l&gt;avy"s view but pointed out that the power of absorp - tion. considered alone, might be very deceptive as he had found that "a pure, infertile clay absorbs in twelve hours • • • more than a very fertile garden soil." l.iebig* accepted Davy's view as to the value of the moisture alisorl&gt;e«l from the air. "When in the hot summer the surface of the ground is dry. and there is no replacement of moisture by capillary attraction from the deeper strata, the powerful attrac - tion of the soil for the vapors of water in the air provides the means for supporting vegetation." I Sachs 5 in 1859 distinguished experimentally between the ilable and the nonavailable water. He grew tobacco plants in ■c different soils. — a vegetable mold, a loam, and a quartz sand — and found that they wilted permanently, while 12.3. 8.0. and Lfi per cent respectively of water remained in the soil. The maximum water capacities of the three soils were 46, 52.1, and 20.8 per cent. He made no determination of the relative hygro - epicity of the soils. The considerations leading up to these leriments he stated* as follows: "If one wishes to learn to know the relation of the plant to •Davy, Sir Humphrey. Agricultural Chemistry, Second Edition, 1814, 1 Ibid., p. 184. Kibler, G. Grundsatre der Aerikulturchemie, 1830, vol. 2, p. 82 ig, J. Letters on Modern Agriculture, 1859, p. 48. 5 Sachs, .1. Ueber den Klnfluss der chemischen und physikalischen Be- schaffenheit des Bodens auf die Transpiration der Pflanzen. Landwirth s( haft lichen Versuchs-Stationen, 1859, vol. 1, p. 235. * Ibid., p. 234. The writer Is responsible for the translation. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 tin- soil. witter it does not suffice to know how much water a cer tain kind of soil en take up. we must much more know whether and liow much of this thf plant can take up. • • • For this I in |&gt;&lt;&gt;se one must determine the degree of moistness of the soil at whicli the plants no longer are in position to withdraw from it the minimum of their needs, where the roots in the soil M longer can take up so much water as may be necessary to re - place the smallest evaporation from the leaves. This takes place when the leaves in a very moist atmosphere, even by night, re - main wilted. Wilting by day and in dry air proves only that the leaves give out more than the roots are able to take up in the same time, but it does not prove whether the roots are no longer able to take up any ; by strong sunlight the leaves can wilt, even when the roots take up very much and stand in very moist soil. When on the other hand the leaves wilt in moist air and by the :il&gt;seiice of light, where their transpiration is almost zero, this proves that the roots are unable to take up even this small quan - tity and that if the plant should need more it w r ould only suffer sci much a greater shortage. When the plant is in this condition, the soil can still contain considerable quantities of water, more or Ic ss according to its nature." To test the commonly accepted view as to the importance of the ability of different soils to attract water vapor from the at - mosphere Sachs carried out two experiments, 1 one with a scarlet runner plant ( I'haseolus nmltiflnru*) and another with a to - bacco plant. These experiments indicated that a very hygro - scopic soil under certain conditions was able to attract enough moisture from an almost saturated atmosphere to maintain the life of plants. Tn the first experiment, that with the scarlet run - ner, he took a young plant with three leaves, grown in a very heavy soil in a porous earthen flowerpot, and allowed it to stand without watering until the soil was fully air-dry and the leaves lic^im to wilt. Then the bottom of a high and roomy glass cylin - der was covered with a shallow layer of water, an inverted beaker placed in the middle of it, and on the bottom of this the flower - pot placed. The upper opening of the cylinder w y as closed with a divided glass cover in such a way that only the thin stem of the plant projected thru the central opening in the cover. Thus the leaves were exposed to the air of the room while the soil containing the roots was in an almost saturated atmosphere. The wilted leaves became fresh and remained tnrgescent during two months ('.Tune and July) without ever wilting. No further development took place, the original leaves remaining healthy but no new ones annearin". Tn the second experiment a tobacco 1 Ibid., p. 236. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Research Bulletin X&lt;&gt;. 3 plant with three large leaves was grown under similar condi - tions but in a soil of vegetable mold. Sachs had expected a more favorable outcome in the latter experiment on account of the greater hygroscopicity of the soil used but the results were simi - lar to those in the first. Mayer 1 in 1871, altho questioning the correctness of the cal - culations which showed a transpiration exceeding the precipita - tion, accepted the old view. "The absorptive power of the soil for water * * * is under all circumstances a useful soil property, as it becomes active only when there is an actual scarcity of water in the soil and so acts as a regulator." "The water thus condensed in porous solid bodies conducts itself ex - actly like other capillary held water and can, for example, when a field soil has in this way condensed water, be taken up by a plant's roots just like that which has entered the small in - terstices of the soil from the rain or by watering." RECOGNITION OF THE FALSITY OF THE OLDER VIEW. Wilhelm, 2 was as early as 1861 inclined to conclude from his experiments that the absorptive power of the soil was useless. fBeisler, 3 according to Hilgard, began, in 1868, the experi - ental testing of the reality of the accepted importance of the absorptive power of the soil for the development of plants. Mayer 4 in 1875 reported experiments similar to those of Sachs, using peas, barley, and buckwheat in flowerpots filled with sand, garden soils, marl, and sawdust, the last as representative of very hygroscopic soils. In the case of each he determined l&gt;oth the water content at the time of the collapse of the plant and the hygroscopicity by Schiibler's method. He concluded that the power of condensation of the soil does not benefit the plants, as these have already been injured beyond recovery before the soil is able to absorb moisture from the air, and that the trans - piration of plants in the field had been greatly overestimated, there being no proof of an actual deficit of water. He recog - nized that the water remaining in the soil on the wilting of a plant was closely related to the maximum amount of S Mayer, Adolph. Agrikulturchemle, First Edition, 1871, Part II, p. The writer is responsible for the translation. 1 Wilhelm, G. Der Boden und das Wasser, 1861, Vienna, as reviewed In Hoffmann's Jahresberlchte fiber die Fortschrltte der Agrikulturchemle, vol. 5, 1862-1863, p. 18. 'Hilgard, E. W. Ueber die Bedeutung der hygroskopischen Boden - feuchtigkeit fflr die Vegetation. Forschungen auf dem Gebiete der Agri - kulturphysik, vol. 8, 1886, p. 93. 4 Mayer, Adolph. Studien fiber die Wasserverdichtung in der Acker - erde. Frfihllng's neue landwlrthschaftliche Zeltung, vol. 24, 1875, pp. 87 - 97, as abstracted in Bledermann's Centralblatt fur Agrikulturchemle, vol 11, 1877, pp. 243-249. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Ration of \onnrailabl,' Water to H m ro*copic Coefficient 11 moisture which the soil was able to absorb from an almost saturated atmosphere. Ho considered this, however, to have little practical importance as "by a remarkable coincidence the most strongly condepsing soils are usually those with the highest water capacity and it would probably only cause con - fusion if we were to mark these soils with a blemish in regard to the supply of water on account of a not very productive Somewhat previous to Mayer, Heinrich 2 had begun a series of experiments which were similar to those of Sachs but in eluded many additional precautions to make his results more ac curate and employed a larger number of different plants and soils Later 3 he continued his experiments, still further improving hi methods. The plants were grown in glass vessels of 80 to 100 c.c. until they had reached considerable development. The room was protected from the direct sunlight and from rapid changes of air, the atmosphere being kept almost saturated with water and care being taken to insure the soil being as thickly penetrated by roots as possible so that at the conclusion of the experiment all parts of the soil would be equally exhausted of water. On the wilting of the plants in a moist atmosphere they were quickly removed from the soil which was then thoroly mixed for a mois - ture determination. The maximum amount of hygroscopic mois - ture which the soils could absorb was determined by exposing them in thin layers, in some cases for weeks, to a saturated at - mosphere. He used six soils, ranging in hygroscopic coefficient from 1.15 to 42.30, and found that in no case was the plant able to reduce the moisture content to the hygroscopic coefficient be - fore wilting. To decide whether plants differed from one another in their ability to exhause the soil moisture, he used nineteen different cultivated plants, including wheat, oats, barley, rye. corn, red clover, alfalfa, and potatoes, and also two plants from dry sandy soils and one swamp plant. From these experiments he con - cluded that "Neither the different cultivated plants nor those designated as swamp and sand plants differ in their ability to extract water from the soil." 1 Ibid., p. 248. The writer Is responsible for the translation. 'Heinrich, R. Die Absorptionsfahigkeit der Bodenarten ffir Wasser - dampf und derm Bedeutung fiir die Pflanzpn. Landwirtschaftliche Annalen des mechlenburglschen patriotlschen Verelns, Neueste Polge, vol. 16, 187'j, pp. 353-358 and 361-363, as abstracted in Biedermann's Centralblatt fur Agrlkulturchemie, vol. 12, 1877, p. 16. I' Heinrich, R. Zweiter Bericht iiber die Verhaltnisse und Wirksamkeit landwirthschaftlichen Versuchs-Station zu Rostock, 1894, p. 2$. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Research Bulh'thi Xo. 3 STUDIES OF THE HYGROSCOPIC COEFFICIENT BY HILGARD AND LOI'GHRIDGK. Hilgard, soon after Mag appointed State Geologist of Mis - sissippi in 185S, began a study of the soils of that state, using essentially the methods of chemical analysis employed by Owen and Peter in connection with the geological survey of Kentucky and Arkansas. The most notable change he made in the method was the introduction of the determination of the hygroscopic co - efficient, altho he did not use this term at that time, it appearing first in 1874. * In the case of each soil sample analyzed he de - termined this first of all. He states : 2 "The methods I have pur - sued in the quantitative analysis of soils, etc., are essentially those described by Dr. R. Peter in the Third volume of the Ken - tucky Geological Report. * * * I have substituted for the determination of moisture contained in the air-dry soil (varying greatly within brief periods) that of the moisture absorbed by the same at a fixed temperature if possible, in an atmosphere at the point of saturation with aqueous vapor; which renders the determinations directly comparable and seems to offer a very important element in the treatment of soils." He recognized in it an index of the degree of heaviness of a soil. Details of Hilgard's method were published earliest by Lough - ridge, 8 who was a student under Hilgard and who continued the study of the soils of Mississippi. The method was described later by Hilgard. 4 Loughridge states: "In beginning the analy - sis of Mississippi soils in 1859 Dr. Hilgard adopted the following method which has also been adhered to by his successors in this work, in over two hundred analyses made. The soil is pulver - ized with a rubber pestle. • • • The hygroscopic moisture is determined, after exposing it in a space saturated with vapor in a layer not exceeding 1 mm. in thickness, for 12 hours, by drying at 200° C. in a paraffine bath." Loughridge expressed this as "the hygroscopic moisture from 7° to 21° 0." Evidently the terms hygroscopic coefficient and hygroscopic moisture had been in common use between Hilgard and Loughridge daring their early association. 1 Hilgard, E. W. Silt Analyses of Mississippi Soils and Subsoils. American Journal of Science, vol. 7, 3d Series, p. 9, 1874. This paper had previously been read at the Portland meeting of the A. A. A. S. in 1874. 1 Hilgard. E. W. Geology and Agriculture of the State of Mississippi, 1860, p. x. •Loughridge, R. H. On the Influence of Strength of Acid and Time of Digestion in the Extraction of Soils. American Journal of Science, vol. 7, 3d Series, 1874. Dp. 20-23. 'Bulletin 38, Bureau of Chemistry, TT. S. Dept. of Agr., 1893, and Cir - cular No. 6, University of California Experiment Station, 1903. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Relation of Xonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 13 I Subsequently in their work in California they changed the ipantnc of drying from 200° C. to 110° C. to avoid expulsion combined water and the partial carbonization of organic mat - in the former temperature; this method is still in use by them. In 1S80 Hilgard 1 reported the hygroscopic coefficients of 435 soils from eleven different states and territories, all the deter - minations having been made by himself or Loughridge in Mis sissippi or by his assistants at the University of California. Hilgard,- using the results of his studies in the arid portions of California, replied to Mayer's sweeping statements, his con - clusions being summarized in the following: 1. "Soils of high hygroscopic power can withdraw from moist air enough moisture to be of material help in sustaining the life of vegetation in rainless summers, or in time of drouth. It can - not, however, maintain normal growth, wive in the case of some desert plants. t2. "High moisture absorption prevents the rapid and undue ting of the surface soil to the danger point, and thus often saves crops that are lost in soils of low hygroscopic power." On Hilgard and Loughridge 8 being associated a second time they win for the first time to have applied to the study of soil* under drouth condition* their knowledge of the significance of the hygroscopic coefficient. "In the following pages the hygro - $eopie moisture and the free water of the soil are frequently spoken of. the latter being that contained over and above what is held in the hygroscopic condition, and representing that which is considered as free to enter the plant roots and upon which the plant chiefly depends." 4 "The actual amounts (of water! required for particular cultures ♦ • • i( re found by elimi - nating the hygroscopic moisture and ascertaining the amount of free irater present in soils where cultures grew and where they suffered and comparing the results."* In this study Loughridge reports upwards of 100 determinations of the moisture in the t Hilgard, E. W. Cotton Production In the U. S., vols. 5 and 6, Tenth &gt;us of the U. S., 1880. 1 Hilgard. E. W. Proceedings of the American Society for the Promo - tion of Agricultural Science, vol. 1, 1882, p. 118. Ueber die Bedeutung der hygroskoplschen Bodenfeuchtigkelt fur die Vegetation. Forschungen auf dem Gebiete der Agrikulturphysik, vol. 8, 1885, pp. 93-100. Soils. New York, 1906, pp. 199-201. ' Hilgard, E. W., and Loughridge, R. H. Endurance of Drouth In Soils o&lt; the Arid Region. Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of California for the year 1897-8, pp. 40-64. — Loughridge, R. H. Moisture in California Soils During the Dry Season of 1898, Ibid., pp. 65-96. •Ibid., p. 66. LMbid., p. 95. Quoted also In Hilgard's "Soils," New York, 1906. pp. -218. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Research Bulletin No. S field— the average of the first 4 feet in each case — stating in each case the percentages of total, hygroscopic, and free water. IHilgard, as pointed out above, had recognized in the hygro - jic coefficient an index of the heaviness of soils — the expres - i, in a single value, of the texture of the soil— thus anticipating by fifty years the view of Briggs and McLane 1 as to the desir - ability in soil classification of a single-valued numerical term ex - pressing a common physical property of agronomic importance. LATER STUDIE8 ON THE NONAVAILABLE WATER AND ON THE RELATIVE HYGROSCOPICITY OF SOILS. Gain,- using Erigeron canadensis, Lupinus albus, and Phase - olus vulgaris, allowed the plants, in porous earthenware pots, to wilt and then determined the moisture content of the soil. He used six different soils of which he had determined the "coeffi - cient of hygroscopicity according to the method of Schflbler." He found rather irregular differences for the different plants but concluded that different plants behave in much the same man - ner as regards resisffcnce to drouth. V * Gain, following Schtibler's example, reported this as the weight of water absorbed by 1,000 grams of soil. To make it conformable with the other data the writer has changed it to a percentage basis. Mitscherlich* carried out a series of experiments similar to those of Heinrich, but allowed the plants to remain undisturbed until they died, when he determined the moisture content of the soil. Oats, white clover, red clover, and white mustard were grown on six soils whose hygroscopicity had been very accurately determined by exposure to an atmosphere in equilibrium with a 10 per cent sulphuric acid solution. He concluded that plants die as soon as they have removed all except the hygroscopic moisture. 1 Briggs, L. J., and McLane, J. W. Moisture Equivalent Determinations and Their Application. Proc. American Society of Agronomy, vol. 2, 1910, p. 138. ■ Gain, M. E. Action de l'eau du sol sur la vegetation. Revue generate de botanique. vol. 7, 1895, p. 71. • Mitscherlich. A. Landwirthschaftliche Jahrbucher, 1901, p. 410. Soil Soil hSSSd&amp; Water contentwhen p««t.wated n»«*_&lt; leathsoil J«y lumus Calcareous sand Jarden soil iilicious sand . . i Percent 9.26 to 11.50 1.75 7.73 to 11.10 6.0 5.92 to 6.95 0.15 2.90 to 5 23 2.6 1.79 to 2.82 0.0 0 33 to 0.76 It-rcent 9.26 to 11.50 7.73 to 11.10 5.92 to 6.95 2.90 to 5 23 1.79 to 2.82 0 33 to 0.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Relation of Nonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 15 ■thus determined — which is much below the hygroscopic co - :ient as ietenriaed by the Hilgard method. IMitscherlich 1 in an exhaustive study of the relation of the itive hygrosfopicity of soils to their other properties con - ies that a knowledge of the hygroscopicity of soils is of ex - rae importance. He holds that the determination by Hilgard's thod gives results much too high on account of the condensa - 1 of moisture on the exposed samples. From theoretical con - eratious he concludes that soils absorb their maximum amount hygroscopic moisture when allowed to come into equilibrium h an atmosphere in contact with a 10 per cent sulphuric acid tHedgcock 2 experimenting with a great variety of plants on different soils concluded that the ability of plants to take ter from the soil varies in an ascending scale from hydro - rtes, thru mesophytes, to xerophytes, there being variations not ly among genera but also among species and among individ- Is. He reports no determination of the relative hygroscopicity the soils used. I Clements 3 has proposed the use of the terms "chresard" and hard" for the available, or physiological, water content and nonavailable water content of the soil respectively. "All soils tain more water than can be absorbed by the plants which w in them. This residual water which is not available use, varies for different soils. * * * It differs, but to a r-h less degree from one species to another. A plant of xero - ■tic tendency is naturally able to remove more water from same soil than one of mesophytic or hydrophytic character. I* * After one has determined the physiological water for i great groups of soils, it is more or less possible to estimate i amounts in the various types of each." He describes in de - 1 the method of determining the "echard" by pot experiments. ter 4 he states: "This available water, or chresard, differs for ■ different soils, and, for dissimilar species of plants." No erence is made in either of these two books to the hygroscopic &gt;fflcient of soils or to any other means of determining the ;hard" of a soil than by the physiological method. "The lonnt of water that a plant can absorb from the soil can be idily determined only by finding the amount left when the mt wilts completely.'* 1 Mitscherlich, A. Bodenkunde fur Land- und Forstwirte, Berlin, 1906. 1 Hedgcock, G. G. Botanical Survey of Nebraska, vol. 6, 1902. •Clements, F. E. Research Methods In Ecology, Lincoln, Nebr., 1905. pp. 5 and 31. 4 p]gni©nts K E Plant Phvsioloffv aim) Ecology. New York, 1907. p. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 i:&lt;x&lt;&lt;iich Hull) tin Xo i nUCTIOUS STUDIES BY THE WBITKK. In IMM ami 1MB, while examining into conditions in the Canadian Northwest 1 for an explanation of the remarkably high yields of small grains obtained on summer-fallowed land, tin - writer took several sets of soil samples to a depth of 6 feet at the Indian Head Experimental Farm and determined the total water in these. Finding that the percentages of total water did not at all correspond with the field notes, which had been it corded as the samples were taken foot by foot, the hygroscopic coefficients of all the samples were determined, following the example of I.oughridge referred to above. The resulting data &lt;ni the free water were in satisfactory accord with the field n" In a single experiment, using some surface soil from Indian Head, barley plants were grown in a glass cylinder 10 iadMi deep. At the end of six weeks water was withheld. After the p!;mis died. 2 the soil at all depths l&gt;elo\v 2 inches contained IS to 19 jier cent total water. The hygroscopic coefficient, as &lt;le termined. was found to be 12. Tt was concluded that: a. In such moisture studies in the field the depth to which moisture determinations should be made depends upon the limit of the root penetration of the crop, being 4 to ." feet for wheat and oats and fi to 7 .feet for grass. - Indian Head. b. Unless the soil under consideration is very uniform a determination of the hygroscopic coefficient of each sample is indisjiensahle. and the determination of this value is extremely important even where the soil is uniform, r. A better idea of the moisture condition of the soil at Indian Head could lie obtained by a casual examination in the field, using a soil auger, than hy drying and weighing samples unless the hygro - scopic coefficient of each sample was determined. rf. The stor - age capacity for available water of the two soil types studied amounted to from ."i to 7 inches of rainfall for wheat and oat crops, e. Comparatively little water is lost by direct evapora - tion from the subsoil below the surface 12 inches of soil. f. In semiarid regions roots penetrate to the stored water and the lat- 'Alway, F. J. Studies on the Soils of the Northern Portion of the Great Plains Region — The Second Steppe. American Chemiral Journal. lOOfi. vol. 31, p. 580. — Some Soil Studies in Dry Land Regions — A paiier read at tho Second Annual Meeting of the Cooperative Experiment Association of the Great Plains Area, held at Manhattan, Kansas. June. 1907. and pub - lished in Bui. 130, Bureau of Plant Industry, V. S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1908, p. 42. — Studies of Soil Moisture in the Great Plains Region. Journal of Aericultural Science, 1908, vol. 2, p. 333. '- Briggs, L. J.. and Shantz, H. I... have Incorrectly referred to this as tho the moisture had been determined when the plants wilted. The Wilt - ing Coefficient for Different Plants and its Indirect Determination, Bul - letin 230, Bureau of Plant Industry, D. S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1912, p. 66. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">['elation of Xotwrailuhh Wmttr 1&lt;&gt; Hpgroecopie VoefHritmt 17 ter does not need to Ik' elevated to the surface foot of soil in order to Ikmoiiic available, g. In dry-land experiments tillage operations should l&gt;e governed by actual determinations of the moisture conditions of the subsoil, but a. fair idea of these con - ditions is revealed to the e.\|K&gt;rienced eye and hand without the weighing or drying of samples. To account for the failure of very heavy crops, maturing during almost rainless weather, to reduce the moisture as low as the hygroscopic coefficient it was suggested that the lower limit of water available for the normal growth of plants m considerably higher than the hygroscopic coefficient — 4.5 to •&gt;.() per MBt— depending u]&gt;on the value of the hygroscopic coeffi - cient — for the two soil types in question in that particular study. For the port ion of the soil moisture above this lower limit the designation ••water probably available for the support of normal plant growth" or "X water" was used. Several years after the publication of the results of this in - vestigation the writer found that the slight modification which he had introduced into Tlilgard's method — the employment of shallow pastelxiarfl trays to hold the glazed paper instead of placing the latter directly on the wooden shelf — while giving con - cordant results with duplicate determinations made at the same time or in the same manner at different times, invariably gave values much below the true coefficients. Thus the results while showing the relative hygroscopicity of different samples gave too high a free water content. Unfortunately, on removing to the University of Nebraska the writer had discarded all the samples taken at Indian Head for moisture determinations. However, part of another series 1 on which determinations of the hygroscopic coefficient had been made in the sajne way and only a few weeks later had been saved. New determinations on the latter gave values 1.5 times as high as the earlier ones. It is evident that had the original determinations of the hygroscopic coefficient of the different samples been correct the importance of the de - termination of the hygroscopic coefficient would have been much more distinctly shown and there would have been a still closer connection between the data on the free water content of that portion of the soil penetrated by plant roots and both the field notes at the time of sampling and the previous historv of the fields. Later field studies 3 at widely separated points in the semi 1 Alway, F. J., and McDole, G. R. Studies on the Soils of the Northern Portion of the Great Plains Region — The Distribution of Orbonatrg on thr Second Stenpe. American Chemical Journal. 1907. vol. 32. ni 1 Alway, F. J. Moisture Studies of Semiarid Soils. Report of Winnipeg meeting of the British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1909, </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Research Bulletin A'o. 3 arid region of summer-rains in the United States indicated that the generalizations previously shown to apply to studies of soil moisture in Saskatchewan were equally applicable to the whole of the semiarid region of summer rainfall from the Saskatchewan River on the north to the Mexican boundary on the south. "The depth to which samples should be taken should extend at least as far as the plants develop roots freely or as far as the moisture descends from the surface. This depth can in most cases be approximately determined by a field examination of the soil. Soils of this region are characterized by their ability to be reduced by the native vegetation and by many annual crop plants to a characteristic easily recognized, dry condition. This state of dryness seems the normal condition in the more southerly regions, while in the most northerly it may be found only at the time of the maturing of the plants. This property facilitates in most cases the ready recognition of the moisture condition by a mere field examination with the soil auger." RECENT STUDIES BY BEIGGS AND SHANTZ. Briggs and Shantz 1 have recently published the results of an extensive series of pot experiments in which they have fully utilized the results of all previous studies along the same line. Also, they have applied the conclusions arrived at from these pot experiments to field studies of soil moisture, but have as yet published but few data on the latter. In their pot experi - ments they have, like Heinrich, used small glass vessels 2 and allowed the soil to become as thickly penetrated by roots as possible, after which it has been allowed to stand fully pro - tected from evaporation until the plants wilted permanently. The per cent of water remaining in the lower two-thirds of the soil mass, where the roots are most abundantly developed, they designate the wilting coefficient. They have met the various obstacles that stood in the way of accuracy by various ingenious methods. Further, they have at - tempted to determine the relation which holds between the wilt- P. 698. Photograph reproduced In Widtsoe's "Dry Farming," 1911, p. 9«. The data of the experiment described below as that of 1909 (page 33) were presented in the paper. 1 Briggs, L. J., and Shanti, H. L. A Wax Seal Method for Determining the Lower Limit of Available Soil Moisture, Botanical Gazette 51, 1911, p. 210. — The Wilting Coefficient and its Indirect Determination, Botanical Gazette 53, 1912, p. 20.— The Wilting Coefficient for Different Plants and its Indirect Determination, Bui. 230, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1912. — Application of Wilting Coefficient Determinations in Agronomic Investigations, American Society of Agronomy, November, 1911. vol. 3, p. 257. 1 Briggs and Shantz have used ordinary drinking glasses. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Relation of Xonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 19 ing coefficient and other physical values of soils, viz. the hygro - scopic coefficient as determined by Hilgard, the maximum water capacity as determined by Hilgard, the moisture equivalent as defined by Briggs and McLane, and the mechanical analysis, us - ing the classification of separates employed by the Bureau of Soils. They conclude, that, while there are slight differences for dif - ferent plants and that these differences hold with the various soils, the wilting coefficient is practically independent of the plants used and is not distinctly influenced by the age of the plant, by the humidity of the air, by the light intensity or by the moisture content of the soil during the growth of the plant ; when the leaves curl or drop the soil moisture is not at the wilting coefficient but below this and above the hygroscopic coefficient; the death point, however, varies with the plant used, some plants dying much more quickly after wilting than others. After the death of the plant the soil still continues to lose water thru the tissues of the plant. "The plants during the drying stage act simply as a medium for the transfer of water and. while the rate of loss is reduced, the final result is the same as if the air and soil were in direct contact." The wilting coefficient "practically marks the cessation of growth and so constitutes a datum from which the water content available for growth in a particular soil may be determined when the total water content is known." From studies of the relation between the wilting coefficient and other physical properties they have deduced the following formulas, which show also the probable error: moisture equivalent Wilting coefficient lM (1 ± Qm) hygroscopic coefficient Wilting coefficient -^-- 0 - fi g ir^ Mlg) - _..,, „ . moisture-holding capacity — 21 U .lting coefficient - - 2 .90 (1 dTO^Tr „_.,„.. „ . 0.01 sands + 0.12 silt + 0.57 clay Wilting coefficient = 1 ft 02g As the direct determination of the wilting coefficient i« more difficult and time-consuming than the indirect method, they con - clude that the former may be altogether replaced by one of the latter, of which they prefer the determination of the moisture Kit. Tt will be seen from the second formula that they ! wilting coefficient at almost one and a half times the pic coefficient. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 They thus really divide the total water content of any par ticuliir sample of soil into three parts: ■ Water available for growth — the difference between the total water content and the wilting coefficient. 2. Portion of the available water not available for growth — the difference between the willing coefficient and the moisture content of the soil when in equilibrium with the air. 3. Nonavailable water — the moisture content of the soil when in equilibrium with the air. or, in other words, the water con - tent of the air-dry soil. They make no distinction between the physiological impor - tance of the portion of the water l&gt;etween the wilting coefficient and the hygroscopic coefficient and that of the portion between the hygroscopic coefficient and the air-dry condition. Tn their latest publication 1 they modify their earlier state - ment in regard to the significance of the wilting coefficient, de - duced from their studies using drinking glasses, when applied to field conditions or to experiments in which large pots are used. "The results of some of the soil moisture determinations made on the Great Plains during the summer of 1911, which was ex - tremely dry, indicate that a crop is capable, under certain con - ditions, of reducing the moisture content of a part of the soil be - low the wilting coefficient, before the crop actually wilts. • • • It follows that the amount of moisture available for growth may be somewhat greater than that calculated by the use of the wilting coefficient as a datum. "It often happens under field conditions and also when plants are grown in large pots that at the approach of a drouth the lower leaves die very gradually. This self-pruning continues in extreme cases until the entire leaf area is dead. Often the gen - eral wilting of the plant can not be observed during the whole process. Under these conditions the wilting point is at best in - definite, and the soil moisture content is usually reduced far be - low the wilting coefficient l&gt;efore the death of the plant. The water which is removed from the soil after the moisture content has been reduced to the wilting coefficient may result in some growth hut this is so small in proportion to the water consump - tion that it is of little practical value from the standpoint of crop production." Their use 2 of the data from the single pot experiment with 1 Application of Wilting Coefficient Determinations in Agronomic In - vestigations, American Society of Agronomy, Nov., 1911, vol. 3, p. 257. • Bulletin 230. Bureau of Plant Industry, p. 66. t </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Relation of yonavailable Water to Hyqroaropic Coefficient 21 rev plants described by the writer and their presentation of moans advocated by him for the estimation of available mois - ture in soils are inaccurate, as is shown elsewhere in this publica GENERAL DESCRIPTION OF THE EXPERIMENTS. KThe experiments were carried out in a greenhouse using water - it galvanized iron cylinders. Except in the case of those with desert legumes the cylinders were C&gt; feet long and 6 inches in diameter, containing known amounts of soil and of water. In these, seeds were planted and the plants allowed to grow, without further addition of water, until they died. Ou the death of all the plants in a cylinder it was opened and the moisture content de - termined in 3-inch sections. The distribution of roots in the sub - soil was carefully observed and in the later experiments these were removed, photographed and weighed. SOILS USED. (Some of the soils used were from the semiarid western jtor - in of Nebraska, some from the humid eastern portion, and the hers from the intervening portion of the transition region. The physical character of the soils used is shown by their hygroscopic coefficients given in Table 1. PLANTS GROWN. Red Fife wheat was grown in the experiments of all four years, inilo.and Mexican beans in the last two. and Kubanka wheat, corn and some perennial desert legumes each in only one year. The last mentioned were Prosopis velutina. Acacia Greggi and Acacia congtricta. GREENHOUSE USED. The only greenhouse available for the experiments wai an old. poorly ventilated one. The ventilators in this were im - mediately above the only portion of it in which the cylinders could be placed. As any rain falling on the cylinders would have seriously interfered with the experiments, the ventilators were kept closed during threatening as well as during rainy weather. A steam-main, which led to another building, and in which the steam was kept at high pressure day and night until warm weather set in. increased the difficulty of keeping down the maxi - mum temperature. The use of whitewash on the glass panes of the greenhouse had to be abandoned, as the wheat plants would be </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Research Bulletin No. S I* GO COMBCOMM d 1 I I f a 5. ¥ OMh'hoO i a rtrtrtrt-H-4 W B ■ m •^ w* ,-t ■* «ooo»« d -* oi oi oo x s 1 ri I O)lC05^HU5;C Z *J cioiciocioe *5 i *~* ►» : * a O ooocec ec m oiouiioiaio i "J a £ h: 2 O I -1 «&gt; «o &lt;o &lt;o «q j £ r 6 * k q « » » i.- 5 -? 1 p i W «*/ WJ V «S « rt «««i; 3 a E s Hi "i « oq eo « Z oo od o osV t^ S a e is &gt; •. i e i 4 99 « , qososic g V W O3 O5 113 , I 1 i-HB^ee^ • oi ui ni co m n HHHriHH .5 t~; n t~ io oo ia ■3 om « — (—:—' HNoose </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Relation of Nonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 23 found noon after its application to be prostrated, but they re - covered when it was removed. Thus the windows were left with - out protection against the direct rays of the sun. As a result the temperature inside the greenhouse rose very high on hot, sunny days — a daily maximum of over 100° F. being the rule rather than the exception. During the preliminary experiment, in 1908, no record was kept of the temperature, humidity, or rate of evaporation in the greenhouse. During the latter half of the experiment of the fol - lowing year a record was kept of the evaporation from a free water surface, using two cylindrical jars, one of glass 4 inches in diameter and the other of white stoneware 6 inches in diameter. These were placed level with the tops of the cylinders, being sap - ported on a table covered with white paper. They were filled to a mark one inch from the top and at the end of each week water was added to raise the water to this mark. The evaporation record of that year is important in that it constitutes the only data recorded which indicate the relation of the general condi - tions in the greenhouse during the experiment of 1909 to those of the following two years. In the experiment of 1910 the evapora - tion from a free water surface was determined from March 12 on, using four glass jars like the glass jar of the preceding year and similarly supported. They were placed at the four corners of the framework enclosing the metal cylinders. There were no im - portant differences between the different jars in the amount of evaporation from week to week. Tn the 1911 experiments two glass jars similar to those of the preceding year were used but they were sunken in the soil surrounding the cylinders so that the mark on each was level with the surface of the soil as shown in the case of the one in figure 21. It will be seen from Table 2 that the recorded rate of evaporation in 1911 was two or three times as great as in the preceding two years. This was due in part to the increased air movement in the greenhouse on account of better ventilation. The rate of evaporation recorded in this year appears remarkably high. 1 A record 2 of the rate of evapora - tion in the near-by open air was kept by the TJ. 8. Weather Bureau, but unfortunately for only part of the period, the evapo - rating pan being less than 200 yards from the greenhouse. The data from this record are included in Table 2. 1 Similar high rates have been recorded In Australia where an evapora tion of from 140 to 160 Inches In 12 months was recorded, using small evaporating cylinders. Report of Meteorological Observations for Western Australia in 1907, p. 7 and p. 110. 1 Loveland, G. A., and Perin, S. W. Evaporation from a Free-Water Sur - face at Lincoln, Nebraska. Twenty-fifth Annual Report of the Nebraska Experiment Station, 1912, p. 193. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">l{&lt; xmnh Hulhtiii \'o. 3 24 Table 2. — Evaporation from a free water surface in the green - house and in the adjacent open air. In (jroenhou.se In open air 1909 1910 1911 1909 1910 Imhet Inches Inehet Incht* huh?* March ' 4.7+ April 5.7 5.5$ 4.7 6.7 May ... 4 0' 4.7 8J 5.9 M May 4.7 S.2 5.9 M June. Ml 3.9{ 13.7 6.7 7 Julv 4.2 13.0 6.0 7 1 August 8.0 September : 6.0 * From the 3d. + From the 12th. I To the 21st. i From the 12th. Tap.i.k ."&gt;. I'rltitirr h iimiilitii at ~&gt; p. in. in the greenhouse ami in the open air. In greenhouse* In open air Differcnre 1910 April . . Second decade 4S 49 . . 1 Third decade :« 29 4 . M:iv . . First ilecade 55 58 .. :{ Second decade 54 .72 Third decade 49 47 ■&gt; ■&gt; June First decade H 51 0 .Second decade i.i 33 10 1911 Murch First decade 43 55 •• 12 Second decade 39 33 6 Third decade . . :i!l * April ...... First decade 41 Second decade 42 40 • 9 Third decade 50 4s 9 May First decade is 49 Second decade 49 43 6 1 Third decade 59 54 S June First decade 40 36 4 Second decade 41 ■ 3 Third decade 38 32 6 July First decade 37 33 4 Second decade 45 39 6 Third decade 40 37 3 August First decade 42 44 ■&gt; Second decade 49 47 2 Third decade 46 September First decade 57 64 ■ • 7 Second decade 56 58 1 Third decade. 57 65 . . I 8 Highest humidity recorded on any day 85 88 Lowest humidity recorded on any day 22 15 • Record incomplete. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">I!) la I ion of Xomtrailahlr Water to H iit/roxroiiic ('ix/fiiimt 25 Thruout the' latter portion of the nperinentl ol 1910 and 1911 the humidity was recorded daily at 8 a. in. and at 5 p. in., using a wet-bulb thermometer. The mean humidity at 5 p. m. for monthly decades is given in Table 3. The data for the humidity in the open air at the same hour are from the record of the Lincoln station of the I'nited States Weather Itureau. which is only three miles from the Experiment Station. The di'Terences in general are not great, the humidity being somewhat lower in the open air than in the greenhouse, notwithstanding the high temperatures which prevailed in the latter, due probably to the presence in the greenhouse of a ranker of pots with plains belonging to other experiments, to which water was applied daily. During the first and the last three decades in 1911 there were none of the watered pots in the greenhouse and during these two periods the air was much drier than that outside. Tn the experiments of 1910 and 1911 the daily maximum and minimum temperatures were recorded from the time the experi - ments were well started until the plants died The daily maxima are shown in Table 4 and the daily means — the average of the maximum and the minimum — in Table 5. The thermometer was hung at the level of the cylinder tops in a well ventilated wooden shelter, placed at one end of the row of cylinders. When in 1910 it was found that under the conditions prevailing the plants in moist soil apparently suffered no ill effects from temperatures up to 111* F.. no effort was made to keep the daily maximum tem - pi r-iturc lielow lfS* F. As soon as the temperature reached this point steps were taken to prevent it rising higher. While the means of ventilation in the greenhouse were entirely inadequate to keep the maximum temperature below 100° F. on bright days, it could lie kept l&gt;elow 112° F. except under very unusual condi - tions. The occasions in 1910 on which it rose above this were afternoons on which after cloudy, threatening weather the sun came out very bright. The ventilators having been closed to keep out any rain from the threatened storm and not being opened on the appearance of the sun. the temnerature rose rapidly. For this reason Sundays were especially the days of high temperatures — as May 8 and 29 and June 12. 1910. The high temperature of June 12, 1910. viz, 12&gt;° F.. practically terminated the experiment of that year, all plants dying rapidly after this. The very high temperatures recorded in 1910 were usually of short duration, because as soon as a visit to the greenhouse showed the temppra ture to be very high rm*m were taken to quickly lower it. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 &lt; | S5SSS8SSSSSS3SSSSSSSS$SSSSSSSS: j S § ? 71 2888282288882 - | §SS2S2§§SSSgs§^2gg§22^2«25Sg22 : 2 -. | 2«**»t«|228883SSS2S81IS22£s888S g - OONt-soto: 83S83SS&amp;S83SS383S &lt; ■2 ss ee ;5aio i "^ 3 i 1 1 l§2Sfe|S255SSS8S^ 3 228818888228 s I | ;:;.:.: : : jssss 2 gggggsgggs § ■=' 52^S5SS22:2iJ2g I |—«*-— x-sssssssassssaasas&amp;ssss &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Relation of Vona callable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 27 | ssossssss&amp;gssasasssossssggsssssge ; » SSSSSSSgSSESSggggfcKKgssi S * f 22§2§»»^*»§SSSgSS3iSSS§gSSSo18§g 5 f ■? ? ? J SSSoSS?8B§§S3SgSs§SS§8SS§S§S§g3gSgS | g _&lt;5 » i o&gt; — i &gt;■ I SSSSRffgg§8gKSScggg§»|2c; K g fes§ g S3gsg eg | fegSSKSf: : ! | j isffSfcfffcgggSSSRgfcSgR I ft i &lt;: 1 I -c I SSfeSSSoSSSSgSSSgSSgSoSgSsSgSSSSSSSS 5 w i ::::::::.::.::■:::: ■ I I;;;;:;:: : : ::•:::: :8S3S i iS§8S§ i I -I i E ■ ft, 1 c * « | SSrrSSSSgggSggggggs : :.:::: i :i :i g j * ff^ggS^t:S{:S?Sf:gS^^ R SSSsSSSr^SigSig : g 4 ? G £ :::•:: :t~t^t~-«o6 as SbSei^t-ooKxSK K ~. . c* c*# cn c&lt; C^ C« P* ?0 CC fi »c t*- -^ as c; ■&lt; o I afcfecssgssssgsfcij^gRSB^sassssBg </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Research Bulletin Xo. 3 lu the 1911 experiment conditions were much more unfavor - able on account of the extremely high temperatures prevailing out of doors. In that year the ventilation of the greenhouse had been so much improved that for ordinary seasons it might have proved adequate, but during the very hot weather of June and July the temperature out of doors on many days rose above 100*° F., while on July 5 it rose to 110° F. On that day it reached i;&lt;0° F. in the greenhouse. This teniix'rature. which did not last long, was not sufficiently high to injure well-watered plants in the same greenhouse. Suspecting the correctness of the remarkably high tempera - tures recorded by the maximum thermometer, it was tested at various times, both in 1910 and 1911, by placing, during the hottest part of the day, a number of accurate thermometers in various parts of the greenhouse and protecting them all both from the direct rays of the sun and from the heat reflected by the brick walls of the greenhouse. However, nothing was found to justify any assumption of inaccuracy in the temperature data. The high maximum temperatures during the early part of each sea son were due to the presence of the steam-main mentioned aWvc DETERMINATION OF THE SOIL MOISTURE. Each G-foot cylinder was opened as soon as convenient after removing the last of the plants from it. About two-thirds of the cylinders were opened on the same day that the last plant was removed, but with the others there was an interval varying from 2 to 16 days. It is probable that no appreciable amount of moisture was lost from below the first foot during this interval, and that the moisture conditions were practically the same at the time the cylinders were opened as they were when the last plant died and was removed. 1 Tt is also improbable that any con - siderable loss of moisture occurred even from the first foot, as in all the cylinders bearing plants the soil of the surface foot was already very dry and was underlaid by at least one foot of com paratively dry subsoil. In order to remove the soil from a six-foot cylinder for mois - ture determinations the cylinder was placed on a table and split lengthwise by shears, 3 inches at a time. (Figure 1. b.) The soil from this section was quickly and thoroly mixed and a sam - ple for the moisture determination placed in a pint jar which was then sealed. After the samples had been secured from the whole of the cylinder, moisture determinations were made, using 10(1- or 1 Alway, P. J., and Clark, V. L. A Study of the Movement of Water in a Uniform Soil under Artificial Conditions. Twenty-fifth Annual Report of the Nebraska Experiment Station, 1912, p. 255. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">llvlutUm of XoHarailaMp Water to Hi/grosco/iic &lt; 'ueffivient 29 200-gran portions, the contents of each jar being thoroly mixed before removing any of the soil. The samples were dried in an electric oven, kept at 110° C, thru which a rapid current of air was kept passing. In the experiments of 1909 and 1910 all de - terminations were made in duplicate, using 100-gram samples, but in those of 1911 a single determination of each was made, using a 200-grain sample. As in such a study the thoro drying of the samples is extremely important, the following method wai followed to insure its completeness. In the earlier determina - tions, after the samples. i&gt;0 to (»fl in all. had been in the oven for 12 hours, five or six from different parts of it were removed and allowed to cool in a desiccator. Tfcnp were weighed, returned to Fig. 1. Cylinders used in experiments of 1909 to 1911. a. Lower portion with nipple N. 6. Manner of opening cylinder in 3-inch sections. At x is shown a 3-inch section of soil ready for removal. the oven and left there for from "&gt; to 12 hours longer when they were again cooled and weighed. If no appreciable loss in weight occurred after the first weighing it was assumed that all the other samples were dry. they having been in the hot oven all the time. If a loss in weight occurred, however, the drying was con - tinued until two successive weighings showed no appreciable change of weight. In the later determinations, instead of using the above method of control, several 200-gram samples taken from a large sample of known moisture content were placed in the oven along with the samples from the cylinders. If after 12 hours in the oven these control samples were found to be fully dried the heating was discontinued, but if not they were returned and weighed at intervals until thoroly dried, the cylinder samples being left in the oven undisturbed until the control samples were dry. The former thus had a longer exposure in the oven than the latter. This modification of the control greatly shortened the time required for the drying, as usually the samples were fully = z 1 a. 1 _ £. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 dried at the end of 12 hours, thus permitting two charges, in stead of a single charge, to be dried every 24 hours. In the tables in the following pages the amounts of water are expressed as percentages of the dry soil. FREE WATER. The free water represents the difference between the total water and the maximum hygroscopic water (hygroscopic coeffi - cient). The soil moisture in the following tables is expressed usually as the free water only but in a few both the total water and the free water are given. In all cases the total water may be found by simply adding the free water to the hygroscopic co - efficient. An expression of free water alone is almost as meaningless as that of total water alone. Thus corn plants may be dying in a soil with a hygroscopic coefficient of 15 and containing 3 per cent free water while plants of the same kind in a soil with a hygro - scopic coefficient of 0.8 may be very vigorous with only 1.0 per cent free water. For this reason in order to give tables of free water their full significance there should at the same time be given also corresponding tables of hygroscopic coefficients or of total water. Any two of the three tables are sufficient but some will find a certain combination the most satisfactory and others another. The writer prefers the statement of free water and hygroscopic coefficient, but those who have made many determi - nations of total water and none of free water will, at least at first, find the statement of total water along with the hygroscopic co - efficient to have more significance for them. Total water — hygroscopic coefficient — free water. The hygroscopic coefficients of the soil samples were de - termined by the Hilgard method with a slight modification. In - stead of using glazed paper to hold the soil, flat aluminum trays were employed. An extensive study of the determination of hy - groscopic moisture had shown that this modification of the Hil - gard method gives concordant and reliable results and also that the modification used in determining the hygroscopic coefficients as reported in previous publications 1 gave results much too low. The discussion of methods for the determination of the hygro - scopic coefficient is reserved for a future publication. For the determination of the hygroscopic coefficients the in- 1 Alway, P. J., and McDole, G. R. Studies on the Soils of the Northern Portion of the Great Plains Region: the Distribution of Carbonates on the Second Steppe. American Chemical Journal, vol. 32, 1907, p. 275. — Alway, F. J. Some Soil Studies in Dry-Land Regions. Bui. 130, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. D. A., 1908, p. 360. Studies of Soil Moisture in the "Great Plains" Region. Journal of Agricultural Science, vol. 2, 1908, p. 333. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">dividual 3-inch sections were not used, but the determination was made on a sample of the bulk soil used, it being taken at the time of filling the cylinders. Thus in the case of the 8 cylinders of the experiment of 1909, in which 16 different soils were used, the hygroscopic coefficients of these 16 were determined and used in calculating the free water in the 192 individual sections. This may account for some irregularities in the free water content of sections adjacent to the dividing line between two different soils. Thus, for example, in the case of cylinder I in Table 8 (p. 41 1 in the lowest section of the fourth foot there is shown only 0.2 per cent free water compared with 1.1 per cent in the section above and 1.7 per cent in the section below. As the soil of the fourth and fifth feet had hygroscopic coefficients of 9.3 and 7.4 respect - ively, an error of one inch in filling the cylinders or in removing the sections would account for the irregularity. In such cases no Empt has been made to increase the regularity shown in the fibution of free water by making determinations of the hygm lie coefficient of any of the individual 3-inch samples. I In the tables of moisture data the water content of the thin d layer, about 1 inch in thickness, which was placed in the hom of each 6-foot cylinder, is not rejwrted for the reason that sand in the process of removal became mixed with the over - ig soil in almost all cases, thus greatly altering the hygroscopic Fficients of the samples as actually dried and the amounts of i water, so rendering the data quite meaningless, unless ;i te determination of the hygroscopic coefficient of each Munple . been made. The hygroscopic coefficient of this sand was &lt;•..*. WILTING COEFFICIENT. The wilting coefficient very frequently referred to in the following pages is that defined by Briggs and Shantz. 1 In no case 1 has it been determined directly, it having been calculated from the hygroscopic coefficient using the formula given by Briggs and Rfcaats, viz: _ . hvgroscopic coefficient Wilting coefficient *-= o 68 1 See p. 18. 1 Dr. Brigss has kindly determined for the writer the moisture equiva - lent of the soil used in the largest number of experiments — the H O Subsoil (p. 47). Five determinations of the moisture equivalent gave an average of 14.2, from which the wilting coefficient of 7.7 and the hygro - scopic coefficient of 5.25 is found by the formulas of Briggs and Shantz (p. 19). As the figures had been completed before receiving the data from Dr. Briggs, the wilting coefficient 8.2, calculated from the hygro - scopic coefficient 5.6, as determined by the writer, is used in the various figures showing the moisture conditions in the cylinders in which H O Subsoil was employed. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Hi ■*, nnli liulhtin \&lt;&gt; i IiKTKRM I NATION OF THE DRY MATTKK Of THE ' lK'I'S. Ill the case of each cylinder all the thinnings, fallen leaves. and dead ]ilanis were saved in a covered jar until all the plants had been removed. The seeds, if anv were present, were counted and weighed: the data on the dry matter of these, reported in the various tallies, were calculated on the assumption that tlie mm contained 10 per cent of water. After removing the seed the ivst of the crop was dried at 110° C. and weighed. PRELIMINARY EXPERIMENT In IMA two cylinders filled with a seiniarid soil were planted with Red Fife wheat. Each was 4 feet long and li inches in diameter, consisting of two lengths of sewer-pipe fastened to - gether with cement, the latter being coated with parafline as soon as dry. The bottom of each, likewise made of cement coated with paraHine. carried a one-hole rubber stopper. The cylinders were filled with air-dry soil from the H O Ranch, which is located at Madrid. Perkins Comity, near the western border of Nebraska. Pix bulk lots of soil were used, viz. the first 4. the second 4. and the third I inches of the first foot, and the whole of the second. the third, and the fourth foot. The soil was placed in the cylinders in its natural order. All but the surface inch was added in small portions and tamped with a two-inch rubber stopper on the end of a three-eighths inch iron gas-pijte. The surface soil was covered with a layer of absorb - ent cotton and water added until seepage thru the one-hole rubber stopjH'r began. Then the addition of water was discontinued and the excess allowed to drain away until seepage ceased, after which the hole in the rubl&gt;er stopper was closed by means of a glass plug. The absorbent cotton was removed, five sprouted ker nels of Red Fife | spring) wheat, from the Experimental Farm at Indian Head, Saskatchewan, were planted one inch deep in the moist soil and the surface inch of air-dry soil was added. The cylinders were placed in the greenhouse on the day the seed was planted. April 15, and given no more water. They were not sunken below the level of the floor and so were fully exposed to the heat of the sun's rays. At the end of ten days the plants were thinned to the most vigorous two in each cylinder. These developed normally until near the end of May when the plants became prostrated. Thinking the experiment a failure no atten - tion was paid to the plants until three weeks later, when it was found that they had quite recovered and were putting forth heads. The whitewash which had been applied to the glass panes shortly before the injury was first observed had been largely removed by </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Relation of Xonacailable to Mffprmetfie Cm/kit mi 33 heavy rains; this suggested a connection between the injury to the wheat and the presence of whitewash on the glass. On July 10, 86 days after planting, the 4 plants were quite dead. They had each reached a height of about 21 inches and had each formed one spike, but only one had formed seed and this bore only two badly shrunken grains. The cylinders were split lengthwise and the soil examined for roots. These were found to reach to the bottom of the cylinders. The weight of dry matter in the two plants from the one cylinder was 3.5 grams and in those from the other 4.0 grams. As, on opening the cylinders, it was found that in each a crevice had developed between the soil column and the cylinder wall, extending from the surface almost to the bottom of the cylinder, thus allowing comparatively free circulation of air and consequent loss of water from the sides of the soil column by di - rect evaporation, the moisture data have been discarded as value - less. In all later experiments this source of error has been carefully guarded against by watching for the first appearance of such crevices and at once filling them with fine, dry soil. GROWTH OF WHEAT ON SEMIARID SOIL COMPARED WITH THAT ON HUMID SOIL EXPERIMENT OF 19O9. In this experiment Red Fife wheat was grown in 6 cylinders. 3 filled with soil from humid eastern Nebraska and 3 with soil from semiarid western Nebraska, all having been saturated with water previous to the planting of the seed. As checks two other cylinders, the one filled with the humid soil and the other with the semiarid soil, were left unplanted but otherwise treated like the six planted cylinders. The cylinders used in the experiment were of galvanized iron. being 6 feet long, 6 inches in diameter, closed at the bottom and soldered to make the seams water-tight. In the bottom of each wag a nipple carrying a one-hole rubber stopper to permit of drainage while the soil was being saturated; a glass plug placed in the hole in the stopper rendered the cylinder water-tight. Be - fore filling the cylinders with soil each was filled with water to test the tightness of the seams. The general construction of the cylinders is shown in figures 1 and 2. The latter illustrates one of the difficulties of working with such tall cylinders; thus, it was necpR8ary to carry the cylinder into the open in order to photo - graph it. the roof of the greenhouse being too low. The semiarid soil was from the same prairie field on the H O Ranch as that used in the 1908 experiment, but taken to a depth of 6 feet, being removed from the excavation in eight portions — a </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 the first, second, and third 4 inches «.f the first foot, and the second, third, fourth, fifth, and sixth foot. The 8 bulk soils were placed in separate sa&lt; ';s for shipment to this Ex]&gt;eriinent Station, where each, in a dry con - dition, was thorolv mixed. The humid soil was from the Experiment Station Farm, at Lincoln, the 8 portions being taken at the depths corre - sponding to those of western Nebraska soil. The soils were placed in the cylinders in their natural order — that is. the sixth foot first and the first four inches last. The weight of each bulk soil placed in the different cylinders was recorded and a sample was saved for the determination of the moisture content and of the hygroscopic coefficient. The cylinders were filled, saturated with water, and drained as in the preceding year. After seepage had ceased a glass pin™ was placed in the one-hole rubber stopper in the bottom of each, and the cylinders moved to the greenhouse and placed in a pit which was ."? feet deep and covered with boards overlaid first with a layer of excelsior and then with one of soil. Thus the lower half of each cylinder was protected from the heat of the sun's rays and kept at a comparatively uniform temperature. In the case of each, except the check cylin - ders III and IV. 10 sprouted kernels of the same Red Fife wheat used the year before were placed in the moist surface soil and one inch of dry soil added. A week later the plants were Fig. 2. One of thinned to 4 in each cylinder, the cylinders. Cvlinders I. II. HI, and I Cylinders I. II. III. and IV, with semiarid soil, were placed in the greenhouse on February 8, and the others. V, VI, VII. and VIII. with humid soil, on Februarv 23. Each cylinder was weighed on scales, sensitive to 15 grams, just before being placed in the pit and again on being removed at the close of the experiment. About the middle of March affthe plants became prostrated. As the windows of the greenhouse had received a coat of white - wash some ten days before this injury was first noticed, it wis suspected from the experience of the preceding year that this might have been the cause. I'sing hydrochloric acid all the white - wash was removed from the panes I March 23). However, no marked change in the condition of the plants was observed until </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Relation of Nonavailable Water to H ygrwnitpic Coefficient 35 B'il 1. after which there was a stead}' improvement, the plants ning fully recovered by April 10. From this time on no tewash was used on the windows. Outside of the injury following the use of whitewash, condi - tions generally were quite favorable. No temperature record was kept. The evaporation from a free water surface in the greenhouse amounted to 12.2 inches between May 3 and July 31 i Table 2). I On account of the experience of the preceding year the ap - rance of a crevice around the edge of the soil column was tched for from the time of planting and was found first on ril 17. Altho the crevice could not be seen at the top of the lch of dry soil, it could be detected by means of a long thin tula pressed down at the edge of the cylinder. By means of ? spatula the crevice was filled with surface soil. From that le on at intervals of a few days, all the cylinders were ex - ined for crevices and these, whenever found, were filled with face soil, from one inch to two inches of loose dry soil being »t as a mulch on the surface of each cylinder. No crevices de - oped in either of the unplanted cylinders III and VI, but mer or later they appeared in each of the others. Later, when : cylinders were opened, the exact extent of these crevices was erniined. tBy May 25 a hard crust had developed at a depth of from 1.0 1.5 inches below the surface in I, II, IV, and VII. Later it eloped in V and VIII also, but not in the unplanted cylinders, and VI. IOn March 13 the numbers of the tillers in I. II, and IV were S. and 9 respectively. In order to determine the effect upon the il moisture that would be produced by reducing the stand, two plants containing 0.439 grams dry matter were removed from II on March 22; on April 24, the four plants in II having 23 tillers. 19 of these, containing 1.16 grams dry matter, were re- Kved, leaving two plants with 2 tillers each. On the latter date four plants in I had 27 tillers and the four plants in IV had 31. The average height of the plants in I. II, and III was 12, 12, and 12.5 inches, respectively. The plants on eastern Nebraska soil had made much less growth than those on western Nebraska soil, having only 0. 3. and 3 tillers and being only 9, 9.5, and 12 inches high respectively on April 24. Altho thruout the experi - f»nt the plants on humid soil made less growth, they were quite healthy in appearance. Not until near the end of May did the inning of the plants in II cause them to show any advantage over those in I and IV, but during the final month of their growth they appeared much more vigorous and they produced </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Be* trek Built tin Xo. S better filled spikes { Table t; i . Nearly all the spikes appeared dur - ing the latter part of May. On June 24 ripe heads were removed from TV and V. By July 4 all the heads were ripe except one on a late tiller in VII, which did not ripen until July 26. The appearance of the eight cylinders on June 24 is shown in figure .t. 1 Rack culm was cut off even with the surface and removed from the cylinder as soon as it was quite dry. The cylinders which had borne no plants were removed from the pit on June 24, weighed, and opened. The others were sim - ilarly treated as soon as possible after all the plants in them had ripened. In the case of three cylinders there was an in - terval of six days between the death (and removal) of the last plant and the opening of the cylinder. The presence of any crevice beside the cylinder wall, referred to above, was recorded at the time of opening the cylinder. Each section, as removed, was carefully examined for roots and well mixed before taking the sample. No crevice was found along the walls in III and VI. In II, V, and VIII a crevice extended to 6 inches, in VII to 18. in I to 39, and in IV to 66 inches. Where the crevices did not extend below twelve inches they were found to have been completely filled with the dry surface soil, which had been worked down into them by means of the spatula, but where they extended to a greater depth they were found to have been only partly filled below the twelfth inch, leaving the portion below as an intercommuni - cating air space. In IV, separate samples for moisture determi - nations were taken from the outer and from the inner portion of the soil column in the case of the four sections of the second foot. Xo difference in moisture content was found, indicating that no loss of moisture had taken place thru the crevice. The explain! tion of this is that the air in the crevice had been kept in a satu - rated condition, it being in contact with soil which contained not less than the maximum amount of hygroscopic moisture. Roots were numerous in the first foot in all the cylinders bearing plants. In I and IV they were numerous and well dis - tributed at all depths to the bottom of the cylinder; in II they penetrated as deeply but were not as numerous, while in V. VII, and VIII they were very scarce below 24. 21, and 21 inches re - spectively, but a few were found to extend to 39. 45, and 60 inches respectively. As no attempt was made at a quantitative separation of the roots from the soil, some may have been over 1 Alway, F. J. Moisture Studies of Semiarid Soils. Report of Winni - peg meeting of the British Association for the Advancement of Science. 1909, p. 699. Photograph reproduced in WidUoe's "Dry Farming," 1911, p. 96. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Research Bulletin No, S 38 looked, the soil in the lower portion of all the cylinders being The stopper of III was removed and the cylinder left in a ver - tical position for 16 hours before opening, but no seepage oc - curred. In the case of VIII the nipple carrying the rubber stopper was found to have been broken off in placing the cylinder in the pit. Accordingly, the half inch opening had remained only partly closed by the rough board on which the cylinder rested; yet the soil was as moist as that in VII. From the conduct of these two cylinders it appears probable that no loss of water by seepage would have taken place even if the glass plugs had been left out of the stoppers thruout the experiment. The data on the experiment are summarized in Table 6, and the moisture conditions at the time of opening the cylinders, and hence at the time the wheat plants died, are shown in Tables 7 and 8. Figures 4 and 5 Rhow the relation of the final water content of the different cylinders to the hygroscopic coefficient, to the wilting coefficient, and to the initial water content of the soil. The initial water content shown in the figures is the average for the six feet and does not at all indicate the initial water eon - tent of the individual foot sections, this not being known. The initial moisture content varied a little from cylinder to cylinder and accordingly on the figures "the initial water content" as shown is not accurate for any one cylinder but is approximately correct for all four. The soils in the check cylinders III and VI, even at the close of the experiment, after having lost about 7 and 3.5 per cent water, were wetter than such soils are found under field condi - tions on uplands, even where conditions have been most favor - able for saturating the soil and subsoil. Thus the soil in the lower two feet of III carried about twice as much water as would have been found in the field. This large amount of water pres - ent at the beginning had permitted a continuous upward move - ment of water thruont the experiment, there still being a con siderable amount of free water even in the second and third incli sections. Tn the case of the three cylinders of eastern Nebraska soil which bore plants, nothing striking is to be observed. The mois - ture content increased from the surface downward. In the first foot it had been reduced below the hygroscopic coefficient, being lowest in VII on which the crop had been harvested last. The statement of the free water is no more striking than that of the total water. The dryness of the surface foot is to be attributed to direct evaporation. The data on these three cylinders furnish no evidence of the ability of the roots of the maturing wheat to re - duce the soil moisture below the wilting coefficient. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 «n»* ■wo I -|§2S 3l^2§ |f 3 3 Si 3 I IT \ a °c ... . . . . . 5 °Jas- ;•! ; : ; ; i ; 1 s a - s s M«-&lt; _^5 i §1 ion M £ ?. •- 1 Nona — « — inrtO s g Ss 1 g i * ! a o s»-.l I i 2 2 &amp; 2 1-1 t~^^fo''^f I «« — -5 s ■ ft -m * 1 1 1 !l if ■ I M-I ■r - o fe f fi ill s 2? J I = ts * -s E e '■'■■** 1 ifl J ■ ::.■■ s c Jit* i :iH I ■ M 1 a 3 § r^ JJi«|l tHui Si 1 ■' ' 1 1 - o iiiiiiiflliii 1} 4HM**h : T'-T' - - = =■■ 2® II -s^ tot^-Hco 2=° "'feSjS r&lt;,n a-v-rn m n «o — o •* - ■* ".&lt;= *.". 5Ip2 M^»S S&gt;&gt; ■* ® e* o - NN 5^^9 ... -W -H » 00 WD OS c = .5 I </seg>
            <seg id="p040">ri t : ; _ 5 J _ S o p»«^ -ci»^ ♦ •« »» i-ess om«« t~;t^r~;"5 tc p« u &gt;6 ■* 'pi i-r^t^c: si««~ c-ft^x sxacs xjhh -» to J j^ I — — — — — «« ««^— NNSM I "&lt; : i_i C ■* ""?'* ns*k — os — p »-*s)— — nxn — « . — *- o ic«— * -i i» d c-orcrc ■^■■■I'sdso 06 r^ to K OOOOJ * ■• ■ u 1 — — — — c* M — I ••* i c C p t^ * i^ ■(•";•": *% — ®pjn — — ?itt &amp;■*•■*"£: coo;*— oe e« '" '" js 1 i i a - 7 6 m 8 "■ P °? ": cj — xq t» »c ~&lt; :*: c^oqs aos«fi oonco^; p ■* I &gt; h^^S — lS '-li'~i 225^ 5S22SJ °' c^?j?5 " i^^"' — § * I R I ■ • I s. . ■•! ;■;-■"♦ sees ----- ***» •*»• «*«!« ~ £g ssiddo «-«- iok-cb; »^k« rcnMj; nnnn • ~ ■ h - Jt — J e -x» 'C'cnx oaas h«99 nnms n « --.fe - — S NNMN SSom jiBBM BMM5) (K | | &gt; « 252^ 5SSS SSiS SSSS BBSS "" k 0C 'S * S *NH TKMS NNMM NOHN »OO-« ««*O N, "5 g H &gt; fc « ».«&gt;ej 225SS SS : Sg 3 = ???2 3?SU S1§SS§ * 9 F SSSS SSi?S S?SS55 S^c?§ SSSS; S ?? I -2 N &gt;OaCN^ NQM« »N«5a h^NQ »«»- N h .2 |-e!i4ri&lt;i £&lt;&amp;&amp;&amp; tiiciJ £&lt;&amp;&lt;hi, 23^6 J. ci ■g — — — — fa nnmm «*■*■* -*ioii5Ss eitoN 9 •: i 9 "s - r .. .. ., . . ■ 3 1, ii </seg>
            <seg id="p041">■■" '" — £ « p-^«i c^Np-; KJi-ffi xpc— ro&lt;NW?r "- — xrc « x c in tt — d •»•«•«»» « — — — d — --d dddd cddd ?i d JB I i I I I I c 1 I 1 E ?i t;~— "■= ~ p i^i-c:"^ — ic — m h-&gt;o«p — — w &gt;e — ■«■ * 5 — i « *" J3 c ■* «« d •*-*iri«5 r,t^i^^ ajt^t^x x'x x'x ?i •■= 5 E M 5 * ?1 — l~ — NX^I- J^ICO hiCfjS O&gt; « OS O — tri •» i- /- - &gt;*-— ; S *V W &lt;|«S !tt5t» ***t BI.*!!) **♦♦ ««•&lt;•&lt; £ — I xz'ii izxic CCO9 es'oiai n^nn n^nn ! V « 1|t^ COXC: SCM^ rtMNN r^sOeCr-- cCC*- ~ — „ HI -tnX OOAOi -i « oddd t^ r^ r^ h^ t^ oc r^ i- •- ai * | r g 05 qsc — ■*t~;X — — me; ■*aq^io &gt;-&lt;a&gt;r&gt;.*f; NNijtc y. c ■* totcx cood cifin-" dodo oioo'ooac oc'ceoc'^ &lt;e c&gt; 1 C r* p49&lt;{ 'X. 0k r^. *r c:^'-&lt;C^ pcoosO t^ecec^f rch-ococ w « _ ?c ic cd oi V *c cp to «t^«'r^ *6»O4r:4c icicicir: « »c jaN";?!^ osh&lt;: ©ccr&gt;.p okkici «««■* netee » us j^SSSS ?I?JSS SSSS SSSS 8888 SS?S?S 3 8 1 I X •* *? -h-^m« MMcycy "P*?"?^ *^ r* s cs^t^o cico'ffoi icafc^i" NQrttc Oic^»cac — c&amp; k*, — NM«W CO^r*«*''«J" CC«tD^ m r- ■s 1 M z. 1 i . I ii x -i </seg>
            <seg id="p042">I 42 Research Bulletin .Vo. 3 Very different from the above are the data on the three cylin - ders of seniiarid soil. In the first foot alone were the conditions similar to those in the three cylinders of humid soil, the drying dne to direct evaporation having extended to the bottom of the surface foot. Below the first foot conditions were very different. There was no regular rise in moisture content with increasing depth, it rising and falling independently of the depth. The nioistnrc in the four 3-inch sections of each foot was uniform within the limits of experimental error. Here the statement of the free water is instructive. In I and IV, which had produced the heaviest crops, the moisture in the different foot sections below the surface foot had been reduced almost to the hygro - scopic coefficient, viz, to 1.4 per cent of free water in I and to 0.8 per cent in IV. In II. which had not produced as heavy a crop, the moisture content was considerably (6.7 per cent) above the hygroscopic coefficient and the moisture rose slightly from the surface downward. In all three the roots had penetrated freely to the very bottom of the cylinders, being found even in^the sand layer. When the soil moisture had run low the roots seem to have drawn quite uniformly on the free water in the different The data given on line 12 of Table 6 on the loss of water per gram of dry matter of crop produced include the water lost by direct evaporation from the soil as well as that transpired. A satisfactory correction for the amount lost by direct evaporation cannot be' made from the data on hand. It is certainly consider - ably below that lost from the implanted cylinders. The great difference between the two unplanted cylinders is to he at - tributed, at least in part, to the marked difference in water ca - pacity of the soils they contained, while the initial total moisture content was very similar in both. The water transpired per unit of dry matter produced lies between the very wide limits of 518 and 934. The yields of grain calculated to an acre basis are interesting, those on the semiarid soil being 26. 30. and 41 bushels and on the humid soil 6. 7, and 10 bushels. Rnch a result could not be obtained in the field on a deep, well-drained semiarid soil Eilar to that used, unless water were added during the growth he crop, for the reason that so much water would not be held he surface six feet. 1 On the H O Ranch, 200 yards from where the semiarid soil wa* obtained, there was a young orchard which had been kept in clean cultivation for 3 years. On November 21, 1907, the soil con- 1 It should be emphasized in this connection that 6 feet is not the limit of root penetration for wheat on all semiarid soils where free water in considerable quantity extends to a greater depth. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">" F*3 I i .1 u H o I s o -r 1 -.1 ?I V &lt; o VI *l 3 -• o — S IO I! noit rune c o Fig. 4. Final moisture coi ao ms 5o NTCNT IN CMCtNT nditions in cylinders of humid soil. ■^9 N N \ 1 \ s. i I I F ,1 0 It I H .*». '• 4 M I- -J 5 r j \ s 10 I M 0 ( S TU RE C INTENT ;n P£(t Cent n Final moisture com ltiong in cylinders of semiar: .. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Research Bulh'tiit \&lt;&gt;. 1 tained an average of 17.8 per cent total water and had a hygro - scopic coefficient of 7.6. In the adjacent prairie a shallow pit. 12 feet in diameter, was dug on November 9, 1907. During the fol - lowing four days 28 inches of water was added. Ten days later the first six feet contained 21.1 per cent total water and at the end of the following April, the surface having been protected from evaporation in the interval, it contained 17.3 per cent total water — much the same as the soil of the adjacent orchard. Thus the same depth of soil in the cylinders with a quite similar hygro - scopic coefficient, averaging 8.5, contained about 25 per cent free water while similar soil in the field, both when saturated by fallowing and when saturated by irrigation, contained only about 10 per cent free water. On the Experiment Station farm, part of a young orchard had been kept in clean cultivation for ten years. In the most moist soil that was found in this field the total water in the first 6 feet was 2ti.l per cent, with an average hygroscopic coefficient of 11.9, while the humid soil in the cylinders contained about 35 per cent total water and had an average hygroscopic coefficient of 12.8. Summary of experiment. — At the time the seeds were planted the cylinders of semiarid soil carried more than twice as much water as the same soil would have retained under field conditions, while the cylinders of humid soil carried at least one-fourth more than the same soil in the field would have retained. The loss of water — wholly by direct evaporation — from the two unplanted cylinders during the four months of the experiment was equiva - lent to about 5.fl inches of rainfall in the case of the semiarid soil and to 2.5 inches in that of the humid soil. Normal plants were produced on both soils and the yields of grain, calculated to an acre basis, exceeded 25 bushels on the semiarid soil bat were less than 11 bushels on the humid soil, the former being much higher than could be expected from the same depth of sub - soil under field conditions, because of the excessive quantity of free water at the time of planting. In no case, however, was the proportion of grain to straw or the loss of soil water per unit weight of dry matter produced more favorable than might be expected in the field. The plants on the semiarid soil made a much greater growth and rooted much more deeply. They also made a more economi - cal use of the soil water than did those on the humid soil ; how - ever, this economy may have been due entirely to a smaller evaporation from the cylinders of semiarid soil. After the plants had matured there was a marked difference between the semiarid and the humid soil in the moisture condition of the subsoil but not in that of the surface foot. The transpiration of water from </seg>
            <seg id="p045">I'i hit ion of \onnrailablr Water to Hygroscojiu- l'i&gt;f/ficient 45 the semiarid soil was lowered by reducing the foliage of the plants, but the depth of penetration of the roots wag not thereby lessened. The final water content of the humid subsoil in this experi - ment bore no relation to either the wilting coefficient or the hy - groscopic coefficient. In the two cylinders of semiarid soil in which there was barely enough water to mature seed there was a direct dependence of the final water content upon the hygroscojiit - coefficient, the former being only a little above the latter. In the seiniarid subsoil in which roots were well developed, the final content of free water was independent of the distance of the sub - soil from the surface, except in one cylinder, and in this there remained an abundance of free water even after the death of the plants. In the latter the free water content increased slightly with the distance from the surface. In all 6 of the cylinders which bore plants a hard crust de - veloped under the surface mulch but appeared to have no in - jurious effect on the plants. GROWTH OF CROP PLANTS WITH DIFFERENT AMOUNTS OF WATER IN THE SUBSOIL. EXPERIMENT OF 1910. The 22 metal cylinders used in this experiment were of the same material, form, and dimensions as those employed in 1909. After being filled, 2 were left unplanted, 6 were planted to Red Fife wheat, 0 to Kubanka wheat. 6 to milo, and 2 to Mexican pink beans. The 20 were planted on February 5, the two un - planted cylinders like the others being provided with a one-inch mulch of dry soil. All the cylinders, as soon as the mulch of air - dry soil had been added, were removed to the greenhouse and sunken in a rectangular pit four feet deep. The portions above the surface were enclosed by planks and banked up with soil as shown in figure 6, thus protecting all but the surface 3 to 6 inches from the heat of the direct rays of the sun and the rapidly varying air temperatures. (When the photograph was taken some of the soil was removed from the sides so as to show the numbers on the cylinders.) Beginning near the middle of March a record was kept of the daily maximum and minimum temperatures and of the evapora - tion from a free water surface. A little later a record of the humidity wae begun. While the humidity did not differ much from that in the open air, the maximum daily temperature on more than half the days exceeded 100° F. and the experiment was finally cut short by a temperature of 124° F. on June 12. (Table 4.) This temperature in itself would not have been fatal to the plants had the soil moisture not already been reduced to such a </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Research Bulletin Xo. 3 low point. Sixteen pots with maize plants from 3 to 4 feet high in the same greenhouse and only a few feet from the cylinder! thruout the day remained uninjured but they had been liberally watered early in the morning of June 12. Xo whitewash was used on the windows of the greenhouse. As in the experiment of the preceding year, a close watch was kept for the development of any crevice between soil column and cylinder wall, and as soon as one appeared loose surface soil was at (ince worked down into it. Later, when the cylinders were opened, it was found that no crevices had extended below twelve inches, and all were full of surface soil. Accordingly there had been no opportunity for direct evaporation from the sides of the ■ columns. In order to maintain a good mulch in some of the nders, it was necessary, on account of a portion of the orig - inal mulch having been worked down into these crevices, to add more dry surface soil, amounting to from 300 to 500 grams, the amounts being recorded at the time and included in the totals given in Tables 11, 13. 15, and 17. Xo soil crust formed below the mulch in the unplanted cylinders but in all the others a very hard crust had developed by the end of the second month after planting. As soon as the plants in a cylinder died they were removed, the cylinder opened as soon as convenient and the moisture of ksoil determined. The roots in the different foot sections of subsoil were separated out. photographed, dried, and weighed. The experiments were much simpler in so far as the soils were concerned than those of the preceding year. Only semiarid soil, again from the H O Ranch, was used and this consisted of only three bulk lots, namely, the first fi inches, the second 6 inches, and a composite subsoil referred to hereafter as "H O Subsoil." The last was taken from the fourth, fifth, and sixth feet in an excavation made in the prairie field from which the soils used in 1908 and 1009 had been secured. After this sub - soil reached the Experiment Station it was thoroly mixed, while dry. by shoveling, passed thru an eighth-inch screen, and airain mixed. This subsoil was not onlv representative of the subsoils of an important dry land area of the state but it was such that it could be placed in the cylinders so as to be very similar to the condition in which it occurs naturally. Extensive studies of this soil in pits and borings on the H O Ranch, as well as in va - rious other cylinder experiments, have shown that there is a very close resemblance between the condition of the soil, both in the wet and in the dry state, in cylinders and the condition of it in the field. 1 I 1 A fuller description of the properties of the "H O Subsoil" Is given p. 249 of the article by Alway and Clark, referred to on p. 2S. </seg>
            <seg id="p047"/>
            <seg id="p048">48 As only three different soils were used in the '2'2 cylinders and as these had been thoroly mixed, the determination of the hygroscopic coefficients was a simple matter. The most inter est attaches to the subsoil and of this a very large number of de - terminations were made, the average being 5.6. The values for the first 6-inch and the second 6-inch samples are 9.:? and 11.0 respectively. FILLING THE CYLINDERS. In all the 22 cylinders when filled there were only three differ - ent soils, the soil below the first foot being uniform, except for a layer of coarse sand weighing 400 grams and about three - fourths of an inch in thickness, which was placed in the bottom of each cylinder in order to facilitate drainage. The method of applying water used in 1908 and 190*1 was not employed in this experiment for the reason that it left in the soil after seepage had ceased so very much more water than the same soil under dry-land field conditions would carry. Ten of the cylinders were filled with air-dry soil, after which enough water warn added to give the desired total amount. The other 12 were filled with moist subsoil, water being added, after the filling, only to moisten the surface foot. Germinated seeds wtm planted in all but 2 of the cylinders on the same day. these 2 being left implanted. Ten, I to X, were filled with dry soil in much the same way as in 1909. all except the surface inch being added with tamping. The weight of each of the three kinds of soil used for each cylin - der, as well as the percentage of moisture in each, was determined and from these data there was calculated the amount of water contained in the air-dry soil of each cylinder; then enough water was added to each to make the total amount present equal to 25 per cent of the dry weight of the surface foot and 18 per cent of the dry weight of the subsoil. During the adding of the water, which lasted over several days, the tops of the cylinders were kept covered to prevent evaporation and the glass plugs were removed from the one-hole rubber stoppers. As soon as all the added water had soaked into the soil, the glass plugs were re - turned, the cylinders were weighed and placed in the pit in the greenhouse, germinated seeds were planted one inch deeo in the moist soil, and the final inch of dry surface soil added. No seep - age had occurred in the case of any of these before the plugs were inserted and doubtless none would have occurred if the plugs had been left out. For the 12 cylinders in which the subsoil was moistened be - fore being placed in the cylinder, eight lots of prepared subsoil were used. Each lot of moist subsoil was prepared by placing a </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Ktlation of Xonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 49 n?d quantity of the air-dry soil, of which the moisture oon - ad been determined, on a smooth cement floor and adding the calculated amount of water in small j&gt;ortions while the mass was being shoveled over. The whole was mixed thoroly, first by shoveling, then by passing it twice thru a swinging sieve of one - fourth-inch mesh, and finally by again shoveling the mass thoroly. The moist soil thus prepared was immediately placed in a large covered can in which it was kept until transferred to the cylinders. The moisture percentages reported in the tallies are those actually found in the soil after it had been mixed and placed in the large cans; thus, for example, where it was desired to obtain a series of moist subsoils containing 0.0, 10.0, 14.0, and 18.0 per cent of water, there was obtained instead a series with 5.8, 9.8, 14.1, and 18.2 per cent respectively. Solid instead of one-hole rubber stoppers were placed in the drainage nipples of these 12 cylinders before the filling was be - gun. A small amount of the subsoil was added at a time and tamped before adding more. When a cylinder was filled to within twelve inches of the top all of the second 6-inch bulk sam - ple, and also all of the first 6-inch bulk sample, except the final inch, was added with constant tamping. The two portions of the surface foot were added in an air-dry condition. Then using the method described on page 48 there was added the amount of water required to raise the total moisture content of the surface foot to 20 per cent. When the water had soaked away the cylin - ders were placed in the pit in the greenhouse, the seed planted, and the final inch of air-dry soil added. SEPARATION OF ROOTS FROM THE SIBSOII.. I As the subsoil was very dry in most of the cylinders, it was f to screen out the roots. In the case of each 3-inch section, &gt;r a pint sample, to be used for the moisture determination, had been placed in a jar, the rest was passed thru an eighth-inch screen. The portion of the section placed in the jar was not thus screened, but as it was being transferred to the jar a care - ful watch for roots was maintained. Where the soil was too moist to pass readily thru the screen, as in the lower part of cylinder VIII, it was allowed to stand in a jar of water for a few hours and then washed thru the screen, using a jet of water. All the roots thus secured from the four 3-inch sections of each foot were placed in a jar of 2 per cent formaldehyde and left until all the cylinders had been opened. Finally the roots were washed on a screen in running water, carefully separated from other organic residues, placed on disks of black filter paper, and photographed. Then they were dried and weighed. No at - tempt was made to separate the roots from the surface foot of </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 soil. As mh| tha notes on each 3 inch section, recorded at the time of opening the cylinders, mention was always made of the relative abundance of roots, there are three checks on the rela - tive root development in each foot section, viz, these notes, the photographs, and the weight of dry matter in the roots. In a few instances where the presence of a very few fine roots was recorded in the notes, the roots were lost in the subsequent operations be- fore the photographs w&lt; Iinders the subsoil 1 pen. nearly all the r. before pliotojjrnp Vrent foot sections in one by one and re While, if or the purp would have been i hed to the plant, si irh was designed ei tribution of the ni ion of the quantit ondary consideratioi ere taken. As previous to the filling of the had all been passed thru an eighth-inch old roots had thus been removed. How- ihing them the root fragments from the &lt; were gone over with forceps, handling pjeeting all that did not appear fresh. pose of securing photographs of the roots, desirable to leave them intact and at- uich was not feasible in this experiment, ■specially to secure accurate data on the il moisture in short sections, the deterim- tative distribution of the roots being a in. Tabi.k 9.— Cu ylindera used in 1910 experiment. &lt;«- Crop Free water at time of planting Surface Subsoil I foot to 6 ft. Date of death of Date of open- last plant ing cylinder XIV xv XVI XVII Mexican beans. . Mexican beans. Milo Milo Red Fife wheat Red Fife wheat . Kubanka wheat.. Kubanka wheat. . No crop No crop Kubanka wheat. MUo Red Fife wheat Red Fife wheat. . Kubanka wheat. . Milo Kubanka wheat.. MUo Red Fife wheat Red Fife wheat . MUo Kubanka wheat. . I'er rent 14.9 14&lt;t 14.9 14.9 14.9 14.9 14.9 14.9 14.9 14.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 9.9 v Per cent 12.4 12.4 124 12.4 12.4 12.4 12.4 12.4 12.4 12.4 0.2 0.2 0.2 4.2 4.2 4.2 7.8 8.5 7.4 11.5 12.6 12.2 May U May Vi May 13* June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 May 9 May 13 May 9 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 14 June 21 June 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Relation of Xonavailablr Wmttr to ffffpPMMpfa Coefficient 51 I Table 9 gives a summary of the initial moisture conditions the different cylinders, of the crops grown, and of the dati I of ■vesting the crops and o|&gt;ening the cylinders. \ CYLINDERS WITHOUT PLANTS. {These were left undisturbed from the time that they were red in the greenhouse until they were removed from the pit opened, except from time to time to examine them by means :i spatula for the formation of a crevice along the cylinder 1 and To test them by means of a sharp pointed stick, for the sence of a crust under the surface mulch. No crevice formed I no hard crust was found, altho when the cylinders were ned on May 13 a crust was beginning to form in each. tAs shown in Table 10. the percentage of total moisture in - ised steadily from the surface to the bottom of the first foot, »re there was a sudden drop from 22 per cent to 13 per cent, im this point on down it increased steadily to the bottom of subsoil, where it reached 21 per cent. There was practically same moisture content at corresponding depths in the two nders. The surface foot was much drier than in the experi - lt in !!•&lt;&gt;!&gt; and much less water had been lost by evaporation. MOIST URC CONTCHT IN PlRClNT Fig. 7. Final moisture conditions in ten cylinders with the moiatest sur- </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 \\ bilp the amount 01 added water had not been enough to cause it to seep from the bottom of the cylinder, it was enough to have supersaturated the soil if it had been under field conditions. The moisture relations are shown in figure 7. BED FIFE WHEAT. »The seed used was from one of the plants grown on semiarid 1 in the experiment of 1909. Ten seeds were planted in each the 6 cylinders on February 5; 23 days later, when the plants were from 4 to 12 inches high, they were thinned to the most vigorous 4 in each cylinder. No further thinning was practiced, except in the case of VI. from which 3 plants were removed on April 27. The thinnings were dried and the weights included in those of the total dry matter reported in Table 11. Little differ - ence between the plants in the six cylinders was observed until the end of the first month. A summary of the data of the experiment is given in Table 12 and the moisture conditions in the soil at the death of the plants are shown in Table 11 and in figures 7 to 11. Figure 12 shows the condition of the plants on April 23 and on June 8 re - spectively. The roots separated from the different foot sections of the subsoil are shown in figure 13. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">* Relation of Xonacailablr Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 53 Table 10. — Moisture conditions on opening unplanted cylinders, experiment of 1910. IX X Cram* Weight of dry soil and subsoil in cylinder. Weight of water in cylinder, Feb. 5 . Weight of water in cylinder, May 13 Weight of water lost in 97 days 43,412 I2.M3 8,216 8,102 7,403 813 Per cent of total water in surface foot of soil, Feb. 5 . Per cent of total water in subsoil, Feb. 5 25.0 25.0 18.0 18.0 Per cent of total water in surface foot of soil, May 13 . Per cent of total water in subsoil, May 13 ... f 14.8 14.5 17.4 16.7 •eptl h ol ■ section ection Tota 'otal il' water Free 'ree water In feet Ii In inches n inches 1-3 4 5-6 7-9 10-12 IX Per cent 3.8 7.6 14.8 20.4 22.5 X \W cent 3.9 7.3 14.5 20.2 22.0 IX Percent -5.5 — 1.7 - 5.5 9.4 11.5 t I' 1 I ' 1 13-15 16-18 19-21 22-24 13.1 13.6 13.5 14.2 12.6 13.1 13.4 13.8 7.5 8.0 7.9 8.6 I 3 i 25-27 28-30 31-33 34-36 14.8 15.1 15.6 16.4 14.4 14.7 15.4 16.0 9.2 9.5 10.0 10.8 I! I I &lt; ( 37-39 40-42 43-45 46-48 16.7 17.1 17.6 17.5 16.3 16.4 16.9 17.1 11.1 11.5 12.0 11.9 i I I 49-51 52-54 5.5-57 58-60 17.5 18.2 18.2 19.3 17.5 17.7 17.5 18.7 11.9 12.6 12.6 13 7 121 11.9 12.1 61-63 64-66 67-69 20.5 21.2 21.5 19.9 21.0 20.9 14.9 15.6 15.9 fe Average . . 1-12 14.8 14.5 4.6 « Average . . . . 13-69 16.9 16.5 11.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Research Bulhtin ¥©. J 54 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p055">■^ ■e iG tr. ; -^ E! *■: *°. "^ s\ f t"»f«tC l~- 1~ t— -&gt; MMM - * •—I "^ . ,- .- — ; ~* -i I I !- 3 W kCXH^f b» Q 1^- O ?C — OlNiOX rt^N CO r5 CC^''^''^' CD^OtO n I x :- = if Zi £ ■* P r-: in 1 'P e&lt; ■• "9 •" • ■*««■* '-'s ■* ■* ■* "O « •&gt;■ « B &gt;t7tfl ! S 5 ♦ *! ■* • "fl i- q — p — w«r&lt; «xp* *'•'* 1 ■* i Si c* :o © N to M U5 ts »^c^— p — -&lt;r •g w C ITT i I I "13 I £ I I I I I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Research Bulletin \o S 56 HoiSru Rt IN PtR C L.NT C ONTCNT »8. Final moisture conditions in cylinders which contained only 0.2 per cent free water in the subsoil when planted. Fig. 9. Final moisture conditions in cylinders which contained 4 per cent free water in the subsoil when planted. s '•^ fc J .8 s ! s 4 c LC6END MILO Clfl K" i KUBAMKA CVt XI ♦♦■»«• RCOfirc CYLXIII s! </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Relation of Xonacailable Water to Hygroxcopic Coefficient 57 Mcisr urn r Cowtcmt IN Pc fi CE h t Fig. 10. Final moisture conditions In cylinders which contained 8 per cent free water In the subsoil when planted. Fig. 11. Final moisture conditions In cylinders which contained 12 per cent free water in the subsoil when planted. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Cylinder with so free water in the sibsoil. — Cylinder XI 11 was filled with subsoil containing 5.8 per cent total water. This is practically the hygroscopic coefficient and accordingly the subsoil contained practically no free water. On the subsoil was placed eleven inches of air-dry surface soil having an average hygroscopic coefficient of 10.1 and enough water was added to raise the average percentage of total water in the surface foot to 20. Some experiments 1 carried out later indicate that practi - cally the whole of this added water would be held within the sur - face twelve inches, allowing only a very little to pass by capillar - ity into the uppermost portion of the subsoil. IV VI XX XIX XIV XIII 12. Red Fife wheat 77 and 123 days after planting; experiment of 1910. The plants in this cylinder did as well as those in the five other cylinders until the fifth week, after which they rapidly fell behind. They made no growth after March 12. On March 18, after three days with high temperatures in the greenhouse, all four plants wilted and did not afterwards fully recover. None formed a tiller or put forth a spike. Their condition on April 23 is shown in figure 12. They grew steadily worse but were ' Analogous to those described by Alway and Clark, Twenty-fifth An - nual Report of the Nebraska Experiment Station. 1912, p. 285. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">1 entirely dead until May 13. The cylinder was opened on date. No free water wan present in the surface soil and ? was practically none in the subsoil. The former contained Eper cent free water and the latter 0.4 per cent. The only that had entered the subsoil extended about two inches be - the surface foot. They are shown in figure 13. The dry er in these roots amounted to 0.003 gram. IThe explanation of the lack of difference in growth during first month is evident from the al&gt;ove. As long as the plants in all six cylinders had their roots confined to the surface foot of soil, all had about equally favorable conditions and made V VI XX XIX XIV XIII Pig. 13. Roots of Red Fife wheat; experiment of 1910. similar growth, but as soon as the roots were developed to the bottom of the surface foot the plants in XIII fell behind the others; the roots did not penetrate the subsoil on account of the absence in it of free water. The final dryness of the subsoil as a tole was due simply to its not having had any water to give up the plants, while that of the surface soil was due j&gt;artly to the loss thru transpiration but chiefly to direct evaporation. The in- Pise of 0.2 per cent in the average moisture content in the five of subsoil may be due to a slight distillation from the moist face soil early in the ex]&gt;erinient. but it is probably rather to considered within the limits of the experimental error. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Research Hullrtin Xo. 3 The prodnction of dry matter for the water lost was very low— only one part for 1315 parts of water, or the equivalent of one ton of dry matter for 11.5 inches of rain. Cylinders with 4 per cent free water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XIV was filled like XIII, except that a moist subsoil with 4.2 per cent free water was used. After the first month the plants in this did better than those in XIII, but poorer than those in any of the other cylinders. On March 18. 2 of the 4 plants wilted and did not afterwards fully recover, altho they remained alive until the middle of May. The other 2 plants did not wilt until April 3, following three days of high temperatures in the greenhouse. Both recovered and on April 30 the one plant hod 2 tillers and the other 3 ; the latter died during the latter part of May, while the former put a spike part way out of the sheath but gave no promise of further development. It was already dying on June 11 — the day before that on which the temperature in the greenhouse rose to 124° F. Two days later this plant was quite dead, having formed no grain, and the cylinder was opened. The surface foot of soil contained no free water (really — 4.1 per cent) while the free water in the subsoil rose steadily from 0.0 in the upper half of the second foot to 2.1 per cent in the lower part of the sixth foot, averaging 1.4 per cent thruout the sub - soil. Roots were found in all levels of the subsoil, but they were scarce in the fifth foot and only a very few small ones were found in the sixth foot. There was still an appreciable of free water in the lower part of the cylinder, but the root de - velopment was not such as to permit of its rapid absorption. Except in the sixth foot the moisture content was below the wilt - ing coefficient. It is possible that under favorable weather con - ditions — cool, cloudy, humid weather — or with a more extensive root development the one plant might have formed some seed. The moisture content of the subsoil was still 1.4 per cent above that of cylinder V and 1.0 per cent above that of cylinder XIX. in neither of which the last plant had yet died, but was 1.2 per cent below the wilting coefficient. It is of interest to observe that the four plants did not all die, or even wilt, simultaneously, but that two acted independ - ently of the other two and of one another, as tho they drew their water supply from different parts of the soil column. This is a good illustration of the difficulty of attempting in the field to decide nj&gt;on the moisture content of the soil corresponding to the wilting point or to the death point. One of these four plants continued to grow and develop for some 80 days after two had permanently wilted and these two continued alive for nearly two months after so wilting. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Relation of .\ onacn ilabk ITafcr I; Hygroscopic Coefficient 61 Cylinder with 7 per cam kuee water ix the subsoil. — Cylinder XIX was filled like XIII and XIV, except that moist subsoil containing 13.0 per cent total water — 7.4 per cent free water — was used. All the plants did well until near the end of March, the four plants having 8 tillers on March 28. About the middle of April two of the plants began to die and were dead by June 11. The other two continued to develop until they had put three spikes part way out of the sheath. By June 8 they had ceased to grow but were still alive when June 12 arrived. The one spike bore three shrunken grains, while the other two bore none. The moisture conditions in both the surface foot and the subsoil were like those in XIII— with negative free moisture ( — 4.3 per cent) in the former and practically none (0.2 per cent) in the latter. The subsoil was uniformly dry at the different depths. There was a fair development of roots to the very bot - tom of the subsoil. In this cylinder also the plants perished independently of one another. Cylinder with 12 per cent free water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XX differed from XIX in that it was filled with moist soil containing 11.5 per cent free water. All four plants in this did well until the end of April when the four plants had 11 tillers in all. One plant began to die. but the other three continued to grow. They all wilted on May 17 but recovered and put forth 4 spikes which were not yet ripe on June 11. The high tempera - ture of the following day killed all the plants. The earliest spike bore 6 shrunken grains. The surface foot contained — 3.8 per cent free water and the subsoil an average of 1.5 per cent, it being quite uniformly distributed. Roots occurred thruout the sub - soil, but in the lower foot sections they were much less numerous than in XTX. Two cylinders with MOisTER son. near the surface. — -Cylin - ders V and VI were filled with air-dry subsoil and surface soil and then to the surface was added the amount of water required to make the total weight of water in the cylinders equal to 18 per cent of the weight of the dry subsoil plus 25 per cent of that of the dry surface soil. The total amount of moisture in V and VI waa almost the same as that in XX — 8,076 and 8,007 grams against 8,060 grams — but the distribution of this thruout the soil mass was quite different. The plants in V and VI made the most vigorous growth of all. On March 26 the plants in both cylinders suffered some slight injury from mice. On April 27 the 4 plants in the former had 19 tillers and those in the latter had 20. On that date there were removed from VI three plants having 11 tillers, thus leaving </seg>
            <seg id="p062">■ Research Bulletin No. S one with 9. The weight of dry matter in the three plants was 4.3 grams. On May 17 the plants in both wilted, the one in VI suffering as much as the four in V. At no time after the thinning of April 27 did the plant in VI appear thriftier than the plants in V. None put forth a spike and all were nearly dead before June 12. The cylinders were opened on June 14. In VI the moisture conditions in both surface soil and subsoil were practi - cally indentical with those in XIX, while the subsoil was very slightly drier in V. Roots were very extensively and uniformly distributed thruout the soil mass. Figure 13 shows well the extent of the development of the roots in both. The weight of roots in the subsoil of both V and VI waB three times as great as that of the roots in the subsoil of XIX. The plants in V and VI, having started with about the same amount of soil moisture and having formed a better developed root system, had made a much less economical use of the soil water, practically exhaust - ing it before putting forth spikes, than had those in XIX. KUBANKA WHEAT. A series of fi cylinders, corresponding to those used for the Red Fife wheat, was planted on the same day with Eubanka wheat, ten seeds being used for each. On February 28, when the plants were from 4 to 9 inches high, they were thinned to the most vigorous four in each cylinder. No further thinning was intentionally practiced, but on March 26, mice ate off. almost level with the surface, one plant in VI T and one in VIII. Both later put forth tillers. As with the Red Fife wheat, little differ - ence in growth was to be observed during the first month. Tables 13 and 14 give the data and figures 14 and 15 show the condition of the plants and the distribution of roots in the sub- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">1 X 1-2-S "' 2 5"mS S = 888 c r-«d--M«««» ■« fig cVe- 5533 a" oo 33s sss8s a «i2s-aaasis-- II s^**- x 3* r.-" = " co SSl SS3S8 S »'2222'22222 o! 5 || S*"'" * - 583S a «&gt; ooo 23i |8888 S 9=-. -«« • : ■ : • fcfc §"S5 X o&gt; 000 oo-. 2SBS5 S i^»»o&gt;a&gt;o&gt;» : : : : : »* o«««: ! s 2 •::St:E:* io . «■:« t -3ES a 9 m 000000 = 3 = 003 oqno 5-WS53 S" OS 332 S.lSoS S »»=222232S22 II «2«*2 -&lt; SM 3 M 3 JL JL &gt; 55'-?-s ooo =2S Soils ?; «=»=s^s^s^ g| as— 1 I 5 i 1 SIS 1 all 1 ;|ij= Jj^d ; iJlllillllil ; : hii ill4i Hit ilpi I HHilliilil ft III! tiiiWtlH ill!! | iiillilllill i! \\l\ §^^if ijmi gnu 1 iiiiiiiiiiii || mi j 1 1 i i ! : -: i J </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 2 { fi n . n .~~.~. ■■=■-= — — sosjoo toxifflas tossfflo eco — — a a a — -- &gt;« in &gt;.- «: m «j &gt;o ui us «j uj «j « « j hj viuiui o &gt;6 5 '■"^-? 3 ? ««»» «.-«-&lt; t-X-O XOO M 5 fe i iT77 — "" N:&lt;5 «'»' &lt;owwt- t&gt;:t-:xx xoiai -* io ■*&gt; * I I ! I I « ! r S&lt;5?S q=; "!^"!"S ■*«;»» ®pqx x-ioc-* t~x^. a, ■c _i &gt; S*|^^^^ «cxxo io^;a&gt;io -*&lt;=&gt;o m q I E I i ■ S "I °!^ ®. °i oq — "flos rot&gt;-«!O •*t~t^«&gt; «&gt;t^o&gt;o •*a&gt;m oo o - «*■■.-; &lt;O'6t^*i ooaoaibi oioJdd --in m x I 5 §WOSOM(N MO^-h pnC)^^ COINING WNOw -h^h^ * - &gt; £ i i i i i i 7 j I | J- -^s sssa £ssa fcss? sssl ssi - s I 1 1 j j j I I ; II I </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Ix'i hit ion of Xonaca liable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 65 K Cylinder with no fbek water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XI &lt; filled, like XIIT, with subsoil containing 5.8 per cent total water. The four plants in this fell behind those in the other cylinders at the end of the first month, making no growth after March 12. On March 28 they all wilted and from this time on slowly died, all being dead on May 9, none having put forth a spike or formed a tiller. Four days later the cylinder was opened. The moisture conditions and the root development were almost identical with those in cylinder XIII of the Red Fife wheat series. The free water in the subsoil amounted to only 0.2 per cent, the same as when the seed was planted, and that in the surface foot was —3.9 per cent. Only one very small root, less than two inches long, was found in the uppermost three-inch section of the subsoil ; this is not shown in figure 15, having been lost. The same remarks are applicable to the growth of the plants in this cylin - der as to those in cylinder XIII. The amount of water lost per gram of dry matter produced was correspondingly high, vir. 1345 grams. Cylinder with 4 peb cent free water in the subsoil. — Cvlin der XV. like XIV in the previous series, was filled with moist subsoil containing 9.8 per cent total water or 4.2 per cent free water. The plants continued to grow until about March 18. On April 2 all were slightly wilted. Later in the month three of the plants began to slowly improve and on April 30 these three car - ried n tillers, but the fourth plant was dying. On May 27 two of these three were dying, but the other had put forth a spike, and altho no distinct growth was made after this date, the plant still gave promise of forming grain as late as the evening of June 11 ; one other plant, altho dying, was not yet dead, but the remaining two were quite dead. On June 12 both plants died. Two days later, on opening the cylinder, the moisture conditions and root development were found very similar to those in XIV. The free water in the subsoil was a little higher, 1.4 per cent against 1.0 per cent, but was similarly distributed, rising steadily from 0.3 per cent in the second foot to 2.8 per cent in the sixth — practically the wilting coefficient. Here, as in XIV, the plants did not die simultaneously, altho they all wilted for the first time on the same day. With more favorable weather conditions, it seems probable that grain would have developed in the one spike which had been put forth. t Cylinder with 8 per cent free water in the subsoil. — Under XVII. corresponding to XIX in the Red Fife wheat series, started with 7.8 |»er cent free water. Three of the four plants grew steadily without wilting up to June 11. when they I </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Research BulUtin Vo. ,1 had pat forth three spikes; the other had begun to die before the. end of April. The high temperature of -Tune 12 killed all the plants before nnv grain had formed. The moisture conditions VIII VII XXII XVII XV XI Fig. 14. Kubanka wheat 77 and 123 days after planting; experiment of 1910. were somewhat like those of XV but more free water remained. It rose from 0.2 |&gt;er rent in the second to 4.7 per cent in the sixth </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Relation of Xonacailable Water to ■jjpnMMpfc &lt; 'diffident 67 foot. The development of the roots was similar to that in XV, except that there were many more in the second and third feet and very few in the sixth. It seems probable that under favor - able weather conditions more or less grain would have been formed. It is interesting to note that in this cylinder, as in XIV and XV. the moisture in the second, third, and fourth feet had been reduced much below the wilting coefficient. Cylinder with 12 per cent m water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XXII differed from XVII in that the subsoil carried 17.8 Fig. 15. Roots of Kubanka wheat; experiment of 1910. per cent total water. Two plants in this censed to grow about the middle of March and gradually declined, altho neither was actually dead even as late as .Mine S. Each of the other two plants developed 3 tillers and each produced a spike, the one con - taining 18 grains but the other foriniiiit none. The death of both plants was due to the high temperature of June 12. The subsoil still contained much free water, which increased from 1.1 per cent in the second foot to 8.9 per cent in the sixth. The roots ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Rtxianh Bulletin Xo. S tions of the subsoil were not as numerous as those in the second foot. These two plants would doubtless under more favorable temperature conditions have continued a normal development. It seems probable that neither of the two plants which dropped out of competition early had developed roots below the second foot. Two CYLINDERS WITH MOISTER SOIL NEAR THE SURFACE.—Cylin - ders VII and VTII were filled like V and VI described above (page 61). The four plants in VII made the most vigorous growth of all the Kubanka wheat until early in May. On May 7 they bore 10 tillers in all and five sheaths were swelling. Ten days later the awns on one were showing but after this no growth was made, the plants slowly dying until killed by the high tempera - ture of June 12. Boots had formed in abundance in all parts of the subsoil and the free water had been exhausted. The plants in VIII on March 18 had ." tillers while in none of the other five cylinders had more than a single tiller appeared. Tho plants made little progress from that date until the early part of May when they seemed to take on new life. On Jut I one spike was out and two other spikes were partly out. but all the plants appeared to be dying. On June 12 they died without having formed any grain. Very few roots had developed below the second foot and none below the third. There was an abun - dance of free moisture in the subsoil, even more than in XXII. it steadily rising from 3.3 per cent in the second foot to 11.9 in the sixth, altho the first foot had no free water. MILO. The seed used was from a good head taken in October. 1909. from a field near Cuervo, New Mexico, where a very severe drouth had prevailed thruout the growing season. The series of 6 cylinders was similar in all respects to those employed with the wheats. In each cylinder eight seeds were planted. On February 28, twenty-three days after planting, when the milo plants were from 4 to 7 inches high, the number was reduced to the most vigorous three in each cylinder. The plants in the different cylinders were much alike in growth until March 19, when those in XII wilted somewhat during the hottest part of the day. On that day the number in each cylinder was again reduced, this time to the one most vigorous plant in each cylinder. The two lots of thinnings were dried and their weights included in those of the total dry matter reported in Table 15. As in the case of the wheat series, little difference among the plants in the different cylinders was observed during the first month. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">Relation of Xonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 69 The moisture conditions of the soil at the death of the plants are shown in Table 16 and in figures 7 to 11. Figure 16 shows the condition of the plants on April 23 and on June 8. The roots separated from the different foot sections of the subsoil are shown in figure 17. Cylinder with no free water ix the subsoil.- — Cylinder XII was filled with subsoil containing 5.8 per cent total water. The three plants in this cylinder wilted on March 19 and two were removed. During the following week the single remaining plant grew a little but from March 19 on it wilted every day and growth had ceased entirely by March 26. its condition steadily growing worse until May 13 when it was practically dead. It was then harvested and the cylinder opened. The dwarfed plant is shown on the left of the upper row in figure 16. As in the case of the corresponding wheat cylinders roots had penetrated only a few inches into the first foot of subsoil and in this also a slight distil - lation of moisture seems to have taken place. The average amount of moisture in the subsoil was the same as when the experiment was begun. In the portion of the subsoil in which the roots had developed, no free water remained. The amount of witter lost per gram of dry matter produced was very large, namely. 131") grams. Cylinder with 4 pee cent free water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XVI was filled with moist subsoil containing 9.8 per cent total water. The first signs of injury from drouth were observed on March 26. After this the plant made no growth but remained alive until killed by the high temperature of June 12. Even on May 27 the plant was green to a height of 8i inches above the soil in the cylinder. Roots had penetrated only to the fourth foot. In the fifth and sixth feet none were found and in these the mois - ture was as high as when the seed was planted. The surface foot was practically as dry as in any other cylinder, but the upper portion of the subsoil was as moist as that of XVIII and the lower portion was much more moist. This moist condition of the lowest foot and a half is to be attributed to the failure of the plant to develop roots to that depth, while the comparatively high percentage of moisture in the upper portion of the subsoil is to be attributed to the very limited development of roots in this portion. Under less trying conditions the plant might have lived for a considerable time altho it had long ceased to make any growth. Cylinder with 8 per cent free water in the subsoil. — Cylinder XVIII was filled with subsoil containing 14.1 per cent total water. The plant in this made a slow but normal growth </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Research Bulletin No. S until the end of April when it had put forth ■ head jKirt way out of the sheath. On May tf it was in bloom and four days later showed the first signs of injury from drouth. It made no fur - ther growth and formed but a single grain. The seed was ripe but the plant was not dead on .lime 11. On the following day XII XVI xviu XXI IV Fig. 16. Milo 77 and 123 days, after planting; experiment of 1910. t! liijrh temperature killed the plant. The cylinder was opened days later. The roots were abundant and uniformly dis - buted thruout the subsoil. The free water in the subsoil had ?n quite uniformly reduced, with an average of 0.7 per cent. § Cylinder with 12 per cent free water in the srusou.. — Under XXI was filled with subsoil containing 18.2 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Relation of Souaniilahlc Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 71 total water. The plant in this made a somewhat more rapid growth than that in XVIII but the two were very similar in growth thruout. forming heads, blooming, and showing signs of injury from drouth at about the same time. Both had ripe seeds and were dying on June 11 but neither was yet quite dead. The plant in XXI bore 21 grains. These two were the only plants in the six cylinders that at any time gave promise of forming heads. In both cylinders the roots were abundant and uniformly dis - tributed thruout the subsoil but in XXI the fine roots were more numerous than in XVIII. In XXI. as in XVIII. the free mois - ture of the subsoil had been almost exhausted, there being only XII XVI XVIII XXI IV in Fig. 17. Roots of milo; experiment of 1910. an average of ft.'A jmt cent, quite uniformly distributed, at the time of the death of the plant. TWO TYLIXDERS WITH MOISTER SOIL NEAR THE SURFACE. Cylin - ders III and IV were filled, as described on page 48, with dry subsoil and surface soil, and then enough water was added to raise the total amount of water to the equivalent of 18 per cent of the subsoil and 25 per cent of the surface foot. During the early part of the experiment the two plants in these two cylinders made </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 -r — q »g (C qs a S «3©©«Q©»oq»&lt;5q»q© — e * qc««a 2 "'-sssgasssg H as 1^ -■*--. -»&lt;^ &gt; 5535"*— §2Si '^-.-.-. a ""s&amp;sggigucstt §i si* 3 - "-»•-» •r -r =: 3 — ?2* — *«. n«« SSSSS B &lt;iooooa«ee« T ooo«x — «Nh&gt; • 2 « JP2*"*- nw« 2 2222 — «oo»ooo«o«o«o«o . . ooewx W PS o~ • ~: "&lt; *&lt; " •* *■ »* -■ -^ *"^ " ., oni ga . ■♦■• ! ; nyi g OOtOO'OOOOOO'C OOO« I :::::•:::::: : : : • ■ : ::::::::::&lt; : : i : : • | ; ■ - I ■ :«s~ :::::::: V i :::: : ::::::::::: : : : :i : hJ Sil!ililS]'JiVlil £i 1 I i Hi 1 ]«l •"•=" = toifcsSS? :; J§ m illillM^i^oojimmnii M ||||| |-a"S£i: ii l^fi ===== I §§§§i§gg§i§ i; •••• „ : • • • • JS .2.S.S5 n 1111 fflfflM § i MS If I ■ 'JilJ U2«l s«s^« a sssasasssas Is -2-s.s.s oailaaaaa" It an *o*o o o'o'o'o'^ 000 «hh4!uh inn ! mmmw i- in 1i 1111 SSSSSSSSiiS illHUlilil Hffl i iiiiliiliii « II -s-s-s-s « 1111 !!»!!»!» sssssssssss </seg>
            <seg id="p073">'lation of Xonarailabie Water to TTva ' n m I .2 A • ■ m | 2S2SS SSSS SSSS ISSS SSSS SSS S 3 * t _J g § §3S2" ««o« c~, M „ „ x £ i T i ii • &lt;n "• i * I «?^^» »-^r~ oc^o x k ! II- ? 4 i — -^ __^ &gt; fjMS ! *«^ "-Z™-*- a -°°.™.*. "=— •§ - 3 !S35S" " q^- -°-~- n - ~-~-&lt;^. **** &lt;*-.* * « I- Ml f ( « ( &gt; 132333 '•••^i '•'ii -J-J*»^ --P - o § 5 BSSS"'" -?-•««« ««*q ooo-. «,-«» - o * i i i i i , ,,■■■■• i ■ I-L 41 a S~~fl &lt;n$«3 S$3? SggS SS5 ~ 3 i I \&gt; !! i i </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Research Hulletin Yo H the most vigorous growth of all (see the upper row in figure 10 1 but they had completely exhausted the free water before any (•hints had put forth heads. These two were the only milo plants which formed any tillers. Each formed one, that in the case of IV being removed on March 26 and that in the case of III on April 16, both being less than 6 inches long. At the end of April both plants were already suffering seriously from drouth and neither showed any sign of putting forth a head. Both were in worse condition on May 13. There was little difference between the two plants at this time but that in III seemed to be in the better condition ; the plant in this was harvested and the cylinder opened. That in IV was left a month longer. It was almost en - tirely dead on June 11 and was harvested three days later, being then quite dry. The roots in both were abundant and uniformly distributed. The surface soil of IV contained 2.0 per cent less water than that of III but there was little difference in the amount of moisture in the subsoil — it being practically exhausted in both. If, as is probable, the subsoil moisture was at least as low in IV as in III on May 13, it is of interest that it was no lower at the end of an - other month, one of very high temperature. The loss of moisture from the surface foot of soil of IV which occurred during the last month, assuming that it was as dry as in III on May 13, is to be attributed almost entirely to direct evaporation, as the free moisture had already been entirely re - moved. MEXICAN BKANS. Mexican pink Wans, from the Sulphur Spring Valley Dry- Farm of the Arizona Experiment Station, were planted on Fel&gt;ru ary 5 in cylinders I and II. filled as described on page 48, the sur - face foot of soil containing 2."i per eeat and the subsoil 18 par cent total water. On February B the plants were thinned to the most vigorous two in each cylinder. On March 2f) all the plants were in bloom, the two in I lieing 7 and 9 and those in II being 9 and 13 inches high. Many pods formed on each of the plants but most of these failed to fill. By April 23 leaves were beginning to drop from all four; the photograph (figure 18 1 was taken on that day. On April 27 the two plants in I wilted badly and did not recover, both being dead on April 30. A week later all the leaves seemed quite dry, but the pods and stems not being dry the cylinder was left until May 13. The plants in II held out for over a week longer, wilting for the first time on May 7. They were dead two days later and quite dry by May 13. On the death of the plants, as will be seen from Table 18 and figure 7. there was a very uniform distribution of moisture </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Uildlion of Xonavailable Water to H ygroscopic Coe/fu-ient 75 tliruout the five feet of subsoil, there being practically no differ- ence even between that in the second foot and that in the lower part of the sixth foot. In the surface foot the inoiBture content increased rapidly from the top to the bottom. The average eon- tent of free moisture in the first foot was — 1.5 per cent and in the five feet of subsoil 0.8 per cent. The roots were numerous thruout the subsoil and quite uniformly distributed, as will be seen from both Table 17 and figure 19. Table 17. — Data on experiment with beans in 1910. I II Weight of dry soil and subsoil in cylinder, in grams 43,593 44,102 Weight of water in subsoil, February 5, in grams 8,220 8,333 Weight of water in subsoil, May 13, in grams 2,849 2,987 Weight of water lost in 97 days, in grams 5,371 5,366 Average height of plants, in inches . 8 11 Number of pods which produced seeds 3 4 Number of seeds . . . 14 14 Weight of seeds, air-dry, in gmm*. j 2.24 2.77 Weight of leaves, stems, and pods, air-dry, in grams . 5.25 5.10 Weight of crop, dried at 110° C. in grams 6.92 7.10 *w • , r . ■ , * r • -vie* -t wet Weight of water lost per gram of crop, in grams . 776 756 Time from planting of seed to death of plants, in days 97 97 Weight of roots, dried at 110° C, in 2d foot, in grams .063 .082 Weight of roots, dried at 1 10° C, in 3d foot, in grams .073 .081 Weight of roots, dried at 110° C, in 4th foot, in grams .084 11* Weight of roots, dried at 1 10° C., in 5th foot, in grams .091 111 Weight of roots, dried at 110° C, in 6th foot, in grams 074 (Kt4 Total weight of roots in subsoil, in grams .385 .486 Date of death of last plant May 13 May 13 Date of opening cylinder May 13 May 13 Per cent of total water in surface foot of soil, February 5 25.0 25.0 Per cent of total water in subsoil, February 5 18.0 18.0 Per cent of total water in surface foot on opening cylinder 7.5 7 ti 18.0 18.0 Per cent of total water in surface foot on opening cylinder Per cent of total water in subsoil on opening cylinder 6.4 j 6.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Research littllctiit Xo. 3 76 Table IS. — Moisture conditions on opening cylinders with beans, experiment of 1910. Total water Free water Depth of section I II 1 II Feet Inchet Per rent Per rent Per rent Per nut I 1-3 3.1 ftj Ii2 —5.8 ■ 4 4.5 4.5 -4.N —4.8 \ 5-6 5.6 5.5 —S.7 -3.8 5.6 5.5 —S.7 -3.8 7-9 9.8 9.6 —1.2 —1.4 10-12 12.1 12.3 1.1 1.3 13-18 6.4 • (I..") 0.8 0.9 K16-1N 6.3 6.5 0.7 0.9 "i HI •)! (I "i R A nT ft ft 19-21 ti.:5 6.4 0.7 0.8 22-24 6.4 6.5 0.8 0.9 f 35-37 M 6.4 0.7 0J „ 2S-30 6.1 M 0.5 0.7 d \ 31-33 6.3 6.1 0.7 0.5 I M-M 6.2 6.3 0.6 0.7 6.3 6.1 0.7 0.5 6.2 6.3 0.6 0.7 f 37-39 6.3 6.4 0.7 0.8 . 40-42 6.3 6.3 0.7 0.7 4 ■&gt; A3-4S I. 4 K 4 OS OS 1 43-45 6.4 6.4 0.8 0.8 LI 46-48 6.3 6.3 0.7 0.7 f 49-51 6.3 6.2 0.7 0.6 ! 52-54 6.3 6.3 0.7 0.7 • 1 55-57 6.5 6.3 0.9 0.7 1 58-60 6.5 6.4 0.9 0.8 ( 61-63 6.5 6.3 0.9 0 7 . -j 64-66 6.7 6.4 1.1 0.8 67-69 6.7 6.3 1.1 0.7 Average .... 1-12 7.5 7.6 —2.6 —2.5 Average . . 13-69 6.4 6.3 0.8 0.7 The total moisture in the subsoil at the death of the two plants was 6.4 and fi..*? per cent respectively, being 1.8 and 1.9 per cent below the wilting coefficient. It seems improbable that this large amount of water was removed between the time that the plants wilted permanently and the time that the cylinders were opened. SUMMARY OF EXPERIMENT OF 1910. The subsoil of the two unplanted cylinders at the beginning of the experiment held nearly twice as much water as the same subsoil would have retained under field conditions. The surface foot of soil, however, was not wetter than it might have been found in the field after a period of wet weather. The loss of </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Relation of Xonu callable Water to Hiigroncopic Coefficient 77 eer during the 97 days of the experiment was equivalent to not •e than two inches of rain and was confined chiefly to' that in the surface foot. The plants in all the cylinders evidently died from lack of sufficient soil moisture. The slow dying of many was cut short by a temperature of 124° F.. which, altho not fatal in itself, caused such a rapid transpiration that water could not be ab - sorbed rapidly enough to meet the requirements because of the small amount of free water in the portions of the subsoil where there was an extensive development of roots. The plants were already dead or dying in all the cylinders except one of Red Fife wheat and two of Kubanka wheat. In their ability to exhaust the soil moisture before dying, the four different crop plants showed little difference, but in their ability to continue alive after first showing serious injury from drouth they showed marked differences. The interval between wilting and death in the case of beans amounted to only a few days but in that of niilo and wheat it extended to many weeks. E Where there was a well -developed root system and no remark - y high temperature occurred before the death of the plants, the moisture content of the soil was reduced almost to the hygroscopic coefficient. Plants in the same cylinder wilted and died independently of one another and simultaneous wilting was not followed by simul - taneous death. k Plants started in cylinders with comparatively little free :er in the subsoil lived longer than some started in cylinders h a very moist subsoil. The plant roots did not penetrate the subsoil where this con - tained practically no free water and penetrated very slowly where the water content was only a little above the wilting co - efficient. While there appeared to be a close connection between the early development of the plants in the different cylinders and the quantity of roots in the subsoil, there was little connection between the quantity of roots and the final development of the plants. W r here roots were uniformly distributed, there was a uniform loss of free water from the different levels, bnt where the development of roots was markedly lacking in uniformity there were distinct differences in the loss of free water. (In one cylinder the removal of the aerial portions of the most the plants, after the root system had been fully developed and the soil moisture so reduced that further root development could not take place, proved of little or no benefit to the remaining plants. Calculated to an acre basis the yield of grain was below 6 bushels per acre except in the case of beans, where it exceeded </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 1.IKNI pounds. In the i)roduction of total dry matter the inilo made the most economical use of the water, but in that of seed the beans made much the most economical use ; but if the cylinder had car - ried several times as much soil, thus giving each plant much more water, the latter might not have been the case. The yield of total dry matter in the case of these cylinders with an initial water content similar to what might be expected to the same depth and in the same type of subsoil in summer fallowed fields varied from 500 to 4,000 pounds j&gt;er acre. The portion of the free water in the surface foot of soil at the time of planting the seed had much lem* Fig. 18. Mexican beans 77 days after planting; experiment of 1910. tjct on the production of dry matter than had an equal amount the subsoil. very hard crust formed below the mulch in all the planted inders. rERIMENT WITH LOESS SOILS FROM DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE TRANSITION REGION. EXPERIMENT OF 1911. t Loess 1 forms the chief surface deposit of more than half of &gt;raska, occurring over the whole eastern end and extending tward for more than 300 miles. The different parts of this nation have been exposed to comparatively uniform tem- 1 Barbour, E. H. Nebraska Geological Survey, vol. 1, 1903, p. 169. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">perature conditions but to great differences in precipitation, if we assume that since the close of the glacial epoch there has been but little change in the climate of what is now Nebraska. In the extreme eastern part the normal precipitation is over 30 inches, while in the southwestern corner it is less than 20, there being a gradual decrease from east to west as shown on the accompany - ing map. While the precipitation decreases from east to west, there is a rapid riHe in the rate of evaporation. As the precipita - tion falls chiefly during the growing season there is but little II I Pig. 19. Roots of Mexican beans; experiment of 1910. seepage from the level prairies in the eastern portion and practi - cally none from those in the western. Uniformity in physical properties has long l&gt;een recognized as characteristic of the Ne - braska loess ami ;i recent chemical study 1 has shown that, except in the content of calcium carbonate, which increases from east to west, the chemical composition is very uniform. Field studies of soil moisture had indicated that there was a 1 Alway, F. J. Composition of the Loess Soils of the Transition Region. Eighth International Congress of Applied Chemistry, 1912, Report of 2(1 M m mk ■ ft. ■ ■ ■ ■ M m m m A fi ■ ■ ■ ■ 4th M » ft. ■ ■ ■ a 5th Am B ft. ■ ■ ■ t&gt;th .v m El A ft. ■ ■ l ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 considerable difference in tin- rooting habits of sonic OOf plants between the eastern and the western portions of the loess in Ne - liraska. and to determine whether there was a gradual change troni west to east this experiment was earned out in Ktll. The location of the places where the soils were secured are indicated on the map in figure 20. At each of the five places an excavation was made and about 150 pounds of soil taken from each of the first 6 feet. These bulk samples were shipped to the Experiment Sta - tion where each soil, in dry condition, was reduced to a fine state of division and mixed by passinjr it several times thru a one - elirhth-inch screen .is previously described (patre 17 1. This screen - ing at the same time served to remove nearly all the roots. Three cylinders were tilled with the soils from each of these places. Evaporation... 5 ft 44.fr 3fr r20. Map showing the loess region of Nebraska (unshaded) and the sources of the samples used, as well as the normal annual precipita - tion and evaporation. Besides the 15 cylinders mentioned. 8 others were used in the experiment. Six were filled with the same H O soils used in 1010. but instead of keeping the upper and the lower half of the surface foot separate the previously unused portions of these were mixed and used as one lot of soil. The hygroscopic coefficient was found to be practically the same as the average of the two parts used in 1910. These 6 are referred to as the H O cylinders. The sur - face 6 inches of soil from a field from the Experiment Station Farm was used to fill two cylinders which are referred to as those of Surface Soil. The hygroscopic coefficients of the soils used are given in Table 19. The numbers given for the H O soils and for the surface soil are the averages of a large number of determinations, and those for the others are the averages of three determinations made on different days. </seg>
            <seg id="p081"/>
            <seg id="p082">82 Research Bulletin Xo. S Table 19. — Hygroscopic coefficients of soils used in the ewperi - ment of 1911. I^ 1 ' HO WauneU McCook Holdrege Hastings Lincoln The 23 metal cylinders, 6 feet long and similar in all re - sjiects to those employed in the preceding two years, were filled with dry soil as in the earlier experiments, then saturated with water and drained as described above (page 32). The loess soils, especially those from the more easterly portions of Nebraska, con - tain so much clay and fine silt and, accordingly, are so easily pud - dled when worked in a wet condition that it was not considered advisable to attempt to add the water to the different foot sec - tions of soil before introducing these into the cylinders. Seven cylinders were planted to Red Fife wheat. 7 to Milo, fi to Mexican pink beans, and 2 to maize. Into one cylinder young mesquites wen 1 transplanted. After planting the seeds, a one-inch layer of dry soil was added to the surface and the cylinders sunken in a pit in the greenhouse as in the preceding year. The general ar - rangement of the cylinders is shown in figure 21. The records of the daily maximum and mean temperature* as well as of the humidity and the evaporation from a free water surface are given in Tables 2 to 5. No whitewash was used on the windows of the greenhouse. Altho much better ventilation was provided the temperature was very high, the daily maximum being below 100° F. on only 7 days between May 15 and July 24. the date when the last plant died. On Jmly 5 the maximum tem - perature out of doors was 110° F., while inside the greenhouse It was 130° F. These high temperatures hastened the death of many of th? plants. The siime precautions were observed as in the preceding two years regarding the formation of crevices between soil column and cylinder wall. As soon as the plants died they were removed from the cylin - ders and the weight of dry matter determined. In most cases the cylinders were at once opened and the soil moisture determined. The roots were separated from the surface foot as well as from t In- subsoil, photographed, dried, and weighed. 1 2 3 4 5 6 10.0 5.6 5.6 5.6 5.6 5.6 9.2 9.5 9.9 10.1 9.5 8.6 9.4 11.0 9.6 9.0 8.8 8.4 10.1 11.7 12.0 10.6 9.7 9.6 10.7 13.2 11.7 11.5 10.8 10.5 12.1 15.3 14.6 13.2 13.2 13.5 I .verage ■ 1 6.3 9.5 9.4 10.6 11.4 13.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Relation of Nonarailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 83 A summary of the moisture conditions in the different cylin - ders and of the crops is given in Table 20, and figure 21 shows the cylinders near the close of the experiment. The moisture con - ditions on the death of the plants are shown in figures 22 to 28. RED FIFE WHEAT. On February 20, eight sprouted seeds were planted in each of 7 cylinders. Four days later all the plants had appeared above the surface and during the next two weeks they were thinned to 4 to a cylinder. Up to April 11 there were no very marked differences between the plants in the 7 cylinders. All were alive and ap - peared healthy on April 15 except in the Hastings cylinder, where one plant was dead, and in the Lincoln cylinder, where one plant was dying. On this date the plants in the Lincoln cylinder and in the cylinder of surface soil were considerably less thrifty than those in the 5 others. On April 30 there was one dead plant m each of the McCook, Holdrege, and Hastings cylin - ders and two in the Lincoln cylinder. Spikes were forming in all except that of surface soil. In vigor the plants seemed to decline in the following order : H O, Wauneta. MeOook. Holdrege, Hast - ings, Surface Soil, and Lincoln. Those in the H O cylinder closely 'able 2i &gt;. 1 "y Hud 'ers use&lt; in M experiment o\ Total water D f Crop -£«£ d-thdT last •3E- /&gt;rcen&lt; 78 HO Red Fife wheat.; 27.1 June 17 79 HO Milo I 25.2 May 30 77 HO Mexican beans. 25.8 May 5 24 HO Maiie 24.3 May 30 76 HO Mai«e 25.1 May 30 25 Wauneta ... Red Fife wheat. 30.9 July 7 26 1 Wauneta . . . Milo i 30.2 July 5 27 ! Wauneta . Mexican beans.; 29.2 June 8 30 I McCook.... Red Fife wheat. 31.4 July 12 29 McCook. . . Milo 31.1 July 24 28 McCook... Mexican beans. 30.7 July 18 72 Holdrege ... Red Fife wheat. 34.4 June 26 71 Holdrege ... Milo I 32.3 July 24 31 Holdrege . . . Mexican beans . ' 32.5 May 18 75 Hastings ... Red Fife wheat . 35.1 July 18 74 Hastings . . . Milo 34.5 July 5 73 | Hastings ... Mexican beans. 34.6 June 6 82 Lincoln i Red Fife wheat . 35.9 June 27 83 Lincoln. . . jMilo 36.9 April 29 84 Lincoln. .. Mexican beans. 36.4 June 27 80 Surface [ Red Fife wheat . 38.1 July 12 81 Surface ; Milo 37.7 June 20 June 22 May M May 30 II July 18 June 26 Es July 7 June 22 June 27 May 6 June 27 July 12 June 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 resembled those in the \\ auneta and those iu the cylinders of Holdrege and Hastings soil were very similar. The plants in Lin - coln soil were in very liad condition, appearing to be seriously suffering from drouth. I hiring- the next month none of the plants made any progress and all were injured during the first week of •Tune with its continued high temperature. The general conditions on May 27 may Ix- seen from figure 21. None of the plants had died since those recorded on April 30 but many were dying by June 9. The plants in the H O cylinder were all dead on June 17; only one spike had formed and that bore no grain. On June 26 the plants in the Holdrege cylinder were dead, having formed only one spike and this being barren. On the next day the plants in the Lincoln cylinder were all dead. The extremely unfavorable weather during the last week of June and the early part of July caused the remaining plants to die rapidly, all being dead by July 18. A single spike — on a plant in the Wauneta cylinder — formed grain. Additional data on these wheat plants are given in Table 21. Couru».c RtfM — e»»7 in Pm CrrvT Fig. 22. Final moisture conditions in cylinders of H O soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p085"/>
            <seg id="p086">86 Research Bulletin No. S Fig. 25. Final moisture conditions in cylinders of Holdrege soil. MOISTURE CONTENT in PER CENT Fig. 26. Final moisture conditions in cylinders of Hastings sou. </seg>
            <seg id="p087"/>
            <seg id="p088">88 I r 1 r? »* A 90 Cj -* — -j- /- * — . — C&lt; ■f jo? ;S2£xS2x?J2£ 5*1 =-. = _,__ I *83R-3-©©28 =55555555 81 .-i--.z -j — sj'N - _r o-c-oodob js j3 " j ~ — ■ i 8 Jjf** "" * iidddcdcd 33 * |"x ■■i .* 32 10 * d * dddddddd ■ | - a •f — " -*-= ' I ■ • H • J3 ..-. • m •■ I— T7 e r : = » :&gt;■ : : : . 1 3 1 § a a s : I : S--^ 1^ e ' "H. ■ M^. • • • • B 6£6tM.t&lt;C!*6£5 • i,-= = Ma. "5 : .S &amp; : 6| : : ■ « c .g.s.s.s.s.S 5 J= ■ if Eftl'l | |iW| N IjJ !| V/^Vr* " M||J^ H H- S*!" 8 : : S. o°o°o°o^b.sl j| ls=l: "e'o'b'c -•£ 2 2"°*="° "o "c "= "c "= "= 'S 'S 1 "= o °"o = - - AAfi**!!!^* 325^32*4 "Bo Illll </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Relation of Xonarailubh Water to Hyqro*copic Coefficient 89 I j iftft f dd " ;;x ' o ' : C--N1M co^iocd oooaoi inn ?! ■^ —** * *^ v^ A,k Al A 1 Z£ 1^ JS ■ c !'&lt;T t ¥&lt;?7 77^3 S^S^ S k-3tid&gt; cities 5^^ sj: s;?5^ sll^ -3 1 a. _ «5 M Ijjfifl ssss aasa ss SS saj gJ ?s jffl? ?=sa S33S 333S K3i 2ffl f5 IfffT 235S W'S i33g iilS 5S55 S^ P I^ N : I «« Nxa* sjffltoa mu:^^ o^ouj n « -"=9 -22ir S22i: »»SS |??f?? 3 23 SSSS 2333 3333 m*« f3 JtTTT f §SS Sn^ 5S « 3333 S55S O i, &lt;° "» --&lt; ■* tdt^t^ac ocoooioi </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 rch Hulletin No. S The crevice between soil column and cylinder wall extended to 6, 15, 6, 6, 24, 18. and 23 inches, respectively, in passing from the western to the eastern soils, but it was found well filled in the first four and filled to a depth of 12 inches in the other three. Roots penetrated to the sixth foot in all the cylinders except the Lincoln and the Surface Soil, but were very few in number below the surface foot, as may be seen from Table 21 and figure 29. The Wauneta and the Hastings cylinders showed the most extensive root development. The moisture conditions on the death of the plants are shown in Table 22. An abundance of free moisture was present at some depth in each cylinder, the moist soil extending upwards from the bottom. In every cylinder, however, the free moisture was practically exhausted from that portion of the soil in which roots had been freely developed. This is evident from a comparison of figure 20 with Table 22. This very close connection between the root distribution and the exhaustion of free water existed in the case of the foot sections and still more closely in that of the three-inch sections: altho the roots were not separated and weighed from the three-inch sections their abundance in these sections was recorded at the time of opening the cylinders. While the plants all died from want of water, they did so with plenty of water just beyond the soil depths in which the roots were freely developed. The slight development of roots in the moist soil was evidently not sufficient to supply the plants with water rapidly enough to maintain life under the extremely unfavorable temperature conditions to which they were exposed. MILO. tOn February 20, six milo seeds were planted one inch deep the moist soil in each of the 7 cylinders. Three days later the ints appeared above the surface. At the end of two weekB i number in each cylinder was reduced to the one most vigor - ous plant. All did about equally well during the first seven weeks after planting, altho the plants on the H O and Wauneta soils were somewhat the tallest at the end of that time. The plant in the Lincoln cylinder died during the second week in April. On all the surviving plants heads were appearing by the middle of April and by the end of the month all were in bloom and appeared fairly vigorous. No tillers formed on any of the plants but branches formed on some. On May 6 a brunch from 2 to 6 inches long had appeared from the second axil of each of the plants in the Holdrege and Hastings cylinders and from both the second and the third axils of the plant in Surface Soil but there </seg>
            <seg id="p091">f •* V V V R V V &amp; -^ y i t ■ II ■c 5 5 * I ■ II i .- E r 1« Q 's = S3 5 5 a i* N s* •••# • </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Research Bulletin No. S Fig. 30. Mllo 96 days after planting; 1, H O; 2, Wauneta 3 McCook - 4, Holdrege; 5, Hastings; 6, Surface soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 #*M*0) 7. c 3 £ as £ «; u 3 3 ° 5 S = a i x i ?6 |1 = « iS 2 5 m a 9 5 ** E i E s = is c; — . - JS ■ 3« MC $■= </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 Research Bulletin ¥•. .1 was no sign of branching in the case of the plant* in the H O, Wanneta. and McCook cylinders. From that time on there was much less uniformity in the development of the plants in the different cylinders. Figure 30 shows the condition of 6 of the plants on May 27, when they had all reached their full development; that on Lin - coln soil had died and had been removed a month before. Table 23 gives the data on the experiment and Table 24 shows the moisture conditions. The distribution of roots is shown in figure 31. On the H O soil the plant matured one head and died without putting forth any branch. By May 18 the leaves were all dead but the seed was slightly soft. Twelve days later the grain was hard and the entire plant dead and quite dry. The plant i tig. 30 1 had formed a good head l&gt;earing 308 seeds. The cylinder was (»lKMied that day. The roots were abundant and uniformly dis- Iributed {fig. 31 and Table 24) thruout the subsoil. The free water in the surface foot had fallen to — 2.0 while that in the subsoil had ben uniformly reduced to 0.7 per cent, 1.9 per cent below the wilting eoHkimt The plant in the Wauneta cylinder put forth a branch soon after May (5 but by May 18 this had ceased to grow, being then :!.."&gt; inches long. On May 30 the seed was practically ripe and theVleaves of the main stalk were dead but the branch was still quite green. The latter continued alive until July, thruout June gradually (lying back from the tip. Even after the first adverse days of July it showed some signs of life, but was &lt;|iiite dead on July "&gt;. Tlie size of the branch is shown in figure 30. taken on May 27. The development of this branch, which had a long lease of life after the main stalk died, is the only point in which the development of the plant in the Wauneta cylinder &lt;Iif fend markedly from that in the H O cylinder. Like the latter it formed a good head and this bore 319 seeds. The cylinder was opened two days after the death of the plant The distribution of roots resembled that in the H O cylinder. The free water in the surface foot had been reduced to — 3.8 per cent and in the subsoil to approximately zero. The plant in the McCook cylinder differed but little in de - velopment from that in the Wauneta cylinder. It formed a branch at the same time as the latter and this on May 13 was 8.0 inches long, and on May 30, when it had three leaves, it was 9.5 inches long (fig. 30), after which it ceased to make any ap - preciable growth. On May 30 the seed was ripe but all the rest of the plant, except the lowest leaves, was green. On June 17 all the leaves except those on the branch were dead, hut the branch </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Relation of Xonnniilable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 95 \v;is still alive and none of its leaves showed signs of injury from drouth. Era the adverse conditions of the first week in July failed to kill the In-.im-li. but from that time on it gradually died. On July 24 it was quite dead and the plant was harvested, it bearing 100 seeds. The cylinder was opened four days later. The root distribution was similar to that in the two cylinders just described. The surface foot contained —3.6 per cent free water and the sultsoil an average of — 0.6 per cent, the latter being quite uniformly distributed when it is considered that the sub - soil consisted of five different soils. The plants in the Holdrege and Hastings cylinders were very similar in their development. On May fi both had formed branches. '-1 and 2 inches long respectively. On May 30 the plants were still quite green and on each the first head was ripe and a second, formed on the branch, was in bloom iflg. 30. 4 and 5). The second head on each was ripe by the end of June and the plant in the Hastings cylinder was dead by Julv "&gt;. whi e the other was not entirely dead until July 24. Tn the case of each the first head ban a fair amount of ne4, 14"J and 177 grains respectively, while the heads on the branches bore only 2 and 3 kernels. Roots in both cylinders were abundant thruoi t the subsoil. The surface foot contained less than — .'5.0 per cent free water and the subsoil in both contained practically none. On April 15 the plant in the Lincoln cylinder, not yet having put forth a head, was seen to be dying, altho on the day before it had shown no injury. Two days later it was dead and quite dry. the whole plant remaining as green as tho it had been cut off and dried in the sun. It was evident that the sudden death of this plant was due to some other cause than lack of moisture in the soil and this view was confirmed by the moisture data ob - tained when the cylinder was opened on May 6. There was an abundance of free water in the fifth and sixth feet and from 3 to 5 per cent even in the second and third feet. The moisture content of the second and third feet was. however,, from 2 to 3 per cent below the wilting coefficient while that of the upper three-fourths of the fourth foot was at the wilting coefficient. Roots extended to the bottom of the cylinder, but were not numerous below the fourth foot. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 |j jSr«"- gSSSS 3WWJ 5" 222 11 s-f2- &lt;-»-* JW« P §,:: |l^ x -~ r . /. I jSgjSSq „ sis &lt;-. U- — '?- ? s?iiS || 55 = f=° 1 i§ !sii2s-s s .«.?sfe fe3i!?52s-ss s§s 2333S 1 i J I |pPi^l=pi -w*w B «• if iPft | : Illfa^isps s*w j2 JJ r?33 I 5 = i : MJllMijjMj HUM jj ill i ! jijji ::::j| ::::::■: : -§ ■ ■ • :j:3::: : :ili :::::! :i ii.i : \ aji ! i liSlimiili iiiiii jlill liflffl li| :4 :• i ••i*i .£.=.2.= =.= I s . -. ■. : . -. ■. •-S|9» pj ijil ami 9 in :: ii|i| !bf ffi«sw«| |l ill i; f||§i flBi H|Ch 222222 -Si 111 Jl i|-:|-! ! !flil1|lfll Iff If! 2MM I! llJli Illltillliii? «li|i -S-3 H^ 11 i*88« *lii^=llfil'll iiiiii II iii ii nil, </seg>
            <seg id="p097">Relation of Nonnrnilnhh Water to Mmrmtmtt Cuefirient 97 2 ii e 8 °? P "? x s&gt; •« m ■ I f TTTT *"" 3a £ c (. t r u ?7« occurs —i-.Mr, «•*« as* ! i i I I ITTTT ■&gt;*• »C -.--.&lt;-. (ffiav* «^.^.^i q O TTTT tft? ffff f° I l t v f ttf § f f f s r § ffff ff I itTtt f ■?- • ? M V » X —; t-'r I-- -r mq -r i- »rr i» &gt;- ic X I iTTTi TTTT TTTT TTTT TTTT ffff ff r CrtL-JN I I IftTf f" s »« ffff. ffff §f?f ff *. -. ~ -r^^t qwww go-* 3 I Ff II ■i !»d I^JCX 3CC3SO C« S&gt; ' I '2222 : SS3 9353 353*! «~^--=* «*»»- »^ ° = 7777 : = = = oo = ° = = === dd = = oodci mo II ItJ^I 77^ "W*L 3*6? 3?«K 2^ I |i^^ a^ mi j^^| IsS^ 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">trch Bulletin \o. 3 98 The plant in surface soil developed much like the plants in the Holdrege and Hastings cylinders, hut unlike these it formed two branches. The second did not grow more than a few inches but the first formed a head. Neither this nor the head on the main stalk emerged fully from the sheath. The head on the branch formed two seeds and that on the main stalk three. On May 30 the plant was dying and on June 20 was quite dead. The cylinder was apcMi on the next day. Boots reached to the bot - tom of the cylinder but those in the lower portion were few in number. The separation of the roots in the case of this cylin - der was very difficult on account of the large number of old root fragments originally present in the soil. Those from the sixth foot were lost before being photographed. Only in the case of the surface foot was the free water exhausted, but in the next three feet of soil, while the moisture content was considerably above the hygroscopic coefficient, it was below the wilting co - efficient. In the lowest two feet free water was still abundant, there being 19.3 per cent in the sixth foot. fThe crevice between soil column and cylinder wall had reached 6. 6. 9. and 9 inches in the case of the H O. Wauneta, McCook, and Lincoln cylinders respectively. In the case of the Holdrege and Ilastings cylinders a small crevice extended to 48 and 42 inches respectively. In the case of the surface soil a large crevice, one-fourth inch wide, had formed to 30 inches and a smaller one, one-eighth inch wide, to 48 inches. This had l»een filled by the spatula with fine, dry soil which on opening the cylinder was found to completely fill the crevice to a depth of 12 inches but not below. For reasons already given (p. 36) it is safe to consider that these crevices had little or no effect upon the exhaustion of the soil moisture. The five plants from the H O. Wauneta McCook, Holdrege. and Hastings cylinders are quite comparable with the ten plants 1 from which the seed had been obtained, altho they were somewhat taller, weighed more, and produced more seed than the original plants. The comparison is shown in Table 25. Judging from root distribution, final moisture conditions, and observed changes in the condition of the plants, the death of the plants in the five cylinders of soil from the areas west of Lincoln was due entirely to exhaustion of the water supply. In four cases, viz. Wauneta, McOook Holdrege, and Hastings, the conditions were extremely favorable to the complete exhaustion of the water, in that after a very extensive root system had been developed thruout the soil mass the death of the main portion of 1 Secured by the writer from a field near Cuervo, N. M., In September. 1910. The seed planted was from the mixture of the seed from ten </seg>
            <seg id="p099">Relation of Xonaia liable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 99 each plant greatly reduced the transpiring surface, thus per - mitting transpiration to continue for a long time before the death of the plants. Table 25. — Comparison of plants grown under field conditions in 1910 with those groicn in greenhouse in 1911. Ten original Five planw plants from grown Cuervo, New in cylinders Mexico, 1910 1911 Average height of plant, in inches 13.0 32.8 Average weight of seed per plant, air-dry, in grams. . 3.91 Average number of seeds per plant 144 7.40 Average weight of single seed, in grams. 0.027 0.032 Average weight of total dry matter at 1 10° C, in grams 9.88 20.89 MEXICAN BEANS. Using seed from the same source as that employed in the pre - ceding year, on February 20 five germinated beans were planted in each of six cylinders. On March 1 all except the Wauneta and McCook cylinders had one or more plants above the surface. Mice ate off a number of the plants and on March 14 more seeds were planted in those cylinders in which plants had been destroyed while in each of the others the number of plants was reduced to the most vigorous four. Part of those from the second plant - ing died within the first three weeks after appearing above the surface, probably for the reason that the older plants with their more extensive root systems prevented the younger one* obtaining the minimum amount of water required. On April 15 the plants were very uneven in growth. In the H O cylinder there were four of the early ones ; these were all in bloom and were more vigorous than those in any other cylinder. The Wauueta cylinder had only three, all from the first planting. These also were all in bloom and nearly as vigorous as the pre - ceding. The McCook cylinder had three small plants from the second planting. The Holdrege cylinder carried one early plant in bloom and two late plants, but both the latter were dead. In the Hastings soil there was only one early plant in bloom together with two small late plants, while in the Lincoln cylinder there was one early plant in bloom and two small late plants, both the latter being* dead. From this time on the differ - ences between the plants in the different cylinders became still more marked. The data from the experiment are summarized in Table 26 and the moisture conditions at the close of the experi - ment are shown in Table 27. Figure 32 shows the distribution of roots thruont the six feet. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Research Bulletin No. .? * s = 5 I? * x 8 J i -.- Sd id </seg>
            <seg id="p101">© © O* 3 3 I 1 5BS -—lite Siiiiiii §s 3222s 3 t "5 V * - WtoisSj ~ -i -, 3f fi ,-; a -txc N " T - ococ ~&gt; T^ Si I Sites 3 M e,a.*5| ~ P *? P ® » T*" 5 g" « OC r- JC M ss Jg a &amp; hi l^SllSag X^ qqimti • : - 2 « "*• a " 1^ - «i * • ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ?i o «; - —s-^ os c; x — -* Spr : . : : • 5 :I ;- : = „« |R 3 M rflfj J t'- = .S :- . |jwJ| S 1 hlllJ |_|_|||| » gate •■■:: ::'::: : : :.£4j : :j : . • ■ • MSi= i s :i :: • : , !! b^J c 11 -1 &amp; a 5 ■ = = =i^'&amp; &gt; ; B l [jllifji ■ I'llp ;8bl .s.s.=.=.s=ol : : =-s^^s p«£. ccococ.H^ "3J h fc r i, ii IjJ ****?*u If iillr liifK f if iff- li llili IS c-i as d x x x m^ x --, «^p:9 SS H I Jgrfh M X I s- -c-c «IH jJitf! ffffffll 1 Isjli --I-3CC.V 0 0 'm'§"."5:[3:'5"5"3'5 e, e. - - - - t- V «r ----.£ s~s~-~ -s. - ~ ■£ - — .».».SfSS g g s "§■&amp;■§ "S'§.^'S'5"&amp; ■-■-■-■- S SEC .S-.2-.2- JiJJ 11 ** -- - - k » « </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 i — ? B^^I 3 ! i^no^ t-j«oeo» ©oo — oo noon « — op op to ej» ejKN-wio cnnpi nmnn pieiriei eimmm &lt;e m = = t I .S Si®*?" P^**: 1 " ««?'":■* =1«5»p -*«i«(m ■*&lt;=©© p«« ts *. 0 Pf'TT «t».«O!O tooooN coeiw^f loioujai hixoox ■- -i I TTTl I" t - = 2 upnoco •*■*•»•* TCtooiiN ■*■*•*•* coctoi^ aoaooi^ — « j (J I I " •*••«■ «--- N « 5 i •o I 5 1 &gt; « 5 g c S»n&gt;-:« Ntp — « ■♦looqtq «-*&lt;no cot»®ao sa«n n  - i- 1 ?"* 0 ! 10 °"" N(M NNNN CINMn INPJriT); lOuio® ~m •? i^ a« c | 00 — »o;oq ooosoqoo o; Oi o; Oi osqcnn cqcpoco c*x ? 5 fa c i 5 1 g *c oo i-H i^ c m «&gt; © e« -h I I i «l II ? 9 &gt; &gt; * Jbt7T° C ' c&lt;e&lt;cti -"•"••* ---- ---in NnM-r eici </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Relation of Nonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 103 In the H O cylinder, which carried four plants from the first planting, the first ripened on April 29, producing 10 beans. Two other plants died during the next few days without having set any seed, and the last plant was dead by May 7. having pro - duced 7 beans. The cylinder was opened on the next day. Boots were abundant thruout the subsoil and the free water in the sub - soil was quite uniformly reduced to 1.6 to 1.9 per pent, it being slightly lowest in the sixth foot where fine roots were most numerous. The moisture content of the subsoil watf 1.0 to 0.7 per cent below the wilting coefficient. In the Wauneta cylinder, in which there were three early plants, the first was dead by May 15, producing 6 beans. The second plant was still in healthy condition as late as May 30 but was dead by June 6. From the third plant 3 ripe pods containing 11 beans were removed on May 18. It continued alive and blossomed again before the end of the month. As late as June •i it was in fair condition, but was found wilted early on the morning of June 7. The next day it appeared quite dead and was removed, but the cylinder was not opened until 15 days later. While some water may have been lost from the surface foot by direct evaporation during these 15 days, it is highly im - probable that there was any important movement of water in the subsoil during the interval which elapsed between the harvest - ing of the last of the crop and the opening of the cylinder. 1 Roots extended to the bottom of the cylinder but were not numer - ous in the sixth foot. The free water in the subsoil had been re - duced quite uniformly to 2 to 3 per cent to a depth of 54 inches; below this it rose gradually to 6.2 per cent. To a depth of ."&gt;4 inches the moisture had been reduced from 2.0 to 3.0 per ceni l&gt;elow the wilting coefficient but in the sixth foot it wm about 2.0 per cent above the wilting coefficient. In the McCook cylinder, in which there were three late plants, one on June 6 ripened a pod containing 2 beans. This plant, however, as well as the two others continued green but made no growth. By July 18 all had died without forming any more seed. The cylinder was opened that day. Roots extended to the bottom of the cylinder and were abundant thruout the first five feet. The free moisture in the upper four feet of subsoil had been quite uniformly reduced to 1.0 to 2.0 per cent. In the sixth foot there was still 3.4 per cent. In the Holdrege cylinder the single surviving plant, from the first planting, ripened on May 18. producing 9 beans in two pods. Roots extended to the upper portion of the sixth foot but they had drawn very lightly on the moisture in the subsoil below the third foot, there being from 14 to 20 per cent of free water 1 Alway, F. J., and Clark, V. L., loc. cit. </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 trek Bulletin \o. 3 moisture reduced to the wilting coefficient. In the Hastings cylinder, which carried one early plant and two late plants, the first ripened May 18, producing a single bean. On May 30 one of the remaining plants was in blossom but on June 6 both plants were dead. The cylinder was opened 16 days later. In the distribution of roots and in the moisture conditions this very closely resembled the Holdrege cylinder. The single plant in the Lincoln cylinder ripened two pods with "&gt; beans on May 11. It continued green and blossomed again from May 18 to June 8. but was dead by June 27 without having formed any more, pods. The cylinder was opened on that day. Roots were quite abundant to the bottom of the cylinder, but not in nearly the quantity found in the H O cylinder. The moisture of the subsoil, except in parts of the second and third foot, where fine roots were not numerous, was reduced quite uni - formly to 2.5 to 3.7 per cent of free water, or to 2.0 to 3.0 per cent below the wilting coefficient. (Figure 27.) The crevice between soil column and cylinder wall was en - tirely wanting in the H O cylinder and reached to only 5 and 6 incheR respectively in the Wauneta and McCook cylinders, to 27 and 18 inches respectively in the Holdrege and Hastings cylin - ders, and in all cases was very small. In the Lincoln cylinder it extended to 18 inches. MAIZE. Four germinated kernels of a white flint variety obtained from the Sulphur Spring Valley Dry Farm were planted on February 20 in each of two cylinders, Nos. 24 and 76. which had been filled with H O surface soil and H O subsoil as described on pages 80 and 81. Four days later all the plants were up, and at the end of another week they were thinned to the most vigorous one in each cylinder. The two plants did well until the latter part of March, when the one in No. 76 from some unknown cause received a severe check. On April 11 that in No. 24 was in bloom and the next day the silk appeared. On April 29 the plant was 54 inches high and had 7 leaves. On May 18 all the leaves were dead, and 12 days later the plant, then quite dry, was harvested and the cylinder opened. The plant had formed a very small ear bearing 13 kernels. The plant in cylinder No. 76 recovered somewhat during April, and on the 2!&gt;th of that month was 23 inches high. It had already been in tassel two weeks but the silk did not appear until May 6, before which time all the pollen had fallen. All of the plant Sthe ear had dried up by May 18 but this was still green he cylinder was opened on May 30. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">I - fe u: iiiilSsS t- « i a re x w s s I L i i L. U 9.9 Hh : : 5 aai|l|l iiii^jl li If Iff j - -. s . : ! s . - . ,^ m - S ?- ti « s- ut x i: .&gt;• -i .- - = - ISc .1: ■= I 1111 S I !&amp;&amp;€% iili h iiiiiiM ; : lull 5l|;|i5l iaaliljl I: Itt|| !r'5£.=-=£o = .= .= .= .= .= .= --•5 • ■ --C"£-i^ til 1^1 II 111111:2:2 5 5=^2£ coco = coo ooocoo'SS </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Figure 33 shows the plants as they ap - peared on May 27. The relation of the distribution of water to the root develop - ment is shown in figure 34 and Table 29. In neither cylinder had a crevice formed between the soil column and the cylinder wall. lit the first cylinder roots were abund - ant thruout the soil mass, reaching to the very bottom of the cylinder, while in the other they were numerous in the first two feet of subsoil and very scarce in the three feet below. In No. 24 the free moisture amounted to about 1.5 per cent at all depths below the first foot while in No. 76 it rose steadily from 1.3 per cent in the upper part of the second foot to over 18.0 per cent at the bottom of the cylinder. The water in the first had been reduced to 1.0 per cent be - low the wilting coefficient but that in the other was still far above the wilting co - efficient. (Figure 22.1 SUMMARY OF EXPERIMENT OF 1911. When the seeds were planted, the cylin - ders carried from one and a half to three times as much fre* water as the same soils would have retained under field conditions. Abnormally high temperatures near the clow of the experiment hastened the death of the wheat and bean plants, which in general had poorly developed root systems. Normal milo and bean plants were pro- . No. 76. No. 24. Pig. 33. Corn plants 96 days after planting. Both dead. duced on most of the soils, but all the wheat plants failed to make a normal growth and died while an abundance of free water still remained in the subsoil. In one cylinder a maize plant de veloped roots to the bottom of the cylinder and uniformly re - duced the water content to a point below the wilting coefficient. In nearly all the cylinders roots penetrated to the bottom but in the case of the wheat and the beans the development was in most cases much less than in the preceding two experiments. Where roots were developed in abundance the water content was reduced almost to the hygroscopic coefficient before the plants » </seg>
            <seg id="p107">Relation of Xonamilablr Wuttr to Hygroscopic Coefficient 107 Table 29. — Moisture conditions in cylinders with maize. 1.5 7.6 1.6 8.3 1.4 9.0 1.3 9.5 28-30 1.4 10.1 1.4 10.6 1.4 11.6 1.3 13.0 1.5 12.7 1.4 13.8 1.4 14.9 1.4 16.5 1.4 16.3 1.4 17.9 1.1 18.9 1.0 18.4 —2.5 ! —3.3 1.3 11.3 Fig. 34. Roots of corn. The branching of the milo plants favored the exhaustion of the soil moisture by greatly reducing the transpiring surface after the root system had been fully developed and the moisture content much reduced. Little difference in the growth of plants and in the develop - ment of roots was observed between the most westerly loess soil — from Wauneta — and the neighboring residual High Plains soil from Madrid. Except in the case of those from the most easterly of the live , ! | 28-30 4 1 31-33 { 34-36 ( 37-39 ! 40-42 4 1 43-45 I 46-48 | 49-51 . 52-54 0 1 55-57 I 58-60 f 61-63 fi 64-66 * •• ) 67-69 I 70-71 Depth of section Free water Cyl. 24 Cyl. 76 Feet Inches j Per rent j Per cent If 1-4 ! 5-6 I 7-9 I 10-12 —5.7 —5.8 —3.8 —1.4 —1.4 —2.6 0.6 —0.5 II 13-15 16-18 •■• . 19-21 22-24 ■ 1.3 1.3 1.2 3.1 1.4 5.9 1.5 6.9 I I 25-27 1.5 7.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 Research Bulletin Wo. J localities on the loess, no difference was observed in the readiness with which roots penetrated the soils or in the extent to which the free water could be exhausted, the latter probably being de - pendent upon the former. The eastern soils, which gave up their free water least completely, were much less calcareous than the others. In all the cylinders a hard crust developed below the mulch. EXPERIMENTS WITH PEKENNIAL DESEBT LEGUMES Three species were employed more or less, viz, Prosopig r&lt; lit Una (Mesquite), Acucia Oreggi (Catsclaw), and Acacia con - gtricta. The seeds of the first two were gathered near Benson, Arizona, and those of the last near Columbus, New Mexico. Both places are in desert regions, the normal annual precipitation be - ing a little under 10 inches. The seeds were planted on December 31, 1910, in small flower - pots filled with surface soil from the Experiment Station farm. Later, part were transferred to larger flowerpots filled with the same soil. Until they were transplanted to the metal cylinder and left to die all were watered freely. Expehiment 1.— -In this there were used two cylinders of gal - vanized iron 6 inches in diameter and 1 foot high, in the bottom of each of which ten small holes had been punched In the bottom of each a layer of coarse gravel f of an inch in thickness was placed and then H O subsoil tamped in to within 3 inches of the top. On February 4. 1911, one small mesquite plant (Pro - soph relutina) was transplanted, soil and all, to each cylinder. The space between the black soil and the cylinder was filled with H O subsoil. The surface was covered with a one-half inch mulch of coarse sand, the top of this being one-half inch below the top of the cylinder. Then the soil was thoroly satu - rated and the cylinders left in the greenhouse without further addition of water and without any protection from the sun's ravs. The mesquites when transplanted were 4 inches high and bore 7 and 9 compound leaves, respectively. On March 18 the plants were both 10.5 inches high and bore 15 and 14 compound leaves, respectively; even on this date some of the lowest leaves had fallen from each. On April 11 the tip of the plant in cylin - der No. 3 was dead and only 6 compound leaves remained, while the tip of the plant in cylinder No. 4 was still alive altho the number of compound leaves on it also was only 6. Nine days later the numbers of leaves were 4 and 6 respectively. On May 7, just before No. 3 was opened, when the plants were photo- </seg>
            <seg id="p109">graphed (.tig. SB), the numbers of compound leaves were 1 and 5 respectively and the tip of the plant in No. 4 was dead. On May 15, when No. 4 was opened, the plant in it carried 4 leaves. t Roots had penetrated the whole of the soil mass. For mois - e determinations, only the most protected portion of the H O woil in each was used. All of the black soil and the 2 inches subsoil below this, as well as the lowest 2 inches of the soil umn and the 1 inch of the soil column next the cylinder wall. re removed and the remaining portion of the soil column, ieh was nbout 5 inches high and 4 inches in diameter, was well No. 4 No. 3 Fig. 35. Mesquite plants of the same age. The two on the left had been watered freely while the other two had not been watered for 92 days. Altho no free water remained in the soil of the latter two cylinders, — even in the most protected portions, — both plants were alive. Eced and moisture determinations made in triplicate. The free ter content in this soil portion from cylinder No. 3 was — 0.8 ■ cent and in that from No. 4 was — 0.6 per cent. tin figure '■'&gt;'&gt; are shown the mesquite plants as they appeared May 7, together with two others which had been transplanted the same time as those in Nob. 3 and 4, but to large flowerpots, erwiirds being watered daily. On May 7 each of the latter was hit 2fi inches hijrh and bore about 30 compound leaves. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 Research Bulletin Xo. 3 Experiment 2. — In this a 6-foot cylinder filled with II &lt;&gt; sur - face soil and H O subsoil was used. It had been filled and nta - rated .along with those described on pages 80 and 81. On February 28. 1911, two mesquite plants were placed in this. In transplant - ing the mesquites the surface soil was removed to a depth of 6 inches and the whole of the soil from The two flowerpots intro - duced so as not to disturb the roots of the mesquites, after which the open spaces were filled with the H O surface soil which had just been removed. A day mulch of H O surface soil was then added. Thus there was some Lincoln surface soil in the first 6 inches of this cylinder but the quantity was small and its relative hygroscopicity was so similar to that of the H O surface soil that it might be considered as part of the latter. The larger of the two plants grew much the more rapidly, but both did well until early in April, when the smaller began dying. The latter gradually declined until on June 6 it appeared quite dead. Its height was 14.5 inches. The other continued to grow until it was 47.5 inches high; then it began to drop its leiives, one by one. but on June 17 it still appeared quite vigorous. At the end of June it had lost most of its leaves and on the evening of July 5. a day when the maximum temperature in the green - house reached 130° F.. it appeared to have l»een killed. On .Inly 12. the plant being quite dry. it was removed and the cylinder opened. About a dozen leaves remained on the plant when it died. A small crevice extended to the 9th inch but there was none below. Roots were well distributed thrnout the subsoil. (See Table 28 and figure 36.) The subsoil, as shown in Table 30 and in figure 22. was very dry. the moisture content being uniform and distinctly below the hygroscopic coefficient. There can be little doubt but that some little time before the death of the larger plant all free moisture had disappeared from both soil and subsoil. Under more favor - able temperature conditions it would probably have continued to live for some time, notwithstanding the entire absence of free moisture, dropping its leaves one by one. Instead of continuing to thus drop its leaves until all were gone it had died with a dozen still adhering. The temperature in the shade in the open air on that day was 110° F.. while the maximum thermometer in the greenhouse recorded a temperature of 130° F. That it was not the high temperature, independent of the transpiration, which killed the plant is evident from the circumstance that various other mesquites and acacias, which were in the same greenhouse but which were watered daily, remained uninjured. Even two milo plants, those in the Mi-Conk and Holdrege cylinders, survived (pages 94 and 9H). </seg>
            <seg id="p111">r lotion of Nonavailablf Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 30. — Moisture conditions cU death ofmesquite. conditions at death ofmetquite, Total water Free water 40-42 4.8 * 1 Hi-IP, 4 7 Fig. 36. Average . . . Average ... 1-12 4.5 13-71 ftj ~~°- 7 Roots of mes- quites. Experiment 3. — In this experiment three water-tight cylin - ders, each two feet high and one foot in diameter, were used. The young plants were transferred from the flowerpots on June 17. 1911. they being nearly 6 months old. The soil used was H O subsoil except for the small amount of Lincoln surface soil from the small flowerpots, this having been transferred so as not to dis - turb the roots. A large supply of H O subsoil had been brought to a content of about 14 per cent of total water and with this the cylinders were filled, with tamping, to a height of 18 inches i ABLE all. — Mouture conditions at i Depth of section Total wat&lt; Feel Incite* Per cent i 1-4 2.7 , 5-6 4.0 1 1 7-9 5.1 I 10-12 6.3 | 13-15 4.5 ., 16-18 4.7 z 1 19-21 5.0 I 22-24 4.9 f 25-27 5.0 , 28-30 4.8 J 1 31-33 5.0 I 34-36 4.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">s =-. « 2^3 S'ss 33:1:1 »«-*"* ~~ -»~ * t 1 |-[- — c I I I '/. X X /. X X X X 5 a V lsli.111111 acbkfefek~fe*irjrti o •- ."51*1* 1*1* !*:*.■*.■*■« tc-s t£&amp;§gggfe£ a IllllSllii |Sx = .-=.^.- 582=2=! 5 5 1 I I 1 1 1 s ac tt _ 1 Jiia^ail ■a&gt;lTJ|||^ = 55 ** ■-j»-"* el JJJ5J5».fc I Iiltlllf-H Sfe-jfiiijfjiiJj J I!!!!!!!!! iiiillillil JT= = = := = = = = = — -g &lt;•!«&lt;&lt;&lt;::: BPPt'fe'&amp;B'I'I'i g^ ******** </seg>
            <seg id="p113">Relation of S onavailablc Water to Hygroscopic CoefficieHi 113 Im the bottom. The leguminous plants were transferred, soil I all, and placed on this subsoil. Then more of the moist H O soil was parked firmly around and on the top of the trans - red black soil. Then the whole was covered with two inches air-dry H O subsoil. After the transplanting the cylinders •e kept in a cool, partly shaded room until July 6, when they ■e so placed in a pit in the greenhouse that the tops of the Protopu velutina and Acacia Greggi Prtuopu vtlutiua Acacia constrict* Fig. 37. Desert legumes in 2-foot cylinders when growth had ceased. cylinders projected from two to three inches above the level of the ground. No water was added. The plants showed no sign of injury from the transfer and afterwards all made considerable growth. The three cylinders carried the following : I. Three plants of Prosopis velutina. II. Four plants of Acacia (hreggi. III. Three plants of Prompts velutina and one plant of Acacia </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 Research Bulletin No. S case of I. and on August 11 the tips of all branches on the plants in this were dead and the lowest leaves had begun falling. In II and III. on the same date, the tips were uninjured and no leaves had fallen. Growth had ceased in I and II by August 15, when the photograph ( figure 37) was taken, and in III by September 1. On August 16 the tallest plant in I was in the worst condi - tion, while many leaves had fallen from the second plant and a few from the third. In II all the tips were dead and the lowest leaves had fallen. In III none of the plants wag yet injured. Cylinder I was opened on September 23 and the other two were opened on October 13. In none were all the plants dead when the cylinders were opened but in the case of each all the tips had died and nearly all the leaves had fallen; the most vigorous plant in each retained only from five to seven compound leaves. The cylinders were weighed on June 17, after the plants had been placed in them, and again on August 17 after the first signs of injury from drouth were noticed. After the latter date they were weighed at intervals until opened, using scales sensitive to 15 grams. During the three weeks preceding the opening of cylin - ders II and III the loss in weight was practically nothing, while during one week, September 23 to 30, there was a slight gain in weight. This week was characterized by cloudiness and un - usually high humidity of the air, and the increase in weight is to be attributed to the increase in the amount of hygroscopic mois - ture in the dry surface mulch. Table 31 shows the loss in weight of the cylinders and the average per cent of water in the soil of the different cylinders. The weights of the plants are included in those of the soil, but the former were too small to appreciably affect the results. In none of the cylinders did a crevice form between cylinder wall and soil column. The roots penetrated to the bottom of the cylinders, being most abundant in the lowest three-inch section. The moisture conditions existing at the time of opening the cylin - ders are shown in Table 32. Free water had entirely disappeared. Below the first foot the moisture content was practically uni - form. The black surface soil, in which the plants had been started and which was transferred with these, appears, from the mere statement of the amount of free water, to be drier than the con - tiguous subsoil, but in reality it is not, both being about half saturated with hygroscopic moisture. This black soil wag pres - ent in the form of three or four conical masses surrounded en - tirely by H O subsoil. Summary of exi-ebiments. — The plants remained alive after water content had fallen slightly, but distinctly, below the </seg>
            <seg id="p115">Relation of Xonavailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 115 hygroscopic coefficient and even to a point at which the milo had died. When conditions were favorable they adjusted themselves to the gradually increasing difficulty of absorbing water, due to the soil steadily becoming drier, by dropping their leaves one by one, transpiration finally almost ceasing. When, however, con - rons causing an abnormally high transpiration suddenly set the plants died without dropping their leaves. rLK .12. — Moisture conditions in cylinders carrying desert le - gumes. * This was between the 4th and the 9th inches and was entirely surrounded by H O Subsoil. The experiments furnish no evidence of any ability on the part of these legumes to utilize for grmoth the last portion of free water, but they indicate that this portion has a very high value for the maintenance of life and that even some of the water below the hygroscopic coefficient may be available for the maintenance of life in these plants. This evident ability of these desert plants to make use of water below the hygroscopic coefficient suggests that the absolute limit of soil water available for either growth or the mainte - nance of life may be the hygroscopidty as defined by Rodewald and Mitscherlich. 1 THE HYGROSCOPIC COEFFICIENT VERSUS THE WILTING COEF - kFICIENT IN COMPARISONS OF THE AVAILABLE MOISTURE OF SOILS. The free moisture in semiarid and arid soils, in so far as the above-described experiments and the results of unpublished field studies permit conclusions to be drawn, appears to be capable of more complete exhaustion by plant roots before the plants die 1 Rodewald, H., and Mitscherlich, A. Die Bestimmung der Hygroskop - izitat. Landwirthschaftlichen Versuchs-Station. 1904, vol. 59, pp. 433-441. 'otal water Free water Depth of section II ,„ II III Inehe* 1-3 4-6 7-9 10-12 13-15 16-18 19-21 22-24 acksoil* Percent 2.6 2.8 3.6 4.3 4.8 4.9 4.9 4.8 5.7 Per cent I'er rent 2.2 2.2 2.7 3.0 3.8 4.0 4.6 4.4 4.8 5.1 5.0 5.2 5.0 5.3 5.0 5.2 6.0 5.3 Per rent Per cent Per rent —3.0 —3.4 —3.4 —2.8 —2.9 —2.6 —2.0 —1.8 —1.6 —1.3 —1.0 —1.2 —0.8 —0.8 —0.5 —0.7 —0.6 —0.4 —0.7 —0.6 —0.3 —0.8 —0.6 —0.4 —5.6 -^5.3 —6.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 than d(M&gt; thai in humid soils. This may be due simply tu tin - more complete j&gt;eiietration of the soil mass by the roots in the case of the somiarid and arid soils, and this in turn be due to the floeculation of the clay in the latter. It is well known that the arid and semiarid soils are strongly calcareous compared with humid soils, a good illustration being furnished by the loess ■oils of the Transition Region. 1 Briggs and Shantz- consider that a statement of the free water may he very misleading in comparisons of the available moisture in soils. The most of the experiments described above furnish little or no evidence as to the correctness of these views, the cylinders in most cases not having been opened until long after growth of the contained plants had ceased. The few exceii tions include cylinders I and IV with wheat in 1909 and cylin - ders I and II with beans in 1910. The former ripened seed nor - mally and as soon as the plants appeared quite ripe the cylin - ders were opened; in both the moisture of the subsoil had been Site uniformly reduced to more than 2 per cent below the wilt - t coefficient. Much the mm was true for the two cylinders th beans in 1910. tSome evidence is furnished by the numerous cylinders in oh when the plants died the moisture content of the upper tion of the subsoil, where roots were the most numerous, was 1 Alway, F. J. Composition of the Loess Soils of the Transition Region, Eighth International Congress of Applied Chemistry, 1912, Report of Sec - tion VII, p. 11. 1 They have incorrectly stated the writer's earlier views as to the basis for comparing the available moisture in soils. They state: "In the absence of a more definite relationship between the wilting coefficient and the hygroscopic coefficient, Alway has advocated deducting the hygro - scopic coefficient from the field soil-moisture determinations as a basis for comparing the available moisture in soils." (Bui. 230, Bureau of Plant Industry, P- 66.) On the contrary the writer had stated that the "free water," obtained by deducting the hygroscopic coefficient from the total water (= field moisture determination), "does not indicate the amount of water that is available in such form that the plant can continue a normal growth. * * * It is probable that the normal growth ceases when the percentage of free moisture falls to from 4 to 8 per cent according to the soil." (Bui. 130, Bureau of Plant Industry, p. 38.) "A comparison of the fields on the basis of the amount of free water in the first six feet assumes that a definite value Is to be attached to a certain percentage of free water, independent of the kind of soil • • * in which it occurs. It is evident from Hilgard's work, however, that a higher percentage of free moisture is required on clay than on sandy soils in order that plant growth may continue. • • • It has been assumed that the lower limit of free moisture in the boulder clay is 4.6 and In the lacustral clay 6.0 per cent. The free water less this 4.5 or 6.0 per cent is for convenience at present designated the 'x water.' " (Jour. Agr. Sc., vol. 2, pp. 338-340.) In the earlier publication this ''x water" had been referred to as "water probably available for normal plant growth." (Bui. 130, Bureau of Plant ' </seg>
            <seg id="p117">much below the wilting coefficient while that of the lower portion, where the roots, altho much less abundant, were still present, was much above the wilting coefficient. This would indicate that when once the roots are developed in the subsoil they fail to dis - tinguish sharply between the portion of the free water above the wilting coefficient and the portion below; otherwise, after the moisture in a portion of the subsoil had been reduced to the wilt - ing coefficient, water removal from this portion would cease so long as roots of the same plant were in contact with subsoil with a moisture content above the wilting coefficient. It seems that in reality the roots in the drier portions of the subsoil may be re - moving "water nonavailable for growth" at the same time that roots of the same plant in moist subsoil are removing "water available for growth." Even if the soil moisture supply is so low that no growth can take place, it may suffice for the maturing of some seed, as with a wheat crop, or for the maintenance of life in the case of per - ennials. With the latter the mere maintenance of life thru a very dry period may bo far more important than any growth in that particular year, as in the case of orchards, hedges, and even alfalfa fields. A slight difference in the ability of a perennial plant to make use of the last jwrtion of the free water may deter - mine whether or not it is adapted to extremely severe conditions. As an illustration of the relative value of the two coefficients in comparisons of available moisture in field studies the data in Tables 33 to 36 are presented. The field referred to in Table 33 is on the farm of Hon. George Coupland near Elgin, Nebraska. It had been in alfalfa for ten years and at the time of sampling there was still a fair stand of healthy plants. The water-table was probably at a depth of 45 to 50 feet below the surface of the field, the soil of which consists of loess to a depth of 35 feet. The alfalfa field referred to in Table 34 is adjacent to the Ne - braska Experiment Station farm. It had been in alfalfa for five or six years and, judging from its vigorous growth during prolonged drouths, the alfalfa plants derived much water from the water-table, which at the time of sampling was between 11 and 12 feet below the surface. The locust grove (Table 35) is on the H O Ranch near Madrid, in western Nebraska. At the time the samples were taken it had passed thru a drouth remarkable both for its duration and for its severity. All the trees, altho not in leaf at the time, were alive, as evidenced by their still being alive a year later. The abandoned olive orchard referred to in Table 36 is near Casa flrande, Arizona, and has been described by Mason. 1 The samples were taken by the writer from a trench 1 Mason, S. C. Drought Resistance of the Olive in the Southwestern States. Bui. 192, Bureau of Plant Industry, U. S. Dept. of Agriculture 1911, p. 13. </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 Research Bulletin No. 3 excavated at the bane of an olive tree beside which was growing a mesquite. The former was about 18 years old, and the latter, judging from the number of annual rings, was 11 or 12 years old. The roots of the olive did not extend more than 3 feet below the surface, but the tap-root of the mesquite extended below the sixth foot. On the day before the samples were taken a rain of 0.7&lt;» inch had fallen. In the case of the two alfalfa fields the plants were growing normally and in the one the roots were evidently deriving much of their water from the water-table. However, in both cases the moisture of the subsoil to a considerable depth had been reduced Table 33. — Moisture conditions in an old alfalfa field near Elgin, Nebraska, August 2-J, 1911. Table 34. — Moisture conditions in a naturally subirrigated al - falfa field near the Nebraska Experiment Station farm, Depth in feet Depth in feet Total water HyP" 0800 ?' 0 Wilting lotal water coefficient "Water Free water available for growth" 1 2to 6 7 to 12 13 to 18 19 to 24 25 to 27 28 to 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 Percent 12.4 8.3 12.2 11.5 9.3 13.7 11.7 10.2 15.0 12.8 10.1 14.8 13.1 9.9 14.5 1 13.6 10.3 15.2 15.6 10.1 14.8 18.1 10.3 15.2 20.1 10.5 15.4 20.2 10.0 14.7 21.1 10.0 14.7 19.9 9.5 14.0 12.6 4.7 6.9 Percent Percent 4.1 0.2 2.2 —2.2 1.5 —3.3 2.7 —2.0 3.2 —1.4 3.3 —1.6 5.5 0.8 7.8 2.9 9.6 4.7 10.2 5.5 11.1 6.4 10.4 5.9 7.9 5.7 Augus 8urfac&lt; ■e water- 'e was oi 1011 1 'eet &gt;tc I Depth in feet Total water Hygroscopic Wilting lotai water coefficient coefficient "Water Free water available for 1 2to4 5to6 : | Percent 10.8 9.7 14.3 13.0 9.4 13.8 14.1 11.6 17.0 22.0 13.7 20.2 25.6 13.3 19.6 25.7 11.0 16.2 Per cent P*r eent 1.1 —3.5 3.6 —0.8 2.5 —2.9 8.3 1.8 12.3 6.0 14.7 9.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">Relation of Xonaiailable Water to Hygroscopic Coefficient 119 rE 35. — Moisture conditions in a young locust grove near Madrid. Nebraska, on April 20. 1911. content much below the wilting coefficient. SUMMARY AND CONCLUSIONS. Water-tight cylinders, 6 feet long and holding about 100 pounds of soil, were either filled with dry soil, saturated with water, and drained before sealing at the bottom, or filled with soil already containing the desired amount of moisture. These were removed to a greenhouse, seeds of wheat, milo. beans, or maize planted in the moist surface soil, and no more water added, the resulting plants being allowed to grow until they ma- El normally or died. Upon the death of all the plants in a der it was opened, both the total and the free water in 3-inch section of soil determined, and the distribution of - Depth in feet 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ™™** I 5SS3? e I'ercent 13.7 9.8 11.8 10.5 10.4 8.2 9.8 7.5 8.5 7.0 7.9 7.2 8.0 7.3 8.1 7.1 8.3 6.7 eoSfnt **•«*« »™^f°' lev cad Per emi 14.4 3.9 —0.7 15.4 1.3 —3.6 12.0 2.2 —1.6 11.0 2.3 —1.2 10.3 1.5 —1.8 10.5 0.7 —2.6 10.7 0.7 —2.7 10.4 1.0 —2.3 9.8 1.6 —1.5 Table 36. — Moisture conditions near Casa Grande, Ar in an abandoned olive orchard Izona, October 6, 191 1. Depth Total water H^^pic J2&amp; *-■ — ™S°' Percent 1 to 4 in. 10.3 6.0 7 to 12 in. 6.2 6.9 13 to 18 in. 6.8 7.2 19 to 24 in. 8.5 9.0 3d foot 13.4 13.8 Pfoot 9.3 10.6 foot 7.8 8.1 foot &lt;U&gt; 7.5 Per cent Percent 8.8 4.3 1.5 10.1 —0.7 —3.9 10.6 —0.4 —3.8 13.2 —0.5 —4.7 20.2 —0.4 —6.8 15.6 —1.3 —6.3 11.9 —0.3 —4.1 10.0 —0.6 I — 3.1 )elow the wilting coefficient. Ii vere alive while their roots oci i the other two instances trees :upied subsoil with a moisture </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 were grown until they died or were near their limit of endiir - ance; then the cylinders were opened and the moisture content and root distribution determined. In all the cylinders bearing plants,) a hard crust developed be tow the surface mulch of dry soil but it seemed to have no in - jurious effect. The formation of such a crust is to be regarded as unavoidable where during a prolonged period of rainl'ss weather plants with a well-developed root system ;m&lt;l ;i nry limited amount of moisture in the subsoil are transpiring ■ largt amount of water. In their ability to exhaust the moisture of the subsoil before dying. Red Fife wheat, Kubanka wheat, milo. Mexican beans, and maize showed little difference, but in their ability to continue alive after first showing serious injury from drouth they ex - hibited marked differences. The interval between wilting and death in the case of the beans amounted to only a few days but in that of wheat and milo it often extended to many weeks. Whnc there was a well-developed root system and no remark - ably unfavorable conditions occurred before the death of the plants, tin* moisture content could be reduced by any of these plants almost to the hygroscopic coefficient. In experiments with perennial desert legumes the plants re - mained alive after the water content had fallen slightly, but distinctly, below the hygroscopic coefficient, even to the point at which all the above-mentioned annual crop plants had died. Under favorable conditions these legumes adjusted themselves to the gradually increasing dryness of the soil by dropping their leaves one by one. but where, with the subsoil moisture already reduced to near the hygroscopic coefficient, conditions causing an abnormally high transpiration suddenly set in. death oc - curred without the leaves having dropped. While the experi - ments furnish no evidence of any ability on the part of these legumes to utilize for growth the last portion of free water, they indicate that this portion has a very high value for the maintenance of life and that even some of the water below the hygroscopic coefficient may be available for the maintenance of life in these plants. In the portions of a semiarid subsoil where roots are well de - veloped the final content of free water is independent of the dis - tance from the surface, except where the stored water is much in excess of the amount required for the complete maturity of the Phen the portion of the subsoil in immediate contact with the contains only a comparatively small amount of free water. </seg>
            <seg id="p121">an unusually rapid transpiration. An abundance of free water in deeper portions of the subsoil, into which but few roots have been developed, may not avail to carry the plant over such a critical period. The economy in the use of a certain amount of free water stored in the subsoil may be much affected by its distribution. A high content confined to the portion of the soil near the surface may induce a rapid growth of the plants and an economical use of the water in so far as the production of foliage alone is con - cerned, but the resulting large transpiring surface may cause the death of the plants before they reach maturity. The same amount of free water distributed thru a greater depth may in - duce a slower growth, allow a longer lease of life, and so permit of the production of seed, while if the same amount be distributed thru a still greater depth the content of free water may every - where be too low to permit of the development of roots, thus ren - dering the free water nonavailable. The loss of water from the subsoil of dry lands under crop seems to take place almost entirely thru transpiration. In the alisence of plants the loss from the subsoil is small. The stored moisture of the different depths of subsoil in the field becomes available to the plants by the roots being developed into these depths, but little moisture being elevated to the roots by capil - larity. However, in the case of subsoils saturated in cylinders or pots and comparable to such field subsoils as are only a few feet above the water-table, the content of free water is so high that large amounts of moisture may be elevated to the roots by capillarity. The amount of water retained by a soil saturated in pots or cylinders is far in excess of the amount retained by a similar soil saturated in a field where the water-table is at a considerable depth below the surface, as in ordinary dry-land To obtain a basis for comparing the available moisture in soils, either the hygroscopic coefficient or the wilting coefficient may be used. In general the one mav prove as satisfactory as the other, but in considering the germination of seeds and the development of roots, and hence the whole of the earlier portion of the life of annual crop plants, the wilting coefficient appears the preferable: while in considering the production of seed in the case of annual crop plants, and the maintenance of life and even the growth of perennial plants, the hygroscopic coefficient appears much the preferable. In the case of ordinary dry-land soils, the water-tabl^ being :it a considerable depth below the surface, the maximum amount </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 • of soil water available to plants, for growth and for the main tenance of life, is approximately equal to the free water — the difference between the tot.il water and the hygroscopic coefficient — in those portions of the soil and the subsoil occupied by the roots. For some plants the available water appears to be some - what greater and for others somewhat less than the free water. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>