<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  ALFALFA INOCULATION TESTS.</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN i AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OP NEBRASKA. Voi i mh XXV. Ai: I n U VI ALFALFA INOCULATION TESTS ■ i XIVKKSITY &lt;&gt;K N KB K A SKA. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION &lt; &gt;1 NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD ■ I' I! c I: I • M . M I) V V w </seg>
            <seg id="p003">ALFALFA INOCULATION TESTS. ■ in .in filnri u;i&gt; made to Kcwf Nebraska to test tin- raise of inMs. 'I'liis investigation was correspondents during I'.HI'.l. perate were we ted l&gt;y r&lt;ir • i-i in i - at the various Short Course* li«* 1 • 1 'in iibom iliiiiv ive fanners, located l:i rtr»-l \ r nibrulge. I'ranklin. and Blair, agreed t&lt;&gt; - seal by the Pnited Btatea Department from will established alfalfa fields, and i Rtanda of alfalfa and &lt;m Hie snhseqiient ■ ini- . mulit iui:&gt; were very ■■favorable and it was repeal the lists in the spring &lt;&gt;f 1911. If in* were lnoi-c HTCTC !li&lt;' second Year. The fed was herame of eitremely di-\ weather and it urn her nl (trnsshoppers. Man\ of tlic farmers applied m ■ iln- rnlrnre bat reported in -Inlv and August of ■ i In- prop wan cut irel.i dead. rhe thirty-five pooperators we save onl\ twelve reparts n-atmentH. The tesis should by all ■ ■i a ii 1 1 ii 1 1 &gt;«•■- of years, and should cover all ite The reports in this balletis rorer seedinjpi :t n&gt; ! observation* during the year \'.)\'2 • testi was as follows: The m _n a statement promising to carry out l&gt;\ the Station and to keep a record of all Instructions wire sent them as hi seeding, the ground, application of caltnre, soil ami other details an were necessary. Wherever it man was sent from the Expert lent in locating the plots and in applyiag the va Tin plo - oeated in sinh a manner that : from iniHiilated to unino'iilated plots 1 would l&gt;i' as uniform as poa- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 ashiht in i he |H"&lt;i|m r interpn low injj questions were ;iskci] cmli roniiei How was ground prepared on whirh 'hi ilialfa was bi What crops were yro» ■ o, when? nnarilv is th^ Was cult i an area? VV;. Wa h? i.urh? V as barnyn low i Ma* The IM1 kill*-.] tli.' alfa killed tin- mIi I th.it I plow to tin- ilr\ ireathei 'rii«- reop&lt; i miner of 1916 -mnmcr of 1911 ■ 'if Mil, ; ' Tile follutt .1 I v II V i; \i I .nii.u- Holt tHanpi Martin I I I - U .1 I ■ I'.ilu I I From (h»- note* which wer* In iiflht in l&gt;\ i </seg>
            <seg id="p005">•" i mis were secured on the fields which i in manure and cjirefnl mltiva- v . iiiiimiiis rrop had Iwen previously grown. r i ured from fields tn which farm it the time nf seedinjr. or during some &gt;r w in fields where farm manure had m-ver ■ -nurse. diM's not mean that a heavy aj&gt; r re plowed under, in the western part of rm. would give any advantage for that - taken Jane 21, 1911, m the farm of Mr. .1 P. nntv, i lie fnllowing is (|iinted: "Alfalfa inueh n nl thi- field to the left. IniniM ulated i.nrtion to Martin. Custer County - m.illlaled. especiall\ where soil was used. &lt; ulllll Lihe ditieieiic-e all spring Made one half more ha\ than nd not inoculated.' KThe following letter, dated -liilv. Ittt, from Mr. \V. [•:. fole of - of inter ■•I can see little differen** in the three plots [liquid treated, rested, and im treatnenf | ai the present time, but I do think that either the liquid culture m- dirt from an old alfalfa field is a help in wearing a stand, especially in a dry time. It seems to ha\e more rigor nnd will stand more nlmse. I think the soil from an old alfalfa Held i&gt;- :i-- as anything." </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Prow tin- ihi 1911, w ■«• timl i In •ml. iln n and. W Iki&lt; tin IMpd. ill' KijMii Kiter ' - in i i Tlit </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 over patch. If ;&gt; few hiin&lt;ln*d n land wlii.li luis km |»n •: I htm 1 r&lt; &gt;t lii-i-H i-X|mim il tn 'I 'ill &gt; I in ill-;, nut. ROnd ITSIllls will RMiall.T fiillnw I'hi by tin- mm- i&gt;f i-iiltiircs. 'rin-ri- arc mam I 1 1 u in her ii 1 reliable c&lt;&gt;tii|Hinira ni;imif;iitiirin^ tin- rnltvr*. h ' ■•iiiii-s 111 hot t leu ;unl i&gt; u&gt;i il i&gt;ti the sn-il. Tin- i)r(liiiiii\ i-ost ill :i the vi nl I'm- mil' mic hi :i b. &gt;i i r S"J in' ■ nlnting the noil. Tli. 1 1 Id. well isi;ililislicil it nil rig&lt;&gt;r«NM pr patch. If ;i few himiln-il </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 E. Soil inoculation is it i&lt; ■*-« ■ certain and i tures where i! • olil and rigorou* alfalfa ■ E alfalfa has never I urn in ihe ooiiimunity, or i or if it is not successful, ii is usnalh advisable to Wherever alfa *isg. during the Ural ' lie entire tic •loculate rhe nil. This can be ilotie ■ to the new secclini! -ml from an old tielil. or b toil in itted niamiri with tlie rultun Pthis with :i \\ li&lt;r&lt; tin rannot &lt;■ r&lt; &lt;lin&lt;-i|. the mixture na I harron tu I" </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>