<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF THE EIGHTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE STATE CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION Held in Lincoln, February 2 and 3, 1904</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">s\\v.w&lt;;iiTii. IVVr(&lt; •"■.'/■.TlNi; STATK CONFKKKNCK H. V. HOAGLAND, .H»HX DAVIS. Pkksidi s i OFFICERS &lt;)K THK STATK CONFERENCE &lt;&gt;K CHARITIES AND CORSBCTIOM I Meeting to t&gt;e held at Kearney. Feb. 1 Vice President Mrs. Amanda Edward* .Omaha. Secretary ..John Davif .Lincoln Treasurer C. K. Pre\. Lincoln. Ex. Committee • CAUSES OK CKIMK Rev. S. S. Batten Lincoln. Prof. C. K. Prevev Lit Mrs. (J. I&gt;. Kollmer. .. Lincoln. Mrs. H. M. Hushnell. . . Lil Judpe K. P. Holmes... Lincoln. Mrs. B. C. Johnston. ... L i i COMMITTEE OX PKKSS ADVKKTISIXC AXI) MEMBERSHIP F. E. Sala. Hw mtf. Hc\ . A. H. 1 Kearney Dr. A. \V. Clark Omaha. Prof. A. L. ( Rev. E. M. Evans. . .Hastings. COMMITTEE ON LEGISLATION Jud), r e Wilbur K. Brvant. Mrs. H. M. Bushnell. Chancellor E. B. At John Da» REVOtf V &gt;K THE or CHARITIES AND CORRECTION lli'M in I. in ■ lent H. I). Hayward. Kearney I Chancellor K. B. Aim lernor J. H. Mickey. ' Re* ToMMITTKK ON INVESTIGATION &lt;&gt;K </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">I I NO OF THE STATE CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTION Kighth Annual Conference of the State Charities and Conro (i in Lincoln on the 2nd of Februarv at the First Chrii 14th and M Streets. following program was carried out: Programme OFFICERS OF THE CONFEKKNCK President, H. V. Hoagland, Lincoln Vice President, Mrs. Zara A. Wilson, Lincoln Secretary, John Davis, Lincoln Treasurer, C. E. Prevey, Lincoln (enrolling Secretary. Mrs. E. C. Johnson i Chan. E. B. Andrew* Executive Committee &lt; Gov. J. H. Mickey ( Rev. A. W. Clark. Omaha TUESDAY. FEBRUARY 2, 1904 Opening Meeting, 10:30 a. m, Prayer. Rev. M. A. Bullock. Address of Welcome on behalf of the City. Dr. Geo. W. Martin Address of Welcome on behalf of the State. Rev J. L. Marsh. Response on behalf of the Conference. Supt. H. M. Clark, of Geneva, and Supt. Dr. A. Johu&gt;"' Beatrice </seg>
            <seg id="p004">6 President's Address, H V. Hoagland, Ex-Chief of Police of Lincoln. Enrollment of Members i . Rev. J. L. Marsh Secretary's Reports. 2:30 p. ll Industrial Schools. B. D. Hayward, Supt. State Indus - trial School for B jys. Kearney. 3:00 P. M. The Problem of Traveling- Mendicants, Rev. S. '/. Batten. . Discussion by H. M. Clark, of Geneva, and Rev. H. 8. Haynes of Lincoln. Dr. Smith, ot St. Paul, was introduced and addi &lt; the Conference. Evening Skssion, 7:30 p. si. Music. Prayer, Rev. B. M. Long. Kemarks by Chancellor Andrews on the Stai ence of Charities. Popular Program by twenty-five pupils from the Stat&lt;- School for the Blind, consisting of music ami exercises in arithmetic, geometry, geography, etc. WEDNESDAY, FEBRUARY 3, 1904 Business Session, 9:30 a. m. Prayer. Rev. Smith. 10:1)0 A. M. The Need of a Juvenile Court, Judge E. P. Holmes 10:30 a. m. The Constitutionality of a Juvenile Court Law in Nebraska. 11KK) A. M. Discussion by Judge M. B. Reese and Mrs. H. M. Bush nell. 12:00 m. Adjournment to the Penitentiary. All members of the Conference are invited to visit the institution and attend the afternoon session which will be held there in charge of Gov. Mickey and Warden IVe - mer. Afternoon Session, 2:3O p. m. Address to the Prisoners by Geo. L. Miller. 3:00 p. M. Address. The Work of Prison Association Aktkknoon Skssion, 2:W p. m. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">charged Convicts, Prof. A. E. \&gt; versify. Music, Miss Dean. Prayer, Rev. N. S. Haynes. Unfinished Busiii. Address, Problems of Poverty. K Smith. D President of the Associated Chariti- Paul. Minn. Music, Solo, Harrv Wharton. The welcoming addresses and the responses were each i The President's address was an able review of the work. A very general discussion was participated in by a number.. rt sent on the needs and political environments of our State Institu - n*. The Rev. M. A. Bullock thought that (here would be b criminals and classes of that nature if there was more attention paid to teaching- the ethics of life in our schoools. Dr. Marsh thought that the politician who was working for his own interest instead of in the •t way as a statesman was largely responsible for the lack of care in keeping our youths from going to the bad. H. M. Clark, of &lt;t&lt;ncva, seemed to think that we should go back of the politician or public man and put the responsibility on the citizen. The interest in the first session was an earnest of the go&lt;*l ings that were to follow. It was evident that those who were in attendance were there for the purpose of informing and being informed i.n the matters that are of such vital importance in the well beinj; ;tt The afternoon session opened with prayer by Kev. Mr. Marsh. Then a report of the work done by the State Board of Chariti*-- l orrection, by the Secretary, John I&gt; Later B. D. Hay ward, of Kearney, and H. M. Clark, of Geneu, each &gt;poke on the problems of the Industrial Schools. .A full explanation wa&lt;&lt; made of the plan of administering the schools Division into fam - ilies and separation of classes was dwelt upon. In each case the end in \iew was to make a strong individual character able to go out in the world and cope with temptation and adversity without yielding or I ing discouraged. The girls are taught to be good housekeepers with skill to manage a home, make and repair their own clothes and given the elements of an education. The boys ~a re taught some useful trade aa well as knowledge of books to the extent of a common school education. When they are put into home- on probation. \vhi iierintendent think- pirn Closing Skssion, 7:.W» y. m. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">8 Bitendent still is held and looks upon himself as being respon - &gt;r the conduct of the child as well as holding the temporary ans accountable for the right treatment of their charges. The problem of the traveling mendicants was discussed in a general way by a number of those present. Rev. N. S. Haynes ex - pressed himself as being entirely out of sympathy with the "Weary Willy. " If he would do anything for him it would be to give him a good Turkish bath and set him to work. He even expressed a doubt as to thi - treatment proving effective. Said that a thoroughly bad and sinful man might be reformed but he had doubts of a man constitutionally lacy. Dr. S. G. Smith, of the Associated Charities of St. Paul, Minn., felt that there might be some excuse or explanation made for th&lt;* "tramp.'' He said "Many tramps are made by boys being compelled to do work really beyond their physical ability and thus, before they are fully matured, becoming discouraged aod useless members of soci- He also favored a bath as the beginning of the means of reform - ation. He said that as a usual thing the tramp is more afraid or water than of the wood pile. The evening session was given entirely to Chancellor Andrews .infl the program rendered by the school for the blind. As the program rendered by the school was quite long the Chan - cellor made his address short. We have thought the account given us by Superintendent Morey of the preparation for the start to Lincoln, of the reception given them here and of their return might be of interest as well as an account of the program which proved so entertaining and inspiring to the large audi - ence which greeted them. Each number was given with an ease that showed thorough prep aration and interest in the work. On the morning of Feb. 2nd our chapel exercises were held a littlr earlier than usual to give time to prepare for the train leaving here at ri:30 a. m. Our two-horse sleigh, as well as the single sleigh carrying two •eats for the occasion, drove up before the door at 8 o'clock, when pupils and teachers, each with the instrument or package assigned to his care, were quickly loaded and the drive made to the depot. The air was sharp and the sleighing fine, so with all in good health and the best of spirits, the journey was most auspiciously begun. The heavier baggage had been taken down the night before, which took but a moment to check, and all were ready to board the train which was but slightly behind shedule time. The ride to Lincoln was made without incident of note. Arriving, we found Dr. Prevey on hand with all arrangement* made looking to our comfort. Instruments and baggage - were loaded into a wagon and taken directly to the church and soon arranged for the evening's use. Mrs. Johnston told me that arrange - ments had been made for our accomodation at the Windsor Hotel. where all not taken in charge by friends were soon comfortably installed. At the church I found the broom press and sewing, machine </seg>
            <seg id="p007">9 ■ ■linif had fully th.i mk of th try, Mr. John I),c nd to hi y and forethought I am certain the smooth working of the n Our programme w.i trioua exercises t k&gt;1 work, and had been done regularly in I ! amt work rooms. None of it had nw"' purposes. th&lt;&gt;" Kse a little extr.t practice hail er ea ad i nests in its delivery. Be first numbei it marred by an accident I truments but the ei I by the performer m is handkerchic irt, when from that tin; the programme moved with nitch. K were in i I with the c. -i, thouffh mine was 1oiik\ occupying nearly two and one half hours i| at ion. The invitation extended us by the Secretary to visit the peniteii - ippreciated. but owing M, and the short time I thought best not to undertake the trip. BKin invitation of Chancellor we occupied the usual time pel exercises in the University chapel, before an appreci Eifter which we returned to the hotel, where after dinner, w- - elv prepared for the homeward journey. L- 1 at A we reached home at 5:25, and fin siM&gt;ii within the walls of the In y the ird of Charities, and th.? four pleasantest mem' Sincerely J. T. Mobky NEBRASKA SCHOOL POK BLIND i.ocatkd at Nkbkaska City. N'ibk Program Selection bv School Orchestra vtette. from Lucia di Lammerm&lt;»&gt;r. Donizetti b. March— The Heart of America, - Hackler By Primary Pupil Jensen-Niemann Koailinjr by Touch, Murmuring Hi 1 Wanced Pupil Keadinif by Touch Dance of the Fair - ... Smart Claire Owens, Nona W Husa ise in Geometry. By Member of (.eometry &lt; Kxercise Illustrating Method of Writing tl Bohm </seg>
            <seg id="p008">10 Exercise in Geography, By Tw Pup; ifraphy &lt; Illustration of Industrial Work Taught in Schoi My Heart to Hear Thy Voice. - - Saint-:- Exercise in Mental Arithmetic. By Member &lt;►! Arithmel Selections by String yuartette b. Pixzicato Gavotte. - ... Lataun Exercise in Algebra. - By Pupil of Algebra I Polonaise, op. 40, No&gt; 1. .... Chopin Soldier's Chorus, from Faust (iouixxl Senior Churn Members of Orchestra Prof. A. Loeb, dii Edna Koonlz. Margaret Kealy, Anna Severson. K.~.i k, violins; Claire Owens, viola; Chas. Zadina, clarinet and piccolo; Prof. E. C. ' [Literary Department) cornet; Prof. Clark Bruce, [Industrial Department) trombone; Lewis Ludwick. drums; Vere Whitehill, violin anil ilium-.. A&gt; panitta Miss Sousley and Miss Hurruss. te*ch« music. Bednesday morning' the Conference opened with | dr. Smith. The following committees were appointed: &lt; &gt;n Resolution Rev. S. Z. Batten, Mrs. G. D. Fullmer. Rev. J. L. Marsh, C. E. Prevey, Mrs. Zara A. Wilson. Judge Wilber F. Bryant. Iittee on Organization for l'KM Dr. A. Johnson, Rev. N. S. Hayii' Emma P. D;i B. D. Hay ward. H. M. Clark. ints — H. M. Clark, Mr. - ;». I&lt;lvl, Traum der Sennerin. - Uabttzky Charles Zadina </seg>
            <seg id="p009">11 y l 1 The appointment of committe- ; lowed by the paper ot Jod|te ■;. P. Holmes on "The N Juvenile Court." If every one In thr tate could have heard his speech it would seem it might be easier t.. :"et our legislature to pass a law ffiviftff the authori' i emirt. His paper should be read by all who are inter - rring youths from becoming hardened crimin.i Jmllfe Bryant's paper forms a part of this report and will itself, being one of the strong addresses of the Conference. The paper of Judge Reece is also a part of this report and -.1 -■fully read and pondered. low i Of the above mentioned papers anil addr ml full discussion of the subjects under consideration. Bie af ernoon at the penitentiary is generally ne of the most intei i-of the Conference Thr irried out as planned with the addition of music precediiii; 'Mowing the addresses. Miss Beemer performed her part at the and a choir of convicts furnished the music. The hr &lt;1 attention of the prisoner- v gratifying e hoping much good to result from this meeting. The addrr lelivered to thom which was read by Dr. Miller, of Omaha, had prepared and read to the prisoners of New York by the personal friend I Miller, Got. Seymour, some twenty-five | . Dr. V. high tribute to his friend's moral character as manifested in hi - life. The address, which is a part of this report, should be ;ad by not oniy those who may desire to reclaim those who be behind the prison bars but by anv one who may be takr istic view of life on account of mist.i. iragemeir inv kind. Bny citizen of Nebraska, who listened to the words which came he heart of our own Dr. Davisson. of the Slate Agricultural K, must have felt a glow of satisfaction that we have such a man institution of learning. Read hi :ch appears ii Kfore the program, however, the visiting members were k through the institution and each department was fully expla umber who were there this was the first time for them to al knowledge of our penal institution. At the close of the program the Conference was invited to the di &gt;vhere a fine luncheon was served bv -ted by two friends of the latter All who had been present during the afteriv rateful to Warden Beemer for his kindly reception and entertaim The evening d by prayer. R&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p010">12 Mis- ig a beautiful solo in her charm inn Reports were made by the treasurer, C. E. Pn ■ i as being exjHM 131.57 130.41 Balance on hand M. The auditing cominir report approving th |K&gt;rt of the treasur- The committee on reported as follows hThat the p. mg for l"05 he Kearney. The time thi - nning of the second week of Febru . that time .t^ :ticai.le. The following officers were nominated or reported for the action &gt;-rence: President. B. D. Hay ward, Kearney: Vice President, Mr - da Edwards, Omaha: Secretary. John Da\: -,rer. C. r y: Executive Committee, Chancellor K. R. Andrews, Govern Mickey and Rev. Geo A. Heecher. Keari. iiove report was unanimously adopted The committee on resolutions had the following rejnirt which adopted : Resolved. That we hereby express our appreciation of tl, A. W. Clark, of Omaha, in so ably performing the duties of th&lt; retary and president of this organisation in I &gt;-Xf)iess our deep regret that sickness prevented hi - this time. Re-olved, That we most heartily endorse the probation svstem am indeterminate sentence, that we authorize the legislative committee t&lt; draft suitable bills for presentation at the next session of the lefcis tiire, and that we urge all persons to join with us in securing theii ssage. tl &gt;lve&lt;l. That we are heartily in favor of a juvenile court lau horize the legislative committee to use all honorable means tu secure enactment. Resolved, That we hereby thank the press of this city for their courtesy extended to this Conference and thank Warden Allan I). r toi his courtesy, hospitality and kindness extended the Confer - -it to the penitentiary. Resolved, That we recommend that a committee of five be appointed t yate tin crime and tc- lines of action in whic nciea and institutions, the home, the church, the scht« and t work either independently or conjointly in ini| </seg>
            <seg id="p011">13 The following thirteen rules were adopted ami recommended animation or officer in: trans is generally i it n i id .nit upon the transportation &lt; another at the expense of charitable anon half rate* granted by railr&lt; ticies. An earnest w of ■Ninth National Conference &gt;f needy people from one city to organizations or communit: ■t the reque&gt;t of charitable precipitated at the of Chariti.- ;ection in June. by a letter from tne ma ; . iri. This commum- 1 w m-'iit of Needy F imilies. T^ -tion that some remedial action b- taken appealed the representative i committee was appointed to pi In accord tnc- with ti P re " pared the rules printed below, to which you are urged to subcribe. It is believed that the observance of these nil v dimini - not eliminate, the following evils, which frequently result at 1 he. gran i tationoc ■ 10 needy indi- viduals or fan thk 1 1. Nr*e;lv people are often pauperized, cruel humiliation and hardship, and often have their condition or oppor - tunities impanel by being granted transportation which they ought not to receive or by lieiuu sent to place* where no provision for them 1 Charitable resources are frequently wasted in providing t: tion which is iimv r inadequate or injuri. Communities and charitable agencies are often unjustly bur- dened by there beinir sent to them, without their consent, dependent* for whom they have no responsibility. y. The tramp problem is extended and complicated by injudiciou portatiou. RULES AND FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES I. Before any charitable transportation shall be granted, the realization or official having the matter under consideration mu- First. That the applicant is unable to pay the regular fare &gt;nd. That the applicant's condition and prospects will be substantially impr. lending him to the place in question. r;tiniza/ion or of i.'ioH of needy people iteil at a largely atteudeil meeting of th- Treat £re&gt;ent that a committee was .ippomteu to leirraphic code, and an explanatory circular &gt;atisfied, by adequate anil reliable evidence 77;. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">14 public charity; or. Bourth. That the applicant has a legal residence in the pl» he is to be Mat or is a proper charge 11(1011 the charity of that unity. * VKKIKICA BAn applicant's statements must in «- |&gt;e substantiated r definite, reliable evidence. When this is lacking the applicant be taken care of, if necessary, until the medful testimony i~ DKSTISA TION SOI : 3. In all cases an appropriate charitable organization or official, it such exists, at the point of destination, should be promptly ,i that the applicants transportation to that place is under consideration. - already been determined upon. EPhen a signer of these rules is listed as be d at th«- pro- I point of destination, it shall not be legitimate to send the appli - thither unless notification is sent to the signer In advance of the portation being furnished or upon the day when it is provided. ■exceptional cases when the sender h;i - for desiring that &gt;rd be kept by the charitable agency at the point of destination. tter may be explained to the latter, who shall then perse t. unless the case is known through sources independent -&gt;f the INQUIRIES AT DESTINATION 4. It is strongly recommended that a report be secured from an appropriate charitable organization or official in the city to which transportation is desired, before any applicant is sent thither. Thi» is especially urged when a signer of these rules is listed as being at the point of destination. All signers have definitely announced themselves a-, willing b operate with other signers by making reasonable efforts to secure need - ful information and to determine whether transjx&gt;rtation ought provided in any given Uher charitable agencies, all usually glad to make any legitimate inquiries and reports which fal! within their customary acti\i THKOIV.H TRANSPORTATION KKyt'IKIK 8 All charitable transportation shall, in every instance. I" that is, the initial or orginal sender shall provide for the appli - lrough to his ultimate destination. When through tickets secured at charity rates, the initial sender mav enlist tl. e charitable agency at an intermediate point, all exfx-. by the initial sender. 6. If an applicant '■ intermediate t&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p013">15 I if his proper destination, without means having been pro - &lt;l for forwarding him to the latter, then no further transportation anted without inquiry of the charitable organization or indi - ;il who sent the applicant thither. This corresjiondent shall be lested to remit the amount necessary either to forward the api to his destination or to return him to the starting point. If tory resp &gt;nse is not pronptly Made, the applicant should be returned to the place where his charitable transportation orginated. In a ■te be ilong" to another community which baa isibility for him. DEPKNDENTS PKrCRNABLK TO SRNDEKS 7. If an applicant, who has been provided with charitable tl ion without the approval of an appropriate charitable agency at nt nt destination, shall there become dependent on public char - thin nine months after his arrival, then the charitable ( or individual who sent him thither should be notified and -vd to provide for the applicant • the money necessary to return him to the place from which his tra n was MAINTENANCE PENDING ADJ I If an applicant has been forwarded in violation of any of the charitable agency which provided him with tran- I be requested to bear the reasonable, necessary expense of pro - for him temporarily, pending investigation and the proper of the case. KRCORDS TO BK HHKSKKVKI) KThe society or official through wh &gt;m charitable transportation ured shall in each c ise preserve a full record of all the essential pon which the ({ranting of transportation has l&gt;een based. E:opy or summary of such record should be furnished prompt : to any charitable organization or official interested in the i such request for a digest of the record comes from a signer of ules, it shall be considered mandatory upon any other signer. KMPr.OYMKNT SKKKKKS In case of persons asking charitable transportation on the ground of being able to secure employment in the place to which trans - portation is desired, definite, reliable assurances of employment must be obtained as part of the necessary evidence. A general report that conditions of employment are better, or that the applicant would be "better off" in the place specified, shall not be considered sufficient ;nds for the granting of transportation. PROMPT A IHIKS 11. ■ these rules there - by pledge • ml the • </seg>
            <seg id="p014">16 Kiveniently at hand, and to use all due diligence in Baking ble inquiries requested by other of the rules and in f to communications regarding transportation ca HKAI.TH CKKTIKIC I PIDKMICS ■ Persons forwarded by charitable agencies or offic where any contagious or infectious i! known to be epi - must be provided with the proper health eertificat APPEAL IN UISAGKKI ■ When disagreement, -ions, arises in re transportation case, one or both the parties concerned m iv i dis its are located in the same State; or, if not. ■ Their two Stale secretaries working jointly or to either one of or. (3) The general secretary of the National Conference of Charities •rrection. ■ie address of the eveniii- ivered by Dr. S. *i. Smith, ot ml, Minnesota, Pa uirch and Professor in the Uoivert Synopsis ot address: THE PROBLEMS &lt;)K POVERTY ■at poverty and its I us that must be confr&lt; will attempt to deny. Where to look I - and lv ater relief are more complicated matt. Dr. Smith stated that he did not believe that intemperance was the sole cause of poverty, though it was usually associated with it ill way, often beinj; a result instead of a cause. Liquor is a luxury, the production of which make the neo f life dearer, aside from tak - rectlv. the money from a man's pocket. However, intoxicating drinks are not the only luxuries that produce the same iesu!t. Am extravagance indulged in by the rich makes the nee of lift - harder for a poor man to obtain by turning aside the labor to produce the luxury instead of keeping it in the channels where nece - produced. But as to the individual, wasteful consumption of what has been honestly earne-: -rty. He said, "It ha&gt; been repeated as a maxim" — the truth of which he was not able to vouch for — "that what is wasted in a common American housekeeper' - kitchrn would keep a French famih To sum up. _:. the very old and those disabled b ease or injury charity. Charit; </seg>
            <seg id="p015">17 ing the family, relief should be Riven by the church. When that fail* some private organized body as a lodge should look after its members. He declared that the public charities more often encourage mendicancy rather than furnish a cure. Public charities as administered by the county boards is often simply a graft and should be discouraged in every instance. Every case of charity should be thoroughly investigated before any relief is administered. It is better that there be some suffering, even unto death, of a few rather than the habit of dependence be fixed on a person who might be self-supporting. The whole object of those who are engaged in administering char- ity should be to raise the ideals of the people to higher levels and make self-respecting and supporting men and women of those who from any reason have become objects of charity. The Conference voted Dr. Smith a vote of thanks for the interest he had manifested in the meeting as well as for the address of the even- The program closed with a vocal solo by Harry Wharton The next meeting will be held in Kearney, Nebraska, and we anti cipate a splendid meeting at that place. The people of Kearney are noted for their interest and push in matters of this kind, and as the President, a member of the Executive Committee, and of the Advertising Committee, are located at that place, we feel that the meeting will be well provided for, advertised, and attended. An interesting program will be arranged for this meeting, and we earnestly hope and urge that every institution, charity and other organization, and every person in this State who is interested in thin great work of uplifting humanity, will think about this meeting, and arrange to come and help to make it one of the grandest meeting ever held in this state. Penitentiary Inmates 1892 average (six months) ...360 1898 average . . .300 1902 average . . . . 290 1903 average ...277 Decrease Kearney Inmates 1892 average . . .224 1897 average .160 1903 average !■*" Geneva Inmates, 1893 to 1903 June 1893 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">18 1*» &lt;* 1*1. « 1103 KKPOKT OF THF. NATIONAL PRISON ASSOCIATION ■his annual report to the Nebraska Prison Association, Dr. G rtin, of Lincoln, reviews the results of the labor of the organ for the last year. He s . "To the Hon. M. B. Reese, President N. P. A. •'1 have the honor to submit to the Conference the first annual report of the Nebraska Prison Association. We have been greatly encouraged by the heartiness with which the work of the Association has been received wherever its plans have been made known; and we are more fully convinced of the wisdom of the movement of organizing in prison reform work, for we have reached the time the people of the state are aroused to the investigation of the problem of caring for the criminal, and it is settled by the Christian world that the individual and society could be greatly benefited by helping back to a pure life and manly standing 1 in society, so far as it is possible, all who from .inv cause once violated our laws, and with this thought the work ha&gt; ully inaugurated in our state. While Nebraska has been the latest to enter upon this work, yet the records of the Association for the year just closed proves it to be an enthusiastic and intelligent member ■ &gt;t the prison association family. ighteen months ago several persons became interested in caring for the discharged persons from the penitentiary and jails, and a WWWiit was begun, and the good results seen were encouraging, and a Meeting was called for those who were interested to meet in the office «&gt;f E. Benjamin Andrews, chancellor of the state university, upon his invitation, to consider plans of operation. While the caring for the dis - charged person was thoroughly discussed, yet the necessity of inter - esting the general public to help prevent crime among the juvenile classes was also carefullv considered. "In our work we have found some perplexing questions to solve. among which is. where and how to find a home and employment for those who have no relatives or friends to assist them as they came back to society from prison life. These questions are easily asked, but hard to answer — it is hard for one to go in, but only a few realize how hard to come out and face a cold, critical world. Good persons are reluc - tant to trust them, and too frequently they are met coldly by those from whom they were entitled to kindly greeting. "We have distributed in Nebraska two thousand copies of the leaf - ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">19 Kat were prepared by our president for the purpose of informing &gt;ple of the object anil aim of the Association, and we know much it has been created by their perusal, and a large number of person* been enlisted in this "one of the most important movement!. iaugurated in our state.' "We have assisted in different way* fifty-six persons, and it is a source of great encouragement that only one has proved unworthy the trust imposed. In every instance of those assisted we have been permitted by the prison officials to carefully plan for their outgoing by personal interviews and thu* know their needs and learn largely their worth, and we have absolute reason to know that the help given ha - been greatly appreciated. "It is possible that you may have felt that all of your sacrificing efforts in this work were in vain. If so, a few instances of apprecia - tion may encourage and cheer. I was passing along a street in one or our cities when I was accosted by a manly appearing young fellow, whom at first I did not recognixe, as his change of dress and general bearing were so dilferent than when I bade him goodby in my office nine months before. A hearty greeting followed. He invited me to lunch with him; and then I visited with him in his place of business, where I learned from his employer that he was as exemplary a youm; man as was in the city. When planning for him I was told by one that there was no good in him, but some way we were impressed there was a pearl under the striped coat, and now every Sabbath morning he can be found taking the Sacrament in the name of the Lord Jmm Christ in one of our best churches. g neither, when writing to us said: 'I am proud in writing to you ling you how happy I am and I intend to be an honest and able man. I do not know how to express myself to you so that 1 understand my appreciation of your help.' ■Another writes: 'Dear Friend — I now take pleasure in dropping few lines. There is not a day but I think of you. I assure ;indness shall never be forgotten.' Still another write; Mass., Dec. 24, 1902. 'Dr. Martin: Dear Sir -I visited W yesterday and called to see the young man you spoke of and found him well and happy. He is working as assistant engineer for a manufacturing company, and says he can never forget the assistance you rendered him. His employer told me he was keeping his mother and doing nicely every way. I am led to believe the work you are doing is far reachiug for the good of i reap.. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">20 "We have others of similar character, but these give you an id&gt; that there may be some good under a rough jacket. The treatment o the ex-prisoner is not a work of charity alone, but of good judgtnen not for philanthropy absolutely, but calls into action the powers an wisdom of all the earnest business men and women interested i humanity. The work of those associated with me has been helpfu They have endeavored to influence the prisoner by the law of lov While we did not get from the legislature all we desired at its late se -ion. yet the association put itself on record as in hearty sympathy wit with the parole law, and also an earnest advocate of the 'indeterm inate sentence. ' "I have endeavored to do my work in such a manner as to encour - age crushed humanity to one more manly effort in the name of Jesus Christ. There is a demand, and a burning desire among the people to join in the work of saving the discharged prisoner to society, and while this work has simply been inaugurated, I trust you will see to it that no halting will be permitted in this philanthropic movement of th&lt; twentieth century hour. Bow, Mr. President, I sincerely thank you and your fellow worker - many courtesies given in my work, and trusting greater good accomplished in the future, I am "Your humble servant. "George W. Martin The management of our state institutions during the present admin - istration has been freed from political domination. The Superinten - dents have the entire management and better service by all employes is the result. The policy pursued by our Honorable Governor, John H. Mickey, of looking to the Superintendent and holding him account - able for all details, is working in a better class of employes, service and efficiency necessary to hold any position. Some improvements bettering the sanitary conditions are in progress and when completed will be a very much needed improvement in all our institutions, besides the general improvements and new buildings. The most important is the rebuilding of the Norfolk Hospital under the cottage plan; also tht - hospital at the Milford Soldiers' Home. Re last offical report we have our institutions have an average tion of 3,060. Total appropriation for maintenance, repairs and ildings, $1,426,140. The average per capita cost for the sis ending November 30, 1903, was 991.95, or per day 50 cents. I wish to note here in comparison. We hear a great deal about our extravagance, etc. Compared with last published report from the the State of Ohio their average is $87.68; the State of Iowa. $83.23. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">21 expense of administration should be greatly lowered in tl that we hear quoted so much, and occasionally some people that informed will tell us: "There is also Kreat need of economy management of our state institutions. Politicians become super; ents of our state institutions. There is need of better treatment inmates in many of our institutions. Fore^om*; are some we ha in print of our state institutions by our own citizens. Wh .. facts? Re-read the above comparisons. Respectfully submitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">22 NEBRASKA STATE BOA HP OF CHARITIKS AM) COHHKCTION KKXoR J. H. MICKKY ■K. FOWLER KOLLMBS DAVIS A W. CLAKK ■. BKABKOOK :PH RUK8IM4 1HNST1 &gt;N </seg>
            <seg id="p021">23 .NAME AND LOCATION Oh' STATE I X STITl T I ( ) X S AND SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE &gt;k;t Hospital for the Insane Lincoln Dn. J. L. Gh ue Asylum Norfolk [rebuilding] im for the Incurable Insane B, Kekn Dr. W Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Grand I&gt; Colonkl W. S. Askwtih Soliliers' and Sailors' Home Milforil Colonkl Chahi.i - Home for the Friendless Lincoln Sarah B. Sohus Kearnev State Industrial School for Boys B. D. Haywakh Girls' Industrial School H. M Clark Milford Nebraska Industrial Home Makgarkt K State Penitentiary A. D Beeiikr Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth Beatrice Dr. A. Johnson Institute for the Deaf and Dumb R. E. Stkwah i J. F. Morkv </seg>
            <seg id="p022">24 Address of Iboratio Seymour to flew Vorb Convicts r Read at Eighth Annual Meeting by 1)r. Geo. L. Miller I have declined all invitations this year to make public addresses, ion your warden asked me to speak to you today, I made up my mind to do so, although at the hazard of my health. My interest in the inmates of this and other prisons grows out of official duties, as I have act on many cases of applications for pardons. I have learned from a long experience with men in all conditions of life that none are it faults and none without virtues. I have studied characters with care. I have hail to deal with presidents and with prisoners. I lated with those held in high honor by the American people. &lt; »n the other hand, the laws of our state have placed the lives of criin - ien in my hands, and it has been my duty to decide if they should r die. The period in which I took the most active part in public - was one of great excitement, when passions and prejudice*. -rd, and, in common with all others engaged in the contrc - - of the day, I have felt the bitterness of partisan strife; never - -. experience has taught me to think kindly of my fellow men. The longer I live, the better I think of their hearts, and the less of their heads. Everywhere, from the president's mansion to the prison - er's cell, I have learned the wisdom of that prayer which says that we be delivered from temptation. ■ther great truth is taught by experience; hope is the great We must instil this in men's minds, if we wish to cultivate enable them to overcome their vices. It has been said </seg>
            <seg id="p023">25 th.tt despair is the unpardonable sin, for it paralyzes every sentiment that leads to virtue or happiness. Tu help us do our duty we must cher - ish hope, which gives us courage, and charity, which gives us hope for others. For this reason, when governor of this state, I did all I couhl to gain the passage of laws which enable each one of you, by good con - duct, to shorten the term of your imprisonment, and it I ha«l m\ vould have a share in the profits of your labor. But I stand before you today to speak on another ground a higher and more lasting character than men gain on shortened terms •&gt;f punishment, but what I have to say does not point to you alone, but to men of all conditions. I do not mean to take the place of those who Teach you your religious duties. They are far more able than I am to make these clear to your minds, yet it is sometimes the case that l that are not usually placed before us. and some thoughts which •ocurred to me, in a review of my life, may be of interest and value to vou. EVhen we grow old we are struck with the flee' time; our seem to be cjmpassed into one brief period; we suddenly find pursuits that we have followed have closed, and we are confronted the question, not what we have gained, not what positions we held, but what we are in ourselves. We know it is our duty to do is right, and to avoid doing wrong, but when we look back, if we up all of our good deeds on one hand, and our bad acts on the !;r, we find a startling balance against us. When me" reach my e of life, their minds turn toward the past, and they travel back - rds the paths they have followed. They see things from the oppo - 1 side from which they were viewed in youth onward, and are struck truths which ne»'er break upon their minds until they look back on them. limt before my fire on a winter evening, and musing, as old men are apt to do, ab »ut their acts, their errors, their su their failures, it occurred to me what I would do if I had the power, and was compelled, to wipe out twenty acts of my life. At first it seemed as if this was an easy thing to do. I had done more than twenty wrong things for which I had always felt regret, and was about to seize my imaginary sponge and rub them out at once; but I thought it best to move with care, to do as 1 had done to others, lay my char - acter out on a dissecting table, and trace all influences which had made or marred it. I found to mv surprise, if there were any golden threads running through it they were wrought out bv the regrets felt at pi; that these regrets had run through the course of my life, guid - ing my footsteps through all its intricacies and problems; and if I should obliterate all these a. hick these golden thr attached, whose length into my very nature, I </seg>
            <seg id="p024">26 what little there was in mv moral n Then I ;at the m d by the fir 1 like errors, n if I hail ii en. In thi* I found r 1 I . anil hop I ion, that. •ii than if you had I A P i men wi; , himself, v nil what li ; the wr« ins tha' a m.. d. not numbe le falls, but by the number ot ti If up. I do falls, but bv the numbi ier of ■ A' tll.lt Y uj^ht which shout) ht which shoul Ih firm purpoi with film pi hall ii i not inak : not mak. or . but of the though but of the thoughts upon our I. v hour. &gt;ur Y» m - which ;it h ii r A ll.lt :. in His . thin .jht, or wi ■ \ ma it, or vvi r ■ think and do after their occurn bink and itf from imp ulents- rrintf judgment. 1 lem their hue. The world may not .vn upon ■ and upon the man, who, nevei fu wh Mlilllls .11 who find no time for th With each of you in a iiiimls .Li tctive ivho find no time for tl hich tend to virtue anil to ha With each of you in a little time, the question will be. not it ■t what the world thin: t you h which teiul to virti ittle time, the question will be. ha| not if voi Kthe world thinks - at the ct number are carried from their narr&gt; vou i cells iir number are carried from their narrou the i ought that I | he r </seg>
            <seg id="p025">But let me look further ct, for it rhouffh we are unable to recall th Though we are unable to recall th with them that they may proo Upon this point I an not theortsiim human experience prov- ■[-&gt; of tin jr virtue, our wisdom and ha Whoever think- jr virtue, our wisdom and ha Whoever think- with them that they may proo Upon this point I am not theoriiinf human experience prov ;t me take tl nld find, if we could rub them thould destroy the lorn thev have given us, if we have taken care to make our ei t'lim. Whocoulil spare tbei nuch thai d sympathetic in our natures, which lead* upturn ', when they b Following on my th uijhts. when I assumed that I had which call for the t: unit that I cou pare error: \ had ' which had on! or trium md 1 little inflii' irtue an': make it givt u right and ritfli' i dent or . Within I: nt qu. ceil upon the mil f t with its criiTv n lift thei r and happier and it cai ll the hitrhest and in he Almiifh All human experien religion th men wh lin ci 1 hich of' sympathies which n \ to the inte went\ I con I 'loom inl trreat trr »r the futuri what - ii, bv thoti &gt;rk ol transmut i«ht as well in the pri- ir when ; ur min&lt;i- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">28 have many theories in these days in which men try to tell us ie world, acting upon certain fixed laws, has made itself; that it &gt;foe» on by a progress that regards nothing but certain rules of oement, regardless of all other considerations save their own irre - '.e, self-compelling principles. But here we have a truth not only us in Holy Writ, but proved by our experience, that mental regret will convert a material wrong into a blessing, or, if the offender will* it, will make the same a hundredfold more hurtful if he rejoices in his wrong-doing, or hardens his heart against regret. Materialism, evolu - :&gt;&lt;ntheism. or any of the theories which deny the government of ire all phases of fatalism, and are confuted by the truth that we can. by conforming to His laws, which demand repentance, convert evil into good, or by violating them, make evil tenfold more deadly am! destructive. We can, by our minds and sentiments, change the influ - f material events; and vary the action of laws which govern the world. If man, with all his weakness, can do this, it can only be by the aid of a higher power which shapes, directs, and regulates. I know that what I have said is but an imperfect statement of great truths, compared with the teachings of the pulpit which you hear each Sunday. As my purpose is merely to speak to you what I have learned in the walks ot life, I can give you from this narrow field but partial views of great truths. They may be of no value to you, yet I trust you will accept them at least as proof of my sympathies with your condition and sorrows, for if any ambition lingers in the bn of him who speaks to you now, it is that he may be the priest and r of the erring and wrong-doer. Khas been taught by self-examination and the study of others that belong' to that class, and that we are to owe to one another any </seg>
            <seg id="p027">29 of a ftebrasba Che Constitutionality JuvenilesCourt law c The judicial power of the state shall be rested ii district court, county court.-., justices of the peace, police m and in such other courts inferior to the district by law for cities and incoporated tow: Department, Constitution of Xcbraska. This provision of the constitution is a limitation upon th&gt; slature. Were it not for this section any court which would fancy of the law-making power of the state might be creat. is limitation in force we must abide by it. Th f the courts, must be taken as excluding all others. Thf secti. ■■ ind designates the courts we may have. We can have no others Any law which tfoes outside of these provisions mi leld unconstitutional and void. This leads us to recognize what law can be enacted, if I that juvenile court may. or mijfht be established, if any. without fraction of the constitution. The answer is plain. A valid jut nirt law may be enacted. Hut such a law must pr urt which ill be inferior to the district court. That is, it must m&gt; ordinate jurisdiction. It must be a Court, the judgments and CM which mav be reviewed and. if n </seg>
            <seg id="p028">30 ■i it into the class which f county courts, justices of the anil police magistrates, or police judges. It can go no higher. Then, we find another limitation which must be observed. The court can be created only "for cities and incorporated town*.' 1 This is probably the most serious limitation contained in the constitution. If the court is created "for cities and incorporated towns" it can exercise no jurisdiction over offenses committed outside the city or town bound aries. It can have no jurisdiction over territory included within county Ixuindaries, but not included within the municipal corporations known a* "cities'' or "towns." This implies, as I think, that the court can have jurisdiction only over the territory included within the &lt;&gt;«&lt;■ city or town for which the court was created. It follows then, that each city n must have its own court, if such are created by law, and th.it court can take cognizance of nothing which may have occurred, or over ho may reside outside the corporate limits of the munici- Iich a law and such a spirit even under the limitations imposed by nstitution, might be of great benefit to the larger cities and towns state, but it would be of but little value in counties where no cities exist, and of no value, in any county, in territory o&lt; &gt;i i a municipal corporation. Indeed, in many of the the counties state the law would be valueless. Biy law which seeks to establish such a court would have to be lim - •eration and terms to "cities and incorporate.! towns." The ust be made "for" them and for no other parts of the state. It have no greater territorial jurisdiction than police courts now I think a valid law might be enacted which would confer upon our judges a jurisdiction over juvenile offenders, and this would pro - be the better plan, but this would be a matter of choice of meth - ■ r I think an independent court might be legally created, but with the limited territorial jurisdiction. This latter course would ha\e ■mmend it the fact that it would have a tendency to segregate and keep separate the prosecution of children from that of the More ind, in most cases, the more confirmed criminal element. I presume there could be no constitutional objection to a law ferring such jurisdiction upon the district Court, the County court am the justice and police courts, and this includes all the territory of th&lt; within su;h jurisdiction. But these all have their objections. Ii of the counties of the state the district courts are in session bir t-ach year and the jud_ uie instances reside a 1&lt;jii^ dis trom the counties within their districts. In sucli !lt. ■erred upon th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">31 be met with the objection that in many of the counties the county judjjes are not students of the law and so important a duty should not be imposed upon them. The same is true of the justice and police courts in the sparsely settled ]x&gt;rtions of the state. It would perhaps be the safer COU1 i current n to the district and count \ </seg>
            <seg id="p030">32 r Ehe Constitutionality of a Juvenile ourt law in fkbrasba ff d (Jentlemen: Before entering upon the theme whicl if, I wish to congratulate you all upon t'u "rides which have been made along the line of scientific char rin the last half century. Just sixty years ago the 20th instant, niel Webster argued the celebrated (iirard Will Case before ttu Supreme Court of the I'liited States. In the argument Mr. V took the position that charity could not be divorced from something which he described in ornate rhetoric and termed Christianity, bu which he failed to accurately define. It was obvious that he mean cal control; for he laid down the proposition that a tnunici could not accept an eleemosynary trust created by a testatn - night by the terms of his will to put that trust beyond tli clerical interference: even where the will itself contained Kmer clause, disavowing hostility to religion. Edward K who listened to Wi i vgument— says in his "Recollection &gt;f .1 Hundred Years," that Webster appeared to have no heart in hi: Be this as it may. Senator L,ixlge is right in his statement tha of standing at this day would take t) i that Web I do not stand hett phen Girard*S inr:h tr education, for I do not believe in it Pardon me right her&lt; At the ' lir in lK7t&gt;. the Kniglr </seg>
            <seg id="p031">&lt; I body, their pr irard had pro uIiiil' the v 1 in his will thai any km allowed to enter the coi 1 gate-keeper saw the prelate ■hop. The following i I per: "You can't v Pki:i The Hell I can "\V;ilk ri^ht in I do i ;st kind of charitv, for mv bt s the contrary. But I . in the .1 methintr at much tr purpose, of mi ire theism of Herbert Spencer mil the father ha. 1 the minister - wh«&gt; his child. Less than f &gt;&gt;rld was outraged by the - hipped his little son to death in n to death in an ite the destruction of children 1 tive in mind or in body, but h u. As man has no inn not first in the I blind 4nd there is nothing in the mind that nd deaf mute was tantamount to an and Rhode his day but for such ben ilind child that the earthly the greatest and most sublime t that the world i- ng better? We have learned in the centuries that have passed, that he relation of parent and child exists for the good of the ch' &gt;f the parent; that though the right of the parent is primar\ ■.acred, yet when parents fail in their duty, the state in her i *ure. &lt; &gt;muion an ctiun of K npreheni In the sixth cen ilren to t! jr era. ti [s. Five years later the kitloapp hiladelphia made the n Mow, the fatherless, the maimed and the blind an Ev. Judf^e Ba: I In a recent opinion, "Women and oh Lve alw.ivs. to a certain extent. lere are intelligent people whi &gt;int with the genius of our cm ! have \» &gt;.iw ti nintf. K . they Eoulci all have been put to death in Sparta. An yron, the historian Prescott, Th Laura I). Bi an, and Helen Keller. We cam octrine of Euthanasia without half jf reform iVhere is the pessimist who dare n </seg>
            <seg id="p032">34 a 1 I l i opinion of all parent offender Bn this . has t edicat fifth of all public lands to th« for (h Idren rtain churches that make I of tlu duty, the men and women ur | Boot be much, if any, Russii Hitfh Schojl ..I ; detita. I that til. 11 heard of and are tolerably familiar with tl of Alex ,. Nero am) other I How man i ever i ;i Cutler? Yet this man I Bam ignorant of the name of the man who first pro uven I have lived too loag and observed too much I i ley who introduces a hill in all itithorahip. ¥ than hair a century tl Liquor Law author w Prentiss Bishop has borne the brand of Neal Dow. In uur o Kumli Law originated in the brain and . the hand ot John H. Anus. The name of the man who t out the ju night to be written on the table side John Howard and William Will. lit the child to wl: tint 1 by that UM &gt;oeiety; that he should be compel •inpany of confirmed criminals; that he should wear •ne; that he should forfeit his self-respect; 'hat should reed into the criminal i doomed of crime. W B thoughts in mind the Chanty Organization of Lincoln I . At the November, 190Z,me&lt; ne directors, the | ry, Thomas J. and the speaker, were appoint -lation in harmony with the pur pi ward P. Holmes of this city «ii Mem of juvenile courts. After . Kring with the author of the bill and othei amended and offered in the Senate by Senat in P. Warner. The members of the committee made an effort tie duplicate introduced in the H ■u-i-, but without ■ •r. appeared bel iate — of (.'.hai which it i red. In spite of strenuous oppositioi It met with atronK opposition in the House, but . which « ,ui\ tin luiisiiiug a svsiem 01 juvenile cuuris. /vuer a prol . anil the speaker, i ertair </seg>
            <seg id="p033">in for the uniform ■ for the uniform juri- the place lo criticii ■luct Let me say ri^ht lv the condu i Let me sav right hi It I ll inluct man. Tl rtiuii or innuendo to impugn i part of the law-makl iiipugn th -1 .11,1 11 tw-makin J 1&gt; the bill. I I lawful i his &lt;lut\ • iiiered the bill the tin that ofhcia ■n it v ri tlature hail adjourned and the b jrned t) i i raba, it died in the haw If we were :r \ d. II he w.t juki like ' him, I Vi with l y ex( ;it an in adopted at tli • rst proposal, and In my humble judgment we XlH'Ct it tO ll n the manner it Ion th i cure tl.e friendlj the pr What fur and he would nt numb- de the executive veto, and t 1 !-.,■• t.. j./.i.l )1to -rli-nHil H«-f»^»«i r»omtF&lt;l ni:t hv th he alleged defect* pointed out bj the Holmes-Warner Bill, the law will be inefficient mu ie i uven tmrt exclusively, or to b- II you K iirt. in by far the greater part of th. luring n f the year the judge will be where ni't iret .it him. The- in certain portions of the ?■ my rea unwi ipoae it em. To give the Count . - of Herod and Pilot, which virrent jui ;im in favor ot it— i the»« uv had be tiny ot ■ line criticism K rum i law. llie pin ; t)\ernor will be e again. It is hanl jurisii lier to the County ( why the County JudR irden. and vvh St.ltr thoilt le repeat e 1. and the other conflict d hut still th. I would recommend, requesting Ju&gt;l&lt;e Holi •ed by the le-islatui irrent jui </seg>
            <seg id="p034">36 t ] ■iththej. until this Slate has a new cunstitu be at til -ia helil undei ciety, in which the constitution o by the men. who frame;! it. Most of them u ■ i that the constitution by a little tinkering woald stand f&lt;a he profoundca med that constitution: they, prob i instrument as the people would have adoptee • time. Hut the State has outgrown it and nothing needs thorough judicial department. forbid) my County Judge; for this reason in mos illed by laymen and too often by men The juveiii lotiid be an independent constitutiona itutional safeguards it should be removed from th n of politics. Then we may hope lo make it efficient. the old Koman closed his every speech made in the Senate with v. we must have the juvenile he beco: iminal rather thai him for subsequent reform. In the words of Iloyle Roach: n the lobby roar; i ker. shall we shut </seg>
            <seg id="p035">ftteed of a Juvenile rt hind : them in dung fact, p- ■n itment of thecrimin f centuries It v if in this rapid day of develop- if in this rapid day of devi *r strange, how nent we had not made some progress, hut it has indeed been - It is only among a fe. . you, that will stop long enough from re and duties of life, prompted by humanitarian impulse and a tter your fellow man, and to think of v long these lines, that reali/ f united action in the ttempt at reformation in the tre.r this unfortunate class, would e hope to m.ike progress in that direction - il for the pre- It is the child that makes the man .it child is t \e had not made some progress, but it has indeed been I tnii a few such a u, that will stop long enough from y re and duties of life, prompted by humanitarian impulse and a fellow man, and to think of what we are ■ it realize ty of united action in the in.ike progress in that direction so essential for the pr. .' child that makes the rr that child is inabilities f good citizenship, so is this _ this great ned and better fitted for the purposes of its organization. Hence the most important along the linns of pen ion is how best to take care of that child, dep per training and pi lat du' existence make ■ led U|Mjii ■ icable </seg>
            <seg id="p036">38 4 V 1 and in importance. In the I' the number ot :ily on the int The numerical ia&gt; ublished by the Census Bureau sh* .itio of juvenile offend' whole population was 237 to the million, a relative inc (itainable only through those member omm rrmatories, no other ace .id being 1 obtainab ■ their ajfe&gt;, the number committed to reformatories •en the ages of 15 and 19; 24O between 2o and 24 yeai ife of al! juveniles confined in reformat w FOf the nature of tl ere against prop* of petit larceny; 2544 were for lar. bur The offenses against property were the predominating forms crimes, and it should be remembered that these figures bear ni ence to the members amalgamated with tlie regular state prim which would help swell the ag^ juvenile offenders very ma ially. - further I the criminal age is between 20 and Kf conclusively that the bulk of en - on the iminatu riminality is increasing, and, therefore, the gubje million, or a total incn 'i&gt; over th beinjf at the average 1 urse. tin the period of 1H80 ami 18&lt;X&gt;. 21 were un.i 7 vv. 10 and 14 fportio: by nrtme its relat! I to the gu ire wit! . lity had still t wakened to the horrors of the p Ey or the in: ,ad tran- ved riyht- . imprisoniDe punis nt. and l&gt;» :he solution renders and the preventive mi The thought has only gradually developed thai to depn m.itter f Fy be ■ urned ■. with perfect The most reliable tainable * England. Germany. Italy, and </seg>
            <seg id="p037">39 te life, win nduring impression upon the pliant character. Tht rst in th&lt; i&gt;e evolution of his moral character. Chllrtho early imp; I that m the teaching of home life ami parental example. And it re-trnj; lo know that from t] confined in reform,' ire either or- ased business of the divorce courts help to swell the growth of unable to furnish bond, mu- PI prison bars a considerable tin). te may r&lt; ii. and then I ponaivi cd formative ■ xperience who ha\e been lieprn ■ utal iiistruci ilin^ 'hat the uformation is ill-founded. The perniciouaw lemnatioo. Tl njf ht in contact with a crim- crimmalism. Divorce and crime go hand in hand, and juvenile crime rtereil beneath its wii ■ _ I!v refei he table l&gt;er cent of the pal ■ rlable, anil but 6 |H'r cent The want of industrial training il mental cul- ■&gt;j lack Ol chief aourcea oi juvenile depra\ i The use of intoxi in-re- strained course of life, under the parental in imporant part in laving the founr ration. * » • The pri - . uish bet but bun- aether the harilened criminal and the f tliat every i- required, no matter how serio iid tfirls appi same as the hardened crimi. t those due administration of the law extend to children the and cumin. Uich they are entitled, and th. jvv them such his dul &lt;■ impri* </seg>
            <seg id="p038">40 v 1 i |3ur jails are conducted as public nto them constabulary and com corruptor- \ouii£, murilerers, burglar - prostitutes, and all the evil member&gt; they can upon, with children convicted of petit Ian noon -. and not tried; inside the walls comfortably bouaed, -clothed (applied with tobacco and cards, with prom inter o durinjf a part, if not all the day, the prof&lt;-&gt;sional criminal and 1 -inner recount their adventu ikintf upon this sabjed ■ in from quoting: detained witi nd people accused of misdemeanor Tiner recount tneir acivennn audten </seg>
            <seg id="p039">41 Che {problem of Hiving Prof. Davisson was introduced by Got. Mickey an ir Excellency, Warden Beemer, Ladies andGentlemen: Th. - ram says I am to speak to you on "The Work of the Prison K atton," but I prefer to speak to you on "The Problem of Li nnd to brinK in the work of the Prison Aaaociatkn in Nebraska at the close. Let all person* present this afternoon lay aside I all thoaffhta of the place in which we are assembled and think th are fathered here as a company of men. I Enctioi died only for the purpose of talking in regard t. etterment of humanity: meeting upon the common ground of hum nd upon the level of equality. All problems of human life are problem^ of education. It has been my lot to spend my life in educational and I see no reason this afternoon why I should address you h nt way from that which I should employ were I before my - talking to them upon the qur- how human life m.i\ in a triumphant outcome. Our vieu ird to the wort &lt;&lt;i human life must depend upon our oilman life. If for a ri - nk that human life comes from a torce that has wrought Address by </seg>
            <seg id="p040">42 is forever, then our view of life wilt be something that ■ &gt;t result in superiority of attainment or worthiness of character. Kon the other hand, we regard human life as originating in a it way, anil as destined for something better than a career of fifty or sixty years, then our views will be very much affected shall conduct ourselves in a verv different way. It has. been my custom to take as mv philosophy the philosophy that Wordsworth expresses in hi.s "Ode on Intimations of Immortality."' the opening stanza of which begins as follows: "Our birth is but a sleep and a forgetting: The Soul that rises with us. our lift- Hath had elsewhere its setting. And cometh from afar: Not in entire forgetful* And not in utter nakedness. But trailing clouds of glory, do we come From God. who is our home. " Bwe take that as our view as to the orgin of human life it seems to it the things that we heard in the admirable address read to you ItrMM by Dr. Miller, are of the utmost importance, but the jn arises how shall these be achieved. It is the duty of every man and of every woman to know; to touch ■ res where truth can be gathered; to explore every unknown sea: to come into contact with knowledge and live in all countries and in all ages. But to know a thing and not have it result in some form of action which is beneficial to humanity and to the race, is to have education fail uirpose. It is said that education is for the purpose of helping men to ascertain the truth, but this must be added, that education should not only help men to ascertain the truth but it should help them to live the truth: that any form of knowledge which may come to any one of us that does not sink down through the strata of intellect and ot feeling into that of will and which does not result in some form of action that has a tendency to move humanity onward and upward, is poor education; worthless education. Then the question arises whether ill to know a thing is of as much importance as it is to feel it and choose it and do it. Bef' ding further along that line let me remark that it becomes necessary for every one of us to get the true meaning of things If you will allow a more technical expression, life is a process of inter - pretation. To illustrate: The poet goes forth into the world and fu - sees things that are beautiful. He interprets them in verse and the result is poetry. The painter also goes forth in the world and makes .in interpretation of life, the result appears on canvas as one form of .irt which i- also ;&lt; form of the beautiful. The sculptor makes an inter - ne beautiful in another way. Hi' </seg>
            <seg id="p041">43 of marble his interpretation of the world's beauties. The mu - toauim; takes in their meaning; puts their meaning into th of musical composition and our homes are made to rej*' the sweet melodies and of the harmonies that are in the soul of the musician. Let me illustrate still further: The historian g ies through th. of the world and see* it as it appeared in the acts of revolut: i-nactments and interprets for you and me the meaning of the struggles which men have made for freedom and records it whetherth.it struggle llils resulted in the establishment of institutions in which free - dom has a part or whether that struggle for humanity has resulted in the establishment of institutions where men are made to bow in the pres - ence of tyranny and lay aside manhood because of might. The - man must have an' interpretation of life and he who interprets the pa*t and is able to put his meaning of the past before the world in such a &lt;s to make the world conscious of the best thing to be done bv Hid by nations is | n, while he who interprets the it any false way and leads ind nations backward - downward to degradation, is a demagogue and a charlatan in national Hence, we are here to interpret life and upon our interpret life will depend our own lives. Let me say that the greatest Teacher • er seen interpreted life in an environment which was entirely wrong. He interpreted it in a way that was altogether right and men are today clinging to his interpretations. They are still following them nut. They assent to his claims. They ar&gt; - following- the interpretations that he put upon human life i! ng and living in accordance with higest ide;i Sus luok into the interpretation this person put upon human life, st meaning he found was that men must live not for them - the advancement of the human race. The most beautiful form h we find life is that of a little child. If a little child were :i and on this platform your eyes would become brighter and hey would assume a brightness that I can not des - cribe and that no power of mine can cause them to have. Why ' se the child is an example of perfect living. Why is it an ,ile of perfeet living.' Its whole nature is perfect. Whenever it mything, it does not spe.ik for the ptirptM ,Tandizin. but because the utterance comes spontaneously. It rep i per - fect life. Ami so the man who forgets himself, forgets he is a man. •iot take as his philosophy that he must triumph over others but that the race must triumph and that he must contribute to its triumph. I life. That is what we 11 altruisii </seg>
            <seg id="p042">44 Hie put -ecurinjf personal triumphs; they are living for the race. That is why an army is an example of the noblest enceavor found in I history. Take the army in our civil war, the soldier who ■oath or the soldier who came north — for we have come to a posi - here we can !&gt;e liberal enough to respect valor wherever we find i the soldier who went into the fij^ht thought not of himself but of his country, not to make a name or fame for himself but of making t- float high over a re-united nation • the volunteers who went forth from 18hl to 18 ule aggregation of men as the sun e\er shone upon, •■lit of self; it was the ap ••{ humanity. Y&lt; have my idea of the achievement of nobility in life. The qi how shall we go at it? I regret to be compel!- v th ftcjTMOW in his address used an expression that was mine ; well as his. I did not know of his address nor of what he won! until I came here. That expression was the word "Hope." If the i» anything that we must not let go out of in our lives it is hope. often speak of hope as a sun. It is evident that a human lif&gt; whose sky hope has disappeared, has nothing to which it can look fo ward to with any courage, or with any expectation of a happy issue. In the second place, there should be a belief in the old fashioned virtue of faith; faith, that the majority of men are good and that the majority of women are pure. We should have faith in the on-march of humanity toward a higher plain of existence. We should have faith in the triumph of rijfht. There should be pity for a man from whose life faith has disappeared. This is a poor illustr he truth perhaps but it will bear repetition. It was forced upon me bv first reading' Tom Hood's poem "I Remember " I presume it appealed to me strongly because in m\ childhood I had the same experience. He sa&gt; "I remember I remember The fir trees, dark and high I used to think their slender top-, Were close against the sky It is a childish memory but now 'tis littli To know I am farther off from Heaven than when I was a bov bThe point is that a man from whose life faith (roes, gets farther ay from all g&lt;&gt; - lift rth living. A few _\ i 1 up to ii .vord - of its colleg-e president whose whole life had been a grand triumphal march. His words were words of wisdom: he was a man to whoa ne could well afford to listen. As the president began hii i young man in tl -eemed n josed to pav anv attti </seg>
            <seg id="p043">45 Pine theory.'' He was going out into life with a fertile soil pois - and covered by a rocky formation that would everlastingly him from producing- anything of value or of worth to soci- I am not going to speak of courage, for Gov. Seymour s{ioke to you in regard to courage. There is one thing I wish to speak to you about anil that is that our interpretation of life will be very much affected by the way we think and feel and especially the manner in which we speak. Dr. Schurman said from the university platfoim a few years ago that ".hi educated man was one who had sobriety of judgment; who was not characterized by inebriety of judgment.'' What is meant by those words? Just this. A sober man knows what he is about; knows that it he does a certain thing just how it is going to result. If he speaks a certain word he knows what meaning is intended to be given. A man - drunk is uncertain in his actions. He does not know when he where he will go; his thoughts and words are not coherent. There is much difference between sobriety and inebriety. It not only important for people to be sober in their thought but also in speech. Would everyone of us like to be held accountable for all the - we have said during the last month? Would the people of whom we have spoken think that we have dealt with them in exact jus - tice, were our words to come to their ears? 5 has been said, that "Speech is silver and silence is golden.'' I to see education work such a transformation in the minds and i of men that speech will be golden because it will come from i that are ruled by reason from minds that have sobriety of tent and seek always to be just. niety of speech is very much a matter of self-control. Permit me to illustrate this. Suppose something displeases us. The unedu - cated man allows himself to fly into a passion and to use all sorts of violent expressions while he is under the influence of passion. The truly educated man says to himself: "Let me think about it; is this worth getting angry about? Is it worth making great outcry about? I will think about it. before I act," and training himself in that way becomes absolutely self-controlled. If the world could be absolutely self-controlled, how beautiful would it be! Do you know, that one of the most beautiful descriptions of manhood I have ever seen is in Goldsmith's "Deserted Village"' where he describes the village preacher who had many cares; many burdens to bear; many sorrows to listen to; whose toils were severe; whose purse was slender and yet he was always calm and serene, and to whom the poet pays eloquent tribute. "As some tall cliff that lifts its awful form. Swells from the vale, and midway leaves the storm. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">46 Though round its breast the rolling cl Kternal smi-.li - on iis hi Why the sunshine? I and the mind of the ma were under absolute control. I once looked upon H grand old mountai that reared its head fifteen thousand the level ■rm gathered about it until it reached half way to th -uintnit. The thunder roared and the lightning darted re but the mountain stood mm. ;&gt;on the summit u i! sunshine and I s:iid to ■ . if we could thus deal wit mU the little things of life, the things that are unimpor ant; if we could keep them down, the thing* 'hat ruin us. I lie little torn; .nd make us guilts all down and rise higher than they the sunlight that inn things that work us in'o ill-advised thing* — if we keep them are. then we shall be surrounded by mountain top, the eternal I g-o through the world men. When I get a younf year I am brought in man to ask himself the qui at it in all its bearings; I \vi t th wh it the proper author &gt; hen I get a young man into that mental atti he is pretty near right, anil that hi* education worth the while. I do not know whether I shall rial heresy when I say that ii Minif man forth into the world with a will-training than i* is for him to ha ;ill the learning of all tl md I believe in learning, to It is of the utmost im that we i • will training. W being pressed hard by his opponent. He had - pushing him back and farther back on his flank in ined doomed U mmand- the i - 'liloh, of V Jir, the eiv flank. Earl] d his lin&lt; mpted to pierce our center. All •ation Grant said, '"T, and strike the apex of the t nd h; Id in -Hi t (it th to himselt, "I wi. think before I do this; I » at it in all its bearings: I w rth while to flv intt fe, and li nt&gt;&gt; life h nethir have it in ord&lt; ible to meet res)Kjnsil)iliti number of men, but h -killful in wa the an^le between the Rapidan and the Kappa I) an nock river* mit i the army of the uniin was thi with defeat, and an im| hai^n seemed doomed to failure. An a nmand— the hero of Shiloh, of Vickabufff, and ■ Saluting he said: "Sir, the I on the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">47 e to make at the moment th&lt; i him. IT WILL TRAINING, combined with sound judgment. An o»fi such training under like circumsta; been I with fear. The great ma i c'ful man, used h living the problem as qu: ment in tlv ash. Early went scampering up f the Wilderness Campaiui Hired i he reason that we should h tjiat when the life blow upon n- When thi ne we may unfurl our I nit, when upon the inmand. til our r mist be clear: c rule in tl. n of fe&gt; !'. Tiny are not bora in an instant. Tl it. They are not born in an instant nd that blows upon it. that blov life tha •intently cherishes th&lt;- ithers ueijrenci' ithers rensrth may hat lan the vear t&gt;efore. The man elings ter, higher, nobler: the man who does not • .irage than h&lt; n« in. He is a m will come man whose fcelii ir undei . ke a crown. The man w year than he knew I i man u Rsr whom the small but the man more things, I me.ii sh life, the . lan of the Americai. 1 whose thought is illumin n.ike him nobler and able to do greater life, while he * ity with head </seg>
            <seg id="p046">48 It is the duty of every man to have this process go on within him every year. It is your privilege for the process to go on in you. It is my duty to have it go on in me. The poet Oliver Wendell Holmes, is known as the Laughing Poet of New England, yet while he laughed he interpreted deeply the me;m ing* of life. Walking- on the shore of the sea, he saw a little anim.il which began its shell very modestly but which every year i - larger. Each vear found its house larger,.. 4nd, at the end it had built nobly and grandly The poet said to hiphself "This is the ultimat. - meaning of life; this is what we are to dy, build ourselves more grandly every year." In the last stanza of "Th e Chambered Kaulilm" may be found his words: / / t Build thee more stately maXuJons, Oh m\ As the swift season- Leave thy low vaulted pa%t. Let each new temple nobler than the last Shut thee from Heaven v»j t h a dome more vast Till thou at length aref re e Leaving thine outgrow-! s hell by life's unresting sea. This, it seems to me, is the/final meaning of life. To build 1&gt; and deep and strong the foundations of our spiritual temple. To erect walls composed of the firrr/j, ran j te of courage, self-control, sobriet) judgment, thoughtfulnes^ j n speech and justice in all our feeling - 11 thelr .'"rt ! 'rfli"fhe' shining decorations of hope, fnith, of love for the beautiful, and of world knowledge. Such a building can never fall. It will endure through all the ages. To lives builded in this way men in succeeding times shall come to find models after which they may fashion their own lives. Such lives can not perUh; they will endure forever. I am here to say just a word in addition to what I have already uttered concerning the work of the Nebraska Prison Rrform A~ tion. The Nebraska Prison Reform Association is interested in this work, and it comes to you with words in which it says to each ■ you "Hope."' Have courage, for, as our means permit we expect to take each one from this institution and place yon in a position — if you need our assistance — where you can make of your life a triumphant closing. In the past year we have met something like sixty men either here or in the city of Lincoln, and we have placed them all in position* of responsibility, and they are all with one exception doing well. Let me say to you that they are not only doing well, but they have a fine sense of honor. Our resources are very limited. The state has not yet taken hold of the work and provided tor us, so we are obliged to raise all our funds by subscription. Every man. I believe, with the exception of three, whom wt iv from here and we nave proviueo a place and position! wnere ikt can earn s </seg>
            <seg id="p047">49 has sent back to us all the money that we expended in getting him tu the place where he works. We know all of you are in need of this. The Nebraska Prison Reform Association has delegated me to speak io you that its members are interested in you; are interested in seeing you become self controlled; are read}- to stretch forth their hands and to provide positions for you that you may make in the at - mosphere of freedom your life something worth the while, something worth living. Et is not necessary to multiply words instating the object of the ciation. We have ;i mething like sixty men in th&lt; and all have been faithful to the responsibilities laid upon them, ave kept from the world their past, confident that within th&gt; ears they will have made for then place in society which :ause them to fear no past, however filled with failures and lack uf on the part of humanity. We beleive in humanity. We believe ill men can do something in the world. We believe in the ultimate ncement of the race; in other words we believe in just what that ■ English poet believed when he wrote the stanza with which I close: 1 hold it true with him who To one clear harp in divers tones That men may rise on stepp Of their dead selves to higher things." Let me conclude by expressing the hope that there has been brought : from us who are out in the busy world a message that will enable each one of you to rise on the - iis dead self to </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">IXDE X Keport of Conference Proceedings Program of Eighth Annual Meeting Remarks on Program. . Letter from J. T. More\ Program by the Blind. g Appointment of Committ- - .10 Further Remarks on Program. 11 Treasurer's Report 12 Report of Committee on Organization . . . 12 Officers for Ensuing Year .12 Report of Committee on Resolutions . . .12 Charitable Transportation of Needy People 13 "The Problem of Poverty,'" by D &gt;pisl...l6 Announcement of Next Meeting 17 Correction Statistics Report of the National Prison Association .. 18 Cost of State Institution- J| State Board of Charities and Correction 22 State Instituti - 23 Address of Horatio Seymour 'The Constitutionally of a Nebraska Juvenile Court Lav by M. B. Reese 'The Constitutionality of a Juvenile Court law in Ne - braska," by \V. F. Bryant ..32 The Need of a Juvenile Court," by E. P. Holmes The Problem of Living," by A. E. Davisson 41 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>