<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00051.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00051.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-Seventh Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction to the Governor of the State of Nebraska for the Biennium beginning January 5, 1921 and ending January 4, 1923</title>
               <date value="1923-01-04">1923-01-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">}ien iepor Mate Superintendent Public Instruction Governor State of Nebraska JOHN M. MATZEh INDKNI Ol IMBI.K INSTRl'CTIO] </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 REPORT OF STATE SUPBRINTE.VDENT INDEX Accredited Schoi Advantages of Standards of Ai-creditnu Appropr Average Daily Attendar Census, Enrollment, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 3 ON TENTS ,x J-12 13-1 I h al and Village High School 1 16-21 ■&gt; Art. VIII » s&gt; ■i 24-2 27-31 32-3 34-54 55-58 59-62 t 1 63-66 »;t 67-1 H </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 5 LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL STATE OF NEBRASKA \RTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION LINCOLN W. Bryan, State of Nebraska. submit, in compliance with Section 6480, Article X\ mpiled Statutes of Nebraska 1922, the Twenty-seventh Biennial tendent of Public Instruction. Most respectfully, JOHN M. MATZEN, Superintendent of Public Instruction. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT STATE OF NEBRASKA Department of Public Instruction LINCOLN EXECUTIVE DIVISION John M. Matzen John Speedie Cora A. Thompson I. N. Clark State Superintend Deputy State Superintended Assistant Superin tender Rural School In Archer L. Burnham Frank R. Beers Lulu S. Wolford ASSISTANTS Cecile Snapp Ruth E. Wheeler Helen Stacy Helen G. Erb Verneda Whitney .. Gertrude Haldiman Lena Gillain Etta Brown Kx Cora D. Wheeler. Lula R. Davis Alta H. Chapman f Ex rk of Exanr Ex Normal Training Inspe Assistant Normal Training Insj Assistant Superinto </seg>
            <seg id="p007">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 7 NEBRASKA STATE SUPERINTENDENTS 1869-1871 K 1871-1877 1877-1881 1881-1887 1887-1891 1891-1895 1895-1897 1897-1901 1901-1905 1905-1909 1909-1911 1911 (Resigned) ..1911-1915 1915-1917 1917-1920 1920- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 8 INTRODUCTION As another biennium closes Nebraska schools emerge wi grip upon our problems. The period has been strenuous and our educational system, so severe at times as to threaten pr ards. During the biennium the schools have come out from a severe teacher shortage. This has been overcome and n&lt; ui m W a sufficient supply of regularly qualified teachers. Mar ever, are young and inexperienced with limited proft ■f, This is indicative •T, with any of its agencies f&lt; ance has largely increased. costs but after mat lem becomes the r( the schools. Tr attendance, the lower the part of the taxpa we have been passing. the reduction of wasU by standardization an The schools m tellectual development of This can be accomplished by relating the work in the sch&lt; munity life and by giving him pr The problerv </seg>
            <seg id="p009">)F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 9 RURAL SCHOOL DEPARTMENT tandardized and Schools in Process of Standardization. Score Card for Nebraska Standard Rural Schools. f Nebraska High Schools. rse of Study for Rural and Village High Schools II &amp; h Schools (Organized under Sub-division VIII). HOOI TANDAKDIZED AND SCHOOl OF STANDARDIZATION wt ,v Ig Knox rhe Off pral Survey </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT No. of No. of County Schools County hoo Lancaster 6 Saline Lincoln Sarpy Logan Saunders Loup Bluff Madison Seward McPherson _ Sheridar Merrick 9 Shermar Morrill Nance Xemaha T Nuckolls 4 Thoma Otoe arv Pawnee . . Va Perkins Phelps U Pierce Platte Polk Red Willow Richardson Rock </seg>
            <seg id="p011">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 11 OFFICIAL SCORE CARD FOR NEBRASKA STANDARD RURAL SCHOOLS No. Standard Official Nine months' term •&gt; 1 j 1 1 1 rent.-* and Countv Superintendent de County Certificate .) ning graduate or equivalent ■&gt; c-e 10 round, well drained and more acre •&gt; 1 10 Two separate closets. 50 feet apart, kept clean and sanitary, and free from marks 5 9 u Ml V.— Water Supr Good well on ground or nearby, using drinking fountain or covered cooler « ith individual cups Well curbing Sink and drain I ■&gt; Basin, soap and tow 10 .) ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT OFFICIAL SCORE CARD— (Continued VI.— Bu Single desk-s of suitable sizt with l.'i square fe flour space per child Light from left or from left ind rear with uindo area equivalent to one-fifth Hour area Heat from basement furnace, room heater jacketed sto\e. the room containing 21)0 cubic cubi n ;nn of air space for each child Building painU'il ■cats, desks, furnishing daily with damp cluth d ui&gt; ups </seg>
            <seg id="p013">JBLIC INSTRUCTION ■i ;l MM AR&gt; BY COl'NTIES OK KOI R, THREE, TWO AND ONE YEAR UGH SCH(X)LS i ear 1 * ei </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SUMMARY BY COUNTIES OF FOUR, THREE, TWO AND ONE YEAR HIGH SCHOOL County 4 Year 3 Year 2 Year 1 Year Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Holt Hooker Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knox Lancaster Lincoln Log-an Loup Madisor McPherson Merrick Morrill Nance Neman* Nuckoll Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platt*' Polk Red Willow Richardson Rock Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sheridan J </seg>
            <seg id="p015">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 15 SUMMARY BY COL NTIES OF FOUR, THREE, TWO AND ONE YEAR HIGH SCHOOL E CO!' USE OF STUDY FOR RURAL AND VILLAGE HIGH SCHOOLS Grade Nine Second Semester Subjects Taught Periods r Week Per Week Algebra English 5 5 Agriculture Bookkeeping 5 5 Grade Ten 5 English 5 . 5 Geometry 5 European 5 Botany 5 European History Botanv 5 5 Grade Eleven tig .... 5 Solid Geo . 5 Beginning . 5 Civics ... . . 5 Physics Solid Geometry Beginning Latin Civics 5 Beginning Latir 5 5 5 Mus Phy Grade Twelve Grade Twelve American Histo .... 5 American ... 5 English American History 5 5 5 English Caesar Reviews .... 5 Caesar 5 Reviews 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT •/ 17,515.00 !KM M)0.(ll NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY •Organized Under the New Law in Force Since July 19, 1919 ■ Upen-Country Consolidations COUNTY NAME OF SCHOOI Z Adams Roseland 42 US, 151.380.0C Antelope Royal IIS 16', HOO.841.00 14.000 t Banner tFlowerfield Brown Johnstown Buffalo J Denman 41-68 124 276,989 Cass Cedar Chase Ender Lama Gurle: Cheyenne Lore Clay Custer IDry Va tGates tTuckervil T.Milburn tWayside fWhitney Dawes Dixon Allen Waterbury Parks Dundy Fillmore Frontier tOrafino f Community Centei Filley C-21 24 166 25 Oaire J.?4,485.0( Otoe 165 36 2.400,000.00 105,000.0( Pickrell ; 14 16'i,000.0( Riverview 162 32 2,400,600.00 125,000.0( Rockford in St. Michael Watertown r&gt;04,207.0( 524,918.0( •Uv&lt; Eajrle Murdot-I Nehawk Wabash Obert Trumbull tCedar Canyc tClimax </seg>
            <seg id="p017">BLIC INSTRUCTION 17 NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATE!) SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY A MIRES Roseland K. Rutherford Roya Johnstowi MU-hut w Ah Murdoi W. B Nehawk Wabash Obert Enders Lamar \ Gurley Lorenzi \\ Sun Tru ( ( Ga Ocont Milburi Whitm Allen Waterbury Parks Milligun Orafino Curtis B. Snvder Filley aude B. Cross Barnesto Piokrell 161! 184 J. K. f .pbell Holmesville Wilbur L. Woodbridgre Rockford </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY •Onjaniied Under the New Law in Force Since July 19. l'.T tOpen-Country Consolidations COUNTY NAMK OK S&lt; HOOI fUnion Center 161 t&gt; 919,400.00 18.200.00 39 Virginia 1.556,270.00 50,000.00 !4C Garden I tGoodview J 28 856,480.00 2:.. i Greeley +Fish Creek 2-NI16* 619,200.00 M&gt;0 Scotia 149 2,240,000.00 30,000.00 1 Hamilton Marquette it; 1,015,780.00 1 i Phillips 95-CI23 1,760,000.00 Harlan __ Mascot 20 Ragan IP 1, 900,000. (K 1 Holt fAmelia Inman tValley CenU Howard — . »fCushing Elba Kearney ; *Wilcox Knox — *tBazile Mil tCenter C-24 16M tPlum Valley Santee Lancaster _ Walton 4»; Waverly Logan i Stapleton 44^ Madison '. -^Liberty Morrill I f_ Nemaha I 'Brock C-14 Julian Nuckolls Nora tSt. Stephens Otoe +No. 10 )0 ( Pawnee Lewiston t;9 29 i00.000.00 )(M).0( Perkins Madrid C-12 ,000.00170 Venango f&gt;5 5:l 000.0071 Pierce tStark Valley 23!17 693,781.00 6,000.00172 tLogan's Pride 44 11 .-.75.667.00 13,500.00 Polk ~ fRiverside 28-66 11 529,830.00 5,800.00174 Red Willow *Danbury 12130 1,001,335.00 9,975.00 IRed Willow 10736 296.045.00 000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 19 ' NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY NCIFAL ADDRESS 501 82 P. H. Cross I Liberty 60 120 Garland Nichols Virginia 41 A. E. Hering Lodge Pole Mrs. Ruby Hahn Scotia 11 140 2801 H. Way Scotia 19 150 James A. Buchan Marquette 12 4 1001 170| B. B. Harris Phillips 10 671 R. H. Rennecker Mascot 105| 174 j J. T. Anderson Ragan 10 36 Bower Sageser I Amelia ?0| 145 J. D. Dasenbrock Inman 301 Minnie Alderson Chambers 4i 75 109| Harold McClary ICushing 80 1671 Alice Vogt Elba 4! 101 1 1961 J. Evan Hutchins Wilcox 42 1 Irene Philbrick Bazile Mills 125 Emma Richardson Center 251 Emily Pischel Center 501 Frances Lamm Santee 1061 1451 Marvin R. Schafer Walton 45! 235 1 A. B. C. Jacobs Waverly 217| F. H. Beedle Stapleton E. C. Blue j Madison S* John G. L. Hanlen j Brock 100| Lena Myers Julian Chas. E. Young 'Nora Clara Weibeler Lawrence Ruby Ganzel lOtoe 1501 J. M. Frazer ' Lewiston 7| 1731 J. B. Worley Madrid 1521 J. A. Sawyer IVenango Catharine Fisher Foster 46! Emma Splittgerber Pierce 681 1751 John S. Burlev Danbury McCook M 76' Georpina Tolbe </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY •Organised Under the New La Force Since July Open-Country Consolidat COUNTY NAME OF SCHOOI Richardson tBratton Unior *Dawson t Honey Crt tPreston.. 4.(li Sarpy Gretns Papillior Springf Mead Saunders War Scotts Bluff ♦tLake Al *McGrew jttsbluff nflow ■\ Victory H Cordova Seward Tamora f Banner Sheridan Clintc Sherman IBloody Rur fWigrple ( +No. 44. Sioux Thayer Wayne Webster Belvidere Sholes Cowles tEckley.. tGarfield 'Benedict K York Totals / </seg>
            <seg id="p021">F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 21 NEBRASKA CONSOLIDATED SCHOOLS GENERAL SURVEY K ADDRKS Irving L. Moore IHumboldt H. Adee Dawson H. Kindigr Salem L. H. Warner Preston E. L. Witte Gretna 24 229 Arthur F. Becker Papillion 33 179 John Mettlen Springfield 120 212' C. M. Ewers Mead 42 •)"&gt; Wendell Sanderson Wann 150 1601 M. A. Sams Scottsbluff 112 Alfred F. Hinze McGrew 160! M. A. Sams Scottsbluff 192 1,675 E. L. Rouse Scottsbluff 182 Harry J. Linton Mitchell 142 W. S. Still Scottsbluff 37 10:; Harry R. Knott Cordova 93 Perry M. Spease Tamora 43 H. J. Finch Hay Sprini 96 Jos. E. Brown Clinton G 28 Alice Jacobson Litchfield 44 99 Lindell C. Hockett Loup City 182 Harry J. Linton Mitchell W. S. Still Scottsbluff Harry R. Knott Cordova Perry M. Spease Tamora H. J. Finch Hay Spring Jos. E. Brown Clinton Alice Jacobson Litchfield Lindell C. Hockett Loup City 63 Evan W. Surber Sholes Sholes CM. Deakin Cowles 121 178 M. L. Vohland Guide Rock Marie Cahill Red Cloud 4 117 186 H. R. Best Benedict IM I 051 394 90' 1023' 209^4233' 12,867 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT N *1 "- 5 5 x i- t &gt; SSu v. x KS-5 I : ■ i 1 : : : : _« I S III 1 51 j 111* i , 5 1 I 1 Z I : : : ■ : ! | | z 6d KW o6&lt;a r *c6K g V gi M v n 5?; c r e ■ SB ♦* «'Sif 5^ </seg>
            <seg id="p023">F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 23 169 Z 7. nMiCKOOIIOANNO 5 o » » n o in to « « n io e z 6 d c oc" «" to od n » s o" o -, - e n n « a oo 16 q « </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 4, 1 I II III COUNTY CERTIFICATES An amendment to the county certificate law becatm- eff&lt; 921. The provisions are as follows: \\ Classes Second Gradt First Grade Requirements for First Issuance tifirate. f a Second (&gt;rade County Cer &lt; Approved chara Academic — Pa jlturt ng, civil government, drawing, theory and art of teaching Profession w standard college, the Univers approved normal school in this the normal training course of superintendent as being equippi I 4. Issued by county suj Fee $1.50 6. Validity — Time, 2 year any other county of the state state superintendent. h Renewable Requirements for Renewal of a Second Grade Count) Certificate 1. General average in all required subjects must be raised by state examination to 85 per cent with no subject below 75 per cent. 2. Applicant must present certificate signed by proper author - ities of institution attended, showing credit for six college hours earned in residence or in absentia since the issuance of the second grade county certificate to be renewed; and thereafter ' it shall be renewable upon the payment of a fee of one dollar and fifty cents and presentation each time of a certificate signed by the proper accepted by the sta grades in said subjec metic, English composition, geography, grammar, United Stat history, mental arithmetic, orthography, penmanship, physioloj and hygiene, and reading; provided, however, that equivalent grad in agriculture, bookkeeping, civil government, English compositio and physiology earned in high school by graduates of the norm training course of approved normal training high schools may </seg>
            <seg id="p025">N'STRUCTK w applicant since the ?wed. suanrr of a First drad&lt;- County Certificate. ny, geometry, and public required subjects of 80 per rage lr ■quivalent grades in algebra, botany. agriculture, bookkeeping, civil gov - and physiology earned in high school lal training course of approved normal be accepted by the state superintendent state normal school, or other ap- another state, or graduation from high school of this state approved Renewal of a First Grade County Certificate men quired subjects must be raised t with no subject below 80 per rtificate signed by proper author nded showing credit for six college hours tia since issuance of the first grade enewed; it shall be renewable thereafter a certificate signed by the proper author- at f the institution attended showing that applicant has earned iv e I rs in residence or in absentia since the issuance he first grade county certificate to be renewed 3. Issued by county superintendent. 4. Fee $1.50. Validity— T ears on in all subjects for t jdition thereto, upon pass ruination grade: \t least 12 weeks of normal training in tht beinj: equipped to give such normal </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT &gt; Examination Dates for 1921 One-day, Saturday, January 22, 1921 One-day, Saturday, March 26, 1921. One-day, Saturday, April 23, 1921. Two-day, Friday and Saturday, May 27-28, 1881. Two-day, Friday and Saturday, June 24-25, 1921 Two-day, Friday and Saturday. July 22-23, 1921 One-day. Saturday. December 3, 1921. County Certificate Subjects Professional Life Certificate Sul Total Total County Certificate Subject Total Life Certificate Subjects fi Certificates Issued by County Superintendents and Reported Superintendent for 1921. Second Grade County First Grade County Certificates Issued by County Superintendents and Reported to Sta Superintendent for 1922. Second Grade County First Grade County Total Second Grade County Certificates for Bienniun Total First Grade County Certificates for Biennium Examination dates for 1922 One-day, Saturday, January 21, 1922. One-day, Saturday, April 15, 1922. Two-day. Friday and Saturday, May 26-27, 1S&gt;22. Two-day, Friday and Saturday, June 30-July 1, 1922. Two-day, Friday and Saturday. August 4-o, 1922. One-day, Saturday, October 21, 1922. One-day, Saturday. December 2, 1922. Number of Examination Papers Graded and Reported to Count &gt; Su erintendents for 1921. County Certificate Subjects 79,t)i Professional Life Certificate Subjects » Total 79,9! Number of Examination Papers Graded and Reported to County Su erintendents for 1922. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">BLK INSTRUCTION 27 STATE CERTIFICATES aw to be properly certificated to ate, denominational and parochial made on forms secured from \ nation shows the character and :ipp reparation of the applicant, to- certificate held etc., and ecord which is filed for ref- nar inds, viz: City state certificates .VI tate certificates shall consist of anted, shall have validity, shall .'V hall be convertible into professional city state cer- sinafter specified. The grade city statt uperintendent of Pub'L- Instruc- ie valid from the kindergarten to the eigh h term of three years in all districts of the state XXII and in districts organized under Article h the county superintendent without fee, and It shall be issued to any person an citi all have graduated from an approved arned a first grade county certificate, iversity, a standard college, a state pproved normal school in this or another state at least four of which must be professional ormal school in this or another state four of which must be professional e payment of a fee of one dollar to payment of a fee of one dollar to ic Instruction and upon application tender.t of Public Instruction and upon application thorities of the institution attended show- ies of the institution attended show- nt of the academic and professional prep the academic and professional prep- e in teaching, the kind of certificate teaching, the kind of certificate ■sired, all certified to by a county or lowledge of the facts stated in the k be renewable thereafter by the state of a statement signed by the tended, showing the completion sidence or in absentia, I'C I'rofessH nal (.radc City State Certificate grade city state cer atisfactory completion of one w iving evidence of three years A'ork a r an aggregate of 24 months of successful teaching experience; second. jpon payment to the State Superintendent of Public Instruction of a »y fee of one dollar. Provided, no life certificate shall be in force after </seg>
            <seg id="p028">V EPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT he holder shall permit a period of )\ving some educational pursuit, un he state sunerintendent. ligh School Citj State C&lt; irate The high school city state iltndenl of Public- Instructk jf three years in all districts &gt;ut fee, and may be valid in mi x&gt; any person of approved char i first grade county certificate. the State Superintendent of P r»ointpH hv him a irrad w i&gt;svcholoirv. zoologv, geology, E i ' physical geogrnph torv. and who has in I'OUPP 1 *' ,t to any person tintht&gt;r air with the advar «;tsifi&gt; tiniv#»rsit issued to any | upon the romp It-trt' nnivpi'sitv tl course is equivalent to the same col braska. It shall be granted upon tendent of Public Instruction of a tion as described in the provision state certificate. It shall be convei city state certificate valid for life, experience. Provided, no life eer holder shall permit a space of thri some educational pursuit, unless th sunerintpnderit. \ The superintendent's city state it Superintendent of Public Instruction, which shall be va! term of three years in all districts of the state organiz Article XXII and in districts organized under Article VI when Article VI when re; e CXII and Article VI when reei teachers, or of a for the training in 1hi&lt; «£tnt*&gt; univ Superintendent's City State Certifical </seg>
            <seg id="p029">)F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 29 h the county superintendent without fee, and may be valid in metro politan districts. It shall be granted to any person of approved char tat who holds a professional high school city state certificate and it experience as a principal of an ap- f a fee of one dollar to the State K Instruction and upon application in the manner le issuance of the grade city state lie into a professional superintendent's after three years successful exper no life certificate shall be in force P» a space of three years to elapse without t, unless the certificate be endorsed t Special City Stale Certificate ficate, issued by the State Su which shall be valid for a t which shall be valid for a term ts of the state organized under Article f the state organized under Ar1 ed under Article VI when regist( ganized under Article VI when registered t without a fee and may be valid in without a fee and may be valic all be issued to any person of approved &gt;e issued to any person of apprc i approved four year high school one year of special work in an approved four year high school and least one year of special work in an ap- ational, or industrial school organ ational, or industrial school organized pecial teachers. Or it shall be iss J for the training of special teachers. Or it shall be issued H'tson of approved character who in lieu of the one year of i-ter who in lieu of the one year had one year of practical experk j one year of practical experience as ha ift or trade for the teaching of wl aft or trade for the teaching of which i issued. It shall be issued upon ued. It shall be issued upon tht dent of Public Instruction of a of Public Instruction of a fe&lt; 1 as prescribed in the provisions prescribed in the provisions for te certificate. It shall be convert rtificate. It shall be convertible ~tate certificate valid for life ai certificate valid for life after perience; Provided, no life certifk shall permit a space of three ye educational pursuit, unless the &lt; Provided, no life certificate permit a space of three years .1 some educational pursuit, unless the cer perintendent. ieneral State Certificate ite Certificate consist of the following classes: the following classes: th ■tate certificate; tht- elementary or second grade state cei lementary or second grade state &gt; ■rtiticate. ti.ate, issued by the State Superinte Instruction, which shall be valid for Hfe, in all distri Provided, no life certificate shall be in force after the holder ace of three years to elapse without following sonif </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT educational pursuit, unless the certificate be endorsed by the sta erintendent. It shall be granted to any person of approved characte who has secured, or who secures, a first grade cobnty certificate and i addition thereto earns by examination before the State Superintende of Public Instruction or before a committee appointed by him, a gra of not less than 80 per cent in each of the following subjects: psycholog zoology, geology, English and American literature, rhetoric, pr geography, chemistry, trigonometry, physics and general hi who has had at least two years additional teaching beyond tha quired for the issuance of a first grade county certificate. ( bo granted to any person of approved character who is a gradu a standard college, or university, in this or another statt ,v had three years of successful experience as a teacher in public, priv denominational, or parochial schools. Or it shall be issue son of approved character who holds a diploma from a sta school or standard college i for life in that state, provided such right i.s based upor preparation and experience for the issuance of the pr above cases, it shall be issue&lt; the issuance of the grade city si Provided, that if a shortag exists, the State Superintend request of all members of tht intendent in schools organizec \ quest of all members of the boar one year. Provided, that not mi I be granted to the same person. It may be granted only wher form prescribed and approved by Instruction and when accompaniet that the State Superintendent ma upon satisfactory evidence that th h. conditions upon which it was issued Se?. 5. Emergency. — Whereas, be in force and effect from and afu Approved April 4, 1921. ent of Public Instruction o cases in addition upon api superintendents in schools orgar issue to any person of appruv valid only in the district desijrr </seg>
            <seg id="p031">PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 31 CITY STATK CER KT1FICATF M) RECOKDF E I El ERTIFK ATES AND RECORD* Y T TIFICATES ISSUED FROM JANUARY 1, 1921 TO JANUARY 1, 1922. ISSUED BY STATE SCHOOLS AND APPROVED 1) IN OFFICE OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 611 323 92 18 1,044 TIFICATES ISSUED FROM JANUARY 1. 1922 TO JANUARY 1, 1923 ISSUED BY STATE SCHOOLS AND APPROVED 1) IN OFFICE OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 8,-&gt;l 469 78 13 1,396 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 32 ACCREDITED HIGH SCHOOLS The University of Nebraska maintains a list of accredited schools, the graduates of which are admitted to the University (and to nearly all of the colleges and universities of the United States) without entrance examinations in subjects that are properly certified as completed within these schools. Unless a graduate of an accredited school, a candidate for admission must be prepared to take examination in those subjects in which entrance credits are desired; provided that graduates of non - accredited four-year high schools may be excused from taking the aca - demic examination by passing with a standing of at least 60 the intelli - gence test given University freshmen. "Accredited" schools are such a; inspector of accredited schools are credited Schools" to a degree apr, The list of accredited schools can b of Accredited Schools., Sta., A, Lani compiled jointly by the University &lt; of Public Instruction, giving detail. schools and suggestions as to cours* is sent upon application to the Regi under inspection by the L'niversit found to mett the "Standards of A ropriate for their respective classe e secured by addressing the Inspect* oln, Nebr. The High School Manua f Nebraska and the State Depart tudy and methods of instructor u sity of N Certificates of graduation froir North Central Association of Coil - crediting associations of equal rar without examination in the suhjet which ar IV An "Approved" high school v. and condition inspected by nt and has been authorised to own and to collect tuition f the pupils are sent. 1. The University of Nebrask 2. The State Superintendent ar pro Standards of Accredited Schools In the interest of true economy in tin and all institutions of whatever natur standards of attainment. In the field are irreparable and are of far r hit- value. For this reason standards havt accrediting schools. They are a How I. Not less than thirty units requ i 1 2. The minimum academic and professional prcparat teachers equivalent to four years !&gt;eyond a high-school course. In dete mining this equivalence, two years of successful experience closely related to the teaching fit year of higher preparation. 3. Not to exceed six daily recitations for each leather, a double period of laboratory work or study room supervision counting as one recitation ■d information in regard to accredit </seg>
            <seg id="p033">F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 33 quired of any nstruc- ,f apparatus and methods of cleaning j nd teachers. me Advantage of Accreditment lation to the University of Nebraska and ted Sta sdying the program of studies and such ecting apparatus, texts, and reference book, , when desired, a confidential report to the scl a confidential report to the school ■nee of the school by publication of the ?rsity publications. ie State Department of Public Instruc- Univer Wrrrdited Schools. 1M21-22 North ( Association »t Colleges mt-et with the above y the above standards. At uction in the high school, visions of Standard 2. the* pr roup ( . 65 school redentials, giving them condi P t Addition credit can be secured by exam- :il 30 hours of college work. Twenty - minimum of one, to meet the pro- with ;he lighting, heating avatories, corridors, labits of thought and study, ehool evidenced by inspection. h&lt;ml~ atirifactorilv </seg>
            <seg id="p034">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 34 NORMAL TRAIXIM IN HIGH SCHOOLS at 4. Graduates from normal t entrance credits to the I r Nebraska 5. Combinations of curr Courses of study in by this department. School must have wr II. Standards of Buildings and Equipment 1. Building— well kept Sanitary toilets. 2. Adequate laboratory and i nized high standard work 3. Adequate, up to date tex material as to provide w&lt; in both elementary and hi 4. Must meet standard apr i HI. Number md Qualification of Teachers 1. Superintendent — legally qualified school district, and must have had teaching experience exclusive of 2. High School Teachers a. Not less than three, exclusive time to high school work. b. Where high school contains more than fou be as many high school teachers as grades c. Must be graduate of standard four year college cou higher course of standard normal life certificate or its equivalent. f </seg>
            <seg id="p035">L'BLIC INSTRUCTION 35 • rial qualifications as defined above uccessful teaching ex- ! teaching, (one of which should al school). each all normal training reviews, ntendent, or except penmanship )y Sup aught y a qualified supervisor of those training when not taught by Sup- ining teacher be required )gy when given as minor reviews numl t grade county certificate or grade city state in valent of either less than one year of successful teaching ar of work above a four year standard high standard college, university or normal school than eight hours in professional training. Article XXII districts must hold city state iene, (*4) public school music d. Not less than twelve weeks in each of the major reviews arithmetic, geography, grammar, reading Nut more than fifty pupils enrolled under any one teacher in any ft ulum and Certification. curriculum in normal training high schools shall consist of a liar four year course as outlined in the bulletin issued jointly the University of Nebraska and the State Department of cation. This bulletin is commonly known as the High School lual. IUB1. normal training course where offered shall be elective. mal training high schools shall require for graduation a mini- 11 of thirty entrance credits, as defined by the Nebraska High )ol Manual, and shall be accredited at least B class. iluates of the normal training curriculum must have completed following courses of study: Not less than four semesters or seventy-two weeks in English. Not less than two semesters or thirty-six weeks in each: European history, American history, algebra, geometry, and professional training. Not less than eighteen weeks in each: (*•&gt;) agriculture, (*6( botany, civics, (*5) general science. (*7) physiology and hy- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 36 10. A county examinatii regulations governin which all grades are 11. A minimum of two day ably under the directior quired of every normal t observation should furn management. 12. A minimum of twenty-fo in&gt;r required for graduat V. Personnel and Required Attendance 1. Members of normal training tion to teach. e. Not less than six weeks in each of the minor review orthography, penmanship. f. A minimum of six weeks (*3) bookkeeping. g. Major and Minor Reviews and Professional Trainii taken in an approved normal training high school. h. Academic work must be taken in an approved or school, or student may be admitted to normal trai culuin by examination. i. Shortages may be made up in college or normal scl during first summer following graduation. "&gt;. No credit can be given in any of the prescribed courses not been completed and taken for the time required in tl tions. High school grades will !«■ credited toward eertifica following subjects when taken a&gt; prescribed abov&lt; geometry, botany, public school music, agriculture , b civics, English composition and physiology. If county examinations are taken in any of these- subjec to claim the higher grade is not forfeited, provided obtains a nuivber for the reporting of the grade to the erintendent. Students must obtain grades upon county examination jects required by law for a second grade count;, eertiti as provided for in Section IV. paragraph 6, above. Grai the normal training course in approved high schools s! upon securing requisite grades on county examinatio grade county certificate. 9. After one year of successful teaching this certificate changed for a first grade county certificate without furt ation if requisite grades have been secured in all con </seg>
            <seg id="p037">)F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 37 I X Memb mi! training class shall Ik- denned as follows: pletion of three years of prescribed curriculum Junior ades on county examination in subjects p re end of fiscal year) a &gt;ur years of prescribed curriculum urrtv examination (before end of *d nr mum of ten tas denned above) classes of less than ten may have the work ation but cannot be approved for State Funds. week or equivalent is maximum a pupil may Report* ignition as normal training high school shall be ibed by this department. This application shall within ten days after opening of school. if board of education shall file attendance report of nor g class under oath. lie under oath grade report of normal training -ade reports shall be filed at earliest possible date ter than two weeks before date on which school tese regulations shall serve to abrogate that clause of Article X, School Laws of Nebraska, which reads as In any county not having a high school which can qualify ; regulations the State Superintendent of Public Instruc- ligh school of lower grade for giving such t;i it- Aid g with these regulations shall be subsidized e hundred dollars from fund appropriated by al training in high schools. gislat First Year Schools No school making application for high school (a' for the first time such for one year or more, nor ( recognition as a normal training nor (b) after having lapsed as •) which has not been approved because of failure to comply with these Regulations shall be ap - proved to do more than that work prescribed in these Regulations for normal training juniors (eleventh gade), nor shall it be desig- \pproval of Non-accredited Schools. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT :i nated to receive state aid for normal training, during year la) for which approval is asked, (b) after such laps after failure to comply with these regulations. gulations ■t r X. Normal Training Curriculum. Subject Cr Value Grade in wl- Ma thematic. Algebra Geometry English (Bookkeeping 6 w Public School Music *4 Social Science European History American History Civics Science Botany »6 Agriculture Physiology &amp; H Professional Tre Reviews *9 Arithmetic- Drawing Geography-Penman Grammar-Orthogra Reading-Elective R Elective studies, contemplates a cour tions. 2. Business Forms — t 3. Elementary laws of negotia debits and credits. 5. Business *4. One entrance credit in Course I the Nebraska High School Mam .V in methods of teaching public school music will bt of the prescribed normal trainin j *5. General science not required if p year; or of Smith-Hughes vocational agriculture students. Gener i icience course in Smith-Hughes vocational home econor ;tt physical geography accepted in u of ger *6. Smith-Hughes Vocational Agricultur two year cour Crops and Farm Animals accepted as satisfying the requires in both agriculture and botany. General S •1. Completion of ar course in State Teachers' •2. As defined by Nebaska H *3. Bookkeeping, grouped wi </seg>
            <seg id="p039">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 39 owing combination courses as outlined in j minor review: Combina- eparatory ; Combination Normal Agriculture. Smith-Hughes physiology, hygiene and home taught only in the twelfth grade. &lt;&gt;t secure credit for taking the aphy, grammar, and reading shall og weeks. Minor reviews, drawing under certain conditions, (see and public school music shall be nimum of six weeks. The reviews shall be taught in either the eleventh or twelfth grades. No credit can be given grades. No credit can be given for reviews taught in other than these grades. The projects in Y handwork and drawing are placed on the same basis as laboratory ed on the same basis as laboratory are pi work and shall occupy a double period to receive credit toward cer- a double period to receive credit toward cer - trance. The reviews of grammar, orthogra- tification or college entrance. The reviews of grammar, orthogra- phy and reading, taught as prescribed in the normal training courses jght as prescribed in the normal training courses with elective review shall be known as Normal Training English and w will be accepted by the University as satisfying a part of the Eng- lish entrance requirement, after four points have been regularly ter four points have been regularly famed previously. Part II I'art II COURSES OF STUDY Summary Statement COURSES OF STUDY Statement ummary Aims and Purposes. The Department, in issuing these courses of study, plans to meet four d I'urpos* ng these courses of study, plans to meet four efinite needs. First, that of supplying a survey from the teacher's point of view of the subject matter in the elementary school curriculum. Sttond, to make this subject matter sufficiently comprehensive to afford rigorous academic training. Third, to supplv standards by which the work of the normal train - ing department shall be judged. Fourth, to define limits in the various subjects within which tht county certificate examinations shall fall. The material of these courses is organized around a series of prob- y from the teacher's point of view the elementary school curriculum. matter sufficiently comprehensive to u which the work of the normal train- n tf various subjects within which the animator shall fall organized around a series of prob- material of these courses i ;ms and projects which are briefly outlined to assist the pupil in gather I projects which are briefly utlined to assist the pupil in gather- ig the facts for the solution of the problems. Related problems are ap- g the facts for the solution of the problems. Related problems are ap- ended to each main problem to throw further light upon its organization rended to each main problem to throw further light upon its organization nd function. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 If students taking these courses are not lead to concentrate upon the ■olution of the problem in hand, they will lose themselves in the detail of subject matter and become confused and discouraged. Here must the skill of the teacher come in, directing the attack of the student so that he sees clearly the objective to be attained and the means and methods of attaining that objective. It will be evident to those reading through these courses that they are not "self -teaching" outlines; they demand a live, wide awake, progres - sive teacher with some professional training and experience, and with a reasonable amount of good judgment and common sense. It will not always be possible for each student to do all of the read - ings cited under each problem, but enough must be done to give the stu - dent a definite idea of the solution of the problem and a definite mastery of its content. It is not necessary, nor is it always wise, that all students always do the same reading where all the reading is not possible. A real recitation can often best be secured when pupils approach the matter in hand from different points of view. This means that it is not required that each student have a copy of each book cited, but there shall be enough books that all students may do all the readings. Since the work is usually prescribed in quite large units, a small number in each will suffice. The single book course is discouraged as inadequate. It leads to narrowness of outlook and to memorizing rather than thinking. The standard tests herein introduced and required, have two fum tions: First, to orient the normal training teacher with regard to the ability of the members of the normal training class. Second, to train the normal training students as prospective teachers in the use and purpose of these tests. This Department is indebted to the following persons for the courses listed opposite their names: Professional Training (Observation, Methods and Practices of Teaching), H. H. Hahn, Dean Wayne State Teachers' College. Professional Training (Rural School Management), A. V. Teed. Director Rural Education, Wayne State Teachers' College. Public School Music, H. O. Ferguson, Supervisor of Music, Lincoln City Schools. Physiology and Hygiene, F. M. Gregg, Professor of Psychology, Wesleyan University Geography, E. E. Lackey, Professor of Geography, Wayne State Teachers' College. Reading, G. A. Yoakam, Director Teacher Training, Kearney State Teachers' College. Reading, A. A. Reed, Inspector Accredited High Schools, University of Nebraska. Handwork, Clara O. Wilson, Professor Primary Education, Uni - versity of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 41 II. Ty •&gt; Drawing, Sue Hoagland, Supervisor Drawing and Art, Lincoln City Schools. American History, E. P. Wilson, Professor of History and Civics, ChadTon State Teachers' College. Agriculture, C. W. Watson. Formerly Director of Smith-Hughes Agriculture in Nebraska. Professional Training — 36 weeks. This course of study is an attempt to introduce the high school student to the modern practices and methods of teaching. While the course does not go into the minute details of the practices of teaching or attempt a refined analysis of the teaching process, it follows in general the method used everywhere in science, a. Observation, Methods and Practices of Teaching — 20 weeks 1. Physical Factors — One Week. Teacher Activities — Four Weeke Pupil Activities — Two Weeks. 4. The Teaching of Elementary School Subject — Thirteen Weeks. Types of Teaching — Eight Weeks. Rural School Management — Eight Week Arithmetic — Twelve Week a. Basic Processes — Four Weeks b. Problems and Problem Solving — One Week c. Statistics and Graphs — One Week. d. Denominate Numbers and Mensuration — Three Weeks. e. Percentage and Its Applications — Three Weeks. Phe undersigned is indebted to the following persons for indispens- aid in constructing the courses listed below: Arithmetic, I. N. ClarK, Rural School Inspector, State Department of Public Instruction. Grammar, Alberta B. Anderson, Normal Training Teacher, Lincoln High School, and Sarah Ryan, formerly Superintendent, St. Ed- ward. Penmanship, Minnie S. Stump, Supervisor Penmanship, Fremont City Schools. The undersigned also expresses his indebtedness to his assistant. ik R. Beers, for his help in the general editing of the courses. Bt-sides the persons named above, many others have given services advice in the preparation and revision of the matter herein contained. For any and all distortions in these courses occasioned by editing andersigned assumes responsibility. ARCHEK L. BURNHAM, Normal Training Inspector. 'ypes of Courses Provided. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 3. Geography — Twelve Weeks. a. Principles of Geography — Three Weeks. b. Definition and Aims of Geography — One Week. c. Cycles of Work in Geography (optional) — (One Week). d. The Western Hemisphere — Five Weeks. e. The Eastern Hemisphere — Three Weeks 4. Grammar — Twelve Weeks, a. Good Form— One Week. b. Common Errors and Their Correction — One Week c. The Sentence — Two Weeks. d. Parts of Speech — Preliminary Survey and Substantives — Two Weeks. e. Parts of Speech — Verb Forms — Two Weeks f. Parts of Speech — Adectives and Adverbs — One Week. g. Parts of Speech — Prepositions and Conjunctions — One Week, h. Summary and Review — Two Weeks. 5. Reading — (This course or the course under 6) — Twelve Weeks a. Teacher's Reading — Two Weeks. b. Silent Reading— Six Weeks. c. Oral Reading, including primary methods — Four Weeks. I Reading — Twelve Weeks. a. Mechanics of Reading— Four Weeks b. Primary Reading — Four Weeks. c. Problems in Upper Grade Reading — Two Weeks d. Assignment and Recitation — One Week. e. Study of Texts — One Week. Drawing and Handwork — Six Week? a. Handwork— Two Weeks. b. Representation — One Week. c. Design and Color — Two Weeks d. Perspective and Construction — One Week 8, Orthography — Six Weeks. a. The Spoken Word — One Week. b. How Words are Made — Two Weeks. c. Acquiring a Vocabulary — One Week d. The Spelling Problem — Two Weeks. Penmanship — Six Weeks. 9 a. Efficiency in Handwriting — One Week h. The Writing Process — One Week. c. Hygiene of Writing — One Week. d. Problems of Learning to Write — Three Weeks. III. The department outlines specific course in American history (36 wks.), public school music (18 wks.), physiology (18 wks.) agriculture (18 wks.) </seg>
            <seg id="p043">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 43 I II III Y \ Part III EDUCATIONAL MEASUREMENTS Summary Statement Elements of Measurement. 1. What to measure. What standard or standards to use How to use the standards. Subject Matter Achievement Tests Only Used Purposes of the Tests in Normal Training Reviews. 1. To disclose abilities of members of class in subject matter. 2. As a means of diagnosing weaknesses of previous learning. 3. As a basis for remedial instruction to correct faults of previous learning and to develop specific abilities. 4. To indicate individual differences ini ability or attainment. B. As a point of departure in conducting the class instruction in the several reviews. Tests Used in Normal Training Reviews. Arithmetic — Monroe's Diagnostic and Standard Reasoning Tests. Geography — Hahn-Lackey Geography Scale. Grammar — Starch Punctuation Scale A — Clapp Correct English Test — Kirby's Grammar Test, Form I. Reading— Monroe's Standardized Reasoning Test, Form III. Penmanship — Ayres Handwriting Scale — Freeman's Chart for Diagnosing Faults in Handwriting. Spelling — Monroe's Timed Sentence Spelling Test. Purposes of Tests in Professional Training Class (as Devices in Teach - ing!. As a means cf standardizing work and classifying pupils in the rural schools. 2. As a means of fair and proper grading of pupils. 3. As a means of testing specific abilities in subject matter. As a basis for correcting faulty instruction by teacher and faulty learning by pupils. As a means of measuring progress of instruction. 6. As a means of bringing rural pupils in contact with achievement of. large groups of pupils. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 44 VI. Problems of Learning to use Teats as Devices. 1. How to find the standards on a given test that should be attained by a given class. 2. How to give and score a test and determine the standard of the class tested. 3. How to use standardized teats for diagnostic purposes 4. How standardized tetrts indicate individual differences among chil - dren. VII. TeaU Used as Devices to Improve Teaching (Prof. Tr. Course) 1. Burgess — Scale for Measuring Ability in Silent Reading. 2. Courtis — Standard Research Tests in Arithmetic, Series B. S. Ayres — Measuring Scale for Ability in Spelling. 4. Hahn — History Scale or Hahn-Lackey — Geography Scale. Part IV STATISTICAL TABLES Normal Training High School* Training of High School Teachers TABLE 1—1920-21 | More Than Bachelor'! Master's No. Vn Training Above SUnd- mrd 4 Yr. H. S. Courae Two I Two— No Dccrw Dccra* Degree •Normal Training Teacher I 21 96 59 6 Superintendent I 11 50 100 26 tOther High School Teachers 105 306 426 29 TABLE II— 1921-22— (229 Schools) e j No. Yn. Above a Standard P 4 Tr. H. 8. Conn* , • o II Jh 'Normal Training Teacher ._ j 16 Superintendent | 9 tOther High School | Teachers | 31 II u Pa Si 54 23 115 27 13 72 ! 33 27 82 I. | 157 I I 457 I 86 127 432 6 24 fi </seg>
            <seg id="p045">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 45 Training of High School Teachers — (Continued) TABLE III— 1922-23— (236 Schools) * Includes Superintendent if teaching Normal Training. •(■Includes only those schools employing less than 25 teachers. o. Yrs. Above a Standard 4 Yr. H. S. Coune a It z * II, »J 1 nl in I u ii I! ■ •Normal Training Teacher | Superintendent j tOther High School Teachers j 17 I 9 j I I 21 i I | 97 i i 2H 17 M I I I 50 33 y4 j 102 | 160 I | 457 | 102 131 | 437 4 26 5 •Includes Superintendent if teaching Normal Training. f Includes only those schools employing less than 25 teachers. jlncludes 1 Superintendent with Ph. D. Degree. Experience of High School Teachers TABLE IV— 1920-21 Experience in Y«« I. cm* Than Three 8 or More — 5 or More— ., .-^ Lcm Than 5 Leu Than 1&lt; " or " or * •Normal Training Teacher.. | 27 44 53 I I 65 Superintendent I 17 26 ,' Other High School 4fi I f 99 Teachers I 328 | 183 | 175 126 TABLE V— 1921-22— (229 Schools) Kxperienee In Leu Than 3 or More — 5 or More — ,„ M Year* Three Leu Than 5 Leu Than 10 lu or " or * •Normal Training Teacher ! 13 | 31 | 100 | 86 Superintendent | 14 | 20 ! 74 121 tOther High School I | Teachers | 298 I 173 ! 196 | 90 TABLE VI— 1922-23— (236 Schoola) I Kxperienc* in I . Yean Less Than S or More— S or More — M Three Lew Th«n S Leu Than 10 l0 or More .&lt;-*» Th»n Three I i i L 3 or More- Less Than i 1 S 5 1.4 5 or More- .«■«* Thmn m 1( 10 or M ♦Normal Training Teacher I Superintendent | tOther High School Teachers 12 14 346 | ! 43 22 154 i I i i i I I i I 96 161 I I 85 112 72 ; i </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Salary Distribution of High School Teachers TABLE VII— 1920-21 a s \ s \ a \a Salary Ran*, - 1 a a m a a a Sjj oo oo So So oo eo en e* oo 09^* *• *o io « isf foe •» O •»«» | •»•» •»«• &lt;•«* •»•» «»«» M.-.l •Normal Training: Teacher 29 211 42! 52 21 10 6 5 $1402.75 tOther High School Teachers 163! 80 199 1 175 85! 42 55 79 1399.4 ('ABLE VIII— 1921-22— (229 Schools) Salary : o * — o ' — = _e H o L.a h u^ 5i I S§ SS S§ Sg S J- sSSS 5 5 bSoSSS Rant'. "^ 25 jS— 2S SS *''£* M •* •»«» | «»«» •Normal Training Teacher 191 19! 63! 581 241 11 10 25 : $1425.14 tOther High School Teachers 70 88 220' 17 TABLE IX— 1922-23 (236 Schools OJ OS OO OO.O© OO ©S O M Ranfre «■* ta I «• wt- t-x xs, •Normal Training Teacher ■&gt; 44 74 41 22 1 tOther High School Teachers 130! 166 222 83 42 22 29 39 1332 •Includes Superintendent if teaching Normal Trainine. ■(•Includes only those schools employing less than 25 teache </seg>
            <seg id="p047">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 47 Distribution of School Tax Levy 'Includes County High Schools tLevy on % Actual Valuation. Median Levy 48.79 Mills. TABLE XI— 1921-22— (229 Schools) No. of Mi No. of Schools *1 Includes County High School Levy on % Actual Valuation. Median Levy 53.73 Mill TABLE XII— 1922-23— (236 Schools) No. of Mil No. of Schools 6. or L&lt; 6.1- 8 ... .20 36 8.1-10 36 10.1-12 4S&lt; 12.1-14 32 14.1-16 25 16.1-18 14 18.1-20 14 20+ 10 'Includes County High Schools. •{■Levy on Total Actual Valuation. Median Levy 11.16 Mills. I : x i— is o- -2 -21 21 Nn n.4 Qy.V fNo. of Mills jno. or set No. of Schools •30 or less 10 81 .: 34 31- 40 41- 50 51- 60 1..1I 20 16 61- 70 71- 80 81- 90 _... 3 91-100 9 18 ........3» 60 - 33 41 _ 24 12 IB </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Enrollment in Normal Training Classes TABLE XIII— 1920-21— (223 Schools) 216 Public Schools— 8 Private and Parochial Schools. TABLE XIV— 1921-22— (243 Schools) || Boys | Girls | Total || Boys I Girls | Total || 463 2832 3285 II 238 I 2410 I 2648 •3 *91 »94 »0 »95 i »95 Total |j 466 | 2923 | 3379 II 238 | 2605 ; 2743 236 Public Schools— 11 Private and Parochial Schools Private and Parochial Schools. II JUNIORS II SENIORS •otal i Boys 218 •0 218 I GirU 1912 »79 1991 Total 2130 *79 2209 Boys 172 •0 172 I Girls 1565 •38 1603 Total 1737 •88 1776 u II JUNIORS II SENIORS lUl 1ST 1^ I Girls 2420 •110 2530 I Total 2714 •111 2825 I Boys 208 •3 211 I I Girls 2031 •75 2106 Tot*l 2239 •78 2317 232 Public Schools — 11 Private and Parochial Schools. TABLE XV— 1922-23— (247 Schools) JUNIORS II SENIORS </seg>
            <seg id="p049">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 49 Type of School 1920-21 Number H. 8. Teaebm I Accredited School* Offering Normal Training Credited Normal Training Smith-Hughe. Sehoota H A C I H. E. I Ag. 4 11 57 I 5 •1 [ •1 *2 II 5-6 22 •2 39 I 4 ♦1 *1 I 7-10 46 i 21 12 11+ T S3 ! 11 1 Total II 102 104 I 9 it 47 I 25 TABLE XVII 1921-22 Number H. S. Teacher* Accredited Schools Offering Normal Training Accredited Normal Training Smith-Hughe. School. 1 1 A B I C || H.E. H. E. I I Ag. Ag. 4 10 L_ 63 | 1 J II 2 I I 12 I! I 12 IL *2 *3 | II I I 5-6 II 35 41 14 I I 9 IL 7-10 *2 45 I *2 1 10 | J 14 _L 8 II 14 I •2 « + II 27 I I I ii II 9 I) i 9 I M_ Total 117 *6 I !__ 114 •6 1 Jl I " II S3 II </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPOB1 OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Type of School — (Continued) •Parochial and Private Schools \oi,r. ai 1922-23 Number H. S. Teachers II Accredited Sehools Offering Normal Training I Accredited Normal Training Smith-Husha Schools A c I Ag. 4 14 58 6 Jl I * I 4 14 5-6 _L 32 I •5 40 _L 1 J 15 J I U 5-6 32 •2 •2 ■4 7-10 7-10 II 53 58 6 i i 19 i I 10 11 + II 26 I „ 9 I 4 ■ Total II 125 104 7 47 28 1 1 II •2 •9 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 51 i •4 5 H «* gJ 8s t- os *»*»S °» os o» ' c-' o •* i«oo n&lt;lnj tj in ■« ce ia ' CUtS 3 ■» OS i-J O&gt; O NIC c«-io-S" 0 5 o MO to o&gt; os 8 S I I t~aoos©ooooooao -O -V-flitOTji 00 04 t~ .. uB_ * 82 * • rt • a * -r « B -j «-2 Tm c ■- u c — p C &gt;§c0« „ OSSJ OT00 W t- t-kO •&lt;«5§ z £ *_ -* i-i oo-^ os © i&gt; 00 5 1= r - 1 N •* Ofl e« 00. i-; r&gt; *° Z 23 » mis « t-_ oso&gt; '„ « ■» O U5 N « as O&gt; = ■— K oiocoiooqeoioio IjJ 1 : 1 SJ-ji * " " . "? «. °» &lt;£■£ "3- Ou5 t- o) -h to •&lt;*•* I I I I I I « o) e- ■* i&gt; 10 10 -* |il| «- 5 at-; « coos osos co us 000 z c z £ BS « * &gt;e ♦ «e im S» * 2r lt " t ~osoot-» ? _-, la 3? 5. H S 3 ?? Jpgll 2 « O "&lt;* *H O CD r^ — ~9 '«_■ OSMIOIOOSOOIMOO B3 to* os» «SS» .5 = 03 , S"S "2-4 os»©iOosio^ii^ U= 8- C ** * Wt-Mi-I W K a 1H i-l &lt;H U9 • I fc C ■» CD © iH — pi s 5 I A gt IT 1 I ■a j </seg>
            <seg id="p052">IT OF STATE SUPI ITAT EMNTEND s I to co O CM s 4 2 3 S IS ===== • • e S 6 U CB CO OS I-; to ih &lt;s ie 00 00 00 — 00 X 00 la US 00 # 00 CO OS CO OS OS 00 O t-^ — 5 o to os 00 00 "* W oo co d co -. tO CM 1 S o n*" la " — f in OS "W i-H i-&lt; • iH ii * CM to ii CO OJ l&gt; Is * — &lt; eo io us — &lt; oo co o — * — — ' OS t&gt; OS &gt;o — ; o 11 H 11 a IB la o O.00 o eo * — &lt; IO &lt;N ts&gt; —J oo co i-l 11 SN N « * t&gt; "W to 8 §3S — -r •» 00 CO tO OS 00 -O" CO n n CO CM * * to eo -p t- c» oo 00 CM -&lt; o I I s-I-5 a llii 1# fa h to t- 1O t&gt; U3 • Oi U3 CO * OS iO -VI- tO IS O) CJ M t- • CM O t- to » 10 cc o * CM M e t- 10 t&gt; os oo *■* *-l M rt IO PJ (* t- • to * co cm » en n eo n © i« — « ■v eo •«• n &lt;n n ~h 00 • t- * T* t- iH IN * CO to CM CO CM 00 n et &lt;• to -* © S to e* • io * oo i-i l-H T-&lt; TH IO • tO IC IO t- t~ c*3 C&gt;4 t- t- 00 "5 tt&gt; o O ■* * oo * n t- &lt;n H r-&lt; N »• to ♦ io CO OS eo to oo &lt; «— i : t C == ra to 00 * o * ■«* i i ~ &amp; J I </seg>
            <seg id="p053">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 53 t Slfl 5«s£o u Ijiji I: SO 00 t-; IO CO ~- TJ M t&gt; 00 O» 00 TO iH l? Z Sn „ eo oo ■♦ io oj w" *- SS . -h „ cm • CO eg •H 00 iH ♦ O&gt; IO co od 1-4 * T» 00 CO t- « CA -■S '2»i &gt;-!ooo«o«e&gt;i a £ 1 I 2 -- -- co « ?ic£ - &lt;e« •g eooo ot- in i-i Us E- &lt;-l * M i-c ec -h 35 O5 1-1 I— &lt; oi co CO i-l » I I I ; ! | i i i= H k C — . M ifii 1 = 111 feo ■» » ih V t* Ol C3 iff 13 o X to T 00 IQ oc~ I IO ■** 00 O5 &lt;N * m u: 1 1 4 M SS g§§ g2 oo • co .-i 5 rt * T to o n co •S_ t- ■» i o «S O • IO i-i T CO X 1-H x S sr e X IO CO oo -&lt;r IO i-i t- • « e tji &lt;e o I l- + 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT »*i*&gt;a g 8 x x 7. ■* ♦M9I» |*« as t- ttta •nit -IOST1 -T92I* U |S III -torn « im N 00 X X IJ -101 nor •m 00«f x L- •M wmr\ -ocit s *• c &gt;■ ~a S "n 00 DO SsS TJ &gt;» - : ' - JC Tl N O C4 x 71 p m p a « 0y C4 CO CM C4 M •MI O&gt; 1O u u g B K H 5 H B K H 01-9 N N N .„ , T o «o m "A oo t- « S-g « t» «« X «C O ■" A z 3 2 2 I M iM t-l ■"Alt- os i-h I - — — — — — ■"^a ■«■ o&gt; w o N eo « » •3 I ""*§ S 5 I i§ '"A o » L g eo t- en « « o ai o ■sji 00 O CM , e&gt;5 Tf oo 'cm n a »^M &lt;-l (N CM 1 I O » Z - SI S g S •«tM -h § S H-II •* os i.- «(M *» ■♦ » I 1 I m»i-oi t- 00 j-J s&gt;(Al S S 2 si | aa T3 8 g S _. .9j£ "A t-S PK M H ! — "A eg uj ui j-I "5 «c eo ■"A ~ -— _ W OS CO OS CO &gt;e os eo ft cm eo CM CM CM </seg>
            <seg id="p055">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 55 THE HIGHER INSTITUTIONS OF LEARNING It is one of the glories of every state in the American Republic that rom the very beginning provision has been made for the education of all the children of all the people. The two years since the last Report of the State Department of Public Instruction have been marked by a steady growth in influence and in added efficiency of all the educational institutions of the state. This develop- nt has not been confined to the schools of elementary grade and the high school, but is seen, also, in the Higher Institutions of Learning. It is a greed by the people that the schools of the state shall provide the kindergarten in a worthy form and equipment as of means and economy to the added end that the children epared for the grades and the grades in turn, for the life and pie of the high school. It is understood, also, by all the people that r the high school there is an open door to the normal schools, to the and to the state university and, also, to the other institutions of learning as each individual boy or girl and family may elect. During the period covered by this report two tendencies have been ecifically marked: (1) A very large increase in the number of persons ed in the institutions of higher education; and (2) the who hav wider scope of subjects granted to all students from the high schools in the selection of courses of study and especially in those subjects which jncrete things, to practical life, so called, to vocational training industrial arts and their everyday application to the affairs and fe. These higher institutions furnish the opportunity to ties of ail shades and kinds and enable young men and women rtain capacities, desires and purposes to make the most of id years. Because of the opportunities furnished, the inspir - and the character formed by the life and teaching of the gher schools of education, the life and well being of every community the state is enriched and thus every home is not only made a debtor but also made wiser and betteT than it would otherwise be. There is a real and most significant lesson in the fact that as a rule the wer in life and work does not push itself up and lift the higher out of its way. But the higher reaches down and lays hold of the lower and pulls it up toward itself. This fact is seen wherever there is a good high school in that the primary and all the other grades are in - fluenced and within certain limits their actions are controlled by the thought and conduct of the high school. Because this principle is true and active in all social affairs and in all intellectual organizations every rural school, every community of men and women, every town and village, and every high school are influenced directly and indirectly and are moulded into this and that form by the life and thought, by the action and scholarship, and by the purposes and </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT character of the teachers who stand behind the desk. And these teach - ers, in turn, have been made what they are in spirit and vision by the normal schools ,the colleges and the university. Thus the life and purposes, the motives and ideals, the virtues and personality of the higher institutions of education are carried to the farms, the shops, the centers of trade, the factories of all kinds, the schoolrooms and homes of all the people. Thus all parts of the state are enriched and influenced for good by the institutions of higher education and of itself that justi - fies their support by the people as a whole. We hear it said sometimes, that all higher institutions, and espec - ially normal schools, are local in their life and influence. Within cer tain limits this is true. But fortunately it is not necessary to live within the shadow of an institution to be partaker of its benefits. There may be in Nebraska, at this very hour, some girl in the seventh or eighth grade many miles from a normal school, from a col - lege and from the State University who may be so inspired by the life and ideate, by the vision and purposes, and by the personality and scholarship of the teacher that twenty years from now she may stand in the same relation to the community and state, because of some much needed undertaking that Mary Lyon did when she resolved to found and to equip an institution which would give to girls th? same oppor - tunities for study, culture and scholarship that the boys were offered by the colleges which opened their doors to them. In such cases the meaning and fruitfulness of worthy institutions are carried by devoted and intelligent teachers. This, in part, is the meaning and significance of the life and presence of the higher institutions and of education. In all such cases and in the country at large there are many, the honor belongs to the home, the girl with purpose and ambition, the school, the teacher and the institutions of higher education which make such a combination and such an outcome possible. For these worthy ends and for the people, pupils and teachers of all grades and kinds, the state maintains the normal schools and the State University and the people as individuals and in groups and societies build and sustain col - leges and universities. The Normal School The last legislature (1921) authorized the addition of two years to the different courses of study offered by the four normal schools. The State Normal School Board acting in harmony with the powers vested in it authorized the addition and designated the schools 'Teachers' Col - leges.' In harmony with the intent and spirit of the act of the legis - lature, courses of study have been prepared coveiintr the junior and senior years and a good beginning has been made to cause the schools to become in fact, as well as in name, Teachers' Colleges. The people of the state have a just pride in the four normal schools whose aims and purposes are to prepare a body of teachers for the schools of the </seg>
            <seg id="p057">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 57 commonwealth. This "just pride" does not mean that there are no other ideals for which to strive; no more ambitions to be gratified; no other practical ends to be sought; and no more real problems in equip - ment, organization and management to be solved. On the other hand it does mean that in the face of many difficulties the results in the past and the success in the present are such as to give full assurance for the future. A day spent in any one of the four will convince any citizen of the state, who has an open mind, that a steadfast purpose is the rule of life and action; that the desire is to render a good account of stewardship; that there is an everyday effort to perform a genuine service for all parts of the state and to all grades and kinds of teachers and schools through those who go from her halls; that the work and training, the methods and teaching service as models for tho body of the teachers of the state; and that the money spent for grounds and buildings, for equipment of various kinds, for libraries and laboratories and for the teaching staff yield a large rate of interest in earnest and intelligent teaching and in honest and conscientious man- agement The State University The State University in its life and work and its varied fields of activity touches all parts of the state and renders a specific serv - ice to all classes of the people. Often people think of the Univer- sity as an institution for a few people who desire to do some advanced work in Latin, Greek, Mathematics, Literature, History and now and again for a few others who desire to go in some other direction. While these subjects and such as there are provided and encouraged, of course, they do not cover the one thousandth part of the activities and points of contact with the life and development of the people of the common - wealth, we call Nebraska. The home, the schools, the citizenship, the trades, the commerce, the laws and courts, medicine and medical science and practice, the farms and shops, the banks and banking, railways and waterways, grazing and dairying, dentistry and pharmacy, com and stock clubs, and many, many other subjects and activities are taken from the class and lecture room and from the fields of investigation and experiment to every community in the state for the information, prog - ress and advancement of the people. This activity does not stop with material things and with physical well-being but is carried to art and culture and to other things which make for taste, beauty, and moral excellence. When the University, the Agricultural College and the Experiment Stations are taken together, the state has an asset and an agency which cannot be prized too highly. They are to be supported and every good work performed by each encouraged, not simply because of that which each accomplishes by itself but also because of the in - fluence they exert on the school system and upon the life, progress and character of the people and state. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Colleges and Universities From the very beginning of Nebraska history the people, as a whole, have been interested in the higher education of the young men and women of the state as well as in the instruction of the children. To this end colleges and universities have been organized and main - tairid by individuals and different religious bodies. During the period 1919-1920 and during the years 1921 and 1922 the ten colleges and uni - versities, (Central College, Central City; Cotner College, Bethany; Doane College. Crete; Grand Island College, Grand Island; Hastings College, Hastings; Midland College, Fremont; Omaha University, Oma - ha; Union College, College View; Wesleyan University, University Place; and York College, York) have had marked success in the growth of the student body and in the character of the work. All of them have been active in gathering endowment funds and in causing their equip - ment and standards to come nearer and nearer to the standards of the older institutions of the states farther east. The same things are true of the two junior colleges in Blair and Wahoo. Both of them are doing a work worthy of the men and women who lead and sustain these en - terprises. The consecrated life, the earnest work, and the growing condition of the ten colleges and universities and of the two junior colleges at the time this Report is made up are but an earnest of that which shall be in the years to come. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 59 VOCATIONAL EDUCATION 1921-1922 hools, Reimbursements and Enrollment AGRICULTURE Day Schools School Reimbursement Enrollment Ashland Aurora Barnes t&lt; $1,000.00 1,000.00 29 23 593.73 14 Broken Bow Clay Center 1,000.00 1,000.00 23 19 1,000.00 Colerid Dix 13 624.99 10 Ea K 1,100.00 1,000.00 :S0 Fairbury Friend . 32 823.95 30 Garden County Geneva 624.99 18 1,000.00 28 Greshar 666.66 14 Holmes vill 989.58 20 Keya Paha Ccu Laurel 1,000.00 1,000.00 875.00 ty 22 17 Logan County Mead" 17 91666 21 Milford Milligan Nehawka 1,000.00 1,000.00 21 21 593.73 6 Perkins County Randolph 1,000.00 1,000.00 19 26 Stapleton 875.00 18 Stromsburg Sunflower . Tecumseh Tekamah 1,018.50 15 643.73 12 1,041.66 1,000.00 33 27 Walthill Waverly York 624.99 14 1,200.00 1,000.00 15 28 Totals I 28,213.17 635 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT TRADES AND INDUSTRIES Evening Classes School Reimbursement Enrollment Omaha I $2,630.76 1320 Havelock 66.00 25 Lincoln _ _... 216.00 55 North Platte 1,496.25 ] 729 Totals $4,409.01 2129 TRADES AND INDUSTRIES Part-Time Trade Extension Classes School Reimbursement Enrollment Omaha $980.69 2045 HOME ECONOMICS Evening Classes Havelock Lincoln . 93.00 20 1,079.00 314 North Platte Scottsbluff ... 1,222.49 929 390.00 161 Omaha Ragan 919.51 38; 50.00 10 Total 3 $3,754.00 1817 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 61 HOME ECONOMICS Day Schools School Reimbursement Enrollment Alvc $525.00 19 Arlington 600.00 26 Ashland I 412.50 17 Auburn I 600.00 19 B «.vard 1 600.00 I 31 Broken Bow I 600.00 I 27 Chadron 375.00 18 David City I 600.00 51 Dix _ I 600.00 10 Eagle __ I 600.00 ' 22 Edgar 600.00 30 Ewing I 600.00 30 Exeter I 600.00 31 Fairfield I 600.00 17 Friend 600.00 19 Garden County I 262.50 24 neva I 600.00 40 Gering 466.66 16 Jltner _ I 600.00 28 Havelock _ 540.00 30 Holmesville 296.43 11 Kearney I 600.00 32 Keya Paha County I 600.00 24 Kimball County 600.00 43 J ewel 600.00 27 433.33 17 Lexington _ 600.00 33 »gan County I 600.00 28 Lyons 400.00 It Madison | 525.00 24 Milford I 600.00 42 Nehawka I 266.66 | 7 Newman Grove | 525.00 30 Oakland I 600.00 42 Ord I 600.00 I 31 Plattsmouth I 321.43 j 19 Ragan I 358.33 8 Randolph I 266.66 9 Rock County I 375.00 22 Scottsbluff 600.00 72 Seward | 525.00 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Enrollment ••&gt; 2t 19 &gt; n S 4 HOME ECONOMICS Day Schools School Reinbursements Stapleton 600.00 600.00 600.00 Strom sbursr Tecumseh Tekamah ... 600.00 University Place Walthill 1,700.00 600.00 Wisner York 425.00 600.00 Totals $26,999.5i PART-TIME GENERAL CONTINUATION SCHOOL Omaha . Lincoln 18.t 1,350.0 Totals XSS VOCATIONAL REHABILITATION 185 Oases, Total Expenditures </seg>
            <seg id="p063">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 63 APPROPRIATIONS EXPENDITURES OF 3 MONTHS APPROPRIATION April 1, 1921 to July 1, 1921 Appropri- Expendi - ation ture Balance Salary of State Superintendent 1,250.00 $ 1550.00 660.00 660.00 Deputy Superintendent Sa Salaries and Wage 4,825.00 4,630.00 195.00 Readers of Examination and Extra Help 1,275.00 1,269.32 5.68 Maintenanc 2,500.00 2,415.84 84.16 Fixed Charges, Aid to Schools 6,250.00 6,250.00 Normal Training 28,090.65 21,349.60 6,741.05 4,500.00 4,500.00 Aid to Weak School Districts $49,350.65 $31,574.76 $17,775.89 EXPENDITURES FROM JULY 1, 1921 to DECEMBER 31, 1922 Appropri- Expendi - ation ture Balance iperintendent I 10,000.00 $ 7,500.00 5,280.00 3,960.00 38,600.00 27,913.59 $ 2,500.00 'eputy Superintendent, cl Wages 1,320.00 10,686.41 K Examination and 2,981.17 Extra Heir 10,200.00 7,218.83 18,000:00 10,542.48 30,000.00 18,050.00 Hi 7,457.52 11,950.00 Fixed Charges, Aid to School Normal Training 224,725.00 104,355.47 75,000.00 39,387.30 120,369.53 35,612.70 Aid to Weak S $411,805.00 $218,927.67 $192377.33 NEBRASKA SCHOOL STATISTICS Financial Statement 1921 TS Amount on hand at beginning of year From County and Township Treasurer.. From Sale of District Bonds From Tuition of Non-resident Pupils From Local Fines and Licenses From all other Sources | 3,387,056.17 18,518,045.58 4,727,058.34 547,260.22 198,764.65 3,793,814.85 Total $31,171,999.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT EXPENDITURES Paid Male Teachers $ 1,844,980.08 Paid Female Teachers _ 12,215,721.34 Building and Sites 2,202,150.04 Repairs 703,762.69 Fuel 939,216.81 Library and Reference Books 70,945.22 Text Books and Supplies 1,005,756.68 Furniture 323,692.67 For all other purposes 5,947,292.64 Amount on hand at close of year 5,918,481.64 Total ..$31,171,999.81 Bonds Issued „....$ 3,096,551.00 Amount Bonds Cancelled - 455,892.00 District Indebtedness: Outstanding Bonds 17381,527.51 Other Indebtedness _ 5,533,183.55 Total Indebtedness $23,414,711.06 Value District Property: School Houses $26,690,667.56 School Sites 5333,485.38 Text Books and Equipment _ „ 2,733,755.98 All other Property 3,130,370.04 Total Value District Property $38,351,278.96 Number of School Districts _ 7,035 Number of School Districts Meeting Compulsory At ( tendance Requirements 6,908 Number of School Houses _ 7,763 Number of Teachers 14,162 Males 1,209 Females 12,953 School Census (5 to 21 inc.) _ 400,358 Number of Children subject to Compulsory Education Law 255,205 Children of Compulsory age meeting requirements of Law 224,977 Total Enrollment 314376 Average Daily Attendance 239,734 Aggregate Number of Days attended by all Pupils 42,311,670 Aggregate Number of Days taught by all Teachers Males _ _ 177,221 Females 2,140,224 Number of Deaf Children. 312 Number of Blind Children 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 65 NEBRASKA SCHOOL STATISTICS Financial Statement 1922 RECEIPTS Amount on hand at beginning of year $ 5,943,144.93 From County and Township Treasurer 23,1974268.61 From Sale of District Bonds _ 2399,093.94 From Tuition of Non-resident Pupils _... 1,009,403.92 &gt;ws,' From Local Fines and Licenses 197,646.77 From all other Sources. _ 2,590,433.56 Total $35336,980.73 EXPENDITURES Paid Mate Teachers '. $2,253,965.59 Paid Female Teachers „ _ _... 13,031,473.83 Building and Sites _ : 3,934,795.67 Repairs „. 631,540.87 Fuel 929,288.61 Library and Reference Books 55,672.72 Text Books and Supplies _ 1,029,209.12 Furniture 304,301.78 For all other purposes 7316,307.01 Amount on hand, at close of year _ 5360,425.53 Tota $35336,980.73 Bonds Issued. $ 4,127,308.22 Amount of Bonds Cancelled - 702,758.64 District Indebtedne: Outstanding Bonds 20,603,271.90 Other Indebtedness 4,326317.81 Total Indebtedness $24,930,089.71 Value District Property: School Houses $41,979,369.32 School Sites 6,025,631.95 Text Books, Maps, Charts, etc 2396,493.74 All other Property 3,114,687.97 Total Value District Property $54,016,082.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Number of School Districts 7,090 Number of School Districts meeting; Compulsory At - tendance Requirements 6397 7,763 Number of School Houses Number of Teachers : Males 1,474 Females 12,666 403,146 256,102 School Census (5 to 21 inc.) Number of Children subject to Compulsory Edu. Law Children of Compulsory School Age ments of the Law meeting require- Total Enrollment Average Daily Attendance Aggregate Number of Days Attended Aggregate Number of Days Taught by by all Pupils. all Teachers: Males Females Number of Deaf Children Number of Blind Children AID TO WEAK DISTRICTS Distribution for 1921 : Number of Counties Sharing Number of School Districts Sharin Amount Distributed Distribution for 1922: Number of Counties Sharing Number of School Districts Sharing Amount Distributed Total Amount Distributed for Biennium (1921-22) Balance on hand Total Appropriation for Biennium (1921-22) </seg>
            <seg id="p067">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 67 i£ n r. Egg ni ■s. H — E *&lt;g /- at — i z H f. s. V- I &gt;O &lt;N 5 8 i :85*»oS.*»SSS 1 nh it-Os't-r-e's'.-i'.-J'o't-^ofeo' 18 ~8 8'8~~:g i i IS i IS ! 188 •"i co^ ©^ : i-h^ : : : c^ :c*l : 5 (O ;5D ;io't-"iO : o6' I i • :« ; a •»" : y-&gt; : S8 : : : ih : ; : ; &gt;o 100 | SioSoioJJioicio^ : 6 -« n Sh oo NnNN»"®««« rt im to t(T «o *"' fH iH eoto Hf»e«iooouMi.N^eoSiow 0OO&gt;NnO!MtC!0t-VNnnI-9OlNXIOie § I 8 o § ; § 8 S 8 8 8 8~8 8 8 88 8 8 § W'H^h H H H H N H H N pj iH H H rt* pj H N liiililljlilriil h : ■ . ■ ■ ■ • :::,;•■•; * : 5 : * : fa *r* *■« : :c : E IlsIi|IjJilf|ll|3!j-J 5oS^&lt;;iao&lt;!;Si«i^o&lt;BSB&lt;.JhKh i qi i • I | 3 : ' 1 1 5 • i 5 I * I ! '• iUUi'MiUiiiiUiU &lt;:&lt;&lt;B!BBBfflBM(a«OyDOOOOUO «i </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT §&gt; C4 CO &gt; i~ to &gt; q ■♦ co t- « §10 : &gt;o : : o. « i : U3 00 I O Ci Q N O j U^ "3&lt;^ O ■ t^ :nHO)AH = 8S : qo : : W : -J 1 I j|| I I : C4 : : 10" m : 04 : : I !"■ ' °* : cTeJ «e oT «o II g§g§g§5SgSS853 ;SS |S5?S ij oc S n » io q t&gt;_ 8 « .^oe^ : t; « h « i-i &gt;a iB**0'-ie&gt;tSi-*co*+ \ ei r* ': d a* cc *- x o s « « a oo'&gt;£ aOo«iao07N«to o^oo m I 5 — — — — — I 1 OOoO^OOOOOOOCOoO O0O0 OOoOOOiCOCSOOOOoO — OOOO H H h h N N N « J « h « «J H „* h ** G$ ** *S I i-itldl-iJiiilliiii-sii- QoJQp &lt; homciii.MMecgiMSoo&lt;;&lt; B ! I ! j j ! \i jl I j MJ II il I ! i ii \\i il il 1 \ \ir It ttii lit I ill • </seg>
            <seg id="p069">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 69 1 I ■2 I* : is o o o : © in © t- o : t- :o : o : : : c- © © © :o«mno :o :e&gt;J S : : I'l'O.CiO, to^io^c^u^M :o :« :S : m h sJ b" lei'-ToT'*' i e&gt; :«T ioT •-* ec *-&lt; : *-h : m z = I | li J : i ! i i I i j ; §: O o : o o o o o : -^ : o : o Q o : o o o Q O :io : o ; o „ : oo :iaooooo :C4 : n : S :O oo o"oo«h ■ V Ih ; oo :»h: is : *p t- *)i iO'' o s S _L : : ; : : : : I i i i§5 ;gS§gg | ;S?2^ ITS ;S§2 6 a : C-rt h h (D ■. oi t&gt; l&gt; : to 6 :t--^o » » S2'°'-' M :"5rtO&gt; :oi-c :eo"o : &gt;h t- Nt-ns'r.' : » oo" •* ■ oo-t-'efloB r. 1. _J |__ : : : : ' t- * »g ■* • 2" ea « io» io« io jj oionioo ~^~m~ n« voo * n eot-oo»-i m sd^-S a - 1 h T. il 3d l_ "' s i ffi § § i^ "§ f § f r"7iTi"i"f Q 2 q Q t- B o&gt; t&gt; s » S &gt;fi rt . S rt Q Q 9 Q t- " t- x 3 i S | iiuilljilliliiiiiill ■r. | I j J \i \\i I jljJ : i^lpi I*i2 «1 1! 1 i ! •5« g W o „ 1 1 1 1 1 S | g d g &lt; &lt; » si | U jij M Ii ! N M ! !g j : ; T </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT i 3 &lt;£ §: 2 S3 • • ♦* o 91 o : m © o o o :&gt;oo o • S! 22 ; 81 " : r- O O O lO ; ggo . O i :o« : :nON x © © 8» t- : oo «i ■ 5 N ; ■&gt;» i-i : o « oo n o* ■*" -w* -*r : t£ : ei | m 1 _l [ j_j ; ; |_ ■ O '■ O CJ O • ■ O O O 1 ' O O ' ' ' &lt;*** :co : : 5 n o : :ooo a o : :o ' : c^ c »" I - : O o N :^»O: :S ■ ■* is : as : t- 05 ■ ■ • '■ ~* : ea « : — i i = i Ma Ill V I j ; ; i_j ; ; ; ; ■ ■: 8-wgjec .ooooooo :«ooio-*oop :o &gt;-; oq oq : o&gt; o o io o o : oc us « t&gt; o o o ; 2 «•»»■* :»fll«ON8 : S t- 3 &lt;N £ to §5 CO - ? 1! I : c-xi-iioiNTTacifit--w-*o&gt;ae i i3Coc&lt;CT'«c&gt;i *^ i»H i—t ft © in c i- :u*; l- h m x w o oj~c*r "— "-•" -" &gt;h — ~i ri — — J - i I "lf8 S a S S f| S S _ S S 1 § 8 S § S S a « 1 (-_ « i&gt; t- ; i- i- - C a i&gt; n t S s k i- _ « N _, _ — _ T !N HHMNH H 'riMM I I I i &gt;&gt; : i # J : 6 &amp; i iio N 2 ■&amp;: J '.i. _UHiIiliiilllliil 111 i i T~b i ! i I i i ! | ; j : ; i i i i r iij|iil:| 1 iiJiji! !l{ll:-" 5 l!i-J 5 mU m j ji 1 1 1 ill ! 1 1 j mi n iiilliiiiHiiiiillli! </seg>
            <seg id="p071">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 71 O 00 O -&lt; N 15 ■x. c 00 rj et f. »t-3»&lt;o-"Oiio -J 8 UHSiCXtX OS &lt;M N 00 X -^ 0C 01 M H 1- •M I- 05 •M ■/. z z'. /: a &gt; x s X ii m Z S, 1 EJS-S &amp;| S^ 3= S £ j: x </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 72 o o o O O O : O •» O O O O O O O O 00 O O O O O C , O 04 00 O 00 O M O O «5 O Q CO « O O IO C =' C —n^ ©»h»h iiopiomoo-^oo—iuotDot-oo* i c;c o^«o icot-^io^ec^t-ei^t-io^^w^oo^^Niop^cc '1 ; i^tlllll 111111 ! ill 'O : :OOOOOkOO :00000 : *. Q o : :OOOOOAO OOTfOO : O ■3'S S. :t ~^.°. c l'^. c i '^. l^. e i®. "^ :e i :o i n o &gt;h* us &lt;o m :ooo"*©"o i !t- ! • • | o t- ej ei •-« : * a&gt; m ■. — I IN ! I I ; ; ; i : I I ' § isionoicge^nne : o ■» r* o &gt;- C CO O i-t : ®FHl*t-clN(CtOQ0lfi O) X Ifl 1^ K "-.c "^0^ : :iO»®O5e0iO_00_00_Oiej : »2un lot- ?3!^ ooo i i t-io"t-^»i""'^'iOoo'eoor « t m us « *' I 1 1 ; : j fc ; ! i ; : : . _ on« : n t- N eT»" &lt;i -&lt; o V o t- t- to io~c . JS* — — — 1 _^ | §&gt;. iooo_ — ooooSoSSooooooSc I j; &amp; © Q Q 0» t-_ t~_ ic N $ o&gt; — -h^ w t- t-_ * o 5 ■"»•_ pT « -&lt;■ « i-T t-T co* "" —* n eJ « "" — e» eJ : : ■ ■ ■ . : : ■ * ttiliiiiiiiilliliil r. 8 c I ■s. &gt;• \ t&gt; .:.'■:'..:■ : . : «:::::: &gt;- ■Sob hi : b k c !tt| E lii i -tJ ill J* • lllii Is* I « MjNI! |i! ! I j.j j I I | j i i 1 i &gt;1 ! i I i i i I 1-2 s» • ysjH j fe i &amp;1 ' its &lt;&lt;^nnnoaniiinnuououuuuu </seg>
            <seg id="p073">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 73 3". r. x 7. H &lt; 4 35 •/: '. H S5 H on - x: u 6 88 8 §§S§S§S8«S8§ 1 8SS - o to is ■ooiaopo-fl'ooo'ioiao : o io © = ,e 5 00 00 : o .*.« H . H .». t " ». lO . t ". ll)t '. :Hiist- i«&lt;S *h t- : »i- » « &lt;o« •&amp; cc ~i n I : oo" »" b-" gcj* »h : 3 — : i-i &lt; i : 5 I | I I i . LJ 88S§S8Sj717iqgSg8 ! it \ \ j Q &lt;^ ; \£^ ; • ; ; ■j * S o_ o_ o _e^ o^ t-_^ : o^ o^ e^ o^ o^ io_ ac^ | : 8 ': i i 3c o" ia o* ci m o e* : g" o » us" ia io" h ! !oT : i i -— t-i 03 : i : : : ; i I i j | ; ; ; £§S ;8S§§SSSJ|g ;SS8SS3S **.C O IO t- :lO i C» i COt-- 1 '-^N,C^e»^Ci5 : IO 5 00 C7 00 ifl 00 yXS eg* -r" „* qscS&amp;oi'Ct^m'ogi : * m co'iot^e* Jj,-| B :h«S M (N!Sl 3 «« S | vnV. "esooiooHaigvaiOMegiiecon fcB 4^a«X4t-NOOO«X3INHHHniot&gt;S iOiaooo50»eoo&gt;iOMt- o&gt;"oo siOHMnioM o»~t^~ H i t " i"8"iT|~i"i"iT8 §8§§§8 o 8sfi" i ii jj ii j i ! \i 1 1 i 1 1 jj i II Ii I II II I IlilJIlJ j *■!■:! J^lS.ifi.siflS*! 1 * 1 ill|l||l!^l]ll^lltl ! M I I I ! I ! I I I | I I I I i i i i </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT I i I ; 8 § § §§§2§gg§5S8 15 _ .. u 8§§§§i?§!S§s§siis eg ; c n ic h « a 10 t-_ e q ej h ffl e e\ ■I o«m « h : » m a" 8i ef 10 « « « 10 &gt;-•: o * ti~T 888?8»?88 8 8 8SS | : • ; 8 =si = oo©«o5o£'oc &lt; -s , ; : o SoooiaooccK, ooi-;S&gt; •S o" a * 1-" 15 O N ••' "C » h N 18 C " tii,!f?S888~ i^&amp;S i88 SSS &lt;= * c JS « w w h w « -** fc o -h i* . « »o «o 1 . i_ : __j : S il &lt; Q a. x | -| p} «* pj -T 3 —* — * — " — " n'mm'M " — — -S x qj : i. &gt; 5 Mliliiilliiliiililll 1 1 : ; i j y g . | b ?g- ■ 2^s ill! -j J« c x i "I — : — i — : — '■ • : : : '■ ! \ '• I ! I • '• : i T i iliiiiitiiijliiiiliii c u </seg>
            <seg id="p075">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 75 S §SSSS : S2 :S * 5 S 5 s ■f. ■r. H /- /■ H H r. *■ ' «cooo» -Sic io n © ■ m i 1 o a &lt;c a :csio : u5 NMMXU O N «" B : t^ us" \ CO g J If ■ *^ »^ CO : I 11 " §S 5 S3 i S § "ITi"^~flTi"s"2TTf = o .N« : O O| io O &amp; -. :nR6NC°S : !* 50 2S S *~ w °c oc eo oT of :n'«NK«Vt-' : uf | i £ I §' S'S S S S B S 8 S 8 3 S 2 S~5"S"3^ — 13 5l 2« t ~"' l&gt;X n i00CCSC000CO 5l^ WCI is iiS||ISSSSS8SSS§SSSS~§ ( , os_ „ c- „ f-.« * t-.i&gt; in a oc « ". J ti 5 5 g \ 5 l si M M N j i i ] ] i i I I 1 i][hlr!i|fiilii!!!|{ c 3 do liiiliil I !!illiiii!liiiiilllil </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ■j. ■i. c ■o c I 1 5 II I =1 i OQOQo :O : O ■» « p OJ O p : O : O « C£) &lt;^ CO t^\ ■ Q^a wo^oS . o o in CO US A io :X ■*-&lt; t™ g •* « • : »" : « g §§ i : g g I" ~B 2§ Sg8 8 «- * 5 - &lt;H S - ro - 2 M « © t- »-^ J! ill I* — rt t* a t- ■* io c o 2 n fi -r =&gt; «&gt; — » — _ n © c" x" — " 3» "5 O I 7. 1 lj -- 1 - - - — _ — e l: i t i- 3 » 1 -r~ 1 II- _ o i :i i- o m ei ce' •» I ! : 3 IS 1 J — — = = 0OO(M© "• - X r- 9 i- t- 1- C_ ! &lt; Hi I j i i i S3 h A. O (C ? k MJ^_1 | I ] be jr S c c j= = .* . =3 | g £ £ a »-"2 I Ill^S^lij J </seg>
            <seg id="p077">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 77 DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS — 1921 Ol'NTY Outttandim Other Total Bon.i,. Indebtedness Indebtedness Adam :«4 ,000.00i$ 16,445.031$ 350,445.03 Antelope Arthur 55,880.00 25,811.14 81,691.14 30, 198.60 6,%0.00 2,469.00 23.248.60J Banner Blaine Boone 2,622.50 5,091.50 43,743.93 17,395.72 18,665.42 74,464.07 61,139.66 112,352.05 132364.07 154,414.05 166,437.31 365,855.33 104,830.72 102,624.42 294,759.58 141,043.14 93,686.63 Box But Boyd 58,400.00 68,900.00 108,610.00 322,079.40 99,000.001 85,514.05 57^27.31 Brown Buffal 43,775.93 5,830.72 j 20,624.42 72,259.58 82,000.00 222,500.00 80,780.901 as 80,780.90| 60,262.24| 141,043.14 eda ha 36,519.46 17,133.56) 53,653.02 53,450.18 33,241.07 86,691.25 152^50.00 108,610.50 261,460-50 1,000.00 613.46 1,613.46 f 67,000.00 502.04 67,502.04 303,000.00 17,992.42 320,992.42 vr 152,147.83 160,179.78 312,327.61 w Dakota Dawes 69,000.00 33,207.67 102,207.67 295,133.88 20,915.00 316,048.88 Dawso Deuel Dixon Dodge 54,220.00 67,165.05 121,385.05 23,517.50 19,260.70 42,778.20 231.800.00J 59,606.05 291,406.05 168.923.6lj 40,276.11 209,199.72 Douglas Dundy 6,212,200.00 2,026,265.451 8,238,465.45 19,085.00 1U13.63| 30,398.63 Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage 70,300.00| 6,255.25| 76,555.25 92,150.00| 33,960.76| 126,110.76 5,000.00| 46,344.78| 51,344.78 92,500.00| 23,935.40| 116,435.40 422,700.0O| 84,795.67| 507,495.67 57.632.45J 34,404.97 1 92,037.42 Garden Garfield 18,100.0O| 8,729.75| 26,829.75 Gosper Grant Greeley Hall 22,000.00 9,646.14| 31,646.14 41,000.00! 638.66J 41,638.66 136,889.88| 20,148.65| 157,038.53 275,614.40! 48,169.331 323,783.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS— (Continued i COUNTY Outstanding Other Total Indebtedness Indebtedness Hamilton 240,400.00 43,341.71 283,741.71 Harlan I 55,300.00 6,977.25 62,277.25 Hayes I 150.00 10,612.24 10,762.24 Hitchcock 22,681.07 23,690.79 46,371.86 Holt 118,988.52 68,131.75 187,120.27 Hooker 150.00 5,293.31 1 5,443.31 Howard 213,000.00 5,400.16 218,400.16 Jefferson 60,900.00 23,885.26 84,785.26 Johnson 2,500.00 21,428.21 23,928.21 Kearney 21,500.00 6,790.98 28,290.98 Keith 50,966.95 36,965.99 42.94 Keya Paha 11,657.50 20,155.84 Jl ,813.34 Kimball 213,266.97 58,268.02 1,534.99 Knox 53,213.71 53,370.91 106,584.6! Lancaster 1,500,186.13 257,258 1 Lincoln 253,921.62 98,361 41,462 Logan 15,725.00 Loup 820.00 4.819.S "&gt;•&gt;. MM f Madison 476,003.35 McPherson 44 Merrick 72,200.00 11,894.30 84,094.30 Morrill 293,640.00 4 Nance 27,320.00 i2.48 Nemaha 59,000.00 Nuckolls 60,500.00 i,- Otoe 148,000.00 16,686.4 686.41 Pawnee 63,180.00 ,547.1 Perkins 164,555.25 22,117.83 186,673.08 Phelps I 15,522.45 10,028.76 551.21 Pierce 132,798 221,652,89 354,451.67 Platte 194,894.19 14,882.19 209,776.38 Polk 44,500.00 2,822.71 47,322.17 Red Willow 44,675.00 18,321.59 62,996.59 Richardson I 65.00 65.00 Rock I 28,135.00 22,208.27 50,343.27 Saline 86,400.00 153,492.79 67,092.79 Sarpy 35,000.00 20,556.17 55,556.17 Saunders 656,040.00 15,799.55 671,839.55 Scotts Bluff 643,624.00 322,377.78 966,001.78 Seward 94,731.00 14,461.01 109,192.01 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 79 DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS— (Continued) COUNTY Outstanding Other ToUl Bonds Indebtedness lndebtedneu Sheridan 111,265.00 69,178.251 180,443.25 Sherman Sioux Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston Valley 49,170.00 23,968.67 73,138.67 15,060.00 38,243.25 53,303.25 33,514.00 3,552.44 1 37,066.44 18,690.00 18,192.36 36,882.36 500.00 8,818.42 9,318.42 271,349.00 46,442.35 317,791.35 40,300.00 22,142.64 62,442.64 Washington Wayne Webster Wheeler York 18,294.35 14,627.70 32,922.05 47,150.00 5,059.78 52,209.78 99,819.64 244282.49 124,103.23 7,200.00 5,694.37 12,894.37 339,570.00 19,784.67 359,354.67 Total 1 17,881,527.51 $ 5,533,183.55|* 23,414,711.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT III ooooooot^eoo^i t o©^^c-:o«o»oO'^oaiOO»c iSiiidvciSHvSaqa^SeBxSMnoedn^ ON3)XOiffOaMa^Ot-lCHHBlOBftH8JXX H . '. *. w . *. B . ™. ». » H N h « t-_ « ■» •» n 18 5 « 19 t- IS S S S S S ° fc 2 2) n 3 2 ®* "" ™ N " °°" °" M " s" &gt;-" a * °&gt; ' ABMMXHOBO^tfOHOlMV^aKVnHMX *%M ?NMNX»li3t-B--M4BB7«NM'« .t» 8 8 8SS§983S8S^StS2SS|88SS ac to — "h n x x «c3T««o"oin«oc«Tift^o&gt;oc«eM*«s .«» S § 89 § § 8 S 8 g g I fpl 8 S § WWt "«8S£SS£3'&lt;SS&amp;8SS&amp;3SSSiSSS^S$ -1 «5 ■ •» t 1 o, » o_ ■* ic q_ « Z S oo t-_ o S_ S « ti S S — B T M 3 M jl h « a «j o t-_ x is •- « w rj b- a * e{ f »i 10 t- c- S j e s - ■&gt; m h « 10 o « » » f" s t-" » o t-' a ei »' o ei M- J 1 "8 8 § 8 § g § 8"8.~§~ 8 § S g 8 8 8 8. g S 8 8 S § Sl§Sl|S|||S|SSS|gi2SS5S£g l^ (O (- © O M U5 tD O^ t* B W M rt O t* « X tfl 00 Ol 2 K 1"N'h««nu;-»^ ~^-&amp;-*rmxw*~*m &lt;» ill 8 8 § S § g g 5 § 8 § 8 8 § § S S § § S S S S S "5. O B M » O lO 1O « O O 4 X « t- » » fj « n « » X g « us « b h o e » h x" o to x" - n « i- n mi m' ■» h « «» 8 itlljiiill^j^ijfliliilll </seg>
            <seg id="p081">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 81 / Z © © © N © X —. © © &gt;." &gt;-&lt; © O ©. © ©. 0C O 5O O, 00 O. O; o'iOrti-'»'"i--N''''"^&lt;orid'&gt;n«Md2 10 ' c S!£$ S © © t- m_ =- v -r ■» ■» » o n a « n x_ n © ei «o in ia_ to ©_ t-" ic io io n x" « ji t-" t-" « o" to* m" -" d o C 2 ? S S 5 xi' - eMcsi'»Ticoi-xhx»noM«t-no&lt; — or? — -r^j'— x©^^ 74 31 ifl v h n — ' 7-1 — ? 5 § g sa s g 8 8 I © 5 © § 8 8 8 8 8 8 © © 8 S 8 MONK; t~t-Mio—iCiNt~X'-tv3iMPJ«©^;'*N 2 o -5 S x 5 o t- t- » f; o co i; a o i n » oc &lt;j I 51 e n * V « n — " sT ©* ©" i-" is" sf ef ef k h n t- " oo n ic g § 8 S 8 8 § 8 8 "8 8 8 8 8 8 S 8 § 8 8 S 8 8 8 - c &gt;•: 'i r: l' d -«' c t^ is oi n d i- &lt;» y t- ic o o o "• « ,c «i t si r. s x * n &lt;» o n o e - « o n e o n n q M ■m* c^j — ri :*: x* x* i-" a o f" m rf x" ~ " ei w — &gt; &lt;o d «-" « i5l52SSg8?SSSSS8S£SS£§!5g.£ °" s s 8 •■* a s s" s 4 " "■""2§2a" a 8"t; 5 ~~© o © © ©" © ooooooooooooooooo© ©©So0^2©©0©©©00©© ©©©©©© # ©i-&lt; ."irinooNodL-'i'dNdctDciofflOioirooK °°" 3 3 £ " 8 2 °° g £ "=* "" "^ "' S 5 P. 2 ~ °° S §5 J ! x I _ 8 8 S $ § 8 g 8 8 S 8. 8 8 8888888S8 8g oo •* V a k" oo h 10 io [-" [-" n" t- o ii is t- oo ic g » i 1 » COXX rt H N (C N I* rt rHCC CCej x" J_ infsliifsiiiiiiiiiisjil </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ;«liiill?i!§5iiiiclit«igs 1 I w i m 1 E I ~7~|Ti i m^ i ITpl sTiTs s § s $ g g I^.S S * * '•3 a S "• -* £ - * v •• • o* 3 ? «o -" «- *5 3 , S § § £ § s 3 5 g g ii§i£g§§if:ig§ = U immmmmimmi §§§§35§ = g§53§5§g§g = §g = = = I ° j 5 3 5 5 5 s "- - * " * t t * s s| s I s i I iflTfffH^ s * g 88888 S § g i g i ? !! I I I ! i i ! ! I ! : ! ! ! : ! : I l p ? lliiiiiiiiilliiililliiii </seg>
            <seg id="p083">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 83 6t £ o x«qc»qqq©©oS55&lt;s©S s o r: e o o oo t-" o" k x a t- o x ciMx'-rccw— —i eg w — ec -h eg &gt; z X si ju s : ;iiJH&lt;ilEa|IIUlU]« s 1 2 S S 2 I S 5 p. || q g 5 8 § g § 5 § I J 3&gt; t&gt; « •*• « eg x r- cc r- ■■ f \ •£. ■ ;•« SS5|S8ggig§2§SS. 2SSSSeS [II S^8.RS.gS2ggSSSSS?i§i|§ \l\ g 1 s a S s g 8 8 S S ? 8 S § § S 5 S S 5 — c n 8 8 8. % 8 "8. 8 8 8 88 8 8. 8 8 S 8 S 8 %% = |5 2Si^2g&amp;a2SS3g = 52iS32S % O a. o^'t-Mi-KS^ •» k t." a - t." d si is I-" m t." &gt;&lt;o. — [ . S 8 8 8 8 8 § 8 S 8&amp;888.888SgS8 - S :t. a . ". « * H x . '■" o n •■ H H o ° » "o » S t! ■■- x s •• i § q § § i S i ; § 5 § S § § § 8 ; 1 ? » ■2 S? "* S ~ ~ 2 w L "" ■"" e " -" °" N " •» e&gt; » -" o" m o» &gt;$ - I. -g gii§p g g 8 g § g I" s i II gaf f-. O °° &lt;N - ■» - "v * "5 - O CO t- § « Sc O S §? I § S w S S S 8 g 2 8 * 5 S « S S •? s 5 - S X W IQ X &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p084">REPORT OF STATfc. SUPERINTENDENT 84 DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS— 1922 COUNTY Ollt-T..| lllti Other ToUl Ron ;i.l.-l.l«lne- ln.M.L.it Adams $ 292,000.001$ 12,243.0ji$ 304,243.0'J Antelope 159,214.20 32,514.4c* 191/i 28.6s Arthur 8,192.70 18,068.38 26,261.08 Banner '. 1,(H)0.00 4,190.64 5,190.64 Blaine 43,673.58 23,509.76 67,183.34 Boone 77,595.00 18,369.12 » .,964.12 Box Butte 255,400.00 72,179.14 527,579.14 Boyd 79,100.00 72,862.70 151,962.70 Brown 108,500.00 67,918.48 176,418.48 Buffalo 408,479.06 62,677.58 471,156.64 Burt 86,000.00 16,901.30 102,9000 Butler 79,000.00 27,725.71 106,725.71 Cass 220 ; 000.00 16,656.47 2~&gt;6.656 Cedar 49,377.82 40,952.75j 90,330 Chase I 30,200.00 25,753.36 Cherry 143,171.57 .2,787 i Cheyenne 241,700.00 70,774.5 -i Clay 3,000.00 533.94 Colfax :&gt;7,500.00 1,464 Cuming 294,500.00 r&gt;,202.16| 299,702.16 Custer 161,525.00 48,294 Dakota 88,000.00 Dawes I 308,308.88 ,616 Dawson 78,848.00 24,454.66 Deuel I 24,609.50 12,907 Dixon 230,600.00 •J7.565 lft Dodge 486,700.00 {0,341 517,041 Douglas 6,195,702.27 1,017,782.52 7,213,484.71 Dundy 18,610.00 5,418.50 24,028.50 Fillmore 51,100.00 13,159.95 64,259.9 Franklin 96,038.961 32,201.25 128,240.21 148,834.49 110,619.26 463,216.54 141,992.30 Fronfer 101 200.00 47,634.49 Furnas 70,000.001 40,619.26 Gage 413,600.00 49,616.54 Garden 106,450.00 35,542.30 3,924.00 33,389.24 3,070.75 7,510.43 Garfield 16,750.00 20,674.00 165,137.24 46,570.75 Gosper 131,748.00 Grant 43,500.00; Greeley 22,000.00 29,510.43 344,519.94 Hall 250,280.00 94,239.94 Hamilton 236.600.00 36.912.33 273,512.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 85 Other Total Imlcbtnln. Indebted n«^ Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Holt Hooker Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knox Lancaster Lincoln Logar Loup Madison McPherson Merrick ... Morrill Nance Nemaha Nuckolh 60,000.00 139,000.00 21,841.85 19,274.53 15,909.76 11,749.41 14,210.06 56,473.23 14,373.33 81,841.85 158,274.53 Koe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce 62,520.00 78,429.76 68,344.70 80,094.11 43,400.00 291,100.00 135,234.05 57,610.06 347,573.23 149,607.38 Platte Polk 40,500.00 144,400.00 125.00 40,625.00 160,903.43 103,500.00 Red Willow Richardson Rock 16,503.43 99,000.00 18,025.00 4,500.00 Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sheridan Sherman DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS— 1922— (Continued) 50,200.00 19,975.07 1 70,175.07 11,126.00 11,126.00 18,906.07 30,199.91 49,105.98 104,512.55 65,024.86 169,537.41 217,000.00 15,563.91 232,563.91 43,500.00 10,923.17 54,423.17 1,765.00 22,905.63 24,670.63 20,960.00 1,307.43 22,267.43 165,600.00 19,050.96 184,650.96 13,300.00 24,305.72 37,605.72 264.226.26 65,234.48 329,460.74 141,238.79 51,532.00 192330.79 2.145.000.00J 157,496.63 2,302,496.63 253.926.27 98,579.73 352,506.00 49,250.00 28,044.16 77,294.16 820.00 5,856.00 6,676.00 919,800.00 20,073.80 939,873.80 l,350.00| 11,948.71 13,298.71 79,844.40 5,294.21 85,138.61 325.878.00j 221,447.25| 547,325.25 28,600.00! 29,571.921 58,171.92 1 8,025.00 ; 24,302.42 42,327.42 75.400.00 52,991.57 128,391.57 40.102.27J 13,949.431 54,051.70 646,870.00; 38,515.02! 685,385.02 l,00fe,238.00i 347,431.15| 1,355,669.15 93,931.00' 11,757.27| 105,688.27 106.1O0.O0J 77,302.46| 183,402.46 73.720.001 26,331.421 100,051.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT DISTRICT INDEBTEDNESS— 1922— (Continued) COUNTY Outstanding Other Total Bonds Imlebt«dness lndebtedne*' Sioux - 14,110.00 40,606.23 54,716.23 Stanton 31,000.00 1,500.00 32,500.00 Thayer 18,105.001 13,085.92 31,190.92 Thomas 500.00 7,908.95 8,408.9:. Thurston 234,460.00i 38,184.781 272,644.78 Valley 37,250.001 9,151.01 ! 46,401.01 Washing-ton 22,000.00] 11,630.33! 33,630.33 Wayne 50,800.00 4,544.601 55,344.60 Webster 109,550.00! 12,538.07 122,088.0 Wheeler 9,700.00 9,951.92 19,651.92 York 14,400.00 44,628.50 359,028.50 Total $20,603,271,901$ 4,326,817.81 $24,930,089.7 i </seg>
            <seg id="p087">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 87 ■M X N go H 7. &lt;■ _ q — oa q ■» as q to q i&gt; -w q t-; S to us to q 5 q x q x0035xx«coa)C5Xicioxt-r-i-HqotocoiON?3 s . ■» = n L *. » o_ a -&lt;. x x_ n w t-. h 5 ■» io x " eo * £i £3 £ 2? "8 rt m in c a to a" f' us « cj oi d oo t-" t-" «' — &lt;NC&lt;ix©ici/:ajirttoO'«'xcoc-t- I -&lt;a5e*)i«t&gt;oeaS q 9. q tt q q q q « q q © o q e e&gt;i e&gt; 9 q o S § 9 OiAUtrri^^sioOXOOTfi^iCCO«CO&lt;3JiOt&gt;iCXO S 0^SS 3C - &lt;s «''t-'n H »NHXt-Hoit-S,; . " O 5 ifl ifl H h t» O 81 H !D iC (fl Ifl O X O M » h h b » x « t eJ o" n* o" as* -h" eo i-T pf of of 9 1 eT t»" «* X 9 9 9 9 = 9 9 9 9 ia 9*9 c- 9 s 9 o e 9 CA*tO I 3 q o 5 «! L? o q q f; o o oi o o q q 5 o a h r^ '^ — io 5 x u: 3i. o t-_ « e h n h h co x o^ « ?• S n — "-^^■^■t^cac^r^otoioro'art-'^'c-^oiar^'orc^ *~* "^ *~^ m *~^ *~i ww^xOC^OOOOOOONCOOiCNOOOOO fCC»MHXX*00^01»«iO*01NflHloc : -. ' : w . x . x . fl . X N t-_ h n x M t&gt; h t- in 01 w t- tt r. w « m a « a e 6 «' * x" h t-" o o o »" a ia o~ to" &lt;c x22S22~ OO( =9^®o 000009990 q q q © q q © © us q p ic q © q © q © q o o ic 5 X E t- X fl N „ 1~ f_ M CO * t-_ N fl «_ O 00. "»_ 00_ CO 5C ~ 2 — ic* 2* o» eJ -h* x* oo ■*" «" o" t-^ t^ ej" eJ « c = t- o q q •» q t-; q q n o q o « o 5 5 S o co oo &gt;c£c4q933Oic'o9oa099&lt;-4aic^ooe9f^i-! 5DNCgxc -'5 M000 ociNt-io — svic "I . N . *. 1 °c w ?: tc w oi a x o; us cj h oc us n io l- t- x «o m o; o in ic" eJ x" «o" V co" o o" o x" V •*** 31 to" us : a/ : • : : : : :::•::• iijjjilifjtiiiiiLjfiiii C -S— OCO-.333«3.C.C.C.So33««MeC &lt; &lt;&lt; 1 m I to ffl » « K ffl n n n n nr-irir^r^o^/!? </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 REPORT OP STATE SUPERINTENDENT t- o o m o m o Tf oj oe o io p o « o — is 5 o o o t~ •- ai d n c d 6 6 h tr t t- c -t ic r! &lt;r c c ?i &lt;r si u: d - e e « o_ x, t-_ »i a t-_ « » t-_ oo * jj i-_ « a -_ o — set- «e — 5 a » « « w « mo" V t-" o" e «" x n m' t-" ci e i-" ©* eg" x % 3$ las !I1 'sTtTtTIT 1 1 5 1 1 888.88.8 8. 8888 'ft 1O 18 - lO B R R » I- h It &lt; ic K l-_ X SJ O "««nNC s° ft N tt &lt;c » k t- n « o o" t-' «" t-" - k e* n n" r: ji a cJ c&gt;i -_e .. — to — — — tn n — — ~&gt; £J — . 888PS.88.^8,8,S8S888S8S38.88S ,| 8S25S285!S£SSSgg£SgS§8ggg °x . N .*.*.'.". ( l*» s ' ! '*'»» l "*''*«*«nS;: ju S n to — tc m — cs t- x" ej t* n 3; N V M • -^ t- o* 1-* o I = I I §§§E:§§§Ss-£5§§g£§£g§§g§i ,| *. «. ». - *. " '-. s. «. e s k x i e » » t n t- 2 ? ;-. H • » £ g " g £ 2 g * * "" £ *&gt;" &gt;•-" g • g * - » * o -" "'§"§ 8 § 8 8 8 8 8 8 8 S 8 8 s 8 § § § 5 g S 8 £ ii °° « § g " S 2 2 §3 g "=" "* !f « •" s s £ ; » 5 g g • - n I S 8 8 8 8 § § § § g § g g g § g g § § § g = g - Si * "i •". « °. * o o » a t&gt;_ « f_ q i-_ » ic c i-c n n oc t =&gt;■£ 3 S? 2 2 o" 3 2 2 "" S f" M "' !.■: o cV o « f" -i oo t-' n -' ■.S3, i-«N H »e»-e»ie«&lt;t-Si:«&lt;fB-OM?ic o" I &gt; ::::■::: Z ! I I : ! i i ■ O I ! I I ! I 1 i I y M M : ; i M M ! ; IsIllc££igISj|||jSJ£iiilS </seg>
            <seg id="p089">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 89 3". r. O 4 0C © IM O t~ N 4 C ■t. 1 1 X vl ?■! ?C T OC 4 oo ai i- n t V. I J T uC M -" « O ■M X " N t- n N T, tC K 31 &lt;D M X X. I •1 00 M X X 00 3 I j a n n » x X 1 - X X T ■X 5 JC l — • w 5 Ifl t- 00 t &lt; C N •»! . i 1 S4 L r "Q I o ei K -t cJ us i-" « oJ 1 M ■1 N « J •-&gt; * (M 0C I-KN M 4 X C^J T (M W A I X t J IN 1 r. 00 iMr.K X 5 t- is i t N » t^OCOittt^Ot-t JTt-OSOCOllOlOPl t t-^MXinnfoot-t X X CD t~ X t X xx^t*-~*oot-sox O O O &lt;N &gt;) -h n eo m N COUNTY UB/JO' 1111 Ob sooooeeu: - d 6 i" m o «i « 5 «0 O_ t", * N T_ U5_ S M l" -' f' * O \2 i j u i I ! ' § : ; i ■ jiMiii Jlijiiiillllllliiillfll? </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT «■ I » - 5 ■« °. ■» 9. « « « o N x t- e * s x Ji ™ « ™ © i -2 — a 2 &lt;£ «o 5 x m &lt;c x ii^ « cc o* tc" — T e&gt;j *£ uf c^ to" " ~ 2 tSM2SlS88$SSS8S8Sg8S | si » m. •» x. ■ S »MNNaeBt.!oaS.jJ°» » -_g — -* — * M i - - — ?1 M 2 -&gt;| Z | E I J 3-. T I I «, , S§8§§§S§£S§S88'gSgSS8g - = 5 n "1 1 "1 N . =H. • - «l t-.*saK.x»sic^io S = a a *~ § " « ® S ?o i- * v "* a N "• °» * N ' *■"" =» -" «"* *• •» B © © N. tt x o -. o x 5 5 5 5 x 5 x S ic 5 8 S »i s m.t-.io f"- « ' = x t- e e ? i? ? ;; J m ; a » n is b n n « ~ i&gt; x -i m' i- s f" k s - x' bo 3 4 X ~- CC :T CJ " — — « •—«?&gt;].— _ ~» i S L i i s i « § = i i g | § § § g x i § § = = i», Siiilli3iis|iis5iiiij &gt; s [ t S S S t M 58*88Sgg828g88g * § I 1 1 3 1 3 x . n °. n n "= &lt;= x « = - « r. S S 3*5 t ; J 5 J 2 x * ff '" s • "' s *' x s » e i 1st I -_- i I - ::::!!;;;;;:; : : : &gt; i : : : i i i i i i ! 2 I ! I i i I I i '■■ i i ! i ! ! i Sliiil liliiiJliJilii I </seg>
            <seg id="p091">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 91 DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1921 OUNTY Number of Number of District* School Houses Adams. I 76 I 88 4ntek&gt;p* 107 113 Arthur 25 31 Banner 27 26 Blaine 30 30 Boone 86 89 Box Butte 57 eo Boyd I 75 76 Brown 65 71 Buffal - 118 133 Burt 73 72 Butler _ _ _ 93 95 ass 82 97 Cedar 109 116 hast - &lt;S1 I 61 herry - 165 181 heyenne _ 67 75 80 91 fax 61 64 ummfj _ gO 82 "ster 246 252 Dakota 39 40 Dawes 83 86 Dawson 95 116 Ueuel — 30 31 Deut Dixon _ _ 79 gj Dodge 84 93 Dodge 84 93 Douglas 58 150 Douglas 58 150 Dundy 62 62 Fillmore _ _ 91 94 Franklin _ 74 77 - 74 I 77 Frontier _ 105 104 Furnas 100 103 Case 138 I 145 Garden 59 54 Garfield 38 I 38 Gosper _ 62 62 Grant _ _ j 9 I 18 Greeley | 63 71 Hall _ 70 I 87 Hamilton _ I 91 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1921— (Continued) COUNTY Number of Number Districts Seboo Hmh Harlan I 72 74 Hayes I 50 48 Hitchcock 79 79 Holt 203 203 Hooker 4 41 Howard 78 Jefferson 100 102 Johnson 76 67 Kearney Keith I 48 64 Keya Paha t&gt;( Kimball 40 -^ Knox 146 168 Lancaster - 130 U Lincoln 131 14 Logan ■&gt;•&gt; Loup Madison McPherson Merrick Morrill Nance Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte Polk \ 70 Red Willow Richardson 97 111 Rock 63 6i Saline 112 121 Sarpy 36 45 Saunders 110 117 Scotts Bluff 45 73 Seward I 89 98 Sheridan 108 111 Sherman I 73 79 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 93 DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1921— (Continued) Number of I Number COUNTY of Districts School Houses 79 74 MOUX 57 58 SUn ton Thayer Thomas Thurston Valley I 95 97 U 22 34 45 73 76 Washington Wayne 58 60 84 85 Kl Webster Wheeler York 70 39 42 94 105 | 7,035 | 7,763 Tota </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1922 Number of Number Districts School CXHNTY Hou»«m Adams _ I 77 I 88 Antelope 109 113 Arthur 26 30 Banner I 27 28 Blaine 32 30 Boone 86 89 Box Butte 58 59 Boyd 75 76 Brown 69 SH Buffalo 118 12* Burt 74 Butler 9S K Cass x2 H Cedar 109 lit Chase 61 Cherry 167 8S Cheyenne 86 Clay 80 Colfax rtl t'uminjr go Custer 249 y Dakota Jti 42 Dawes 83 Dawson ;• Deuel :u i Dixon Dodge &gt;4 Douglas &amp; 4 Dundy ti2 Fil'more HI Franklin 74 Frontier ior. 105 Furnas 100 104 Gage 138 15 Garden ..._ I 5 1 x Garfield I 38 39 Gosper 62 62 Grant I 8 15 Greeley 62 86 Hall _ „ 79 90 Hamilton 90 96 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 95 DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1922— (Continued) Number of I Number of • ■orxTV District* School BOOHI Harlan Hayes 72 75 51 49 Hitchcock Holt 73 72 204 206 Hooker Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith 4 41 78 83 99 104 - 76 I 77 67 69 48 64 Keya Paha Kimball 61 60 40 48 4* Knox 149 157 Lancaster Lincoln .. 130 158 - 131 149 Lofrar Loup Madis 23 24 32 32 - 78 88 McPhersor Merrick I 35 34 56 65 Morr Nann 52 72 69 71 Nemaha Nuckolls 72 81 89 93 Otot 100 107 Pawne 72 74 Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte 60 55 74 76 KS n I 81 87 Polk 70 71 Red Willow Richardson Rock 79 86 96 109 63 61 Saline Sarpy 113 121 36 42 Saunders 110 117 Scotts Bluff Seward 46 78 86 92 Sheridan Sherman 109 112 75 79 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT DISTRICTS AND SCHOOL HOUSES— 1922— (Continued) Number of I Number Districts Houses COIN TV School Sioux Tit Stanton Thayer . Thomas . Thurston Valley ... 57 58 ' 111 111 I 11 23 J5 44 19 7:i Washington Wayne 59 60 M s Webster Wheeler York . S2 40 M 40 101 Total 7090 770 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">)F PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 97 SCHOOL TAX, NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID 1921 At Total Wages Earned by all Money Vot- Qualified Teachers for the Year uchers Whether Paid or Unpaid V. Employed ales | Females | Males Females Adams Antelopt Arthur Banner Blaine Boone Box Buttt Boyd Brown Buffalc Burt H las her ming: jstt Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel . Dixon Dodge Douglas Dundy Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage Garden Uarfield Gosper Grant ,i68,664 23| 180|| 37,876.35j$ 185,228.00 248.898J 8| 164j 12.790.00J 160,948.08 j 3| 29| 2,169.75| 20,260.82 21,495, 41 22 2,405.00j 16,107.75 20.020J 4 29 1,450.00 21,083.32 j 11 142 j 15,745.00 133,976.67 125,501 5 106 10,937.06 91,284.32 86,680 121 106 15,880.001 97,138.20 118,199 7 87 8,765.00 1 76,202.94 375,087 24 241 39,645.75 1 243,651.45 233,579 13| 144 23,533.30| 134,408.55 236,970 20 142 29,449.82, 141,388.45 291,349 18 192 32,698.68 182,248.73 251,483 16 159 32,818.83 164,782.13 72,589| 7 68 6,095.00 53,205.21 229.839 23 209 27,782.55 145,935.28 199,388 12 128 20,336.75 113,820.24 261,944 30 149 40,942.56 144,422.84 165,566 9 111 14,570.00| 108,947.49 191,373 11 111 19,869.98 110,021.44 396,335 28 331 35,918.75 295,342.48 75,029 4 74 8,574.93 72,842.75 176,092 5 119 9,309.00 105,242.10 246,340' 13 175 21,461.72 182,972.61 62,606 6 41 8,566.50 35,721.85 204,241 16 136 24,862.50 139,725.00 342,150 15 206 28,425.01 215,134.76 4,011,799 66 1,180 174,143.91 1,969,256.58 77,233 7 82 7,231.00 56,873.25 203,781 16 146 27,990.30 150,585.82 151.840 8 130 13,725.00 120,093.79 12 125 15,655.00 95,253.00 194,902 20 155 26,418.05 130,334.73 531,957 30 279 51,639.38 288,834.05 85,020 8 68 8,235.00 52,689.00 47,542 9 46 7,090.00 33,848.50 68,256 3 66 3,800.00 53,406.28 48,292 8 19 9,629.79| 17,879.00 236,970 291,349 251,483 72,589 229,839 199,388 261,944 165,566 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 98 SCHOOL TAX, NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID 1921— (Continued) Amount of Number of Total Wase. Earned by all COUNTY Money Vot- Qualified Teacher, for the Year ed for l,acher» Whether Paid or Unpaid Part Year Employed i Male. Female. Male. j Female. I | Greeley 112,165 4 98 4,950.00 87,610.05 Hall 357,197 18 219 23,662.50 234,125.80 Hamilton 16 146 19,852.80 141,697.69 Harlan 195,996 10 126 13,680.00] 106,787.13 Hayes 30,625 1 50 120.00 31,669.50 Hitchcock 116,240 5 92 6,744.93 76,731.15 Holt 236,221 18 225 18,946.65 173,391.10 Hooker 21,500 4 39 3,960.00 32,852.00 Howard 155,176 9 108 12,227.50 100,937.86 Jefferson 162,625 24 158 38,177.00 157,880.90 Johnson 143,176 8 111 13,730.00 86,316.89 Kearney 133,646 9 102 13,415.00 93,388.50 Keith 103,905 6 78 6,595.001 68,724.25 Keya Paha 51,392 5 62 3,905.00| 41,795.96 Kimball _ 119,323 7 65 ll,568.40| 65,587.55 Knox 331,914! 16 218 22,006.52| 207,467.01 Lancaster 1,346,559| 621 658| 104,904.81| 841,631.34 Lincoln 367,5721 16 2441 23,258.311 228,2i7.22 Logan 52,7Oo| 5 32 6,226.25 25,807.15 Loup 27,095 2 29 1,950.00 -rl-l:l&gt; Madison 375,834| 18 194 34,400.00 11,332.95 McPherson 22,097 4 30 2,002.50 17,613.8( Merrick 165,133 5 114 9,025.00 121,838.15 Morrill 244,348 10 107 16,788.751 116,908.81 Nance 135,3241 91 106 14,974.00 94,328 Nemaha. 166,732; 13 124 20,524.92 109,598.6 Nuckolls I 238,1671 201 157 24,857.00 134.167 Otoe I 270,6571 17J 176 27,365.00 182284.50 Pawnee 149,0931 12 101 16,157.34 456.2 Perkins 105,069| 9| 69 8,719.30 57,531.74 Phelps I 155,1871 8| 104 16,562.54 100,475.83 Pierce I 178,6551 141 132 19,587.36 117,319.79 Platte 218.162J 11 133 18,551.22 130,838.44 Polk 180,600! HI 1171 19,925.00 112,126.99 Red Willow 923841 14 127 37,189.37 121,861.98 Richardson _.| 262,8491 18| 1571 28,657.00 151,721.00 Rock 52,915| 6 651 1,780.00 43,925.70 Saline 272,7261 191 1921 30,935.78 177,763.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 99 SCHOOL TAX. NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID Amount of Number of Total Wace« Earned by all Money Vot- Qualified Teacher* for the Year Amount OUNT Teacher* for the Year ed for Whether Paid or Unpaid -at: hers Part Year Emoloved Male* |Female*| Male* Female* 1921— (Continued) Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward i i .1 137,031 309,112 386,370 239,046 6 21 26 25 84 192 211 143 I 11,443.00 1 32,294.50 :*9,032.10 35,909.30 j 86,011.48 194,954.03 237,930.74 133,615.87 Sheridan Sherman Sioux Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston Valley Washington Wayne Webster Wheeler York 198306 141,250 70,665 108,021 210,402 38,625 149^25 147,056 211,110 178,991 196,284 31340 297,045 20 s 4 9 18 6 7 12 6 18 4 20 147 106 86 73 148 28 U 115 125 103 135 :59 172 j 19,860.80 9,125.00 3,270.00 9,220.00| 25,214.97 1 3^67.50 12,478.80 10,455.00 18,853.29 9,233.30 16360.00 4,020.00 35,497.92 1 125,144.50 100,824.00 58,370.00 73,715.00 132,373.94 21,750.00 93,373.26 104,700.50 129,092.40 123,045.85 118,625.10 27,517.25 167,288.06 i Total $21,148,325 1,209 12,9531$ 1.956,236.45 $ 13,190,704.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SCHOOL TAX, NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID 1922 ount of ! Number of Total Wages Earned by all Amount Tulal Wages E irned by ; the Year or Unpai Money Vot- ley Vot- Qualified Teachers for the Year Teachers f. COUNTY ed for Past Ye; ■d for I urtmn Whether Paid or Unpaid Whether Paid *t Year Employed Maii-s Females Main Females 1 h ,1 Mali Females M:.l. Femalei Adams $ 375,155 21, 179i$ 375,155 21 ( 179|$ 41,063.44|$ 209,534.11 Antelopt 252,153 18! 173| 23,512.54 167,519.85 252,153 Arthur 21,870, 10, 26 8,461.13 16,456.20 21,870 10 26 27,132 3 25 1,930.00 19,950.00 27,132 Banner Blainc 19,684 7 26 6,242.50 18,333.47 19,684 26 242.50 18 236,058* 17' 137 2C.736.09 136,296.92 Boone 23t;.or&gt;» 137 26,736.09 136,296.92 Box Butte 162,331 7 105 14,525.00, 97,320.80 162,331 105 14,525.00 19,015.00 Boy,! 136,613 17 110 19,015.00 88,795.75 136,613 17 110 Brown 127,016 11 89 12,918.00 8O,6M.O0 127,016 12,918.00 mi/,: Buffalo 433,962 28 241 45,375.86 240,911.81 433,962 28 241 i:&gt;.::7r,.8.-, 240,911 235,140 16 132 21».o.t1.25 128,675.25 Burt 236,140 Butler 241,537 28 134 38,760.00 126,032.1". II Cass 386,467 17 191 36,428.17 Is*. 196.24 {86,467 297,314 18' 162 34,724.96 159,923.40 Cedar 14 89,980 5 70 56.634.4d Chase 89,980 Cherry 250,78:; 23 197 24,091.95 145,951.76 250,7 Cheyenne 251,225 251,225 15 117 23,787.00 117,153.25 Clay 253,056 26 153 40,300.96 152,134.94 253.056 179,484 12 108 21,396.70 105,314.84 Colfax 179,484 Cuming 209.42U 11 105 17,260.00 105,126.2:, 209,421) 385.410 40 325 52,696.95 281,511.90 385,410 Custer in 113,750 5 75 9,022.00 69,405.2". Dakota 113,750 Dawes 192.169 .". 126 9,824.99 1OH,O"&gt;4.:51 192,1611 302,869" 16 176 2."..."&gt;27.46 175,928.01 64,629 6 4"&gt; 7.360.00 38,396.2". Daw son :iO2,869" 16 17* Deuel 329.411 17 134 27.142.50 133,122.00 Dixon Dodge 379.170 17 203 34,792.11 230.527.H1 4,792 Douglas 3,957,090 82 1,23 237,518.60 2.093,983.4( Dundy 98,299 1" :»,510.00 li Fillmore 234,677 20i 141 i2,324.49 137,452.68 Franklin 152,943 101 117 16,880.00 109,415.2 Frontier 172,890 241 121 20,711.12 91,628.9:) 223,308 30,776.81! 140,813.9s Furnas 181 144 Gage 541,091 37 I 272 59,287.78 282,253 Garden ' 108,490 10' 80 11,518.00 63,145.00 Garfield 43,6041 61 46 5^36.25' 35,406.00 10,335.00 86,375.2 r &gt; Gosper ' 141,123 7' 98 Grant I 40,300' 9' 22 10.585.00' 22,164.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p101">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 101 SCHOOL TAX, NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID 1922— (Continued) Amount of Number of Money Vot- Qualified Total Wage* Earned by all Teachers for the Year Whether Paid or Unpaid OUNTY ed for Teachers Past Year Employed u .les ' Females Males Females Gre«ley | 64,540) 4| 64 3,410.00| 52,163.75 Halt 418,482i 24 1 222 41,032.45| 238,643.90 Hamilton | 264,985 23 140 27,612.50j 136,437.20 Harlan 183,639 12 112 19,204.00j 103364.70 Hayes 54,375j 3 50 39,737.00 Hitchcock 120,659 12 86 12,327.00 72,218.75 Holt I 243,906 19 228 20,795.84 175,228.48 Hooker | 28,420 4 44 2,200.00 15,625.00 Howard | 176,815 10 111 15,065.00| 99,805.70 Jefferson 275,828' 26 165 33,872.601 161,955.30 Johnson 152,268 10 109 18,020.00 94,481.95 Kearney 145,922 16 97 19,375.00 88,970.80 Keith 124,027 9 76| 8.522.25J 66,091.50 Keya Paha 58,045 10 59i 6,250.00; 32,694.00 Kimball I 129,014 11 67J 17,787.47| 71,699.42 Knox 280,410. 2 59 1 30,487.36; 182,360.60 Lancaster 1,749,179; 66j 667 126,376.05| 900,308.79 Lincoln 375,088 1 29 242 34,384.32 226,448.32 Lo^an 27,375 6 26 6,045.00 , 22,886.00 Loup 19,764 8 29 8,091.90 20,660.75 Madison 436,212 19 209 34,397.25 214,793.63 McPherson 18362 7 30j 4,961.25 12,835.75 Merrick 204,885 6| 87 13,985.00 123,359.85 Morrill 263,258 10 111 15,582.50 116,985.65 Nance 164,657 9 97 14.315.00j 92,983.55 N'emaha 193,584 18 113| 19,150.00; 103,619.01 N'uekolls 251,216! 27 1481 34,320.00! 136,052.00 Otoe 280,219! 18 172 29,430.00 167,928.00 Pawnee 158,654 221 97 26,221.43; 86,017.25 Perkins 90,7O5i 10 1 58 6,955.00 47,612.34 Phelps 179,044' 10 111 17,807.501 106,113.76 Pierce I 213,853 13 132J 18,966.41| 112380.19 Platte I 233,825 9| 137] 20,869.98! 148,606.38 Polk 179,801 15 107 22,080.00' 110,224.20 Red Willow 221,848 22' 140' 28,300.48 132,561.99 Richardson ' 271,775| 20| 164! 36,301.74! 149,525.47 Rock I 64,890' 12| 55! 7,563.50! 35,208.50 Saline 305,113' 28! 184' 27,012.981 93,497.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SCHOOL TAX, NUMBER OF TEACHERS AND SALARIES PAID 1922— (Continued) Amount of Number of Total Wanes Earned by all COUNTY Money Vot- Qualified Teachers for the Year ad for IVacher* Whether I'aid or Unpaid Paat Year Employed Males ! Female* j Main j Female. Sarpy 159,230 8 82 10,345.00 79,932.50 Saunders 343,036 28 191 39,925.27 186,828.06 Scotta Bluff 500323 25 224 17,638.65 218,502.54 Seward 212,471 24 135 37,374.80 133,730.17 Sheridan 228,009 21 134 23,620.25 116,093.75 Sherman 163,842 13 107 16,062.88 95,424.03 Sioux 70,618 11 70 6,918.00 49,662.87 Stanton 108,199 7 75 9,402.50| 70,896.83 Thayer 22 144 32,726.84| 130,117.40 Thayer 22 144 32,726.841 130,117.40 Thomas 38,870 4 26 2,672.00! 21,723 Thomas 38,870 4 26 2,672.00! 21,723.50 Thurston 134,986 10 84 17,221.50 87,540.84 Thurston 134,986 10 84 17,221.501 87,540.84 Valley 190,995 11 116 13,175.001 105,251.34 Valley 190,995 11 116 13.175.00 1 105,251.34 Washington 204,628 7 1221 13,300.00 125,847 Washington 204,628 7 122 13,300.00 125,847.75 Wayne 179,827 10[ 1091 15,120.93 110,559.4 Wayne 179,827 10 109 15,120.93 110,559.41 Webster 273,906 16 125 19,004.31 118,055.42 Webster 273,906| 16| 125 19,004.31 118,055.4; Wheeler 42,944 5 39 5,086.00' 24,525.70 Wheeler 42,944' 5 39 5,086.00' 24,525.7 York 244,658 26 168 44,560.45 204,545.07 Total $23,389,296 1,474 12,666$ 2,224,400.491$ 13,045,649.31 York 244,6581 26 168 44,560.45 204,545 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 103 1921 Over Under J ot *', STY * fe* ; n I s *""&gt;»- ment ill 4,296 3,490 5,411 1 II 8 1 5,420 \dan 6,608 .-&gt;,192 Antelop Arthur Banner 3,273; 2,714 3,890, 3 191 3,912 449 3461 2Sli 3521 352 491 3591 314 358 I 358 Blair Boon 581 397i 388 469| 1 _ 470 4,756 3,168 3,033 3,726 8 3,734 Box ButU Boyd 2,861 1,849 1,619 2,291 3 2,294 3,016 1.987J l,746j 2,297 3 12 2,312 Brown Kutfali 2,357 1,439 866 1,391 2 1,393 7,275 4,688 4,462 5,782 2 15 5,799 4,072 2,744 2,232 3,631 7 3,638 2,744 2,232 3,631 7 3,638 3,152 2,767 3,518 6 3,523 4348 3,152 2,767 3,518 6 3,523 5,826 3,747 3,601 4,616 1_ _„ 4,617 5,906 3,697 3,062 4,060 18 4,068 1,621 1,115 937 1,346 1,346 has 3,408 2,181 1,559 3,013 1 13j 3,027 2,181 1,559 3,013 1 13 3,027 1,864 1,779 2,494 2 12 2,508 2^89 ley 4,457 3,0051 3,042 3,889 1 8 3,898 lay olfax 3,950 2,401 2,054 2,945 28 1 2,973 4,540 2,609! 1,868 2,602 23 2,625 jminp 8,630 5,993 5,589 7,658; 5 21 7,684 Uaki 1,447 1,218; 1,988 1 3 1,992 Dawe 2,825 2,032 1,642| 2,2171 7| 5 2,229 DawBon Deuel 4,970 3,281! 3 &gt; 178 4 - 301 5 i 4 . 306 775 533 836 51 841 1,022 Dixon Dodge .5,866 2,6951 2,407 3,116| 4 3,120 7,199 4,3941 3,8651 5,409! II 24 5,434 Douglas Dundy 49,582 29,603! 23,498 37^93| 58 145 37,496 1,691 4,074 1,027 9101 1,439| 1,439 Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage .... 2,6071 2,5521 3^761 11 3^87 2^79| 1,732 1^84 2,640 2,640 2,9001 1,928| 1355 231 12 2303 2,373| 2^60| 3,221' 1 3^22 3,703 9,021| 5,5081 5^381 7,156' 21 12 7,170 Garden Garneld Gosper 1,5841 1,0601 9321 l,300| j 4 1304 70l| 619| 1,0251 1 51 1,030 1,133 1,570 1,0511 775! 1,095! 7 1,102 &lt;-&lt;l;u </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 1921 B « j ti til °?r Uf «£i'l - 1 It III 1 COUNTY COUNTY 5 z i ill =§ Grant 432 324J 324 400 : 400 Greeley 3,072 1£35| 1,712 2,335 | 111 2,346 Hall 6,800| 4,566| 4,453| 5,832| 60 5,892 Hamilton 4,186| 2,669, 2,647 3,315, 45 3| 3,363 Harlan 2,932 1,988; 2,2801 2,788 2 4 2,794 Hayes 936| 650 563 ; 996 996 I- Hitchcock | 2,024| 1.387J l,262j 1,799 1 6| 1,806 Hitchcock 2,024 1,387 1,262, 1,799 1 3,391 : 4,323 6j 1,806 12' 4,335 Holt 5381 3,542| 3,391: 4,323 12' 4,335 Holt 5,331 3,542 Hooker 468 340 275J 468 46* Hooker 275| 468 2,052 2,813 9 773 •} QQfi 468 Howard 4,021 2,582 ( 2,052 2,813 2,81! Howard 2,81 Jefferson 5,084 3,315'; 2,773 3,990 2 2 3,994 Jefferson 994 Johnson 2,983 1,835 1,673 2,372' 11 2,38:S Johnson Kearney 2,5871 1,686* 1,695 2,165 2| 2,167 Kearney Keith 1.600J 1,028 1,109 1,351 1 1,351 Keith Keya Paha 1,107 732 626 937 11 2 950 Keya Paha Kimball | 1,548! 1,057 883 1,261 2 1,26:; Kimball Knox | 6,558 4,250 :},880 5,019 1 27 5,047 Knox 6,558 4,250 3,880 5,019 14,086 18,836 Lancaster j 24.604J 16,014, 14,086 18,836 15 :S20 19,171 Lancaster 24,604 ! 16,014 Lincoln j 6.889J 4,432 3,595 5,366 4 18 5,388 Lincoln Logan I 748 507 426 591 1 592 Logan Loup 682 440, 323 611 611 Loup Madison 7,565 4,790 4,315 5,883 8 5,891 Madison McPherson I 537 .572 281 413 3 416 McPherson Merrick 3,461 2,205 2,290 2,938 8 2,846 Merrick Morrill Morrill 3369 1,721 1,723 ; 2,861 10 8 2,ST!&lt; Nance j 2,846' \JQ6 1,686 2,377 5 2,:582 Nance Nemaha | 4.0O7 1 2,743 2,063 2,966 2 5 2,97:i Nemaha Nuckolls 4,010 2,640 2,311 3,307 16 :;.:!2:: Nuckolls Otoe i 6,002 3,571 3,422 4^92 7 8 4,307 Otoe 4,307 Pawnee j 3,058; 1,962 1,739 2,386 1 13 2,400 Pawnee 3,058 1,962 1,739 2,386 1 13: 2,400 Perkins 1,598 77lj 7721 l,032| 1,032 Perkins 1,032 Phelps | 2,737 1,736 1,624 2,237 1 20 2,258 Phelps li\ Pierce Platte Polk Pierce 3,825 2,624 1,932' 2,512 3! 2,515 2,51 Platte 7,042 4,141 3^48 3,328 5 3,333 D Polk 3,184 1,966 1,999 2,675 7 2,682 Red Willow 3,574 : 2.457 1 2.634 3,134 1 2 3,136 Red Willow Richardson Richardson ! 6,142 3,760 3.342 1 4,653' 4,65'i </seg>
            <seg id="p105">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 105 1921 Enroll- Bluff ,1 300 482 530 711 1G 599 4,18 4,191 ,205 224,977 313,333 205 1,338 : 314,876 Over I Under TotI11 21 k ment l,280| 782 573 968 968 5,168, 3,266' 3,397 4,304 1 29 4,334 2,883| 1,888 1,555 2,114 2,114 6,600 4,117 3,991] 4,910 2 32 4,944 7,817 i 5^44| 3,892| 7,172 43 7,215 5,566, 3,598 2,960 3,733 1 51 3,785 2,988 1,998' 2.174 1 2,666 2 51 2,719 3,253 2,067; 1,700 2,485 1 21 2,506 ,684; 1,235 987 1,331 1,684 1,235 987 : 1,331 5 1,336 2,516 1,561 1,461 2,079 ' 10 2,089 4,526 2,865 2,360 3,262 2 3,264 21 484 ,394 2,190 1,726 2,464 5i 2,469 ,309 2,060 1,836 2,875 2 18 2,895 2,669 2,694 3,084 1 1' 3,086 2,109 1,831 2,870 14: 2,884 2,244 1,931 2,742 1 12! 2,755 </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 1922 B •1 ;J tit u Ig III f *r «-~ £3 county h ill if Adams | 6,837 4,442j 3,842 5,195 j 3| 3| 5,201 a Anteiope I 5,416i 3,69oi 3,02d| 4,360i 9| 19. 4,388 3361. Arthur I 457, 258i 126 Banner I 504, 340i 292 400 1 i 400 Blaine I 551| 377i 350 4401 1 i 44 Boone I 4,8671 3,146; 2,860 3,609 'J Box Butte | 2,885i l,838i 1,561 2,337 2 1 9'- Boyd I 3,078! 2,009i 1,454 2,302 2, 7 1 2,311 Brown I 2,3041 l,611i 1,448 2,073 1 1 Buffalo 7,514| 4.548J 4,359 Burt | 4,094i 2,4401 2,472 6,010j 2 5 6,017 8 Burt 3,416, , li :i,41T Butier I 4,885 2,964 2,695 3,500 iO Caw I 5,866i 3,957i 3,358 4,865i 5i 4 4,8 Cedar I 53311 3,754 2,774 4,089, I 6 4,C Chase I 1,691 1,199 1,094 1,331 Cherry I 33051 2,093| 1,431 2,930 Cheyenne i 2^30i 1,863| 1,701 2,503 Clay - 4,466 2,742 2,852 3,847 Colfax i 3,918 2,4581 2,101 2.8M Cuming 4,403 2,664 2,054 2.572 Custer 8,845 6^67 5,711 7,789, 12 29 Dakota I 2,555 1.573J 1,371 1,999 H Dawes 2,8411 2,0731 1,633 2^79; 1 2,280 Dawson 5,180 3,3521 3,682 4,305 4! 9 4..! Deuel l,099i 768 700 9121 i i &gt;»12 Dixon 3,967 2,591 2,353 3,325 Dodge 7,362 4,587 4,192 5,636| 12; 5,64&gt;« Douglas 50,433 30,905i 24,378 i8,464j 61 1 491- .!9,016 Dundy 1,710 1,049! 805 1,396! | l,39t Fillmore 4,183 2,563 2,463 3,228! II 20 3,249 Franklin ! 2,936 1,946 1,694 2,490 ; 7 2,497 Frontier I 2^921 1,9141 1,4751 2,451! 2 4 2,457 • Furnas 3,709 2^151 2,384 3,228 2; » 3,239 •&gt; Gage 9^921 5,554] 5,499 7,338! 3! 25 7.36G Garden 1^581 l,047 ! 953 1,448 1 1,449 Garfield 1,1821 726! 647 9851 1 4 989 Gosper | 3,070 2.032 1 1,507 2,460! ■&gt; 2,462 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 107 1922 l,532j 943 711 1,073 4,149 5,898 2,536 3,297 1,892 2,400 1,073 Greeley Hall 6,8021 4,347 1 4 2 2 5,901 4.2.-.ii 2,609 Hamil 111 3,312 Har 1,975 8 2,410 Have 980 664 628 829 3 832 3! 832 2,074 1,375 1,255 1,795 2 1 1,798 2 1 1,798 Hitchcock Holt 5,738 3,538 3,005 4,384 1 22 4,407 301 266 266 301 301 1 22 4,407 Ho. 301 Howard 3,843 2,365 2,195 2,909 2,909 2,909 5,284 3,277 2,992 4,161 3 6 4,170 Jeffers 3 2,999 1,837 1,818 2,411 6 2,417 hns Kearn 2,628 1,699 1,623 2,199 8 2,207 Keith 1,589 1,191 1,239 1,394 3 1,397 1,129 748 642 927 1 2 930 Keya Paha 1 1 2 930 Kimba 1,558 964 897 1,332 1 2 1,335 2 1,335 Knox 6,678 4,333 3,992 5,084 9 5,093 9 5,093 Lancaster 25,2541 15,551 25,254 15,551 15,022 19,688 28 337 20,053 6,871 4,379 4,254 5,402 4 8 5,414 695 462 409 603 3 606 2h 4 337 20,053 Lincoln 8 5,414 Logan 3 606 I.i&gt;U| 533 375 347 470 , 470 470 Madison 7,617 4,683 4,012 5,752 2 2 5,756 501 332 278 381 _ 381 2 2 5,756 McPherson 381 Merrick 3,407 2,333 3,407 2,333 2,281 2,850 2 2,852 2 2,852 Morrill 3,297 2,299 1,658 2,884 1 17 2,902 1 2 1 17 2,902 2,854 1,833 1,776 2,567 2 13 2,582 Nance 13 2,582 Nemaha 3,973 2,555 2,542 3,089 1 2 3,092 2 3,092 V Nuckolls 4,116 2,818 2,354 3,217 4 3,221 4 3,221 Otoe 6,007 3,720 6,007 3,720 3,695 4,361 1 12 4,374 121 4,374 1 2 Pawnee 2,963 1,857 Perkins 1,543 805 2,963 1,857 1,726 2,473 2 9 2,484 9 2,484 Perkins 1,543 805 801 948 948 948 Phelps 2,731 1,833 1,624 2,252 1 1 2,254 1 1 2,254 Pierce 4,012 2,675 4,012 2,675 2,039 2,726 2 2,728 2 2,728 Platte 7,185 4,066 Polk _ 3,128 1,961 Red Willow. „ 8,819 2,302 7,185 4,066 2,917 3,423 6 7 3,436 6 7 3,436 1 3,128 1,961 1,876 2,716 3 6 2,725 3 6 2,725 '» Red Willow. 3,819 2,302 2,509 3,329 2 7 3,338 2 71 3,338 Richardson 6,051 3,790 6,051 3,790 3,580 4,811 6 8 4,825 6' 8 4^25 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT IMS c 14 c c ■1 HI II 111 5* ■53 5 COUNTY ||| Over Under ™,. *£ ™5 ■'•«« 5 Enrol I if 111 I BJJ &amp; zi 111 si* SIX Rock 1,289 770 702 973 1 974 Saline 6,157 3,147 3,341 4,186 3 4,189 2,934 1,991 [ 1,714 2,328 | 2,328 Sarpy Saunders 6,650 4,054 3,681 4,941 5 39 4,985 Scotts Bluff I 8,1491 5,4431 1,395| 7,694| 1 5 7,7 Seward 5,350 3,3891 2,997| 3,716 91 3 725 Sheridan I 2,9381 1,963 1,933! 2,609( 2 71 2,618 Sherman I 3,375 2,198 1,879 2,577 151 2,592 Sioux 1,510 l,05ll 92l! 1,351 2 Stanton 2,502 1,589' 1,339' 1,984 1 11 Thayer 4,502 2,720! 2,181' 3,105 2 Thomas 512 339 1 3121 4141 21 41 Thurston 3,430 2,262 ! 1,769! 2,671 2 1 6 2,679 Valley 3,351 2,1901 2,133' 2,943 Washington 3,948 2,406 2,4571 3,064 Wayne 3,4191 2,0481 1,9601 2,8041 161 5 Webster 3,434 2,201 2,055 2,778 Wheeler 913! 57ll 499' 689 York 3,832 3,1411 2,791! 4,183 Total 403,1461 256,102| 225,208' 318,515! 2111 1,4021 320,12 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 109 &amp; § v ««.«»«« N«=.O OB 5 S£ NO S a«SNO°»S ii_ . I. « J S22S2SS2 H " ooaxoot "« olao » NOOt " 1 ' 1 5~ 10. ". *"«««'*t-'»(qHOioaHOCi6iooot-aM I! 1 — - 1 - •-1 Jjl i i i ! i ! ! i i ! i iii •I. I ■- s 11 '■ '■ '■ i i : I ! I ! ! ! ! I ! • i ! s- : : : : :::::: : • ■ ■ : • • = x ■ ■ ■ ■ .:■.:■.■. : : ; ; : : : : : - s. « i -O 111 - - -- ■- ill 4*1 q x n ti n e e 10 e » (-_ t-_ e (i a « t- o &gt;&lt; 01 Mt e ji " M N ri t-T *£ e£ d CC tt «" &gt;■' M «* r&gt;" C r&gt;" ?H «* So? a tec- X M O 1O ffi O K IO 01 « M a « O C S K o: O S IC O « ffi S S £ £2 "5 £ S t- « » ih V eo x oe «i ee oi »f i&gt;' b « eg c~»c nwic — « 2 E» - 8 I „ i ! I ! I i i I I |i I i « I I ! I i i *OG»j«.S5oOt.3:33«S.C,C.C,2^33&lt;»«l« </seg>
            <seg id="p110">11 i] ii n n o o n w_ o » q » e o a t-. ". * &lt; o h n » « « to" n e t- o a » us t-* a w" o" n &lt;o" t-" V » »" io V od » C4 s-. T I 1 " — a iai-i«ow©©op^eo« | 5©©©wo»eiejo«©aot-o sinnHSiiiMO^xooisvt-igoiaiHNonnxii: o f » « x &lt; o t- • « -; m n « n a n n &gt;" t- o i ej t- «-T e&gt;f eJ ~* tt •&lt; •• w *f »&lt; *&lt; oJ of -^ of h « I! I = |1| III : : ~* ** in ** : : •* : :^* ! :^^ : h h t» w :^HfHr-teo Si '. '. '■ r- X " — h _ : (M ; • ; ; — ; — III m x us t- : so : : o : : oo N &lt;o •«* ic «: nm; M«^ in:: 1 — :oo re th i— •+ ■ : »h III" Sisnioiov«9eeistDoi&lt;«eiMnt-isu:cina n H4if)is«^OHgi«exXMKaAHnNNeCn «o io_ co^ oo^ o&gt; «&gt;_ oo^ ic^ oo_ x -j c- co o, ic_ &gt;o_ o_ eo ©^ m «_ oi n I i hi* 2 Z*s m hi* SoiOriisioioMSttNfnoicsMOxnveao "I '. °. 1 M . ®. "°. ". °. ®. °. "^ °°. "i. 1 °. "*. H . ". °l H . °. —. — : — : *—. : — : : : — : — : — : — : — : — : : : t I B i o ■I:::::::::: i : ::::::::• Ml I j I i I I I I ! I I I ! i i I ! ! I ; I i i i ! i i I i • ! I I I ! |! J j j j | | ! : j i | ! ! ; | ! ji I : I i : i i I!::! i : !!!;!! i i i :::: I I j I [ j | ! ! i | ! i i ! ; : | | ) ; j ! ::!!! i ::::!!: I ::!:: i i i ! :::::::::::::::::::::::: ; : ; ; i : : ; ; ; : : : : : : j | : ' : | : : ijtitJliifiiiiiJijiiJiii o.5oo3=22aea&lt;ssoC.C&lt;»«««.-ooo^ QQQQQ££££oUUOCialD«SSSK«8&gt;^ </seg>
            <seg id="p111">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 111 ill, 4! HoeHKnot-oicasKii-oBMttioo-'iea tSHOOkQnOVtDiHOinOkQiCCX^O^lQHMO^ — — — _ i « « eo m -&lt; — -i « n n h i-i ih ea -• M ; 6-r Si' c&amp;^Nt-Hegoovc40icncooDcQioion(Ooot*conifi » « i- to h ih q o&gt; e n a f t- ie « n oo q t-, t» n o_ » o_ ■"■■»■« -h n" o&gt; " eJ &lt;-? i-~ oJ eJ » 1-7 i-T of i-T i-7 r-' = I i i i ill I «n :co-hn:;:i-ci i ; :mh | )« jm SB &lt; Q _ «-&lt; ; h is h :::him::::}::::h : I ! : i : ■ : ■ ■ i i : i : • : : : : : : : : | : : : : at H M 111 ot- :hno^ : :ic : ii" : le oo : »-i : i :oc — n i-i &lt;a«c« icc:©!:^ : O* : : : »-i : i—i : - i i &lt; I ict-^iogioonNiSMMncitiHrtiovoiieoinegx 50Mt-i-iNTl'03CO'HOON^ 1 TfiOi-iOOOOO&gt;OOt-00^' » (•_ o e » r-_ «»»*i» m m « n * n » f t; « &lt;f h h h « m is m *t" eJ i-T i-&gt;" pa" eS n «-T i-T i-T ef eJ , t iflOHAHXHeooosA^ov^^t-ti^aonnfHO) &lt;MiDo&gt;o&gt;Hisot-NO«H»«^t.«aioa^»aR a&gt; k «o^ii^oc^io &gt; eo&lt;e i aic«^i-^'^.'^o^5C_e&lt;3£oe^o»t&gt;.oqte«co»^ oi » t-" io eo »" w o n x t-" oc n oi a n V n n « o a mw— h te qo to c- ■* « « « v © « ec^^eo IN* - I Z o o I Jliilijlljliiiilliyiii? </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 'I N«N«OinOKNt'HHISXt-«CiniONt- NnU3^l-C«C4«u:(|KMrtWHXN&gt;Ot- CH t^_ us evj, ec_ eo io_ o, oo N t» oo -h_ -&lt; 1-^ e^. o&gt; -h ■* ■» t-_ eo ei o&gt; t- oi eo h n &gt;4 n n oo m* m is V a a* m V m* is t- o 1 N «"HC0^MN-&lt; — iiN rt H N H N SN * I. I o ss«nNxn9)e«&lt;foeoNno«x4 •-&lt; e&lt; » • * M q » n h _^_ e m n » » h oi » io « » o e&gt;i nn' n «-T n « W &lt;n* •h'n' J k —T m 1 t- P4 I ii ""III 11" : : : : : : : I ii = x s. N^:rsN::«— :::-&lt;: :::-h: :|^i % M n: : -h eo *h to M . r: so »« N « oo : x so : «e : © ei N N N «©■*■: in o — ■» — 2 ; : e» PJ Oldt-Ot-iOiOOCt-IOV^QCO^lSNitXrtn C3 &gt;» w a o ia o t- oo o, oo fi n « h o h ej ia m «&gt; Nee w h n V « n h — &lt;*eJe^e&gt;fe&gt;i n «" H ml l_ t- h h us h a M » ih o i&gt; o « o «" n h u o" oT •-? o^onooxNHionnuinisnt-voinxti ii n s i 1 co r &gt;c m_ ei - ' . i to Z O z 5 ::::::::: ; :: i : i : ■ : iiiiijiiiiiiiiiiiiil! l </seg>
            <seg id="p113">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 113 J i a n o «_ « o_ t-_ oe 9i_ q o w^ tt_ no &lt;; «, oo q S_ « ■» «i * a-g'2 o o n n n kT » V « r&gt;" n n oo o" oo ot n oi oi n" ef » £■ Sic COM N-"rtHflNNM«HNHM«-&lt;iOrtHN I *3 _. „ », ~a&gt; ecsis&gt;ii&gt;ii«iOHO)Hogosnt-'-K8iHnoo&gt; 32 0"»t-o]t-o»ejejot&lt;3t-oot-«OT»oot-«eoot-e»r; e»_ te^ i 1 o^ ao_ e± t- &lt;o_ q eo^ co_ r^ o_ —i o&gt;_ ■*_ m^ q a » » t- O^ I! 1 i t e „ (M : : • : -&lt; ; : :^h : : : : h « n : :o5i-i :*1 |*6 ; i ! ; ; : : i i i j j j ; Ijl i ! i ! i I i II : -r. I l ""*, ** It jl MIM-iriillllilllillll z m DQ _ s. 'ft N M M ! ! ! ! ! N " i i I i g « n - « n t- t- io » e 9i a&gt; n si h «_ &gt;h ia^ ai. a_ us, t-, » J*^ ■♦ n ci***+~-*Gie*nm a ~ n &lt;zt ~* m &lt;-&lt; ** m . o»ocoen-&lt;«ooMS»xe'&gt;o | 5wt''S5 le • U, O*HlOB(»10»O(5lO««eN01MMMW»J00H 5 * — 3 ««oiioooiacooiH*^ooint'Ooa*«^oi»ia[- S- 7 a t-" so ■» I-" ■» N •* o ® o « io « n ■»" w oo io » £ S S t" 5 a &gt;■ ::::;::: : : ; : i i j • j • j i j | Z i i j : ! i : j ! j i ! j ) : ! | • : ■ • ■ ! j O i i i i : i i ! : i i i ; i i ; ; j j j j | j | O :;:;:; : : : ; : : : : ; : ; ••::::• M I ! I J M M ! ! ! : - I I I i | j i : ! : ; I I i j ! : i : i ' "3cun.2ooo2333«aSx.c.c.2o33«';'» &lt;&lt;&lt;Bnan«PQ««BoaoooooooOQO </seg>
            <seg id="p114">111 z&lt; I •-&gt;_ t~^ e^_ oo_ so, oq^ os, o^ oi^ t-_ in_ 5&gt;i c» c»_ x^ — &lt;_ m_ oc x_ o» t^ as N, £ t-" « * « o a » i- io" » -"" t-" » n o «" » is ei i- cc o t~" I. z&lt; t-a)-«ejo«mx«ommo«inoosc0'-iooooo« *H«HN»-*ioOt-1KNeNt-«N«NONX 1 1 1 *. °. *. 1 1 ''. 8 h is 16 a i- # « h e h « o t c H _J | i , T - "° j | I 5 | | i MM ! ! i :»h:co::»-i:~*« : «o »^ ; : : ■= A7 oo : N t- iff « f s - ffi :rr ««co ■ ?; : :o» : ill hi ill **{ i &lt;j MIOXlCHItHH(fflNHS!IK»(l«ll!0«I-00 jj g t- t; 10 « o » « « is o q e x k i t-_ s s n * n n n » " &lt;l . loeNMt-K^xsicaxn-sOfi-iONNt-ooe «, &gt;,} . &lt;SN»NOoiaoo?jcsi-ic~e4e4KC3KOm&gt;i:pjc&lt;i&lt;c&gt; • n ~ "1 1 H . a . M . ffi . ". ". n . u i t^. r1 ". « t". * W * M O) * N O&gt; •* t^-o. 3 N««t&gt;»xNat-Ht-ooo&lt;»^'»r-«xaef«e rt'VC-CX3&lt;-''^'«&lt;N-«'Nrt^iM hHi- 9 2 MO &lt;ll&lt; - I ;;;;;; Mi i i M ! i I i i i M i i i ••:■••:■!•: i : i i i : I!!:: Si:!i:i:ii:!!i;M:; ! ! ««:::::::::::::::::: : : : : • i i • • • : ! i i • ■ i : : ! • • !!!!■! ! i i M : MMMM ••!••• ;•••••;.•; • ■ ; ; ; ; ; : : : ; : ; ::::::; ::::::::•::::: iiliiiiiiiiiiiitiiiiiiii ; ; ; ; ; ; ; ; ; M M i ! • ; i i : i i ! i i i ! ; M i i i i i ki H i i i i i i i i ! ! i ■ ; • i i i i i ! i ; i ! z O jj : i j | j : j : j : ; u i I : : i I : : : : i :••!:::•:::: ■s § 6 ■at I -Si S «■€&lt;£ 2LS-S liS-^^^Sfc </seg>
            <seg id="p115">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 115 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ;i S •M :■: o t re ac N o x c C S O) ~ t- f t- 8 U t- t- I- » M t - t- it OC i X I! M 1 a CM = a - Tl ZA OB 4 z i s s. M - t- c- i" n t^ co o; o oo i£ — i eg — E &lt; h - a z o -- ■ • t :"'-. s . :i .«in N . tc " J - « * " « = n x ■» « 5 z&lt; ■» = ■= ■J5 J = =©-* — C5— t~ « *~ i ? X* N* C* N O &gt;O t-^ i-T t- i-r-- 3 OC-N-fl. — O-*5I~~ m - =- -^ so &lt;-&lt; to n i~ x i- :t - » ! : ; £ « c c it T : S T3 S S 3 = 3 j 3 S I x £ .; * X a v. v. y. v. -s. x -y; y; X </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>