<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE FOOD, DAIRY AND DRUG COMMISSION OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FOOD, DAIRY AND DRUG COMMISSION OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA HY J. W. JOHNSON DEPUTY COMMISSIONER </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">litmn of the foods, drugs and dairy f the Food. Dairy and Drug Nebraska consideration ;t statement of th nd dairy business in this state and of meiit which commenced operations under ml dnii.' law July r&gt;th. 11107, I want 1 that the department has been able in this part of what was and is to do to b ' business in this state up to the ntemplated in this law. partnient 1 read the law very care purpose was to interfere with dis - •ln of publicity that would ei hat the national food and drag law the harmful adulteration in foods emed to me the duty of this ■ particularly at the first to n ecution and publicity the short brought into the system under h nd sold .tend to reach the short weight y net weight statement made on ver to the food factories their ig products. The farmers have not shortweighted the buyers of their heat, corn or cattle lint when these products have come back hey have come in secret packages. In this law went into effect were pyramids t' thi.s food producing </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 of beautifully decorated food packages, in each of which was a secret as to how much food it contained. The miller had for years been handing oui to th mid the groceryman to the farmer sacks of floor that pretended to contain ."&gt;(» pounds, Imt which in reality contained l&gt;ut 47 or 4 The cereal factory had handed out to the dealer and tl B customers packages of oatmeal and Inindreds ires that pretended to contain two pounds i hut which really contained 15 to 20 per cent The packing houses had sold to tin tailers anil to the consumers pretended three p&lt; lard at the three pound or five pound or 1 which were short weight 1"&gt; to 17 per cent. Thea I to the local meat dealers throughout th packages of cured meats th; t amount of meat charged for on the hooks of the packing The butter makers, forced by tli that had crowded itself into 1h Irocerymen to the hoi dupe, ;it the pound price, tha in money less than a pound. '! weight butter package amoanta eoaaoaen of package butter in net weight branding pequireme used the i:&gt;. 14 and 15 onnc pound dupe, at the pound in money less thai short weight butter packai: the butter makers to get together on urn minim &gt;rr mon honesty around the hot truthfully said now that the short weight cheat in butt business in Nebraska, except in by retailers handling bulk butter and weiirhinir thf ages to their patrons the retailers' package beinar exempt from t r branding requirement under this law A suit pending before the supreme court in a butter &lt;-t brought by this department involving this net weiirh r requirement has been recently withdrawn by the appellants wh denied that the law oould compel them to brand thei pad. but the butter makers of the state are not waiting for the of this suit TIipv 81*6 V)r8ncIin fT thpir nfloWfl^ps 1 fi on n ops adH t H </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I hid 1 } 1 Y ndous \ lire svst t sturdy men. the ret •-&gt; • they are irlail to have the short weight unpetition that is in it eliminated forever Should the supreme court at any time hold w worded is not sufficient to to»pel the but- its net weight, the law will surely be buttermaken nor the butter consumers of satisfied to pi hai-k to the old method by , competed against each other as to which the smallest amount of butter of the pound c The immorality in this short weight cheat. hroagh the whole food system is enough of bolishment by law to say nothing of the vast illy by the consuming public for food that this department is pending before th&lt; be packing houses claim immunity from the 1 honesty on which this net weight clause miony in the district court trial of this case iska packers shortweight the retail meat he amount of over $90,000 annually. The retail dealer, for example, a box of meat 100 pounds and charged to the dealer as lie current meat price. On opening the • !»t&gt; pounds of meat wrapped in four or rapping paper, this wrapping paper being he meat price, perhaps SO rents per pound, o the packers being perhaps one and a half packers get a dollar on each hundred pound lich they do not deliver, an extra profit by short transaction, a ■hortweight profit of five ■ If the [wickers charged the retailers for d then made an additional charge of $1 for there would lie at least a show of regularity pinir in the transaction and the retailer could pay the bill so rendered. We get some idea of il that this short weight trick has on the whole m when we consider that these hundreds of ail meat dealers of the state, pay. without pro- and week after week and vear after vear a in the pai-kiitr </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I B extortion of four or five per cent ou each porch never delivered to them. If the Nebraska farmers were weighing out th cattle to the packers. shortweighting the per cent on each transaction, tin ite in their demand for the enfi hem at the rate packers would cement of a is x th comi&gt;el basest weights. It is remarkable that these hundreds &lt; meat dealers, to say nothing of the consuming public. \vh the end must stand the strs this extortion cai audacious dishonesty practised by the meat trust that ti: price when it buys, fixes the priee when it sells and then ei price when it buys, fixes th. weiL-ht by delivering less than it ehargea for oa its books. I5esules this system Df shortweighting tin- local dealers 000 annually by weighing out to them cheap paper and charging si at the meat price, t i packers gel from the consuming public a profit !&gt;' hi bv deliverin ha Besides this system of ghortweighting the local d ■t in lard that i ited by tins d against local i weigh! in lard that amount* annually to a large sum. Prose instituted by tins department are pending u parts against local dealers who handle the short weight la up in tin containers. These tin pails of lard are in soa up m tin con •■d &lt;&gt;ut as ■ iid •■ 1(K". the consumer under* I" means three pounds, the "5" five pounds and th. iikIs of lard, hut when attention is called t&lt;&gt; the short ed nut as lid "• 1 lit p. unds of in these pails the agents of the packing boua in these pjiils ill,. ;m,.n around the proposition with an eloquent and plausibli around the proposition witli that the •■is" are not guaranteed to hold three pounds, i five pounds, nor the " Ids" 10 pounds, for no definite i mds is specified on the paekage, that there is really i that th five pounds, nor the " 1&lt; of pounds is specified on the package, tl statement on the package, that the words i ' and statement on the package, that do not really mean so many pounds, these inly n do not really mean so many pi terms used to designate the various sizes, that the purchase tin pails of lard at his own risk as to how much tin terms used to designate the V tin pails of lard at his \vn tain, takes them and pays the regular lard priee for wh; pposed to contain, takes them for- better or for worse, tain, takes them and pays th ful if he gets a pail now and then that contains within - of what he pays for. thankful that although the [ • and higher each year the short weight cheat runs ful if he gets a pail now and then that contaii ounces of what he pays for. thankful that although thi ■r and higher each year the short weight cheat rur about the same. ?*&gt;« 1 1 1 1 1 • of" th(* ] 4 H "1 1 ( 1 1 *'l 1 1 ■ ' liter! t'lii* hon Iliri +1 about the same. I * * Mcl[['l,,j_ III* </seg>
            <seg id="p007">1 packages have complained that the re to brand is the fault of the paeken hould not be proseeatod. Hut, it a lealer becomes the medium through which tuff is handed oat to the public, to that the "3" whii-h he sells lire is unlawful, participating lit cheat that is in the package, it seems should be held responsible and proee - for, otherwise, the local dealers feeling &gt;uld beeosne an army of law breakers to the iniquity, the packing house, and no in am state so long as the local dealers he unlawfulness of the factory while rnorant of the wrong that is put upon it dealers are not ignorant of the cheat but ■aler brings the wrong home to thai goes along with the pr bhcitv the public to sec the subtle cheat in tli aroused public sentiment beco withstand When the local de the interest of their patrons refn- food stuff, the greedy factory feels the rendering practical assistance a pht requirement into effect. The grocery be short weight poods, for he can find plenty of honest "ids in the market. Rut the meat dealer ild blooded monopoly that sneers at common law. seldom having been made to feel and ■ev law. The meat trust smiles complacently at the ineffective- out suits against itself. Tt uses the army of ■il agents to hand out its short weight It uses them as its servants to handle and slice up nd hand out its hiirh priced meat stuffs on every pound of which I M l, &gt;rtion in price and ■ shortage in weight. It can do not contain three pounds, knowing ust give up its trraft ndent. The frroeCTyman &lt;-;in n </seg>
            <seg id="p008">« this became it has do reaped for nor fear of the rtate gorenuMi and it never will have until the state government, th if strict inspect ion anil local control takes tlu public out from under the thumb of the meat pack tlie meat packers under the thumb of just laws i-i^rht v The National Cracker trust trot its tip to di law from the meat trust. These largi Deems stand back t n in defending themselves against law. It is the these large concerns that prom by adulteration ,o browbeat and delav am they call "busin When the Xati ■tied to withdraw its one Oniah required by this law to sh the] contained it believed that the Nebraska peo] with fear of the eonsequ l told to (JO and diil go, the independi -lillLT for 8 llllMlh !■ the oppo a the opportunity ruhe oe, In it four erael ■lie. but f I and two jobbing hi ■ad two jcihhimr how I i-;ill attention toil object k - now tl ,,-,.,. exerted by thnt i ■ ; 1 1 •- promptly calls the I opens thi' door of opj I call attention to th tl the state promptly calls the bluff and it is certainly the business of government t tunity wherever they have been lew Pa— ing from butter, meat am port that most of the ■_!!)&lt;) millers in Xi formal reaped for the law by the marked w I of Hour, corn meal. Graham, stock foods and otht but in the case of some mills these marked i kat hed in the balances are found wanting. The millers complaii that the net weight requirement is a hardship on them. Th. forth that the wheat must be wet before grinding: to tou&lt;rhen th bran, and that this wet wheat loaded with water makes water loaded flour and that this water loaded Hour shrinks by evaporation and when the packages get into the e they are nee« ■ • ' ■ ** * * — </seg>
            <seg id="p009">• t ion has been made to this department by food factories all ach demanding exemption from the net weight ■nization threatened that this law en - lit packages would quarantine the State of n Miid other fruit package floods bseanss ioration in fruit. The cereal and cracker concerns argument The meat packers set :it ion in meat and therefore the meat nka •quired to show his customer! how much I'he salt makers of Michigai Ilioliev iir attorneys to show that while all other held strictly to aei-ount as to the net might, xempt. for salt, they said was by the very i weather environment from which it could ial package of salt, they said, would swell town heavily in the scale at every little would instantly lighten in weigh! with !t works, they said, could comply with iid if it was enforced against them they would hdraw their hi, mn this state and leave ;alt makers did not withdraw their prod - are properly branding them and there roseeute any short weight salt pael davs of June. the fruit packers and the out of the v showing the amount their packages eon- ivith the law, although there is in some eases ht used of too wide a margin and in many packages hidden away in some corner of the package gainst this net weight requirement. ndoubtedly unpopular, this requirement to show how 1 for the money, unpopular at the short weight &gt;ry. but the Nebraska farmer who has never had the if weighing out to the buyer his food products is satisfied with the law that goes into the grocery store with his wife and says to the man behind the counter "you make this woman as cer - tain of the amount of food you deliver to her as you are certain of shrinkage by evaporation. The Cali- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 C&lt;auag Imck to the plea of the millers that the short &gt; • I in their mill sturt's is due to evaporation, this d in. nt weighed Hour- in Omaha, Lincoln and oth wi the state and found that while there was a general sh ing less than the marked weight, some of the brands showed tr shortage wherever their stu Omaha or elsewhere. It Wl ier shortage in the squall nek le. ximi saeks of flour weighed aids averaged over ii ounces ti ■r of the L'4 |&gt;oiinil sneks showi ■ack. Here is nearly twice .tuft' was found was also fount whet hi that tiler than in tin i short \ i the lartre on 1 four times as much. ( an tin and siftiiiL' out twice as mui Some |l purchaser of th with hundreds would lose by this II sum. easily compn li When this law went in bottled whiskey of aboj whiskey bottles purchased eiirht honest bottles in the tain what thev were mar one half pint bottles that should hold in but 4 :{ , ounces. These short handed out for years in most ea* numlter of prosecutions and fines again branded liquors have broufcht the bottlei ful condition as to this net weight reqi niiinv eonsimiers buying by the bottle m label or to eoinpute lhat they are payim tli» \\ »-t ' !&gt;♦ I ft! 1 t I ♦ 1 1 tli It il p th( utiiin in pounds thai pound shortiiL'f on the 10 not much of ;i In*- to thf Pul Rhortage eompul fiir on e*eh Mo.&lt; m m» j </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 If by little educate the consuming pub - squan deal, a ihmriag of the amount and the educating of the public ag hing of the aggregate loss to the public item will ultimately make a demand ; of every character and the tri&lt; will disappear from here are MH) saloons in N'ebras latrona u average of $10.&lt;&gt;00 annually, taking •(Hi annually, a large proportion of the stuff h this heavy short weight run- kjlLTCS. Wl st the consumer ;■ t the rate of :i:{ 1-9 per cent the ins to me the state, through a hould say to the man Iwhind the bar. "If must lead you to prey upon the wea; you shall not cheat him continually as for his money he 47 creameries of this state and t i if this butter fat. Before this law went 1 deal of complaint from the cream pro - ud testing of their cream at the various throughout the state was manipu shortweiirhtinu the fannei butter fat than thev delivered. There re local testing throughout the state. The 1 by the creameries to the extent that d testers in the state as against l"&gt;0 I side the creameries when the law took effect. This is practically no complaint now from the cream the measurement of butter fat. but there has been ilaint from the creameries that the farmers too long before delivering to the shipping station, h mistreatment of cream through exposure to had hat th ited and foul smelling back rooms of gi 1 of every dollar he spends on Ixittli-d goodi ling sboni 2.-&gt;.&lt;&gt;tX).O&lt;M) poun There luis been mom jeakmi is to the accuracy and honesty pit </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 l stores, that there is unnecessary exposure of the cream to sun ht while waiting for shipment at the railroad stations and that tht ■ • is abuse and loss in value from the unnecessary delay in the 1 by rail from the point of shipment to the butter factory. Tb a tendency for the cream buyers in the local towns to bid f&lt; cream business by offering and giving a hiyher test to m-l the In many cases the cream buyer uses the cream busin* bring the farmers into his store for his more important trade. the whole there is a general want of knowledge and accuracy in some cases of honesty among men who act as airents to buv ai 25,000,000 pounds in farmers to the butter tact weight trick to be played thousand places through* this vast field of butter f means that tli ouirhi to In intended hv th If the erean treated in the bad air is foul with the od cream is further abuse* on the slow run to the butter I', - in the testing and sampling b; carelessness or dishonesty of the reason of all these things the ere; the price paid for batter fat on could afford to pay if the abov exist, this one cent per pound on the annual output a quarter of a million dollars annually is a reasonable r dairy department of this commission should b. is certainly worth while to strengthen the dairy depa commission and to put into action a more efficient i the whole dairy business, not only that the quarter of a millioi more in higher price may be paid annually to the farmer cream, but that the price may be still further enhanced by th higher grade and the consequent higher price of Nebraska batte in the Eastern market. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 luirement in this law to have the hurtful habit forming and heretofore secreted drug advertised on the m package there n mbm contention on the part of some holding of this department has been unfair provision which applies to all 'hat in any prosecution it shall led dealer to show that he had the goods on h;md May 1st. 1907 im that this provision was i u t • food by them when their committee was )f the law, to shield the unbrandi-d w makm I believe that all fair minded drum his provision does not shield from the offending dealer from the Baa ution has been instituted. I : department to bring every drug i iwimlj forming and inhibited drugs n by prosecution of the dealer. Irug if he could, for I could see that ut would indirectly force the i lignal on the label lers would rather brand all the old - nder the above provision. On the the Lincoln druggists proposed th.r ng of this department, would brand all the old stock showing the inhibited drags, and •position this department has sent out to n tlic state a circular letter to the a printed list showing the proportion of the hundred remedies, sn that at this writing he State should have the old stiwk as well as 1 and in a lawful condition One of the most widespread and harmful abuses by adulter- the mixing of sulphite preservatives with old and tainted i grinding the meat into hamburger steak and sausage lit The preservative deodorises and brightens the bad smelling and lead colored meat, enabling the butcher to sell five or ten pounds &gt;f meat every day that ou&lt;. r ht to be thrown away. The sulphite rvative acts on the meat as formaldehyde acts in milk, pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 composition hinders digeation. When the sulphite ,\ tie stomach along with the Meat there is a eooihel beti e juice nt' the stomach and the sulphites, for th. vanta to decompose the neat as soon ;&gt;s poarible while tin to hinder the decomposition and delay the d nible. The effect is the breaking down of t li&gt; w this law came into effect nearly every butcher shop ma wing these preservatives. A few pn ut ions the city of Lincoln failed to stop this miachievoaapraetiee t\ out the stiite tor these prosecut ions advertised in tht brought ii band of hustlers from the Chicago concerns t red that the new harmless and that in ;mv n inventive genius, bnsii tment the departm analyzed hamburtr the space of about tw various parts of the phite preservative ti in this state, temporarily Investigation by tin and liasi mints and sho|&gt;* shows that these places \\ h pared need the application of them in proper sanitary ndition. A bread and meat shops through tl in the refrigerator, or the ha tact with dirty utensils, dirty provide for the application of compel these place* to clean up and keep dean. In thi *tai has come to the knowledge of this department where an\ *1 m patron has looked into the secret places of his meat shoi if it was dean. Many f th ira hav i . i r th - it by preventing decomposition. Whatever hin those preaerval ives and tl temporary . Realizin other secret place where the f of hundreds of them place*, Kirae of tlx-i hmild be tinea </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 heir duty to investigate for them* -: 'lean shops atul clean ven publicity to the investigation ge number of unsanitary bakeries and ■M good and there is a cleaner condi - i the history of the state. Dg out "Unclean!" "Unclean!" will not nrae of these places auy more than the MM n old Jerusalem. ic akng this line should I*- followed up by n of legal fone from an amended law that an food manipulator to forsake his unclean y inspection department of this law 'It is un - fi-om cows kept in a filthy or unsanitary eondi - nspecton report that 85 per cent of the dai lilk supply t&lt;&gt; the people of Lincoln and Omaha insanitary. A nuinl&gt;er of these wo have ution and some Hnes have been assessed. been reported where any housewife of taken the trouble to examine the dairy B are drinkintr milk. Here a&gt;;ain is another sum ing public fails in its duty to eoatribatc ■ities where they have made a ti&lt;rht for id the death rate in children one-half. This lines is certainly a work that insanitary hould !«• no sentiment or sympathy that anitary milk producer, became he fanner and because he thinks his milk is good enough, or e he is a renter and cannot afford to dean up the rented where there is an accumulation of ten years of filth, or be - lie is a poor man with a bunch of cows tryinir to make an living for his family. No man can make one honest dollar lin? dirty and dishonest milk, and no class of men will more ly applaud the energetic enforcement of proper food laws he clean farmers and clean dairymen who are smart enough t 1, iry to compel cleanliness in foods. In </seg>
            <seg id="p016">M to know that the enforcement of cleanliness and honesty in is important to the business success of food production. Nebraska hens. Mending to statistics from the Nd bureau of statistics are producing 100,000,000 dozen fresh annually. TV re worth $18,000,000 to the .Nebraska :t the price paid for them in their present condition. If properly eared for. marketed fresh and clean they won worth five cents per dozen more in the Eastern market and th would make them worth Bve cents per dozen more in the X market, and this tiv nts per dozen would mean $5,00000 to the value of the annual output This mistreatment of this great supply of the h. mrst producers, the hens, to the consumers, nktreatmei a {fathering and slow delivery from th tment by exposure to foul odors fioin kerosene ant in the back rooms and basements of the sjrocery st ment by the mixing of bad egga with the mod al nest to the egg expert in New York. Philadelph more who docks Nebl because they are that much below the stands atment of our N'ebras '.him i annually This tremendous waste in tht of the rights of the people in &gt;w • good eggs for their non should provide for a more thorough supervisi prosecutions and a good deal of newspaper abuse of eggs has don. ood. Th&gt; much improved condition, but more f&lt; bad &lt;-i:i; out of but id keep it out and should come in the way of additional help ment of this law. P'he activity of this department during these eighteen months it commenced business can be judged somewhat by the I table which shows that durinsr this time over 800 ion reported by the inspectors have been certified from this to the county attorneys of the state, and that from these cases reported for investigation and tboot MO prosecutions </seg>
            <seg id="p017">s 11 n reported from this office the prosecuting I and in som practically refused to court, on one theory or another, irenerally that hail not really violated the law, that they had it. and that they would not do it again. Tak- ve no complaint to make of the prosecutors as 1 &lt;lo that there is room for difference of opin - law should be put into effect, and realizing that i this office of these wrongs against food have learly the need for energetic action. Th icy to exeuM and overlook the tricks of dishonesty xplained away as l&gt;eintr a part of the '"business." ind every short weiirhter is ready with an ex - vrong complained of has grown up into a rule the "business" and should l&gt;e approached by any straint with irrent care lest the business nil - ■ interfered with. It has seemed to me that a x should not l'o down to adjust itself to the estabi should rather bring: the business up to the nuis should ever be tolerated on the t!i voted right this report 1 want to thank you, Governor Sheldon, iciieral Thompson, for the moral support you t rtment and this law. I want to thank the Nebraska •a ■ rendered valuable assistance by publicity. ule to protect the consuming: public can I the large concerns and set itself into effect fearless publicity. ■■•t fully submitted J. W. Johnson HOWIXG VIOLATIONS REPORTED BY INSPECT - AM) CERTIFIED TO COUNTY ATTORNEYS \ &lt;»i; Misbranded Butter </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">M I Dr til 11 : •&gt; s 1 1 pciitints. 34 12 i\ 1 1 \ megar Breakfast Foods 11 11 iham Flour 11 4 I Inspeetoi 1 1 1 1 1 1 Baking Powder lapioea. 3 i : Coffee 6 i' 4 li -&gt; (iirranis 1 1 i i • loeoanut : ? :{ :: Health Food Health Food o Sage -2 •_' •&gt; •&gt; B91 345 546 891 345 546 FINANCIAL STATEMENT. OFFICE EXPKNSKS. FINANCIAL STATEMENT OFFICE EXPENSES. hud July ")th. 1907 11,449.09 ■£2 nee July 5th, 1907 to Jan. 1st. 1909 972J1 &gt;n hand Jan. 1st. 19(»f» | 476.12 1908 _ | 476.12 TKLEPIIOXK. TKLEGRAPH AND SAI^VRY IF IN'SPKCTORP. expenses, tkljephotm, telegraph and salary of inspv:ctors hand July 5th, 1907 $15,8 \ lan. 1st, 1909 10,130.66 Fan. 1st. 190! ■ DEPUTV SALARY Amount &lt;m hainl -I nl v 5th. 190 $3,15 "2.700.00 o Jan. 1st .al </seg>
            <seg id="p020">91 tonal on hand .July 5th, 1901 mix .Inly 5th, littiT to Jan. 1st. 1 Balance on hand Jan. 1st, 190! TEXOCRAPHKR'S SALARY tininl mi hand July 5th, 190 Miy .Inly 5th, 1907 i" Jan. 1 Balance on hand -I [CENSE FKi titbit i &lt; • 1 1 I itern' Lii I- when ins|)i-ct tl3.. r i 4.1 M Duriiiir tilt E-cllsc tecs aihl till! mine into the ( ton d in tv 1 Deduct ill'-' tll'-si t by the department tin State hat) been only $9 nf *l.O25.1 h, it In these eighteen niDiitlis the laboratory iniseellaiieoii- articles, making in il 1 r-iiiniTV 1 1909 E7.63. Dnrii inuary 1st, 1 lama &lt;&gt;!' nir analyzeil SIS] nmplra "f creun :u 140 wamfim of drag*, 563 «am|&gt; </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>