<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00041">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00041</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  SPRAYING FRUIT IN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. SPRAYING FRUIT IN NEBRASKA. By J. Ralph Cooper. Distributed June 24, 1914. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD ■RABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. RABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. RABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. RABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. RABLE FRANK L. HALLER. Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LVFORD. Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS ■JEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc, Director of Extension Senice. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor THE WORKING STAFF Kad Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. Buss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. I Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. ence Bkunek, B. Sc, Entomology. Kiesrelbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. Flit. by, A. M., Farm Management. W. J. Morfiu., M. For., Forestry. •R. A. Emerson, D. Sc, Horticulture. G. A. Lovelavd, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Snyder. M. S., Superintendent of Experimental Substation. North Platte. *W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Associate in Soils and Crops, North Platte ; Assistant Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture. C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Entomology. PE K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Calvin, B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). » Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). Ratclifp, B. Sc. Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. Howard J. Gramlich. B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Sturdevant. A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward. A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc. Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc. Assistant in Experimental Agronomy James Cowan, M. E.. Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fkttz Kkorr. B. Sc. Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. •S. W. Perix. Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nve. Foreman Demonstration Farm. Cuibertson. ITHI HIOIUTI OF TH&lt; U«.V€««ITY&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 3 CONTENTS. PAGE Introduction _ 5 Sp raving machinery _ 7 Engine : _ 8 Pump . 9 Fungicides : Bordeaux mixture _10 Resin Bordeaux mixture 15 Lime-sulphur _ _ 15 Self-boiled lime-sulphur 20 Ammoniacal copper carbonate 21 Insecticides : Stomach poisons _ 21 Contact poisons _ 21 Lime-sulphur _ 22 Tobacco extract 22 Hellebore 22 Pyrethrum _ 22 General treatment for apples _ _ 22 General treatment for pears _26 General treatment for peaches _ _.27 General treatment for plums _ 26 General treatment for cherries „ 28 General treatment for grapes 29 General treatment for cane fruits _ 30 General treatment for currants and gooseberries _ 30 General treatment for strawberries 30 General treatment for all kinds of plants _ 30 General recommendations _ 31 Sorav calendar for apples 32 " * Spray calendar for pears - 33 Spray calendar for peaches _ 34 Spray calendar for plums _ 35 Spray calendar for cherries 35 Spray calendar for grapes 36 Spray calendar for cane fruits 36 Spray calendar for currants and gooseberries 37 Spray calendar for strawberries _ _ 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BY J. RALPH COOPER. INTRODUCTION. Ee most serious annoyance of the farmer, gardener, and orch - t of to-day is the liability of attacks upon his Crops by insect Fungous enemies. The crops are few, indeed, which are not ged by the depredation of one or more of these pests. Espe - is this true of orchard crops. This being the case, measures be taken to combat these common enemies, or the small profit discourage not only the continuance of fruit raising by the nt grower but its choice as a business by the prospective However, there is no reason why, with the present knowledge of spraying and culture, the fruit grower need fear these insects and fungous pests any more than he fears the weeds which begin grow - ing as soon as his crops are planted and with which he must wage unrelenting warfare if he is to realize any benefits from his labor. Proper spraying with the right materials at the right time will pro - tect the crops from insects and disease just as surely as good cul - tural methods will conserve moisture and protect the plants from There is always hesitation about trying the unknown. This is one reason why many men do not spray. Often they do not under - stand all the principles involved. They are not quite sure what mixture to apply or when to apply it, or why one time is not just as good as another for the application. The small degree of success of the neighbor who sprays is another reason. Perhaps he did not succeed in controlling the pests, and his fruit dropped. The fruit may have been injured from using the wrong material, too con - centrated a mixture, or from some cause entirely foreign to spray - ing, such as drouth, sun scald, or hail ; but this is not considered when judgment is being passed. I cess lies, first: In knowing what is causing injury to the second, in knowing the remedy for the trouble; and third, ng thoro treatment. In case of fruit trees, we find many ene - which appear at different seasons of the year, work in a differ - anner, and require different treatments. By using judgment, rer, in the combination of materials and time of application of &gt;, these may be all controlled. EXTENSION BUL. NO. 24, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Spraviiuj Fruit in Xcbraska For the money and labor invested, spraying yields larger returns than any other investment the fruit grower can make. Spraying materials are not expensive when compared with the benefits de - rived from their use. Material enough to spray the average tree, 20 to 25 years old, during the entire season, will cost from 10 to 1 -! rents. iiccordiii&lt;r 1n the mixture used, ami will vary from year to yiar as the cost of chemicals varies. Labor for applying four sj:rays will amount to about 12 to 14 cents a tree. This brings the total cost of labor and material for spraying up to 22 to 28 cents a tree. The outlay of, say, 25 cents for spraying will not only increase the yield, but give a better quality of fruit so that it will command a much higher price on the market. I late years there has been such a marked difference between lality of the sprayed and unsprayed fruit, especially apples, ne of the first questions asked by a prospective buyer is, you spray your fruit?" If the answer is in the negative, ances are that he will pass by the product of the unsprayed d as not worth considering. Fig. 1. — a, unsprayed fruit; h. sprayed fruit. Which kind have you in your orchard? Which kind do you prefer to have on your table? I loss from insects and fungi amounts to thousands of dollars ly to Nebraska growers. These pests not only cause the 3 become knotty, spotted, wormy, and to decay, but they in - : with the setting of the fruit by damaging the buds and ns. By the destruction of the foliage by insects or disease, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 7 the processes of elaborating plant food for the building of both the fruit and the plant are interfered with. In this bulletin will be found directions for combating the common and most injurious insects and diseases of our tree, vine, and small fruits. It is not always advisable, however, to follow these general directions exactly. The concentration of mixtures and number of treatments should be varied to meet special condi - tions. However, systematic and thoro spraying must be done every year, and it goes without saying that the orchard, vineyard, or small fruit patch must be well cultivated and pruned in order to obtain the best results from spraying. SPRAYING MACHINERY I most economical sprayer is one which delivers the mixture h a way as to cover the trees thoroly in the least possible Spraying may be done effectively by using a hand sprayer : quart capacity, Imt the time required for a thoro application great if much spraying is to be done. The things to be co:i - il in buying a spraying outfit are : size of the orchard to l&gt;e :d ; power of the outfit ; capacity and durability of the pump, extension rods, nozzles, and agitator. Kit;. 2. — One of the largest imwer •■units in a ynuiis orchard. While spray - ing larger trees, one man works trmm a tawar, fastfiuM to the sprayer. In onler to cover the tops tlioroly. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Spraying Fruit in Nebraska Gasoline power outfits (fig. 2) are now made in many sizes. They are usually designated by the number of nozzles which the capacity of the pump will supply. A two-nozzle (mist) outfit will usually deliver 3 to 4 gallons a minute. The capacity of the ma - chines range from this up to the six-nozzle types which deliver from 10 to 12 gallons a minute. These machines cost from $125 to $350, depending upon the capacity. Hand power sprayers (fig. 3) are cheapest and most practicable for orchards of less than 300 trees, unless labor is scarce. — A very efficient outfit for small orchards. One man can run the p, but two can maintain a better and more even pressure. The size of pump to purchase is determined largely by the time required to make the petal-fall application, since the time available for making this application is limited. Igine. — The engine should always be powerful enough to oper - le pump easily when running at full capacity. Engines which id upon speed for their power are more liable to give trouble those of slower revolution. However, engines are now so cted that little trouble is liable to occur, if the electrical con - 3ns are kept tight, batteries kept strong, and the supply of ine well regulated. The greatest enemies of the gasoline en - are a monkey wrench and an inquisitive disposition. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 9 Fig. 4. — l, duplex or two-cylinder pump; 2, triplex or three-cylinder pump: &lt;-, valves are easy to get at to clean; &lt;/, large air chamber; r, pressure gauge; /, cylinders are easily detached. Rmp. — A pump, to be satisfactory, should be made of such rial that the parts will not corrode by coming in contact with pray material. Bronze or brass resists all sprays but lime-sul- When using this mixture the pump should be thoroly washed out each night. The linings of the pump cylinders should be easily detachable so that they may be removed when worn. Enamel £ings are proving very satisfactory for pumps when lime-sulphur ■ays are used. ; </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 The air chamber (fig. 4, d) should be so large that the liquid ill be delivered in a steady stream. The cylinders (fig. 4, /) lould be large enough that the pump will not have to work faster lan 50 strokes a minute. At a higher speed than this the valves may not operate perfectly. Three cylinders give a more even pres - ure than two. Detachable valve seats (fig. 4, c) are necessary n order that the valves may be easily cleaned. A good relief valve fig. 5) is indispensable. It must be of large calibre and so ac - urately regulated that whether the nozzles are shut off or turned n, a steady pressure is maintained. A reliable pressure gauge fig. 4, e) is necessary and should read to at least 350 pounds. Hose which will withstand a pressure of 300 pounds is preferable fifty foot lengths are best) and should be equipped with coup - ings with long shanks (fig. 8) to prevent the hose from blowing ff. Bamboo extension rods with aluminum centers are superior o brass line^fr rods. Two sets of nozzles, Bordeaux (fig. f&gt;) and Mil (fig. 7) types, are necessary for satisfactory results. The ropeller type of agitator is the most efficient. Agitation is one of le most important factors to be considered in spraying. rg. 6. — Two types of Bordeaux noz - zles. Both are good. Nozzles of this type should be used for the rluxtrr-bntl and /iriitl-i'alt sprays and for the iturmunl application. KiR. 7. — The most common type of mist nozzles. FUNGICIDES. Bordeaux Mixture. — Bordeaux mixture is one of the oldest and most widely used of the common fungicides. It is more effect - ive than any other fungicide on apple scab, apple blotch, bitter rot, and black rot, and is fully as effective in the control of practically ft JJH ■ Lfe A C </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Fig. 8. — Nozzle protector. The spray mixture enters at u, and passes thru a screen at b&gt; Which removes all particles of solid matter too large to pass thru the nozzles. The hose is attached at It. When the screen becomes clogged, it may be cleaned by turning the all other fungous diseases which may be controlled by summer spraying. However, there is danger of burning the foliage and russeting the apples if used during prolonged wet weather or while the fruit is very young and tender. There is little danger of rus - seting apples after they are one-third grown. Small fruits and stopcock, c. i ! 4 A/ 9 7 Kig. 9. — A very good type of hose clamp and couplings. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Spraying Fruit in Nebraska ■J. — Three different types of reflllers. All work Is on the Injector prin - !. The refiller Is placed In the water, and by turning a stopcock on compression chamber, air is forced thru a hose a into the injector b returns thru c carrying with it a stream of water. grapes are, in most cases, not susceptible to Bordeaux injury. Bordeaux mixture is made by combining a solution of copper sulphate (blue vitriol) with a solution of lime. The copper is the active agent. The addition of lime neutralizes the injurious effect of the copper sulphate by combining with it to form copper hydrox - ide, which is insoluble in water. In this form, it adheres better to The ingredients are combined in various proportions, depending upon the season of the year and the kind of plants to be treated. Most varieties of apples and pears may be sprayed with a more concentrated solution than cherries and American or European plums. These fruits will bear, however, without injury, a stronger solution than peaches or Japanese varieties of plums. In fact, these last named fruits cannot be treated successfully with Bordeaux mixture. Standard Bordeaux is usually 4-4-50, or with poison included 4-4-2-50. This means that there are 4 pounds of copper sulphate, 4 pounds of lime, 2 pounds of arsenate of lead (when the poison is added), and water to make 50 gallons. When spraying with Bordeaux mixture it is desirable to have the copper sulphate and the lime in "stock solutions." These may be prepared by placing the copper sulphate in a clean gunny sack suspended in a barrel of water so that the crystals are just covered. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 13 FiC' 11' — Equipment for making Bordeaux. a, elevated water supply tank; '-. tank for diluting copper sulphate stock solution; c, tank for diluting lime solution; &lt;t and e, barrels for holding stock solution of copper sul - phate; / and a, barrels for holding stock solution of lime: A, mixing tank. This tank is unnecessary, since the dilute solutions from b and e may be run together directly into the sprayer tank. If this is done, the plat - forms need not be so high as are shown in the illustration. Rway it will dissolve very readily. The barrel should con - gallon of water for every pound of copper sulphate to be ed, so that 1 gallon of the stock solution will equal 1 pound _ per sulphate. The stock solution of lime may be made by slaking the lime and then adding water until there is in the solution 1 gallon of water for every pound of lime. Fresh stone lime gives the best results, but if not obtainable a fair grade of Bordeaux may be made by using hydrated lime (never use air-slaked), but in this </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Spraying Fruit in Nebraska case one and one-half times as much lime must be used as would be used of stone lime. After slaking, lime may be kept for several weeks if kept covered with water. The copper sulphate and lime must be brought together in very dilute solutions for the best results. Spray mixtures are spoken of in terms of 50 gallons. If a 4-4-50 Bordeaux is desired, take 4 gallons of the copper sulphate solution and add water to make 25 gallons. Treat the lime in a similar manner. Pour, or let these two run, together into a third con - tainer or directly into the sprayer tank. The mixture must alway- Fig. 12. — A side view of the same equipment, a, elevated water supply tank; 6, lank for diluting copper sulphate solution; &lt;/, and e, barrels for holding stock solution of copper sulphate; A, mixing tank. be strained before going into the tank. Never attempt to mix the stock solutions without first diluting them. Bordeaux may be </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 tested by dropping into the mixture a very little ferrocyanide of potassium. (Ten cents worth dissolved in a pint of water will last a season.) If a reddish-brown color apj&gt;ears, more lime must be added. Another simple test is to take a piece of iron or steel, newly filed or ground, and hold it in the mixture for about a minute. If a copper color can be detected when it is removed, more lime should be added. Another way to determine whether or not there is sufficient lime in the mixture is to pour some of it into a flat dish and blow on it for a few minutes. If a film forms on the surface, enough lime is present ; if not, more should be added. !in or iron containers should never be used for copper sulphate Bordeaux solutions unless lined with some substance which will 5t the action of the material Vessels made of wood, crockery. &gt;orcelain will answer the purpose. Copper sulphate will destroy els of tin or iron in a very short time, and besides dissolving metal, will spoil the Bordeaux. E'hen spraying with Bordeaux mixture, it is often desirable to some insecticide at the same time. This may be done by com - lg 2 pounds of arsenate of lead with every 50 gallons of the ure. Resin BoantAUX IflXTCTE. — This is the standard spray for blackberries, raspberries, and other cane fruits. Boil together until the brown color appears, then add the fore - going to each 50 gallons of Bordeaux mixture, made according to the 5-5-50 formula. (&amp;ee page 12.) The reason for using the resin mixture is to cause the Bordeaux to spread and adhere better. Lime-Sulphur. — Lime-sulphur can be purchased in a concen - trated form, or it can be made at home. This solution has come to be widely used as a summer fungicide. It is also used as a con - tact insecticide in some cases. For dormant spraying (a spray before growth starts in the spring) for the control of San Jose scale, and some other insects of similar habits, it is superior to any other spray. As a summer spray, lime-sulphur is a preventive against apple scab and many less important summer diseases. How - ever, it is not nearly so effective against apple blotch and bitter rot us Bonoesux mixture In sections wnere these cii senses 3 re ore v*i- Kesin 1 poum Salsoda crystals ]/&gt; pound Water y 2 gallor </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Spraying Fruit in Nebraska lent. Bordeaux must be used. Bordeaux must also be used in the control of grape diseases, since lime - sulphur proves very injuri - ous to the foliage of that plant. The reason for us - ing lime-sulphur instead of Bordeaux in spraying ap - ples is that it is somewhat less injurious to the fruit. As a rule, apples sprayed with lime-sulphur are not russeted, and therefore, have a better color than those sprayed with Bor - deaux. However, in locali - ties where weather is hot and dry, lime-sulphur usu - ally causes more severe in - jury during the latter Fig. IS. — A convenient equipment for making home-boiled lime-sulphur. sprayings than Bordeaux mixture. Lime-sulphur injury on the fruit can readily be told from Bordeaux injury from the fact that it produces a deeper and more continuous burn than the Bordeaux, which usually causes but a superficial russeting. On the foliage, lime-sulphur injury appears almost immediately after spraying; while in the case of Bordeaux mixture the injury never appears for several days after the spraying is done. In making homemade lime-sulphur, when a tester is not avail- able, the proportions of lime-sulphur and water according to the most recent investigations are : Lime (unslaked high grade) 50 pounds Sulphur (flour or flowers) 100 pounds Water to make 50 gallons total product when boiled. First slake the lime in enough water, preferably warm, to cause first a thick and later a very thin paste (ten gallons is enough to start with), strain and pour into the kettle or boiling vat (fig. 13), add the dry sulphur, and mix it thoroly, adding enough water to maintain a thin paste. The sulphur should be sifted so that there will be no lumps. After the materials are thoroly mixed, add water to the amount of about 50 gallons, as shown by the measuring stick, or a mark on the side of the boiler, and boil, stirring until the scum disappears. Add water to make 60 (more must be added during warm weather) gallons and boil down to 50 gallons. The mixture must be vigorously stirred while boiling. As a rule, 60 minutes of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 17 vigorous boiling is sufficient where the mixture is cooked over a fire. If steam is used, 30 minutes is usually sufficient. In either the mixture must be constantly and thoroly agitated mechan- i-n!1\\ Properly made lime-sulphur is an amber colored liquid, and there should be very little sediment. It does not pay to overboil, for this only adds to the ex- pense and does not benefit the mixture. In order to secure the best results, the lime should be tested. An excess of either lime or I bi In sulphur must be avoided. An excess of sul- phur causes an increase of sediment. An excess of lime causes the solution to crystalize easily, and also causes an increase of sediment. According to the Bosworth formula, the pro- portions, when the purity of the lime is known, s' are as follows : Lump lime pure calcium oxide 36 lbs. Lump lime 95 per cent 38 lbs. Lump lime 90 per cent ' 40 lbs. - %&gt; '■'■a Sulphur 98 per cent pure or over 80 lbs. Water 50gals. It will thus be seen that when lime contains im- purities, more must be used. Amount of lime to use when percentage of purity is known : Percentage of purity. Number of pounds of lime to use. 100 36 95 38 90 40 85 42 80 45 75 48 70 51 65 55 60 60 55- 66 50 72 The apparatus required for testing consists of a 2-quart porcelain or granite vessel, a spoon or ladle of the same material, a rod (for stirring and measuring on which is a mark to indicate the point where the surface of the water stands Tit- 14- — Geneva lime tester for determln Ing purity of lime. when 1 quart is placed in the dish and the rod placed vertically in the water, one end resting </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 on the bottom of the dish), a Geneva Station lime tester (fig. 14), (a special form of hydrometer), and a glass cylinder about 2J/2 inches in diameter and 15 inches high, graduated to hold a quart. The test is made as follows : Weigh out 2 ounces of lime, place it in the boiling vessel, and slake, adding the water gradually. Care should be taken not to smother the lime with too much water. Stir until the lime is thorolv slaked and a thick paste is formed. Then add water enough to fill to the mark on the rod, place over the fire, and boil. Weigh out 4 1 _&gt; ounces of fine, high-grade flowers of sulphur; and when the lime begins to boil, add the sulphur grad - ually, stirring vigorously with the spoon. Allow the mixture to 1 oil gently for an hour, stirring, most of the time, to dissolve any lumps of sulphur. Measure the height of the mixture about every 10 minutes by means of the rod, and if the level of the liquid has dropped below the mark add enough hot water to bring the level back. After boiling one hour, allow the mixture to cool to atmos - pheric temperature and then, after stirring thorolv. pour quickly into the glass cylinder, being careful to get in all the sediment. Do not pour the hot solution into the cylinder for it will break it. Add enough water to bring the mixture up to the quart mark. Pour back into the dish and stir in order to mix in the water thoroly. Now. return again to the cylinder and allow to remain until all sediment has settled to the bottom of the cylinder. Xow introduce the lime tester. The reading obtained at the level of the liquid on the scale is the percentage of purity of the lime. The reading on the other scale gives the number of pounds of lime to use in the ( ieneva Station formula in order to have the equivalent 36 pounds &lt; f pure lime. The tester must not be left in the solution after the reading is obtained. It should be removed and washed clean with water. If the solution is allowed to dry on the tester it will give incorrect readings. I fore using, any lime-sulphur solution, either commercial or made, should be tested. In determining the strength of lime - ur it may be reckoned either in the terms of specific gravity, :grees Baume. By consulting the following table, dilutions be made using either a Baume or specific gravity hydrometer 15). m -* ■Those Instruments with a range of 0 to 36° Baume or 1.000 to 1.330 »-&gt;eclflc gravity are recommended for this work. They can be purchased from the Bauach * Lomb Optical Company, Rochester, N. T., or Elmer * Amend, New York City. The price* range from $1.25 to 11.76. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 / TABLES COMPARING BAUME'S HYDROMETER AND SPL ECIFIC GRAVITIES. Degrees Specific Baume gravity Degrees Baume Specific Degrees Specific gravity Baume gravity gravity 0.0 1.0000 1.10691 27.0 1.2288 14.0- 1.0 1.0069 1.1154 28.0 1.2393 15.0- 1.1240 29.0 1.2500 2.0 1.0140 16.0- 1.13281 30.0 1.2609 3.0 1.0211 17.0- 1.1417 31.0 1.2719 4.0 -.1.0284 18.0- ■ ■••• cb ,..- 1.0357 19.0- 1.1508 32.0 1.2832 6.0- •■••■•••1.0432 20.0- 1.1600 33.0 1.2946 7.0 1.0507 21.0- 1.1694 34.0 1.3063 8.0 1.0584 22.0- 1.1789 35.0 1.3182 9.0 1.0662 23.0- 1.1885 36.0 1.3303 10.0 1.0741 24.0- 1.1983 37.0 1.3426 11.0 1.0821 25.0- 1.2083 38.0 1.3551 26.0- 1.2185 39.0 1.3679 12.0 1.0902 40.0 1.3810 13.0 1.0985 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Usually lime-sulphur should not be used of a strength greater than 1.008 specific gravity. To determine this specific gravity of the concentrated lime-sulphur, lower the hydrometer into a deep glass cylinder filled with lime-sulphur and note the reading just at the top of the liquid. The number of dilutions to make are obtained as follows : Divide the decimal of the concentrate by the decimal of the spray de - sired. The quotient will be the number of dilu - tions. Example: The concentrated solution has a specific gravity of 1.283. It is desired to use a solution with a specific gravity of 1.008. The decimal is .008. The decimal of the concentrate .283 divided by the decimal .008 equals 35.3, which is the number of dilutions and which is obtained by adding 34.3 gallons of water to 1 gallon of the concentrated solution. If a hydro - meter with only the Baume reading is used, it is sufficiently accurate to make as many dilutions plus two, as the hydrometer test shows in de - grees. Thus, if the test shows a concentration of 32° Baume, 33 gallons of water should be added to every gallon of lime-sulphur solution. This will equal 34 dilutions. It will thus be seen that the use of the hydrometer makes it possible to be accurate in making the dilutions. It also makes it possible to know the value of lime - sulphur purchased. If a barrel of lime-sulphur shows a specific gravity of 1.250 or a Baume test of 29°, and another should show a specific gravivty of 1.306, or a Baume test of 34°, the lat - ter would be worth about one-fifth more than the former. For the greater the specific gravity the greater will be the amount of sulphur com - pounds in the solution and consequently the more valuable the lime-sulphur. Fig. 15. — HyJro- meter for test - 1 n g lime-iul- f?-BoiLED Lime-sulphur. — This is the rd summer spray for peaches and other which have very tender foliage. It is than dilute lime-sulphur solutions as it phur. Should read in term* of both specific gravity and de- grees Baumt.' will not injure foliage. It is formula: made according to the following Lime (unslaked) 8 pounds. Sulphur (flour or flowers) 8 pounds. Water 50 gallons. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 The lime should be placed in a barrel and enough water added almost to cover it. As soon as the lime begins to slake, the sulphur should be added. Having first been made into a thin paste by stir - ring in a small quantity of water, the mixture should be stirred and more water added as needed to form a thick paste at first and then gradually a thin paste. The heat from the slaking lime will cook the mixture in from 10 to 15 minutes. If allowed to cook too long, compounds will form which will burn the foliage. As soon as the solution has cooked sufficiently, fill up the barrel to the 50-gallor. mark with cold water. Do not use hot water in making this mixture. Ammoniacal Copper Carbonate. — It is sometimes necessary to spray fruit, especially grapes, when ripe, and the use of Bordeaux mixture at that time would stain the fruit. Under such conditions, ammoniacal copper carbonate may be substituted. Dissolve the copper carbonate (6 ounces) in 30 pints of strong ammonia (26° Baume) and add water to make 50 gallons. INSECTICIDES. There are two important groups of insecticides : Stomach poisons, which cause death by being eaten by insects; and contact poisons, which cause death by coming in contact with the bodies of the Stomach Poisons. — This group of poisons is intended for insects which chew and swallow portions of the foliage or fruit. It may be placed upon the exposed surfaces, where the insects usually feed, either while they are present or before they arrive. These poisons must necessarily be exposed to the weather for a consider - able period of time — hence, it is imperative that they adhere to the foliage, and that they do not deteriorate upon being exposed to the air. Arsenic put up in the form of arsenate of lead is, in general, the most satisfactory stomach poison on the market. This form of arsenic has been adopted because it has so small an amount of water-soluble arsenic acid, that it does not burn the foliage or fruit, and because it adheres exceedingly well. It is most commonly sold in paste form, containing about 50 per cent of water. Two pounds of this paste to 50 gallons of water, are sufficient in spraying apples. In spraying grapes and small fruits it is sometimes necessary to use more poison. E using arsenate of lead, great care must be taken to reduce it very thin paste before it is poured into the spray tank. As as the lead is emptied into the tank, the contents should be ly agitated in order to insure the proper mixing of the ma- Contact Poisons. — This group of poisons is intended for insects </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 which suck rather than chew. Since poisons can be placed only on the surface of the plants and these insects feed below the surface, they are not destroyed by spraying with stomach poisons, but must be combated by something which kills by coming in contact with the bodies of the insects. Lime-Sulphur. — This is one of the most valuable of the con- Krays, especially for the San Jose scale, and for general dor - spraying. For dormant spraying, as a rule, 11 dilutions :d or 1 gallon of concentrated lime-sulphur (32 Baume) to 10 gallons of water. Tobacco Extract. — Sulphate of tobacco or Black -leaf 40, as it E:ommonly known, is a / verv valuable contact insecticide. It is erally used at the rate of 1 pint to 125 gallons of water, but it 'ell to follow the directions furnished by the manufacturer. Com - l Black-leaf is only about one- fourteenth as strong as Black- Tobacco extract may be made at home as follows Tobacco stems 1 pound Water 2 gallons The tobacco should be placed in water and brought to a boil, after which it should be allowed to simmer for an hour, then water added to make 2 gallons. Hellebore. — White hellebore is the powdered root of a plant. It kills both by contact and as an internal poison. It may be applied either dry or in the form of a liquid. When used dry, it should be mixed with 3 or 4 times its weight of flour or plaster and then dusted on the insects. Applied wet, 1 pound should be mixed with 25 gallons of water and this liquid applied as a spray. In the pur - chase of this insecticide, care should be taken to see that it is fresh, as it quickly loses its effectiveness upon exposure. Pyrethrum. — This remedy has one drawback, its cost. It is too J J r expensive for use on a large scale. It kills insects thru their breath - ing pores, but is harmless to man and beast. It will kill many of the insects of the garden if dusted on or applied as a spray at the rate of 1 ounce to 2 gallons of water. Use the powder when it is undesirable to use poison, but never Bany unless it comes in tightly sealed packages. It loses its gth on such short exposure to the air that an hour is time jh to weaken it. It must be applied from time to time, as it quickly loses its strength. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR APPLES. Spraying is done to protect the trees and fruit from insect and </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Sprayiny Fruit in Nebraska 23 fungous enemies which attack them thruout the growing period. In order to secure thoro protection, it is necessary to keep both fruit and foliage well coated by a protective covering, especially when most susceptible to injury. Too much time and money are required to spray for each individual enemy, but fortunately by spraying for the most serious insects and diseases, the minor ones are also con - trolled in a large measure by the proper mixing and application of the spray materials. For the best results, the number of sprays must be concentrated at the beginning of the season in such a manner as to keep both fruit and foliage covered while young. There are certain times when spraying will be more efficient than ;it any other period, and these dates should always be kept in mind. ■•"&gt;. — Apple buils at just stage for the chute r the hint Fig. 17. — Apple buds too nearly open to spray. The first or cluster-bud sfra\, which is intended to combat apple scab, black rot, curculio, and early leaf eating insects, should be applied with Bordeaux nozzles, as coarse, driving mist under 200 to 225 pounds pressure, just as the flower buds are separating and "showing pink" (fig. 16). This spraying may consist of a lime - sulphur solution (specific gravity 1.009) plus arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water; or Bordeaux mixture plug arsenate of lead, 4-6-2-50 (4 pounds of copper sulphate, 6 pounds of lime, and 2 pounds of arsenate of lead with water to make 50 gallons). Bordeaux is preferable to lime-sulphur for this spray. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Spraying Fruit in Nebraska Fig. is. — The proper time to apply the i&gt;&lt;lal-/till spray. Fig. 19. — Too late to apply the i»ial - jull spray. Calyxes are almost closed. The second or petal-fall spray, which is intended to control cod - ling moth, curculio, apple scab, rust, black rot, and other less im - portant insects and diseases, should be applied with Bordeaux noz - zles from above as a coarse, driving spray under 225 to 250 pounds pressure as soon as the petals have fallen. Where a large area is to be covered, it is well to begin when three-fourths of the petals have fallen (fig. 18). This spray should consist of Bordeaux mixture plus arsenate of lead (2-3-2-50), or of lime-sulphur ("specific gravity 1.008), plus 2 pounds of arsenate of lead to 50 gallons of water. Lime-sulphur is preferable for this appli - cation, since Bordeaux is liable to burn some varieties of apples if applied at this time. This application must be thoro and fill all the calyxes with poison, since 80 to 85 per cent of the codling moth are controlled by this spray alone if the work is well done. The calyxes should be examined occasionally to be sure the spray is being driven inside. The third or three-weeks' spray, which is intended to control codling moth, curculio. lesser apple worm, apple scab, apple blotch, black rot, etc., should be applied as a fine mist under high pressure, 3 to 4 weeks after the petals have fallen (fig. 18). By this time the spray material from the second application will have been par - tially washed away. New unprotected surfaces are appearing and the first brood of codling moth larvae are hatching. This spray </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 25 should consist of lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.008) plus arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, unless ap - ple blotch is present, when Bor - deaux should be substituted. If the weather is damp at the time when this spray should be ap - plied, it will be safer to use lime-sulphur and to follow with Bordeaux a week or two later. In any case, a spray of Bor - deaux, 3-4-50, should be applied 5 weeks after the petals fall if apple blotch is especially prev - alent. Fl«. 20. — Time to apply th« three nab' apray. Sie curculio becomes serious, the third spray should be applied s to 2 weeks after the blossoms fall, and another spray ap - ! to 3 weeks later, especially if blotch also appears and the apple worm becomes serious. B fourth or second-brood spray may consist of arsenate of one, 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, if no fungous diseases :sent. This spray is intended to control the second brood of I moth larvae and for the lesser apple worm, and should be I as a mist just before the second brood of codling moth larvae Fig. 21.— A combination of spray injury and sun scald. begin hatching (see note), which comes in this state, as a rule, from the latter part of July to the middle of August. If fungous dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 ■are present, some fungicide must be used, preferably lime - r (specific gravity 1.008) under ordinary conditions, but, the weather be extremely hot and dry, or blotch or bitter present, Bordeaux (3-4-50) should be used. Note. — To determine the date of appearance of the second brood of codling moth, band a number of trees during the month of June, prefer - ably unsprayed ones, with strips of burlap from 4 to 6 inches wide. Leave the bands loose at the bottom. Examine for codling moth cocoons during July. Remove any cocoons found, by cutting out a small piece of the cloth to which it is fastened. Place the cocoons into a glass cylinder open at top and bottom (a lantern globe will do) and cover the top with fine screen to prevent the escape of the moths. This cage should be set on soil which is kept slightly moist and should be protected from rain and sun. As soon as the majority of the moths have emerged, the second-brood spray should be applied; for the moths deposit eggs as soon as they appear, and the young worms hatch in from 5 to 10 days. B-ing excessively hot, dry seasons, the codling moth multiplies rapidly, and a partial third brood may appear, as was the he season just passed (1913). Krder to control this brood, an additional or third-brood spray - arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water is some - necessary about August 15 to 25. If the orchard is in a where bitter rot is serious, Bordeaux mixture (3-4-50) be used with the arsenate of lead spray. In case San Jose scale is present in an orchard, a dormant spray should be applied just before the buds begin to swell. This spray should consist of lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.028 or 4° Baume). This will also control to some extent oyster-shell scale lice, woolly aphis, and other fruit tree aphids, besides destroying certain insect eggs and fungous spores. It "cleans up" the trees, and disinfects bark wounds as well as those made in pruning. The efficiency of dormant spraying depends largely upon the thoroness of the appli - cation. It is important to cover every particle of the surface from the ground to the tips of the twigs. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR PEARS. I ply the same general treatment to pears as is given for apples ! earlier part of the season except that in case lime-sulphur is it should not be as strong as for apples. The specific gravity d not as a rule exceed 1.006. The first spray, which is intended for the control of scab, curculio, leaf feeding insects, etc., should be applied just before the blossoms open, as with apples, and should consist of Bordeaux mixture plus arsenate of lead (3-4-2-50), or of lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.008) plus arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 I second or petal-fall spray, which is intended for the control ing moth, curculio, pear slug, scab, leaf blight, and other minor and diseases, should be applied in the same manner as the all spray for apples and should consist of Bordeaux plus te of lead (2-3-2-50) or of lime-sulphur (specific gravity plus arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water. As pples, lime-sulphur is preferable to Bordeaux for this spray. The third spray should consist of the same materials as the second spray and should be applied about 3 weeks after the petals fall. R fourth spray of arsenate of lead, 2 pounds to 50 gallons of should be applied at the same time as the second brood of moth spray for apples. Dormant spraying with the same materials and at the same time as used for apples may be practiced with pears with good results. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR PEACHES. ■ first spray, which is intended to control the curculio and leaf eating insects, may consist of arsenate of lead, 2 pounds gallons of water, and should be' applied as soon as the calyx (shuck) has dropped (fig. 22, a) from the little peach. The life history of the curculio in the peach is the same as that in the apple except that a larger percent - age of the larvae reach the adult stage, and because the curculio prefers the peach to the apple, it is a more serious pest on this fruit. The second spray, which is intended to control the curculio, brown rot, and scab of the peach, and minor insects and diseases, should consist of self-boiled lime-sulphur (8-8-50) plus 2 pounds of arsenate of lead and should be applied 2 to 3 weeks after the calyx has dropped. Commercial lime-sulphur should never be used as a summer spray on peaches on account of the danger of burning. This applies also to Japanese plums. Fig. 12. — a, peach from which the shuck ia just ready to drop: h, cherry at same stage of growth. The third spray, which is intended to control peach scab and brown rot, should consist of self-boiled lime-sulphur and should be applied 3 weeks later. Add poison if insects are present. A fourth spray, consisting of the same material, should be ap- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 * J j ■to late varieties of peaches one month before ripening, if rot is present. Treat the scale insects on peaches the same as for apples. It is sometimes advisable to apply a spray of lime-sulphur (specific grav - ity 1.028) to peaches just before the buds swell to prevent leaf curl. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR PLUMS. 1 first spray, which is intended for the control of curculio, leaf or shot hole fungus and minor diseases and leaf eating should consist of Bordeaux mixture plus arsenate of lead 50) or of lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.006) plus arsenate 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, (on Japanese varieties use led lime-sulphur plus 2 pounds of arsenate of lead) and be applied just as soon as the calyx tube is off the young ■e second spray, which is intended to control the before-men - 1 insects and diseases, also brown rot, should consist of the materials and should be applied about two to three weeks later. ■brown rot becomes serious, later sprayings of Bordeaux mix - lime-sulphur, or self -boiled lime-sulphur should be applied at als of two to three weeks. ■ 'tnant sprayings, just as the buds begin to swell, may be prac - with plums as well as with peaches. ■iphids appear on the leaves at any time, a thoro spraying with :o extract will destroy them if applied before the leaves curl. Tobacco Extract, page 22.) GENERAL TREATMENT FOR CHERRIES. IE first spray, which is intended to control leaf spot, powdery w, and minor diseases and leaf eating insects, may consist of :aux mixture plus arsenate of lead (2-3-2-50) or of lime - ur (specific gravity 1.006) plus 2 pounds of arsenate of lead, spray should be applied just before the blossoms open. The second spray, which is intended to control curculio, pear slugs, powdery mildew, leaf spot, and minor leaf eating insects, should consist of the same materials as for the first spray and should be applied just as soon as the calyx tube is off (fig. 22, b) the young fruit. B third spray consisting of the same materials may be applied weeks later if necessary. For aphids, treat the same as plums. It may become necessary to spray with arsenate of lead for insects after the fruit is harvested. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 GENERAL TREATMENT FOR GRAPES. K first spray for grapes, which is intended to control black rot, cnose, downy mildew, and leaf feeders, should be applied the new shoots are 8 to 10 inches long, and should consist of aux plus arsenate of lead, 5-5-3-50. Never use lime-sulphur ipes, for even in dilute form it injures the foliage. The second spray, which is intended to assist in the control of the above insects and diseases, should consist of the same materials and should be applied just before the blossoms open. The third spray of the same materials as the second spray should should be applied just as the last blossoms are falling. Pe fourth spray of the same materials should be applied 10 to 2 weeks later. Subsequent sprays of the same materials be applied at intervals of 10 days to 2 weeks if needed. Where the grape-root worm becomes a serious pest, the vines should be sprayed with Bordeaux mixture plus arsenate of lead (5-5-5-50), or with arsenate of lead and water (to which a quart of molasses has been added) to make 50 gallons. Bordeaux acts as a re - pellent and causes the beetles to seek unsprayed leaves, so the spray - ing must be done thoroly. Molasses added to arsenate of lead makes it more appetizing and causes more poison to be eaten. The poison should be applied as soon as the beetles begin to appear, which is usually after the middle of June. This may be ascertained by watching for the first signs of the chain-like feeding marks on the leaves. One or more additional sprays may be necessary at inter - vals of a week to 10 days. The grape-root worm is much more destructive in vineyards where insufficient cultivation is given. Much may be done toward con - trolling the insect by cultivation at the time when the insect is in its pupal stage. In this state the insects usually begin to pupate about the 1st to the 15th of June. The majority of these insects pupate 2 to 3 inches below the surface of the ground and within a radius of 1 or 2 feet of the vine. At this time they are soft and helpless, the earthen cells are readily broken, and the pupae crushed or exposed to the weather. This is facilitated if, at the last culti - vation in the fall, a ridge is thrown up 12 to 14 inches on each side of the row and 3 to 4 inches high. The majority of the insects will pupate in this ridge, and it may be easily torn down. One spraying with Bordeaux and arsenate of lead during the middle of July may be necessary if the grape berry moth becomes serious. The Bordeaux acts as a repellent to the moth besides con - trolling fungous diseases. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 For grape leaf hopper, spraying with tobacco extract is effective. B prevent staining the fruit, ammoniacal copper carbonate may •d instead of Bordeaux for the late sprayings where a fungi - s necessary. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR CANE FRUITS. (Blackberries, raspberries, dewberries, loganberries, etc.) The first summer spray, for the control of anthracnose and leaf feeders, should consist of resin Bordeaux mixture (See resin Bor - deaux mixture, page 15) plus arsenate of lead 3 pounds to 50 gallons, and should be applied when the young canes are 10 to 12 inches high. ■ second spray of the same material should be applied 2 weeks and if other sprays are necessary they may be applied at ils of 2 weeks during the growing season. I eases in cane fruits are best controlled by rotation and selec - of plants. When orange rust appears, the affected plants d be cut out at once. Various insects may be sprayed for arsenicals as they appear, but if near picking time use helle- Dr pyrethrum. Cut out and burn tree cricket eggs, borers, etc. ERAL TREATMENT FOR CURRANTS AND GOOSEBERRIES. Ee first spray, which is intended to control mildew, leaf spot, foliage eating insects, should be of Bordeaux mixture plus ate of lead (5-5-2-50) and should be applied as soon as the Subsequent sprayings with the same materials may be applied at intervals of 10 days to 2 weeks if necessary. For insects alone, use arsenate of lead 2 pounds to 50 gallons of GENERAL TREATMENT FOR STRAWBERRIES. Ier growth starts in the spring, spray with Bordeaux mixture irsenate of lead (5-5-2-50) at intervals of 10 days or 2 weeks there is danger of discoloring the fruit. 1ST the fruit is picked, mow off the tops and burn over quickly, ground is moist. Injury may result if burned during hot, dry :r. Choose a day when there is a light wind to avoid burn - : crowns of the plants. Spray with Bordeaux and arsenate of s soon as growth starts again. GENERAL TREATMENT FOR ALL KINDS OF PLANTS. Br all leaf eating insects such as caterpillars, slugs, beetles, etc., with arsenate of lead 2 to 3 pounds to 50 gallons of water as as the insects appear. One pound of soap added to 50 gallons e above solution will cause it to spread and adhere much better. For sucking insects, such as aphids or plant lice, spray with some </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Spraying Fruit in Nebraska 31 Bof tobacco extract, (See Tobacco Extract, page 22), or soap nds to 50 gallons of water as soon as the lice appear. Do ait until the leaves begin to roll. K scale insects, such an San Jose, oyster-shell, and scurfy spray with lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.028) before the art in the spring. GENERAL RECOMMENDATIONS. Bhas already been stated, high pressure is essential in spraying . especially for the petal-fall application. At this time the must be forced into all the calyx cups. This necessitates iray being applied in coarser drops than for the later sprays. The spray should be applied by a sweeping or stroking motion of the rod beginning at the ends of the limbs and following down toward the trunk with the spray directed in and down. This will insure the trunk and center of the tree being well covered by the time the outside and top are finished. Wormy fruit is the result more often of poor spraying than of an insufficient amount of poison in the spray. Iider ordinary circumstances, Bordeaux causes more spray in - than lime-sulphur, except for the cluster-bud and other sprays n the season. Bordeaux should never be used during a pro - d period of wet weather or soon after the fruit has set. I.ime - ur should not be used during a period of excessively hot, dry tier. The spray for the dormant, the cluster-bud, and the petal-fall applications should be put on as a coarse, driving mist, by using Bordeaux nozzles, and the remaining applications as a fine mist. Coarse sprays under high pressure may cause burning if used after the fruit has set. Iray mixtures should be always strained before being placed e spray tank to remove any particles which will not readily thru the nozzles. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 WHEN TO SPRAY , FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE San Jose scale, Coarse mist of lime-sul - phur ( specific gravity 1.028. Use Bordeaux noz - zles and 200 to 225 lbs. pressure. Just as the buds oyster-shell scale, begin to swell — if woolly aphis, and to needed. Called the assist in preventing dormant spray. the spreading of can- ker infection. Coarse mist of Bordeaux plus arsenate of lead (4-6 - 2-50), or of lime-sulphur (specific gravity 1.009) plus arsenate of lead 2 lbs. to 50 gals, of mixture. Bordeaux is preferable. Use Bordeaux nozzles on 45 degree crooks and 200 to 225 lbs. pressure. As soon as the buds in the clusters Scab, black rot, begin to separate and curculio, and leaf turn pink. Cluster- eating insects. hud spray. Coarse mist of lime-sul - phur (specific gravity 1.008) plus arsenate of lead 2 lbs. to 50 gals, of mixture. Use Bordeaux nozzles on 45 degree crooks and 225 to 250 lbs. pressure. Just as the petals Codling moth, cur - have fallen. The culio, scab, rust, petal-fall spray. black rot, and leaf eating insects. Fine mist of lime-sul - phur (specific gravity 1.008) plus arsenate of lead 2 lbs. to 50 gals, of mixture, or if blotch is ser - ious and weather will per - mit, use Bordeaux plus ar - senate of lead (3-4-2-50) unless the five-weeks' spray is used. Use mist nozzles and 200 to 225 lbs. pressure. Three to 4 weeks Codling moth, cur - after the petals have cu ij Oj lesser apple fallen. Three-weeks' WO rm, scab, black spray. rot, blotch, and leaf eating insects. Fine mist of Bordeaux (3-4-50). Include poison if necessary. Apply same as three-weeks' spray. Five weeks after the petals fall, if Same as for three blotch i s serious, weeks' spray. Five-weeks' spray. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 SPRAY CALENDAR FOR APPLES— (Continued). WHEN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE Fine mist of lime-sul- phur (specific gravity Just before 2d brood o f codling moth appears. ( See "General Treatment for Apples," page 22.) Second-brood 1.008) plus arsenate of lead 2 lbs. to 50 gals, of Second brood of water, or Bordeaux plus codling moth, lesser arsenate of lead (3-4-2 - apple worm, bitter 50). Bordeaux is prefer - rot, and sooty blotch able if rot is present or if weather is hot and dry. Use mist nozzles and 200 in 225 lbs. pressure. E« "General tment for Ap - ' page 26. Third - i spray. Third brood of cod ling moth, when pres- The same as for the we - ent. ond-brood spra\. SPRAY CALENDAR FOR PEARS. WHKN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE Just as the buds be- gin to swell. Dor- Same as dormant Same as dormant spray mant sprav. spray for apples. for apples. Coarse mist of Bordeaux plus arsenate of lead, (3- Just as the blossoms '• Scab, curculio, and 4-2-50), or lime-sulphu: begin to show pink, j leaf feeders. (specific gravity 1.008) Cluster-bud spray. plus 2 lbs. arsenate of lead to 50 gals, of mixture Coarse mist of Bordeaux, plus arsenate of lead, (2 - 3-2-50), or lime-sulphur plus arsenate of lead as foi" cluster-bud spray. (See "General Treatment foi Pears," page 26.) Just as soon as the Codling moth, cur - petals have fallen, culio, pear slug leaf Petal-fall spray. blight, scab, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 SPRAY CALENDAR FOR PEARS— (Continued). WIIKN TO SPRAY I FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE ■ ree weeks after Same as for petal - l&gt;etals fall. Three fall spray. Same as for petal-fall spray, applied as a tine mist! week* spray. (See "General Treatment for Second brood of Pears," page 26.) i codling moth. Arsenate of lead 2 lbs. to SO gals, of water, applied as a tine mist. Second-brood spray. SPRAY CALENDAR FOR PEACHES. WHIN Tl) SPRAY I KIR WHAT To SPRAY WHAT TO USE Same as for apples. ( Set- Before buds swell. Same as for applet, "(ieneral Treatment for Dtrmml spray. Applet," page 22.) Arsenate of lead 2 U&gt;s. to as UK calyx Curculio and leaf 50 gals, of water, applied cks) drop. eating insects. u a m i s t. Self-boiled lime-sulphur tfo to 3 weeks af- Curculio. peach scab, (8-8-50) plus 2 lbs. *ne» calyx tube drops, and brown rot. ate of lead, applied a-- a mist. Self-boiled lime-sulphur Five to 6 weeks af- Peach scab and (8-8-501 applied as a mist ter calyx tubes drop brown rot. Include poison, if M sarv. One month before Same material and man ner of application as fore- ripening, (on late va- Brown rot. going. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 SPRAY CALENDAR FOR PLUMS. WHIN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE \\ liile dormant. See See peaches. See peaches. Bordeaux plus arsenate of lead (2-3-2-50), or lime- Curculio, shot hole sulphur ( specific gravity fungus, and leaf eat- 1.006) plus arsenate of ing insects. lead. Use self-boiled lime- When the calyx tube drops. sulphur on Japanese varie- ties. Apply in each case as a mist. Curculio. shot hole Two to 3 weeks af - ter the calyx drops. fungus, brown rot. Same as foregoing, and leaf eating in- sects Use insecticides or fungi- Subsequent sprays at intervals of 2 to 3 cides, alone or combined Same as foregoing, us necessary, and apply same as foregoing. SPRAY CALENDAR FOR CHERRIES. WHEN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO L'SE Leaf spot, powdery Bordeaux plus arsenate Just before the bios- mildew, and leaf eat- of lead (2-3-2-50). or lime soms open. ing insects. sulphur as for plums. Ap- ply as a fine mist. Curculio, pear slugs. Same material as fore- Just as soon as the powdery mildew, and going spray ; same manner calyx tube drops. leaf eating insects. of application. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 SPRAY CALENDAR FOR GRAPES. WHEN TO SPRAY I FOR WHAT TO SPRAY I WHAT TO USE When the shoots are Black rot, downy Bordeaux plus arsenate 8 to 10 inches long, mildew, and leaf of lead (5-5-3-50). feeders. Just before the bios- i Same as foregoing. Same as foregoing, soms open. Just as the blossoms Same as foregoing. Same as foregoing. are falling. Ten days to 2 weeks Same as foregoing, j Same as foregoing, after blossoms fall. Subsequent sprays, intervals of 10 days Same as foregoing Same as foregoing, to 2 weeks, as neces- tFor control of special insects see "Stomach Poisons," page 21 ; itact insecticides, page 21 ; and "General Treatment for Grapes," ? e29. SPRAY CALENDAR FOR CANE FRl'lTS WHEN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE Eien the young s are 10 to 12 :s high. Use resin Bordeaux (set Anthracnose and page 15) plus 3 lbs. of ar- leaf eating insects. senate of lead to 50 gals of mixture. Two weeks later. Same as foregoing | Same as foregoing. Kbsequent intervals ks. sprays of 2 Same material as forego- Same as foregoing, ing. (See "General Treat- ment for Cane Fruits,' , page 30.) </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 SPRAY CALENDAR FOR CURRANTS AND GOOSEBERRIES FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE WHEN TO SPRAY After growth starts. Leaf spot ami leaf Bordeaux plus arsenate ■ating insects. of lead, (5-5-2-50). of lead, (5-5-2-50). Ebsequent sprays intervals of 2 ks. Same as foregoing. Same as foregoing. SPRAY CALENDAR FOR STRAWBERRIES WHEN TO SPRAY FOR WHAT TO SPRAY WHAT TO USE Bordeaux plus arsenate of lead, (5-5-2-50). Isoon as the fruit Leaf spot and foli - age eating insects. age eating insects. rbsequent sprays intervals of 10 Same materials as fore - going, combined or separ - ate, as needed. (See "Gen - eral Treatment for Straw - berries," page 30.) days until there is Same as foregoing danger of discoloring $ rn i t </seg>
            <seg id="p038">AVAILABLE BULLETINS. Bulletins in this partial list may be had free by residents of Nebraska, upon application to the Bulletin Department, Uni - versity Farm, Lincoln. EXTENSION BULLETINS. 1 Alfalfa Management. Cost of Growing Crops In Nebraska. Testing Seed Corn. i Cooking and Sewing. Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle. Part II. — Corn. Part III. — The Home Garden. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. ! Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm Organization of Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) Agricultural Extension Short Courses. The Climate of Nebraska. A Course of Study for Home Economics Clubs. Twelve Lessons in Sewing. Twelve Lessons on Foods and Their Preparation. Simple Water Systems for the Farm. Inexpensive Silos and Silage Machinery. Saving the Corn Crop. Filling the Silo. Sweet Clover in Nebraska. What is a Farm Demonstrator? Spraying Fruit in Nebraska. The Babcock Test and Its Use In Herd Improvement. EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETINS. Locusts or Grasshoppers. Feeding Experiments with Cattle. Cattle Feeding Experiments. Fattening Pigs on Corn and Tankage. Growing Hogs in Western Nebraska. 1 Changes in the Composition of the Loess Soils of Nebraska Caused by Cultivation- Economical Beef Production. i Growing Feeder Steers in Western Nebraska. Growing Crops In Western Nebraska. Spraying as an Essential Part of Profitable Apple Orcharding. Growing Hogs in Nebraska. Fattening Hogs in Nebraska. Fattening Hogs in Nebraska. (Technical Bulletin.) Wheat Breeding Experiments. Native Seed Corn. Forage Rations for Growing Horses. Beef Production. A Dry Rot of the Irish Potato Tuber. Growing Crops in Western Nebraska, Alfalfa Inoculation Tests. Growing Forest Trees in Western Nebraska; Shrubs and Ornamentals. Silo Construction in Nebraska. Dairy Herd Records for Fourteen Years. The Storage and Use of Soil Moisture. Irrigated Field Crops in Western Nebraska. Vegetable Gardens on Irrigated Farms in Western Nebraska. Feeding Baby Beef. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">n </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>