<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Further Experiments With Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers</title>
               <date value="1927-05">1927-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 41 Further Experiments With Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers M. H. SWENK DEPARTMENT OF. ENTOMOLOGY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA May, 1927 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Summary ... , . ... 3 What is the optimum strength of amyl acetate (technical No. 1 grade) to use as an attractant? 7 What is the optimum amount of white arsenic to use, from the attractiveness standpoint'? ... 1) What strength of white arsenic gives the greatest killing power? ... 11 What is the optimum amount of sodium arsenite to use, from the attractiveness standpoint" .. 14 What strength of sodium arsenite gives the greatest killing power? 1"&gt; Is a bait increased m attractiveness, or the reverse, by allowing it to ferment before scattering? . 20 Does molasses have a value m the poisoned bait thru preventing it from drying out too rapidly after having been scattered? 22 Does calcium. chloride have a value m the poisoned bait thru adding to its attractiveness or preventing it from drying out too rapidly after having been scattered? . 2.'! From the standpoint of the actual effectivene.-s of the poisoned bait, what is the best time t.i scatter it? 2 1 How heavily should the bait be scattered to si-cure maximum efficiency" 32 In the alfalfa field, is it always necessary to s.atter the poisoned bait over the entire field? . .'!(&gt; Is spraying the alfalfa with arsenicals any more effective m destroy - ing the grasshoppers than the use of poisoned bait? . 37 In the light of both the 1H22 and l!»2.'i experiments, what seems to be the best poisoned bait to use for grasshoppers m the North Platte valley? .41 Literature cited . 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The experiments of 1923 with poisoned baits for grasshoppers were based, as were the experiments for 1922, almost entirely upon the reac - tions of the two-striped grasshopper (Melanoplus bivittatus), and may be summarized in the following conclusions: Amyl acetate is much more effective as an attractant to immature grasshoppers than to adult grasshoppers. It is of very high attrac - tiveness to grasshoppers of varied ages when used at a strength of % ounce to 25 pounds of bran, and that strength is recommended for general use. Baits containing white arsenic reach their maximum attractiveness when the white arsenic is used at strengths of 1% to 2 pounds to 25 pounds of bran." White arsenic sometimes - gives a high killing efficiency when used at as low a strength as % to % pound to 25 pounds of bran, but a high efficiency is not to be depended upon at those strengths. The consistently highest killing efficiency is obtained when strengths of 1 V_ to 1V_ pounds to 25 pounds of bran are used. On the basis of both attractiveness and killing efficiency, the strength of 1% pounds to 25 pounds of bran is recommended. Baits . containing sodium arsenite solution show little difference in attractiveness when a solution containing 8 pounds of arsenious oxid to the gallon is used at rates of from % pint to 1 pint to 25 pounds of bran. The average killing efficiency also shows little difference when the same solution is used at strengths of from V_ pint to 1Y_ pints to 25 pounds of bran. On the basis of economy the strength of y_ pint to 25 pounds of bran is recommended as the best to use. The 1923 experiments corroborated the. 1922 results in indicating that molasses not only does not increase, but actually reduces, the attractiveness of baits poisoned with white arsenic, for such baits were 22 per cent more attractive without molasses than with it. On the other hand, the 1923 experiments indicated that molasses quite mate - rially (32 per cent) increased the attractiveness of baits poisoned with sodium arsenite solution. It is recommended that molasses be omitted in baits poisoned with white arsenic or other dry poisons, but that it be included at the rate of 2 quarts to 25 pounds of bran in baits poisoned with sodium arsenite solution. The addition of 1 pound of calcium chloride to 25 pounds of bran would be advantageous in helping to keep the bait in a moister and more attractive condition in hot, dry weather, were it not that its high cost makes its use impractical. Baits that have been recently prepared are distinctly (21 per cent) more attractive to grasshoppers than are baits of the same composition that have been allowed to become stale and fermented. . Oh a bright day, when the grasshoppers are chiefly immature, if a large acreage is to be treated, it is well to begin to scatter the bait as </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 early as 7:00 a. m. But where the acreage to be treated is small, the scattering should be begun nearer to the period of maximum feeding of the immature grasshoppers, about 9:00 a. m. When the grass - hoppers are chiefly adult, the bait should not be scattered before 9:00 a. m., and when the acreage is small not before 10:00 a. m., nearer to the period of maximum feeding of the adult grasshoppers. Where the grasshoppers are abundant, in order to secure maximum efficiency it is necessary to scatter the bait at rates of not less than 20 pounds of the bait, wet weight, to the acre. Adult grasshoppers are more likely to survive the ingestion of poisoned baits than immature ones. When an alfalfa field is cut, if strips of standing alfalfa are left around the edges of the field and these are heavily treated with poisoned bait, a large kill can be secured without treating the entire field. Spraying an alfalfa field with arsenicals is not a more effective method than the use of poisoned baits. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Further Experiments With Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers M. H. SWENK 1 In the summer of 1922 a series of experiments was carried on at the Scotts Bluff Experiment Substation for the pur - pose of finding, if possible, a formula for preparing an inex - pensive and efficient pdisoned bait for grasshoppers that could be recommended to the farmers of the North Platte valley, and also of learning more concerning the relative values of certain attractants and poisons commonly used in such baits, as well as the best time to scatter them to obtain the most satisfactory results. A report on this series of experiments was made in Bulletin 183 of the Nebraska Agri - cultural Experiment Station, and, while the results there given were fairly conclusive from a qualitative standpoint, the time was not available in the summer of 1922 to secure data that would enable the recommendation of a formula giving definite quantities of the ingredients. The experiments were continued, therefore, during the summer of 1923, to secure these lacking data, and the present bulletin is a report, sup - plemental to Bulletin 183, giving the final conclusions reached from the experiments of both 1922 and 1923. The more important questions to be investigated in 1923 were the following: What is the optimum strength of amyl acetate (technical No. 1 grade) 2 to use as an attractant? What is the optimum amount of white arsenic to use, from the attractiveness standpoint? What strength of white arsenic gives the greatest killing power? What is the opti - mum amount of sodium arsenite to use, from the attrac - tiveness standpoint? What strength of sodium arsenite gives the greatest killing power? Is a bait increased in attractive - ness, or the reverse, by allowing it to ferment before scatter - ing? Does molasses have a value in the poisoned bait thru preventing it from drying out too rapidly after having been 1 These experiments were planned and the results prepared for publication by the author of the bulletin, who hereby recognizes his indebtedness to Messrs. E. E. Wehr and L. G. Worley for carrying out the" experiments as planned, during the period June 6 to August 15, 1923. Mn Bulletin 183 (pp. 14-15) the term "banana oil (amyl acetate)" was used for this material in preference to the term amyl acetate, in the belief that the material would become better known under the former name. The material used in the 1922 experiments was. however, the " technical No. 1 " grade of amyl acetate. In 1923 it was learned that sometimes lower grades of amyl acetate than the " technical No. 1 " were also sold as " banana oil," these sometimes really containing only a very small percentage (5 per cent) ot amyl acetate, and frequently also containing Im - purities repellant to grasshoppers, thus making the continued use of the term •' banana oil " quite unadvisable. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 scattered? Does calcium chloride possess any such value? From the standpoint of the actual effectiveness of the poisoned bait, what is the best time to scatter it? How heavily should the bait be scattered to secure maximum efficiency? In the alfalfa field, is it always necessary to scatter the poisoned bait over the entire field? Is spraying the alfalfa with arsen - icals any more effective in destroying grasshoppers than the use of poisoned bait? In the light of both the 1922 and 1923 experiments, what seems to be the best poisoned bran bait to use for grasshoppers in the North Platte valley? The experiments were planned to bring out, as clearly as possible, the correct answers to these questions, as applied to the con - ditions obtaining in the North Platte valley of Nebraska. The methods employed during the summer of 1923 to determine the relative attractiveness of the baits, and their relative killing power, were exactly the same as the methods used in the summer of 1922, as explained in Bulletin 183 (pp. 7 and 20-211, except that in the killing power tests the baits were scattered in the morning, before 11:00 a. m., instead of in the afternoon, between 4:00 p. m. and 5:00 p. m.., and the cages were placed over young and thrifty growing alfalfa, instead of having cut fresh alfalfa plants inserted daily, as was done in the summer of 1922, while in the attractiveness tests the count of the number of grasshoppers on each pan, or within a distance of 6 inches of it, was taken at intervals of 10 minutes thru the day, instead of at intervals of 5 minutes, as was done in the summer of 1922, and in the first two of these tests (June 12 to 19 and June 22 to 27) the counts were begun at 6:10 a. m., instead of at 8:10 a. m., as in the other attractiveness tests (July 23 to 28 and July 30 to August 3), or at 8:05 a. m., as in the tests in the sum - mer of 1922. The pans were arranged in a circle, as in the summer of 1922, this circle of pans having a diameter of 10 feet in 1923, and the relative position of the pans was changed every 2 hours, or 5 times in the first two attractiveness tests in 1923, viz., at 8:00 a. m., 10:00 a. m„ 12:00 m., 2:00 p. m., and 4 :00 p. m., instead of 4 times, or at the 4 last mentioned hours, as was done in the other attractiveness tests in 1923 and in all of the tests carried out in the summer of 1922. The total number of grasshoppers included in all the counts made during each 10-hour or 12-hour period was taken as an index of the attractiveness of the bait on that day. All of the tests described in this bulletin were made at the Scotts Bluff Experiment Substation, unless otherwise noted. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">1 Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers What is the optimum strength of amyl acetate (technical No. 1 grade) to use as an attractant? The 1922 experiments indicated that a good special attract - ant, such as citrus fruits or amyl acetate, added sufficiently to the attractiveness of the poisoned bait to amply justify its inclusion (Bulletin 183, pp. 13-14) , and that as between citrus fruits and amyl acetate, which possess approximately equal attractiveness to the grasshoppers, the advantage as to lower cost, convenience of storage, preparation, and keeping qualities lay so decidedly with the amyl acetate (Bulletin 183, pp. 14-16) that ordinarily its consistent use is to be recom - mended in poisoned baits for grasshoppers. In the 1922 experiments, following the recommendations made by Parker and Seamans (1, p. 138) as a result of experiments conducted in Montana in 1919, 3 ounces (=12 teaspoonfuls) of amyl acetate was used with 25 pounds of bran, and no effort was made to determine the results that would follow a variation in that amount. In the 1923 experiments, therefore, it seemed desirable to first ascertain the optimum strength of amyl acetate that should be used when that material is included in the bait as an attractant. Accordingly, 14 baits were made up and tested on the basis of a formula including 25 pounds of bran, 1 pound of white arsenic, and amyl acetate varied as follows: J£ ounce, y% ounce, % ounce, 1 ounce, V/_&gt; ounces, 2 ounces, £ l /_&gt; ounces, 3 ounces, 31/2 ounces, 4 ounces, 4 i/o ounces, 5 ounces, 5Y_&gt; ounces and 6 ounces. The results of this test follow: </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 2. CO Date of test Ounces of amyl acetate SERIES 1 a '4 \-i % 1 1 '■• 2 2'_ 3 :i'-_ 1 4Vi 5 5&gt;/i 6 June 12 173 254 410 404 687 098 800 2lW&gt; 10.. 119 52 68 114 97 W June 13 4:1 til. 31 65 Hi" 11)7 283 385 :1H4 (ill 427 228 128 77 £^ Juno 14 159 22:. 211 248 161 18!) l'.il 1.".:! 156 2(11 212 126 211 172 June 16 40!) 61!) 848 6 15 67:5 52!) 7(11 55s .1211 326 .121 225 219 281 Cfl June 18 355 .'..'Il 474 304 301 274 237 256 343 349 421 393 336 408 g June 1!) 356 216 223 153 173 136 151 197 212 27(i 425 274 360 308 t_ Total 1495 1709 2197 1789 2132 2023 1816 1765 1669 1882 1858 1309 1368 1343 2 SERIES 2 W Julv 23 13S 94 C&gt; 1 74 79 70 71 II) 73 125 96 93 102 114 w Julv 24 84 85 11 68 63 57 8 1 128 151 113 .62 110 62 75 &gt; Julv 25 126 105 60 64 54 59 73 39 52 68 121 83 78 116 Julv 26 47 46 82 20 31 53 4fi 40 35 82 54 37 57 57 « July 27 46 44 37 58 30 37 34 4 1 48 45 62 97 79 73 July 28 48 44 48 49 61 71 60 51 39 40 57 32 84 46 °? Total . . 189 118 252 333 818 347 .365 345 398 423 452 152 462 481 £ Grand Total 1984 2127 2119 2122 2150 2370 2181 2110 2067 2305 2310 1761 1830 1824 H r-s </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers From these results it is evident that amyl acetate was much more effective as an attractant to the voracious, mostly very immature grasshoppers which predominated from June 12 to 19 (series 1), than it was to subadult and adult grass - hoppers which predominated from July 23 to 28 (series 2). The immature grasshoppers were attracted about equally to baits in which amyl acetate was used at strengths of from y_&gt; ounce to 414 ounces, but when it was used at a strength of over 41/2 ounces it became a repellent to them, rather than an attractant. Used at a strength of less than y_\ ounce, with immature grasshoppers the amyl acetate was too weak to bring out well the attractiveness of the material. The maxi - mum attractiveness to immature grasshoppers was obtained when the amyl acetate was used at a strength of % ounce to 25 pounds of bran, and, since economy is subserved by not using more, of the amyl acetate than is necessary, that strength is evidently the best to use when immature grass - hoppers are exclusively concerned. The adult grasshoppers were not strongly attracted by amyl acetate used at strengths of from % ounce to 3% ounces, but at strengths of 4, &amp;y_&gt;, -5, 51/2 and 6 ounces there was a proportionately increasing attractiveness of the material. Also, a very weak strength of amyl acetate — 14 ounce or y_&gt; ounce — seemed to make the bait highly attrac - tive to adult grasshoppers, tho not to immature ones. Evi - dently, then, in the case of preponderatingly mature grass - hoppers, the amyl acetate might be used either very weak — 14 or y-i ounce to 25 pounds of bran — or else very strong — : 4 ounces or more to 25 pounds of bran — and, in the inter - est of economy, the weaker strengths would of course be pref - erable. Where both immature and mature grasshoppers are about equally concerned, apparently the optimum strength would be % ounce to 25 pounds of bran, as that strength showed a very high attractiveness in the grand total of the combined counts. On this showing, the strength of % ounce to 25 pounds of bran is obviously the best to recommend for general use. What is the optimum amount of white arsenic to use, from the attractiveness standpoint? The 1922 experiments indicated that as between the three dry arsenicals that are commonly used in poisoned baits for grasshoppers — viz., Paris green, white arsenic and crude arsenic — the baits containing white arsenic were distinctly (8 to 10 per cent) more attractive to the grasshoppers than were the baits containing Paris green, and very much (25 to </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 35 per cent) more attractive than were the baits containing crude arsenic (Bulletin 183, pp. 11-12). They also indicated that while the baits containing white arsenic killed the grass - hoppers a little more slowly than the baits containing Paris green, and much more slowly than the baits containing crude arsenic, their final killing power was but little inferior to the final killing power of the baits containing the more ener - getic arsenicals (Bulletin 183, pp. 20-25). As a result of these findings, considering together the attractiveness, final killing power, and cost of the three arsenicals, the recom - mendation was made that a fine light grade of white arsenic was, on the whole, the best dry arsenical to use in grass - hopper baits. In all of the tests from which this conclusion was reached the white arsenic was used at the rate of 1 pound to 25 pounds of bran. Consequently, no data were available as to the comparative attractiveness of grasshopper baits conr taining lesser or greater amounts of white arsenic than 1 pound to 25 pounds of bran. In the 1923 experiments it seemed desirable to secure this information. Accordingly, 6 baits were made up on the basis of 25 pounds of bran, *■/._. ounce of amyl acetate and white arsenic at the rates of 4, 8, 12, 16, 24 and 32 ounces, respec - tively. These 6 baits were tested on immature grasshoppers in late June (June 22 to 27). The results of this test follow: Date of test Ounces of white arsenic 4 8 12 16 24 32 June 22 850 531 401 484 374 518 June 22. 509 636 628 678 779 845 June 25. 257 287 229 275 652 522 June 25.. 212 156 148 137 486 493 June 27 449 400 384 340 234 324 June 27.. 601 435 544 479 579 449 Total 2878 2445 2334 2393 3104 3151 This test showed 12 ounces of white arsenic in 25 pounds of bran to have the minimum attractiveness to grasshoppers, or at least to immature grasshoppers, the attractiveness in - creasing regularly as either lesser or greater amounts were used. The greatest attractiveness was shown by the bait containing 32 ounces of white arsenic, but the attractiveness of this strength was only very slightly (1.1 per cent) greater than the attractiveness of the bait containing 24 ounces of white arsenic. On the other hand, the bait containing 24 ounces of white arsenic was very considerably (29.7 and 32.9 per cent, respectively) more attractive than the baits con - taining 16 ounces or 12 ounces of white arsenic. On this showing, the strength of 24 ounces, or IV2 pounds, of white </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers arsenic to 25 pounds of bran, tho not actually the most attractive, was regarded as the most practical one from the attractiveness standpoint. The relatively high attractiveness of the bait that contained only 4 ounces of white arsenic was a surprising showing in this test. What strength of white arsenic gives tlie greatest killing power? The baits containing white arsenic used in the 1922 experi - ments having all included that arsenical at the rate of 1 pound to 25 pounds of bran, it seemed very desirable in 1923 to test the comparative efficiency or killing power of grasshopper baits containing both lesser or greater amounts of white arsenic than 1 pound to 25 pounds of bran. Accordingly, 8 baits were made up on the basis of 25 pounds of bran, % ounce of amyl acetate, and white arsenic at the rates of 4, 8,. 12, 16, 20, 24, 28 and 32 ounces, respectively. These 8 baits were tested on prevailingly immature grasshoppers in early July (July 2 to 9) and again on prevailingly adult grass - hoppers in early August (August 5 to 11) , following exactly the same method as was used in the killing efficiency test in 1922 (Bulletin 186, pp. 20-21) except, as has previously been mentioned, that the baits were scattered before 11:00 a. m., instead of between 4:00 p. m. and 5:00 p. m., as in 1922. This change was made • because the experiments of 1922 showed that thereby the grasshoppers would have more of an opportunity to feed on the fresh baits during the same day that they were scattered, and also because it gave the worker more time to collect and cage his grasshoppers on the following day. The results Of these two tests follow: series i n , "O Ounces of « -g &gt; &gt; &gt;&gt; &gt; &gt; m c white .SS n . z« =._. -so St- ••=-&lt;. = e&gt; .go g arsenic "o u *__ &gt;, &gt;, . „ . &gt;, . &gt;, , &gt;. u u 6.Z _f d*-_ d*« o*^_ o*-l o"^ o"« o*a v-_ liiS Hi Hi ssS z.Z zZ zZ zZ p.3 4 269 150 96 85 83 72 72 197 73 8 ' " 165 109 85 66 40 40 40 125 76 12 166 120 86 73 70 68 68 98 59 16 203 108 108 91 85 68 68 135 66 20 " 251 113 113 106 106 82 71 180 72 24 ..256 248 160 101 86 78 '67 189 74 28 171 126 126 113 109 91 89 $2 48 32 -""l65 106 100 94 92- 83 83 82 50 Check 1 ..568. - 524 44 8 i This check is the combined results for two cages, .one In an alfalfa field over youns alfalfa, and the other one not in an alfalfa field. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research BULLETIN 41 series 2 Ounces of g a J J &gt; &gt;e &gt;- 5- £ white «.5&lt; --J- »» :=s» =-h r~ o" a* arsenic * „ * . «. «. «. «. * . »-g 0 — 9 OS 0= S3 0= 03 C 3 a — Z"S? 2&lt; Z&lt;S Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; 6.3 4 . 160 63 56 56 33 127 79 8 65 63 41 41 41 24 37 12 . .... 81 81 44 44 44 37 46 16 128 . ... 117 57 57 55 73 57 20 168 163 50 50 50 118 70 24 134 . 91 73 73 45 89 66 28 116 91 53 53 53 63 54 32 96 91 72 72 72 24 25 Check 1 173 155 18 10 Deducting from the percentages of mortality obtained fol - lowing the use of each of the 8 baits, as shown in the preced - ing table, the per cent of grasshoppers dying in the check cages accompanying each series of tests, as representing the normal rate of mortality of unpoisoned grasshoppers in con - finement (cf. Bulletin 183, p. 24), we get the following approximate actual percentage of kill due to the ingested poison : Per cent of grass- 1'cr cent of grass- Ounces of hopper.) killed hoppers killed Average per white l'Jlt.41 per cent (56.4 per cenl cent of arsenir immature) adult) mortality 4 65 69 67 8 68 27 48 12 51 36 44 16 58 47 53 2(1 64 60 62 24 66 56 61 28 40 44 42 32 42 15 20 The discrepancies in the results of these two tests, in gen - eral indicating a distinctly higher average final mortality due to poisoning in the first series (57 per cent) as compared to the second series (44 per cent), is probably to be accounted for by the different ages of the grasshoppers used in them. In the first test, made July 2 to 9, the grasshoppers were practically all (99.4 per cent) immature, mostly (60.3 per cent) in the second and third instars, adult grasshoppers constituting only .6 per cent of the whole number, while in the second test, made August 5 to 11, most (56.4 per cent) of the grasshoppers were adults and most (32.6 per cent of the whole) of the immature ones were in the fifth instar, only 1 This check is the result of a single cage placed in an alfalfa field over young alfalfa, like the other cages containing the grasshoppers that had been exposed to the poisoned baits. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers a small number (11 per cent) being younger than that, and none younger than the third instar. In other words, the adult grasshoppers are apparently more likely to survive the ingestion of poisoned baits than are the immature ones. An exact analysis of the ages of the dead grasshoppers found in the cages at the close of each test gave the following results : series i Ounces of white First Second Third Fourth Fifth Total arsenic instar instar instar instar instar Adult No. 4 18 95 75 8 1 0 197 8 22 40 ■ 51 10 2 0 125 12 10 18 35 25 9 1 98 16 ....:. 26 26 39 32 12 0 135 20 25 56 55 33 10 1 180 24 33 85 27 . 35 9 0 189 28 6 17 21 22 16 0 82 32- 4 15 13 20 27 3 82 Check 0 6 9 7 20 2 44 TotaI..144 358 325 192 106 . 7 1132 Per cent 12.7 31.6 28.7 17.0 9.4 .6 SERIES 2 Ounces of white First Second Third Fourth Fifth Total arsenic instar instar instar instar instar Adult No. 4 0 0 3 20 56 48 127 8 0 0 0 4 8 12 24 12 0 0 3 5 8 21 37 16 ...... 0 0 0 13 17 43 73 20 0 0 5 6 38 69 118 24 0 0 0 4 26 59 89 28 0 0 0 0 18 45 63 32 0 0 0 0 5 19 24 Check 0 0 0 0 11 7 18 Total.. 0 0 il 52 187 323 573 Per cent 0 0 1.9 9.1 32.6 56.4 On analyzing the killing efficiency of the 8 baits used in these two tests, the most surprising thing was the high killing power of the bait that contained only 4 ounces of white arsenic. Both tests showed a high killing power for the bait containing that strength of white arsenic; in fact, it was the highest in the second test and stood a high third in rank in the first test. This fact, coupled with the high attractiveness of the bait containing that strength of white arsenic shown in the attractiveness test discussed on a pre - vious page of this bulletin, indicates the possibility of very efficient results following the use of very small amounts of white arsenic in the bait. The bait that contained 8 ounces of white arsenic was the highest one in efficiency of the entire series in the first test but it failed miserably in efficiency </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 in the second test, rather indicating that a high efficiency with baits containing small amounts of white arsenic is not to be depended upon. Eliminating from further consideration the baits contain - ing 4 and 8 ounces of white arsenic in 25 pounds of bran, the first series of tests shows an increasing killing efficiency from 12 ounces thru 16 ounces and 20 ounces to the maximum efficiency at a strength of 24 ounces, and then a sharp and decided falling off in efficiency at the 28 ounce and 32 ounce strengths, while the second series of tests shows an increas - ing killing efficiency thru the 12 and 16 ounce strengths to the maximum efficiency at a strength of 20 ounces, and then a gradual falling off in efficiency thru the 24 and 28 ounce strengths to an exceedingly poor efficiency at the 32 ounce strength. This might be taken to indicate a maximum killing efficiency when 24 ounces of white arsenic are used with 25 pounds of bran against immature grasshoppers, and when 20 ounces are used with that amount of bran against adult grasshoppers. But in their average killing efficiency (62 and 61 per cent, respectively) against both immature and adult grasshoppers there was practically no choice between the 20 and 24 ounce strengths of white arsenic, and inasmuch as the attractiveness test showed the optimum strength from that standpoint to be 24 ounces, or IV2 pounds, that strength may also be recommended as the best to use from the killing efficiency standpoint. What is the optimum amount of sodium arsenite to use, from the attractiveness standpoint? The 1922 experiments included a test of a grasshopper bait poisoned with a solution of sodium arsenite, which bait gave the highest efficiency (75 per cent kill) of any of the baits tested that year. Because of this high efficiency, we recom - mended the use of sodium arsenite in grasshopper baits (Bulletin 183, pp. 25-26). The sodium arsenite used in the 1922 test was made by boiling 1 pound and 10.8 ounces of white arsenic with 3 pounds and 12 ounces of sal soda in 10 quarts of water, thus making enough of the solution to poison 25 pounds of bran. Simultaneously with the publication of Bulletin 183, Corkins (5, p. 13) recommended a grasshopper bait containing sodium arsenite as the poison, used at the rate of 1 gill of a solution containing 8 pounds of white arsenic to the gallon to 25 pounds of bran. In addition to its unquestionable high killing power, sodium arsenite has the advantage over white arsenic of being easily and wholly soluble in cold water, and thus capable of being much more easily and uniformly mixed with the bran than the very heavy and only slightly soluble white arsenic powder, and </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers also of. being less expensive when used at its optimum killing strength. Early, in 1923 our attention was drawn to a new com - mercial sodium arsenite solution l that was being manufac - tured for use as a weed killer and that seemed to have much promise as poison for grasshopper baits. This product was being marketed in two strengths — one containing 4 pounds of arsenibus oxid (As 2 0 3 ) to the gallon, and the other con - taining 8 pounds of arsenious oxid to the gallon. The latter strength was the one used in all of our tests. In order to learn the optimum amount of this poison to use with 25 pounds of bran, from the attractiveness standpoint, 6 baits were made up on the basis of 25 pounds of bran, % ounce of amyl acetate and sodium arsenite at the rates of 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 and 8 gills, respectively. These 6 baits were tested on immature grasshoppers in late June (June 22 to 27), at the same time that the parallel attractiveness tests with white arsenic, already mentioned, were being made. The results of this test follow: Date of test Gills of sodium arsenite (containing 50 per cent arsenious oxid) 1 9 °. ' A R J_ June 22 498 331 489 369 401 259 June 22 373 532 333 395 242 345 June 25 219 326 499 380 462 403 June 25 141 148 '330 311 334 281 June 27 209 239 226 281 314 298 June 27 '.. 641 422 419 466 258 304 Total 2081 1998 2296 2202 2011 1890 This test shows 3 gills of sodium arsenite (containing 50 per cent arsenious oxid) in 25 pounds of bran to have the maximum attractiveness to grasshoppers, or at least to imma - ture ones, tho its superiority in this respect over the bait containing 4 gills of the sodium arsenite solution was but small (4.2 per cent), and it was not greatly superior (only 13.3 per cent) to the bait containing but 1 gill, which ranked third. The baits containing 6 gills and 8 gills were increas - ingly less attractive in proportion to the increased amount of poison used. What strength of sodium arsenite gives the greatest kill - ing power? The grasshopper bait that gave the highest efficiency (75 per cent kill) that was obtained in the 1922 experiments was, as has been mentioned, a bait poisoned with a solution of sodium arsenite. The strength of the sodium arsenite solution • This commercial sodium arsenite is a heavy liquid ot tho consistency of thin syrup. One pint ol the solution used by us contains 1 pound o£ white arsenic. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 used with 25 pounds of bran in the 1922 test was the equiv - alent of 6.7 gills of the commercial sodium arsenite solution containing 8 pounds of white arsenic to the gallon, such as was used in the 1923 tests. Corkins (5, p. 13) at practically the same time recommended a much weaker strength of sodium arsenite, only 1 gill of the solution containing 8 pounds of white arsenic to the gallon with 25 pounds of bran. Later, Corkins (7, p. 9) recommended the use of 2 gills with 25 pounds of bran where killing within 24 to 48 hours was desired. It seemed very desirable, therefore, in 1923 to test the comparative efficiency or killing power of grasshopper baits containing these and both lesser and greater amounts of sodium arsenite with 25 pounds of bran. Accordingly, 10 baits were made up and tested on the basis of 25 pounds of bran, % ounce of amyl acetate and sodium arsenite at the rates of | 2l 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8 and 10 gills, respectively. These 10 baits were each tested 3 times during the season of 1923 — first on heavily prevailing immature grasshoppers (92.9 per cent in the first to fifth instars) with only a small number (7.1 per cent) of adults, in early July (July 6 to 12) ; second on again heavily prevailing immature grasshoppers (90 per cent in the second to fifth instars) but with a slightly larger proportion (10 per cent) of adults, in late July (July 20 to 27) ; and third on grasshoppers nearly equally divided between immature grasshoppers in the third to fifth instars (51.7 per cent) and adult grasshoppers (48.3 per cent), in early August (August 8 to 14). The second and third tests were carried out on the farm of Mr. Andrews, in Sioux County, owing to the scarcity of grasshoppers at the time on the Scotts Bluff Experiment Substation. The results of these three tests follow: SERIES l Gills of I JS * ■- ■- ■- -_ "-. "= sodium "_■-••. __[- r r _r- _•_£ __:— _z— Zl_ _ arsenite *" _ _ « * ._, *'_, a &gt; -&gt;. - ~ .. '-? Z « t i i Z -. Z -X Z -. Z n z; Z i _._\ \i_ .... 162 04 87 87 64 64 98 60 1 .... 181 84 65 58 54 .... 50 131 72 2 .... 254 90 80 71 71 71 183 72 3 .... 323 172 149 122 122 .... 122 201 62 4 .... 174 07 83 83 83 .... 83 91 52 5 .... 150 94 79 53 50 .... 43 107 71 6 .... 183 94 84 71 71 .... 71 112 61 7 .... 166 90 74 74 74 .... 74 92 55 8 .... 150 114 101 56 56 .... 56 94 63 10 .... 173 119 107 107 107 .... 103 70 40 Check' .. 568 524= 44 : 8 'The check used in this test is the same as the check used in the first series of the efficiency tests of the different strengths of white arsenic. July 3 to 9, as given on a preceding page. "July 9 instead of July 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">•; Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers series 2 o CI Gills of | * S ' 'i I S g ■ 2 t -o sodium arsenite «£». =S ~%% =S "•jS '•jS J5 5„ St .'*&gt; .* .*&gt; . * .* •&gt;&gt; .Jb • *&gt; J." £=« g = =3 °"3 6"3 O's 5= fs °3 j&gt;S ZSU Z-J Z^ £►&gt; Zr, Zl Ze, ZH Z*S P*X M 462 114 90 65 45 43 43 42 420 91 1 320 109 75 44 44 44 44 44 276 86 2 506 65 50 31 31 31 31 31 475 94 3 220 110 90 64 36 36 36 34 186 84 4 463 134 105 72 50 50 50 50 413 89 5 484 135 99 60 52 47 47 38 446 92 6 396 94 55 40 38 38 38 32 364 92 7 :... 415 74 70 40 40 40 40 40 375 90 8 500 109 83 46 36 36 36 35 465 93 10 356 71 65 36 36 36 36 36 320 90 Check 332 265 264 264 263 263 263 263 69 21 SERIES 3 ao ■3 Gills of. S 2 S So £_ S M ?. o- • H - - sodium arsenite &lt;_£% __ a __° _\Z __% £5 &gt;\% 82 g *§« ** •;* ".«■ ".« «.« ■».* -*.* it °__: _.°3 0 s 03 Op OS OS oa 5= ZoS Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; Z&lt; £3 y_ 61 61 42 41 34 33 21 40 66 1 386 293 156 100 33 33 14 372 96 2 105 104 72 54 44 42 42 63 60 3 281 144 92 62 38 16 13 268 95 4 79 52 52 49 35 35 35 44 56 5 327 140 105 80 30 27 14 313 96 6 300 166 105 75 53 37 37 263 88 7 241 160 113 111 85 85 85 156 65 8 217 141 107 96 84 84 84 133 61 10 104 97 71 65 65 43 41 63 61 Check 136 112 112 112 112 103 103 33 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 Deducting, as before, the percentage of grasshoppers dying in the check cages accompanying each series of tests from the percentage of mortality obtained following the use of each of the 10 baits, as shown in the preceding table, we get the following approximate actual percentage of kill due to the ingested poison : • i 5 5 .t. a a = a _. u __ a. . u_ u__ *± = £ --H _.!- -I* «| ?■,=__ \___ | E _. S^| -li T -'z iic.l i^^l &lt;Se i._ 52 70 42 55 1 64 65 72 67 2 64 73 36 58 3 5 4 153 75 64 4 44 i&gt;s 32 48 5 63 71 72 6'.1 6 53 71 61 63 7 47 60 41 52 8 55 72 37 55 10 32 60 37 46 There was a considerable variation in the results of these three tests. The mortality in the second test ran highest (average of all 10 baits 69.1 per cent), and corresponded best with the result obtained with the sodium arsenite bait in 1922 (Bulletin 186, pp. 22 and 25-26), but the mortality in the third test ran much lower (average of all 10 baits 50.8 per cent) than in the 1922 test. One might deduce that this lower mortality in the third test was entirely due to the greater average age and larger proportion of adults used in it were it not for the fact that the grasshoppers used in the first test were younger than those used in the second test and the average mortality was scarcely greater (52.8 per cent) than that obtained in the third test. Nevertheless, in the third test at least, the age of the grasshoppers was undoubtedly an important factor in the results; for, if the baits giving the higher efficiencies are compared with those giving the lower efficiencies it will be found that, in general, the efficiency decreases as the per cent of adult grasshoppers increases, viz. : Gills of sodium arsenite ... 3 15 6% 7 10 824 Mortality 75 72 72 64 42 41 37 37 36 32 Per cent of adults 36 44 45 40 72 63 42 65 65 50 In other words, as was found in the test of the killing power of baits containing white arsenic, the adult grasshoppers are </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers more likely to survive after eating poisoned baits than are the immature ones. The actual ages of the dead grasshoppers found in the cages at the close of each of these three tests were as follows: series 1 Gills of sodium First Second Third Fourth Fifth Total arsenite instar instar instar instar instar Adult No. % 3 14 27 19 27 8 98 1 ...... 2 23 50 17 30 9 131 2 0 16 59 39 61 8 183 3 0 17 71 38 56 19 201 4 0 5 31 12 35 8 91 5 0 17 35 21 28 6 107 6 4 11 38 17 29 13 112 7 0 8 44 8 26 6 92 8 0 6 33 9 40 6 94 10 0 2 27 12 27 2 70 Check 0 G 9 7 20 2 44 Total.. 9 125 424 199 379 87 1223 Percent 7 10.2 ( 34.7 16.3 31.0 7.1 SERIES 2 Gills of sodium arsenite Second to fifth Instars Adult Total No. % 380 40 420 1 258 18 276 2 443 32 475 3 161 25 186 4 • 401 12 413 5 430 16 446 6 329 35 364 7 277 98 375 8 383 82 465 10 308 12 320 Check 59 . 10 69 Total 3429 380 3809 Per cent 90.0 10.0 SERIES 3 •Gills of sodium First Second Third Fourth Fifth Total arsenite instar instar instar instar instar Adult No. y, 0 0 0 0 11 29 40 1 0 0 0 56 150 166 372 2 0 0 0 9 11 43 63 3 0 0 10 50 110 98 268 4 0 0 0 0 22 22 44 5 0 0. 0 62 109 142 313 6 0- 0 3 9 145 108 265 7 0 0 0 5 52 99 156 8 0 0 3 9 35 86 133 10 0 0 0 9 16 38 63 •Check 0 0 3 6 10 14 33 Total.. ~0 0 19 215 671 845 1750 Per cent.... 0 0 1.1 12.3 38.3 48.3 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 In spite of the variation in the results of these three tests, certain general conclusions can easily be drawn from them. In the first test the maximum efficiency was secured with baits containing 1 or 2 gills of the 8-pound to the gallon strength of the commercial sodium arsenite solution, altho the efficiency of these strengths was scarcely greater than the efficiency of the 5 gill strength. In the second test the 2 gill strength gave the maximum efficiency, altho again this efficiency was scarcely greater than that of the 5 gill strength. In the third test the 3 gill strength gave the maximum efficiency, altho this was but little greater than the efficiency of the 1 gill and 5 gill strengths. Evidently, then, strengths of from 1 gill to 5 gills of the 8 pound sodium arsenite solu - tion gave the maximum efficiency. On the average, the effi - ciency of the 1 gill strength is almost exactly equal to the most efficient strength as shown in these tests - — 5 gills — and, of course, it is greatly preferable to the 5 gill strength on the important basis of economy. The strength of 1 gill of the 8 pound sodium arsenite solution to 25 pounds of bran is, therefore, recommended as the best strength to use, from the killing efficiency standpoint — a conclusion exactly in agreement with the recommendation made by Corkins (5, p. 13) following the experiments made in 1922 in Colorado. We find, then, that the results of the 1923 experiments are not consistent from the attractiveness and killing efficiency standpoints, the optimum strength in the former case being 3 gills and the best strength in the latter case being 1 gill. But, as has already been noted, the difference in attractiveness between the 1 gill strength and the 3 gill strength is not great (13.3. per cent), so it would seem evident that the best strength to use, from the combined standpoints of attractiveness and killing efficiency, would be that of 1 gill to 25 pounds of bran. Is a bait increased in attractiveness, or the reverse, by allowing it to ferment before scattering? In 1922 it was learned that frequently poisoned bran mash bait was made up and allowed to stand unused for several days, sometimes for a week or more, before it was finally scattered in the fields. During this period of non-use of the bait the fermentation process had set in, of course, and an altered odor was imparted to such baits. It was claimed by some that these fermented baits lost nothing in their attrac - tiveness to grasshoppers ; in fact, that they were more attrac - tive to grasshoppers than were fresh baits. In order to definitely determine this point, two poisoned baits were prepared on the basis of 25 pounds of bran, % </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers ounce of amyl acetate, and 2 pounds of white arsenic or 5 gills of the 8 pound to the gallon sodium arsenite solution, respectively. The 2 pound strength of white arsenic, as was shown in a test recorded on a previous page of this bulletin, was the one that proved to have the maximum attractive - ness. The 5 gill strength of the sodium arsenite solution, as has also been recorded, later proved to have the highest average killing power. These baits were prepared and allowed to stand unused, for several days. After fer - mentation had become very evident, they were tested on Q successive days (July 23 to 28) in competition with freshly prepared baits containing exactly the same ingre - dients in exactly the same amounts. These fresh baits were prepared on the evening of each day before they were to be used in the tests, while the fermented baits were used con - tinuously thru the 6 days of the tests, merely being moistened with a small quantity of water as they became somewhat dried on hot days, so as to keep the moisture attractiveness uniform between the two sets of baits. Three pans each of the fresh white arsenic, fermented white arsenic, fresh sodium arsenite and fermented sodium arsenite baits were used in each test. The results of the tests follow : White arsenic Sodium arsenite Unfermented Fermented Unfermented Fermented Date of test 123 123 123 123 July 23 76 49 - 74 22 17 25 23 39 48 63 61 71 July 24 63 74 67 105 69 116 88 76 101 39 50 45 July 25 58 90 77 69 53 65 55 101 57 59 22 26 July 26 26 42 36 44 40 23 58 47 45 81 59 56 July 27 26 32 28 8 12 29 30 31 37 23 19 26 July 28 22 45 38 . 44 25 45 55 34 51 15 16 26 Total....271 332 320 292 216 303 309 328 339 280 227 250 Grand Total 923 811 976 757 This test proves conclusively that freshly prepared baits are more attractive to grasshoppers than are baits of the same composition that have been allowed to become stale and fermented. The fresh white arsenic baits were 13.8 per cent more attractive than the fermented white arsenic baits, while the fresh sodium arsenite baits were 28.9 per cent more attractive than the fermented sodium arsenite baits. Aver - aging both baits, the fresh baits were 21.1 per cent more attractive than the fermented ones. It is, however, a good practice to prepare the bait one day and scatter it the next day, keeping the mixture over night in a tightly closed receptacle, if possible, as this permits the amyl acetate to permeate the mass of bran more thoroly and to carry its odor to all of the bran flakes. Baits poisoned with white arsenic </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 and thus left standing over night have a sweet odor the next day, while baits poisoned with sodium arsenite develop a very sour smell, which does not, however, seem to injure the attrac - tiveness of the bait. Does molasses have a value in the poisoned bait thru pre - venting it from drying out too rapidly after having been scattered? In the 1922 experiments it was shown that where perfectly fresh baits were used, that is, baits freshly prepared each day, and in which Paris green was included as the poison, the addition of molasses at the rate of 2 quarts to 25 pounds of bran not only did not add to the attractiveness of the baits to grasshoppers but in fact seemed to detract somewhat from their attractiveness, those without the molasses- proving to be 14 per cent more attractive than those with it (Bulletin 183, pp. 12-13). However, as was stated in Bulletin 183, the point was not determined whether the inclusion of molasses might not even so be desirable, by effecting a mixture better able to retain the original moisture of the bait. The desira - bility of including or excluding molasses as an ingredient in poisoned baits largely devolving upon this point, some tests were carried out in 1923 to determine the possible value of molasses in preventing the too rapid drying out of poisoned baits. Two baits were prepared on the basis of a formula including 25 pounds of bran, '•]■'• ounce of amyl acetate and 2 pounds of white arsenic and 5 gills of the 8 pound to the gallon sodium arsenite solution, respectively, and to one-half of each of these baits black strap molasses was added at the rate of 2 quarts to 25 pounds of bran. These 4 baits were then tested as to attractiveness on 5 consecutive days (July 30 to August 3) , the baits as originally prepared being used thruout the tests. This furnished comparative counts in - volving baits containing molasses and lacking it that were fresh (on the first day) and 24, 48, 72 and 96 hours old (on the following 4 days). The results of this test follow: White arsenic Sodium arsenite Without With Without With molasses molasses molasses molasses Date of test 12 12 12 12 July 30 89 47 113 44 57 97 84 102 July 31 74 58 73 31 56 39 55 68 August 1 ' 13 12 0 0 10 August 2 87 71 49 38 41 47 53 76 August 3 10 25 9 20 11 5 17 9 Total 261 204 245 135 165 188 210 255 Grand Total 465 380 353 465 1 Cold and misty all day, greatly reducing the count. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers From the above results it is evident that the baits poisoned with White arsenic, as was also found to be the case in 1922 with baits poisoned with Paris green, were not increased in general attractiveness over a period of days by the addition of molasses, but rather the reverse, the poisoned baits with - out molasses proving 22 per cent more attractive than those with it. Moreover, there was no evidence that the addition of molasses tended tcr maintain the attractiveness of the poisoned baits by preventing them from drying out too rapidly, for on each of the 4 days after the first day (when all of the baits were perfectly and equally fresh) the number of grasshoppers attracted to the 2 pans of bait without molasses was greater than the number attracted to the 2 pans of bait with molasses. On the other hand, with the baits poisoned with the solution of sodium arsenite, the adition of molasses for some cause, possibly by disguising the taste of the sodium arsenite, con - sistently increased the attractiveness of the baits, not only their general attractiveness, which was 32 per cent greater in the baits containing molasses than in those lacking it, but on each of the 5 days of the test, considered separately, inas - much as on each of these days the number of grasshoppers attracted to the 2 pans of bait with molasses was greater than the number attracted to the 2 pans of bait without molasses. The conclusion . may, therefore, be drawn that while molasses may very well be omitted in baits containing Paris green or white arsenic, and possibly any other dry arsenical, as the poison, it may very well be included in baits where a solution of sodium arsenite is used. as the poison. Does calcium chloride have a value in the poisoned bait thru adding to its attractiveness or preventing it from drying out too rapidly after having been scattered? Early in 1923 the suggestion was made to the author in a letter by Mr. Don B. Whelan, then Extension Entomologist of the Idaho College of Agriculture, that possibly the addition of calcium chloride to poisoned baits for grasshoppers might remedy their drying out too rapidly. "With Mr. Whelan's permission, a test was made of this point in the experiments of the following summer, in connection with the test of the value of molasses in that respect that has just been reported. One pound of calcium chloride to 25 pounds of bran was the strength tested. The calcium chloride was added to one - half of each of the white arsenic and sodium arsenite baits in the same manner as the 2 quarts of black strap molasses was added in the test just reported upon, and the 4 baits thus produced were tested on the same days and in the same man - ner, with the following results: </seg>
            <seg id="p024">&lt;!ebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 White arsenic Sodium arsenite Without With Without With CaCl 2 CaCl 2 CaCl 2 CaCl 2 Date of test 12 12 12 12 July 30 89 47 79 96 57 97 69 72 July 31 74 58 68 89 56 39 45 138 August 1 ' 13 0 1 0 0 0 1 August 2 87 71 113 73 41 47 64 40 August 3 10 25 18 13 11 5 9 8 Total 261 204 278 272 165 188 187 259 Grand Total 465 550 353 446 In both the baits poisoned with white arsenic and those poisoned with the sodium arsenite solution, the general attrac - tiveness of the baits containing calcium chloride was greater (18 per cent and 26 per cent, respectively) than that of the baits without it, indicating that this material may possess some intrinsic value as an attractant. Probably, however, this showing was largely due to the attraction of moisture by the baits containing the calcium chloride, this serving to keep them in a moister and more attractive condition. In 7 of the 10 direct comparisons between the two, the pans containing baits with calcium chloride attracted more grass - hoppers than the corresponding pans lacking that material. In very hot dry weather the addition of calcium chloride to poisoned baits for grasshoppers might be desirable, in order to help maintain the bait in a moister and more attractive condition, were it not that its prohibitively high cost (85 cents a pound) makes its use quite impractical. From the standpoint of the actual effectiveness of the poisoned bait, what is the best time to scatter it? In Bulletin 183 (p. 27) a summary was given of the number of grasshoppers observed during each hour from 8:00 a. m. to 6:00 p. m. at the baits in the pans used in the attractive - ness tests conducted on June 16, 17, 18, 20* 22 and 24, July 12, 13, 15 and 18 and August 9, 11, 15 and \% 1922. A brief summary was also given (pp. 26-27) of the field observations made on the feeding habits of the grasshoppers. It was pointed out on the basis of this double evidence that the grass - hoppers began feeding on the ground about 6:00 a. m., if the day was clear, their voracity increasing as the temperature rose. Feeding was observed to be at its height from 9:00 a. m. to 10:00 a. m., the feeding activity diminishing somewhat after 10:00 a. m., but continuing at a fairly high level until 3:30 p. m. to 4:00 p. m. A steady and fairly rapid falling off of ground feeding was noted after 4:00 p. m., and by 6:00 p. m. the bulk of the grasshoppers had ascended the vegetation more or less, tho continuing to feed some. 1 Cold and misty all day. greatly reducing the count. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">• Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers It was thought to be desirable to check up the results obtained in 1922 by preparing and comparing a similar sum - mary of the number of grasshoppers observed at the baits in the pans used in the several attractiveness tests, conducted on June 12, 13, 14, 16, 18, 19, 22, 25 and 27, July 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 30 and 31 and August 1, 2 and 3, 1923. This sum - mary, which corroborates the findings recorded for the sum - mer of 1922 quite closely, except that the morning decline is more gradual after 10:00 a. m. and the afternoon decline in feeding activity begins about 2 :00 p. m., rather than about 4:00 p. m., herewith follows: . k June June July July July 30 - 12-19 22-27 23-28 23-28 Aug 3 Total Hours 8:00— 9:00 a. m 3215 3031 523 299 140 7208 9:00—10:00 a. m 3256 5174 982 617 306 10335 10:00— 11 -.00. a. m 4823 2946 770 395 215 9149 , 11:00— 12:00 a. m 3021 1891 1020 580 363 6875 12:00— 1:00 p. m..... 841 1355 197 120 104 2617 1:00— 2:00 p. m 2631 4211 632 492 323 8289 2:00— 3:00 p. m 2385 2552 367 249 264 5817 3:00— 4:00 p. m 1590 2434 413 331 464 5232 4:00— 5:00 p. m 606 962 470 261 274 2573 5:00— 6:00 p. m 265 296 161 117 183 1022 Quite obviously, the heaviest feeding of the day is done from 8:00 to 11:00 a. m. As was true in the summary of the 1922 counts, the drop in the number of grasshoppers visit - ing the pans during the hours from 12:00 to 1:00 p. m., as compared with the 4 preceding hours and the 3 follow - ing hours, was due to the fact that the observer took out a short time for lunch during those hours, which resulted in fewer counts being made, and. was not due to any greatly diminished feeding on the part of the grasshoppers during those hours. In the 1922 counts, none were made for the hours of 6:00 to 7:00 a. m, and 7:00 to 8:00 a. m., so in 1923 •| the counts made during June were begun at 6:10 a. m. instead ; of at 8:10 a.m. The summary of these 2 twelve-hour counts |.' follows: V Hours June 12-19 June 22-27 Total 6:00— 7:00 a. m 381 590 971 7:00— 8:00 a. m 1253 3233 . 4486 8:00— 9:00 a. m 3215 3031 6246 \: 9:00 — 10:00 a. m 3256 5174 8430 V. 10:00—11:00 a. m 4823 2946 7769 ' 11:00—12:00 a. m 3021 1891 4912 ! 12:00— 1:00 p. m '841 . 1355 2196 L 1:00— 2:00 p. m 2631 4211 6842 J» 2:00 — 3:00 p. m 2385 2552 4937 I 3:00— 4:00 p. m 1590 2434 4024 4:00 — 5:00 p. m..: 606 962 1568 5:00 — 6:00 p. m 265 296 561 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 This summary indicates, in addition to the conclusions given in Bulletin 183 and briefly summarized on a previous page of this bulletin, that feeding by the grasshoppers is on a higher level as early in the day as 6:00 to 7:00 o'clock in the morning than it is at any hour in the afternoon after 5:00 p. m., and also that during the hour from 7:00 to 8:00 a. m. there is an amount of feeding activity that approximates equality with that of any hour after 2:00 p. m. and compares favorably with the late morning feeding, from 11 :00 a. m. until noon. The heaviest feeding of the day comes from 8:00 to 11:00 a. m. The conclusions reached from these data are that on a day promising to be warm and bright, if a large acreage is to be treated and the grasshoppers are prevailingly immature, it would be decidedly advantageous to begin to scatter the poisoned bait as early as 7:00 a. m. Of course, if only a small acreage is to be treated, the bait should be scattered nearer to the maximum feeding period of the day of the immature grasshoppers — 9:00 to 10:00 a. m. — so that it will be as fresh as possible at that time. It is a well recognized fact that the general activities of grasshoppers, including of course their feeding activities, are largely controlled by the varying conditions of temperature and sunshine ' obtaining during the day. Even a superficial study will show that the feeding activities of these insects are more pronounced, as a rule, in warm, bright weather than in cool, cloudy weather. Of the two controlling influences, temperature is undoubtedly by far the more important one, and by some has been regarded as the only influence of im - portance governing the feeding of these insects. The counts secured in the attractiveness tests afford an excellent basis for elaborating the facts in the matter when they are correlated with the temperature and sunshine con - ditions obtaining at the time of the counts. A record was taken of the temperatures at 6:00 a. m., 8:00 a. m., 10:00 a. m., 12:00 m., 2:00 p. m., 4:00 p. m. and 6:00 p. m.. on June 12, 13, 14, 16, 18, 19, 22 and 27, 1923,- these being days on which attractiveness tests were made with prevailingly immature grasshoppers, and the correlation may be expressed in the following table: 1 The effect of sunshine and cloudiness upon grasshopper activity was rather adequately described in Bulletin ]*:. (p. 27). •The temperature record for June '25 is incomplete, so the counts for that day are not useful in this analysis. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 June 12 June 13 June 14 June 16 June 18 Juno 19 June 22 June 27 © -t en n en t. f. to to ■ . 35 _\ — ft — ft — ft — p. — a — a — p. O *) S p.. q. p. a p, ft-ft ■ 2. 3, • 2 ? £» S» 2„ 2» 2„ £„ 2„ 2„ 2„ 2„ 2„ 2» 2 „ * g 3 ss £5 as "§ as tt = as m s as «s as «= as *s as «£ •=£ . w e . . £ e" ft r * g p 2 « 5- E a 5 E g SB g c! a 3ft • P-£ __ P to J P 61 -.' C Cm .Si CU _fP&lt; P U ..ft tit P M .-.ft n ■ H-S Zb h-o Za E-i-S -So H-o Z o E-i-3 Za S-S Za fvS Za i":M ZM O 6:00 a. m 49 60 61 60 60 65 .: 63 50 \_[ 8:00 a. m 60 34 65 . 135 66 122 67 716 70 273 75 254 66 309 60 2203 4046 £ 10:00 a. m .65 697 73 886 71 455 72 2211. 75 1305 79 917 79 3379 65 3131 12981 5 12.00 m 71 1524 81 1122 76 845 77 1864 80 1483 80 1006 87 2291 65 1161 11296 ra 2:00 p. m 77 618 88 296 80 564 82 754 85 775 84 462 92 2654 67 1668 7791 2 4:00 p. m 74 516 78 486 76 365 81 1118 80 700 84 720 91 2732 60 573 7210 o 6:00 p. m 72 257 74 27 70 254 69 0* 70 237 80 96 82 466 67 434 1771 % f * Rained during entire 2-hour period. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 It may be observed that considering the entire 8 days the maximum feeding took place between 8:00 and 10:00 a. m., tho the feeding between 10:00 a. m. and noon was almost as heavy. Also, that on 3 days (June 16, 22 and 27) the maxi - mum feeding occurred between 8:00 and 10:00 a. m., while on 5 days (June 12, 13, 14, 18 and 19) it occurred between 10:00 a. m. and noon. The temperatures during these 8 two - hour periods of maximum feeding varied from 60° to 81° F., with the mean temperatures ranging from 62.5° to 79.5° F. and averaging 72.4° F. The optimum feeding temperature for immature individuals of the two-striped grasshopper in the North Platte Valley during middle and late June may, therefore, be placed at 72.4° F. A record was also taken of the temperatures at 8:00 a. m., 10:00 a. m., 12:00 m., 2:00 p. m., 4:00 p. m., and 6:00 p. m., on July 23, 24, 25, 26, 27 and 28, 1923,' these being days on which attractiveness tests were made with prevailingly adult grasshoppers, and the correlation in this case may be similarly expressed in the following table: 1 No temperature records were kept on July 30 and 31 and August 1. 2 and 3 so the counts on those days cannot he used in this analysis. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 July 23 July 24 July 26 July 26 July 27 July 28 .&lt; g a £ ca 2a 2 a 2 =_ 2 a S o t— ! Em gm Cm' _« -.in an Cm am Em am 2 OT an *r _, ,j mm hp a. w B p w w he w w ftp w w £ c do . h p • • _2 aw "« a « »a aw «a &amp;w »a aw w « aw Ma —5 OT ES _.« E£ .» £&amp; .&lt;=• .Eg j* E&amp; .5 E5 „• ° 5a w WW __ +. Ww o M _« o — ww ° *. ww o ._, Ww ° *- o*. 8:00 a. m 83 69 70 71 68 72 10:00 a. m 85 371 76 502 77 571 74 317 76 352 78 308 2421 S? ■"2:00 m 86 705 83 684 84 612 72 328 81 223 86 213 2765 &gt; &lt;J:00 p. m 73 188f 87 291 84 365 76 45 80 200 82 342 1431 g_ 4:00 p. m 71 29f 85 481 79 286 75 320 86 170 66 74f 1360 ffi 6:00 p. m 77 510 80 175 73 0* 71 138 84 83 07 103 1009 2 * Rained during: entire 2-hour period. 2 t Rained during part of the 2-hour period. §2 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">i. Mebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 It may be observed in this table that considering the entire 6 days the feeding was distinctly the heaviest between 10:00 a. m. and noon and that on 4 of the 6 days (July 23, 24, 25 and 26) the maximum feeding occurred during the same hours, while on one day (July 27) it occurred between 8:00 and 10:00 a. m., and on another day (July 28) between 12:00 and 2:00 p. m. The temperature during these 6 two-hour periods of maximum feeding varied from 68 to 86° F., with the mean temperatures ranging from 72 to 85.5° F. and aver - aging 79° F. The optimum feeding temperature for adult individuals of the two-striped grasshopper in the North Platte valley during late July may therefore be placed at 79° F. It is interesting to compare these optimum feeding tem - peratures with the range of daily temperatures obtained from the entire series of readings taken every 2 hours on the days when attractiveness tests were in progress, at 6:00 a. m. (8 readings) and at 8:00 a. m., 10:00 a. m., 12:00 m.,. 2:00 p. m., 4:00 p. m., and 6:00 p. m. (14 readings each). These readings may be expressed in the following table: 6:00 a. m. 49' F. to 65° F., average 58.5° F. 8:00 a. m. 60° F. to 83° F., average 68.7° F. 10:00 a. m. fi5" F. to 85° F., average 74.6° F. 12:00 m. 65° F. to 87° F., average 79.2° F. 2:00 p. m. .67° F. to 92° F., average 81.2° F. 4:00 p. m. 60° F. to 91° F., average 77.1° F. 6:00 p. m. .07° F. to 84° F., average 74.0° F. It may be noted that the period of the day when the opti - mum feeding temperature for immature grasshoppers first occurs is between 8:00 and 10:00 a. m., and that the period when the optimum feeding temperature for adult grass - hoppers first occurs is between 10:00 a. m. and noon. This coincides very well with the summaries of the total number of grasshoppers observed at the baits in the pans each hour, as given on preceding pages, where the heavy feeding of the day was shown to occur between 8:00 a. m. and 11:00 a. m. During the same summer that these experiments were carried out in Nebraska (1923), Parker (10, pp. 32-39) made similar studies on the relation of temperature to the feeding of the clear-winged grasshopper (Camnula pellucida) in Min - nesota. Briefly stated, his studies show that the individuals of that species began moving about when the temperature reached 60° F., were all active at 65° F., fed sparingly at poisoned bran mash baits at temperatures from 65 to 68° F., more actively at temperatures from 69 to 70° F., and most actively at temperatures from 71 to 77° F., while at tempera - tures higher than 77° F. feeding rapidly declined until 90° F. was reached, when feeding in the field practically stopped. The hour of maximum feeding, he found, usually occurred </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers during that hour of the day (anywhere between 7:00 a. m - and 2:00 p. m.) which first had a mean temperature of 73 to 77° F., or, on cool days, the nearest approach to those tem - peratures. The two-striped grasshopper in the North Platte valley of Nebraska seems to have a much greater range of maximum feeding temperatures than has the clear-winged grasshopper in Minnesota, feeding actively at temperatures from 60 to 86° F., as compared to 69 to 77° F. for the clear - winged species. In order to check up these conclusions in yet another way, the following test was carried out. On July 12, 1923, a pois - oned bait composed of 25 pounds of bran, % ounce of amyl acetate and IV2 pounds of -white arsenic was made up. On July 13 — a warm day, partly cloudy in the morning but clear in the afternoon — 6 pounds (weighed wet) of this bait were scattered between 11:00 a. m. and 11:30 a. m., when the temperature stood at 81° F., while another 6 pounds were scattered between 4:30 p. m. and 5:00 p. m., when the tem - perature stood at 80° F. On July 14, the morning of which was clear, a third batch of 6 pounds of the bait was scattered between 8:00 a., m. and 8:30 a. m., when the temperature stood at 70° F. In all cases the bait was scattered in selected isolated strips of alfalfa left standing along the irrigation ditch laterals, where the grasshoppers were numerous. A heavy rain fell about 2:00 p. m. of July 14, following which, between 5:00 p. m. and 6:00 p. m., a number of grasshoppers were swept from each treated alfalfa strip and immediately transferred to cages that had previously been placed over young and thrifty growing alfalfa. Nine cages were used in all, 3 for the grasshoppers from each of the 3 areas treated with the poisoned bait. A week later the number of living and dead grasshoppers in each of these cages was determined, and from this the per cent of grasshoppers killed was com - puted. The results were as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 73 &gt;_ _A s- i- t . J w . &gt;. ._&gt;. jj Zif z4 Zt ____ Cage lot and number 8:00 — 8:30 a. m. Cage 1 2110 12 284 Cage 2 290 21 275 Cage 3 325 15 310 Total ,)17 48 869 94.8 11:00—11:30 a. m. Cage 4 309 21 288 Cage 5 .. 157 14 143 Cage 6 342 l'.i 323 Total ... .808 54 754 93.3 4:30—5:00 p. m. Cage 7 171 15 150 Cage 8 .. 173 20 147 Cage 9 HK! 24 109 Total 537 0.7 472 87.8 The bait scattered between 8:00 a. m. and 8:30 a. m. proved to be the most effective, that scattered between 11:00 a. m. and 11:30 a. m. was only slightly less effective, while that scattered in the late afternoon — 4:30 p. m. to 5:00 p. m. — was distinctly less effective than the others. From the stand - point of effectiveness, therefore, the best time to scatter poisoned bait for grasshoppers is very evidently in the fore - noon, from 8:00 to 11:00 a. m., whenever the day develops normally warm, and certainly it should be scattered so that it is out by 9:00 a. m., where the grasshoppers are prevail - ingly immature, or by 10:00 a. m., where they are prevail - ingly adult. How heavily should the bait be scattered tu secure maxi - mum efficiency? The question as to how thickly to scatter poisoned bran bait to secure the maximum efficiency compatible with an economical use of the bait is one concerning which our definite information has been rather inadequate. Several years ago the current recommendations of entomologists were to scatter the bait very thinly, only about 5 to 7 pounds to the acre (e. g., 2, p. 3), but during the past 4 years the tendency has been to recommend a much heavier application. For example, the Montana Agricultural Experiment Station in 1923 and </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers again in 1925 (6, pp. 14 and 16; 12, p. 4) recommended from 10 to 25 pounds of poisoned bran bait, wet weight, to the acre, according to the abundance of the grasshoppers, 20 or 25 pounds to the acre being the amount recommended where the pests were very plentiful. Again, the Minnesota Experi - ment Station (9, p. 4) in 1924 recommended 20 pounds, wet weight, to the acre for an ordinary infestation, more to be used where the grasshoppers were heavily massed. In the summer of 1923, in an effort to secure some definite data on this question, 8 areas (numbered 1 to 8), each one about 50 by 55 feet in size, (thus containing 2,750 square feet, or approximately one-sixteenth of an acre) were meas - ured off in an alfalfa field on the farm of Mr. Ora Randall, just east of the Scottsbluff Experiment Substation, in which the grasshoppers were abundant and where no poisoned bait had been scattered that season, and early (before 8 :30 a. m.) on the morning of August 10, a warm clear day, a poisoned bait made up of 25 pounds of bran, 5 gills of the 8-pound to the gallon strength of commercial sodium arsenite and % ounce of amyl acetate was scattered over areas 1 to 7, at the rates of 2 I / 4, 5, 7*4, 10, 15, 20 and 25 pounds, respectively, of the bait, wet weight, to the acre. Area 8 was left untreated, as a check. Immediately after scattering the poisoned bait the oper - ators (Messrs. Wehr and Worley) walked straight across each area twice, first across on one side and then back on the other side, sweeping up the grasshoppers in their path with a large hand sweeping net. The number of grasshoppers thus caught in each traversing of each area was counted and recorded, and the results of both of the sweepings of each area were totaled. Twenty-four hours were allowed for the poisoned bait to take effect upon the grasshoppers eating it, and on the mornings (usually between 8:00 and 9:00 a. m.) of the third, fourth, fifth and sixth days after scattering the bait (i. e., August 12, 13, 14 and 15) , the operators traversed and swept the areas in a manner identical with that employed on the day that the poisoned bait was scattered, similarly counting, recording and totaling the number of grasshoppers caught. It was expected that these counts would provide data for at least approximately determining the relative kill of the different rates of scattering the baits on the different areas. However, one difficulty was experienced in this test that to some extent unavoidably vitiated the value of the counts thus obtained, and that was the tendency of unpoisoned grasshop - pers to migrate on to the poisoned areas from the outside, after the scattered bait had largely lost its attractiveness and therefore was no longer a menace to them, thus reinforcing </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 the numbers of the grasshoppers that had been present on the treated areas at the time of the scattering of the poisoned bait, but that had survived. This complication was not unan - ticipated, and in order to avoid or minimize it the areas (Nos. 1-3) on which the bait was scattered at the rates of 2*4, 5 and 71/2 pounds to the acre were placed 100 feet apart and 250 feet north of the areas (Nos. 4 and 5) on which the bait was scattered at the rates of 10 and 15 pounds to the acre, while these latter in turn were 100 feet apart and 250 feet north of the areas (Nos. 6 and 7) on which the bait was scattered at the rates of 20 and 25 pounds to the acre, these being also 100 feet from each other. The check area (No. 8) was placed across a ditch, 200 feet south of the area on which the bait was scattered at the rate of 25 pounds to the acre. Nevertheless, despite all of these precautions, there was un - doubtedly a considerable migration on to the treated areas during the progress of the experiment. The results of this test may be shown in the following table: </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Per cent ot hri increase or _% Area Founds to decrease hh No. the acre '. AuKUstlO August 12 Au B ustl3 Au B ustl4 .Aui.u-.t_ 16 g 1212 121212 __ 1 2% 99 58 70 65 185 _ 90 102 45 15 °_ _ 108 _,., „ « Total 157 135 275 147 258 +64.3 • w 2 5 73 55 61 45 . 31 . 55 50 45 68 .55 Tntal 128 106 86 95 123 -d.o « 3 7% 42 75 43 22 90 45 45 32 52 53 S_ Total 117 65 . 135 77 105 -10.3 « 4 10 93 71 195 146 263 176 234 115 ' 143 130 o Total 164 341 439 349 273 +66.5 w . K iK 59 58 103 129 135 73 114 99 118 119 O 5 5 Total 117 232 208 213 237 _ +102.6 g 6 20 65 88 79 31 100 57 32 34 53 37 g Total 153 110 157 66 90 -41.1 __ 7 25 65 172 41 42 59 42 12 18 27 23 g Total 237 83 101 30 50 -78.9 3 8 Check 72 106 82 103 305 90 95 106 190 91 g Total 178 185 395 201 281 +57.9 w </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 While, owing to the considerable daily variation in the counts due to the movements of the grasshoppers on to and off of the several areas, the above is not entirely satisfactory as a basis for accurate conclusions as to the rate of mortality on the several treated areas due to poisoning, it is, neverthe - less, quite apparent that there was no marked and consistent decrease in the grasshopper population of the several areas except on Nos. 6 and 7, where the baits were scattered at the rates of 20 and 25 pounds, wet weight, respectively. It appears, therefore, that in order to secure maximum efficiency where the grasshoppers are abundant it is necessary to scatter poisoned bran bait at rates of not less than 20 pounds, wet weight, to the acre. In the alfalfa field, is it always necessary to scatter the poisoned bait over the entire field? Where the grasshoppers are rather evenly distributed thru a field of growing alfalfa it is usually necessary to scatter the poisoned bait over the entire field. But it is not always neces - sary that the bait be scattered over the entire alfalfa field, for. when the alfalfa has reached the stage of growth that it is ready to cut, a simple expedient that is instrumental in effecting a considerable saving of time and material is feas - ible, and in fact is frequently used by progressive farmers in the North Platte valley. It was frequently observed during the course of these experiments with poisoned baits for grasshoppers, both in 192__i and in 1923, that very soon after a stand of alfalfa had been cut, and the leaves had begun to wither and dry, that the grasshoppers in that field began to migrate to its edges, and, if necessary, on out of it in search of green food. Any field of corn or small grain adjacent or close to the cut alfalfa field was practically certain to be invaded and more or less damaged, at least about the margins. But whenever narrow strips of alfalfa were left standing around the outer edges of the alfalfa field when the remainder of the field was cut, the bulk of the grasshoppers was held in great concen - tration in these strips until the leaves had all been devoured from the stems, for as long as the insects found green food to eat anywhere in the field they were loathe to leave it. Under these conditions it was found that all that was necessary was to drive around the edges of the cut alfalfa field with a barrel of poisoned bait in a wagon, and, as the team slowly pulled the wagon along, to scatter the poisoned bait heavily — at least 20 to 25 pounds, wet weight, to the acre — over these strips in which the grasshopper population of the field was temporarily concentrated. This operation can be completed in a surprisingly short time and a heavy kill </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers of grasshoppers can be secured as a result of it. As a rule, farmers are very busy putting up the hay and irrigating at the time of the season that the alfalfa is cut, so that the sav - ing in time and labor that can be effected by destroying the grasshoppers by this plan is as valuable as the very consider - able saving of bait that is made possible by it. A general poisoning effort immediately after the first cutting of alfalfa hay, using this method, is very desirable in years when grass - hoppers are seriously injurious, Altho the latter cuttings of hay come on rather too irregularly for a general effort of this sort, individual farmers can profit by employing the method in their fields whenever the hay does reach the stage of cutting. The hardest part of the fight against grasshoppers is in the alfalfa field, hence any method of making that fight more successful should be taken advantage of whenever possible. Is' spraying the alfalfa -with arsenicals any, more effective in destroying grasshoppers tlian the use of poisoned bait? The question is frequently asked whether it would not be a more effective method of destroying grasshoppers to spray an alfalfa field with arsenicals, rather than to scatter poisoned bait over it. In July, 1922, several preliminary tests were made at the Scotts Bluff Experiment Substation by Mr. J. A. Holden, the superintendent, in an effort to find the answer to this question. These tests may first be briefly reported upon. In the first test, 3 large areas of alfalfa were sprayed on July 8, one area with Paris green at the rate of 3%, pounds to 50 gallons of water, the second area with the same solu - tion, to which about 2 quarts of sugar-beet molasses was added, and the third area with white arsenic at the rate of 2 J /o pounds to • 50 gallons of water. Altho it rained on Jufy 11, when the results were checked up on July 14 only a very few live grasshoppers were to be found on any of the areas, while a considerable number of dead ones were to be found on the ground. The foliage was, however, consider - ably burned, especially that sprayed with the white arsenic. In another test, an area of alfalfa was sprayed on July 10 with a similar spray of Paris green and water, to which, however, a quantity of lime and some salt were added, and a large cage, measuring 6 by 6 feet, was placed over a part of the sprayed area, to receive between 500 and 600 grasshoppers that were caught in an unsprayed field with a hoppercatcher. In spite of the rain of the next day (July 11), on July 14 only about a half dozen living grasshappers were in the cage. In a third test, more carefully conducted, a field of alfalfa about 15 inches high was sprayed on July 14 with three solu- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 tions — one area with Paris green at the rate of 5 pounds to 50 gallons of water, with 1^ pounds of salt added, a sec - ond area with the Paris green and salt solution to which some sugar-beet molasses was added, and a third area with the Paris green and salt solution to which some soap was added. A large cage, measuring 6 by 6 feet, was placed over a part of each sprayed area, and a similar cage over some unsprayed alfalfa, to serve as a check. Between 800 and 1,000 grass - hoppers were placed in each of these four cages, and a like number in a similar cage over unsprayed alfalfa where the imprisoned grasshoppers were offered a poisoned bran mash bait composed of 25 pounds of bran, 1 pound of Paris green, 3 ounces of amyl acetate, 2 quarts of molasses, 1 pound of salt, and 2'/» gallons of water. It rained some on July 15 and again on July 16. When the results were checked up on July 17 there were about 2 dozen grasshoppers alive in each of the cages over the sprayed alfalfa and approximately 40 per cent of the original number in the cage with the pois - oned bran mash. On July 18 there were only about 6 live grasshoppers in the cages over the sprayed alfalfa, about the same number alive as on the day before in the cage with the poisoned bran mash, and about 90 per cent of the original number alive in the check cage. The alfalfa of all of the sprayed areas was badly burned, that on the second area (Paris green-salt-molasses) the most, that on the first area (Paris green-salt) next, and that on the third area (Paris green-salt-soap) the least. In 1923, in order to learn what the mortality would be in alfalfa fields sprayed with arsenicals at such strengths as not to produce serious burning of the foliage, and how this mor - tality would compare with the mortality in alfalfa fields treated with poisoned bran mash, the following experiment was performed: About 10 days before the alfalfa in the selected field was to be given the first cutting, four strips, each about 12 feet wide, were cut completely across the field, so that by the time the remainder of the field was cut, on July 7, these four strips had started a tender new growth of alfalfa that was very attractive to the grasshoppers. Allow - ing 48 hours for the grasshoppers to concentrate in the strips, between 1:30 and 4:30 p. m. on July 9 these four strips of well-infested tender alfalfa were each sprayed with 50 gallons of spray solution, using a field sprayer, one (strip No. 1) with Paris green at the rate of 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, with 2 pounds of lime and 2 quarts of New Orleans molasses added, another (strip No. 2) with arsenate of lead at the rate of 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, with the same amounts of lime and molasses added as in the solution </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers used on strip No.l, the third (strip No. 3) with arsenate of lime at the rate of 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, again with 2 pounds of lime and 2 quarts of molasses added, and the fourth (strip No. 4) with a sodium arsenite solution contain - ing 8 pounds of arsenic to. the gallon at the rate of 1 quart to 50 gallons of water with 2 quarts of the molasses added. Immediately before the spraying was done, the operator (Mr. Worley) walked across each strip twice, first across on one side and then back on the other side, sweeping up the grasshoppers in his path with a large hand sweeping net. The number of grasshoppers thus caught in each traversing of each strip was counted and recorded, and the results of both of the sweepings of each strip were totaled. The day was cloudy, and by evening a rain was falling which no doubt washed some of the poison from the leaves, but on the follow - ing day a sufficient amount was found adhering to the leaves and stems as to indicate that a respraying was not necessary. Twenty-four hours were allowed for the poison to take effect upon the grasshoppers eating of the sprayed foliage, and on the mornings (between 8:15 and 9:45 a. m.) of the third, fourth, fifth and sixth days after the spraying (i. e., July 11, 12, 13 and 14), the operator traversed and swept the strips in a manner identical with that employed on the date that the strips were sprayed, similarly counting, recording and totaling the number of grasshoppers caught. These counts provide data for determining the kill of the different spray solutions on the four strips, and such data can be regarded as fairly accurate since there was little or no migration to the sprayed strips except on the fourth day (July 13), when there was a very obvious influx of grasshoppers to strips Nos. 1 to 3 from the outside and probably also from strip No. 4. The results of this test may be shown in the following table: Strip Poison Per cent of No. used July 9 July 11 July 12 July 13 July 14 decrease 1 Paris green 1523 594 225 243 208 86.3 2 arsenate of lead 1019 337 253 432 268 73.7 3 arsenate of lead 1019 337 299 432 268 73.7 4 arsenite of soda.. 997 137 On the second day after the spraying, and before the results became complicated by the influx of new grasshoppers on the fourth day, the apparent per cent of grasshoppers killed on strips Numbers 1 to 4 was 60.9, 66.9, 61.4 and 86.2 per cent, respectively. On the third day the apparent mortality on strips Numbers 1 to 3 was 85.6, 77.1 and 70.1 per cent, respec - tively. These percentages are probably more correctly repre - sentative of the actual kill, especially on the heavily invaded </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 strips Numbers 2 and 3, than the final figures of the fifth day, when strips Numbers 1 to 3 showed an apparent mortality of 86.3, 73.7 and 73.2 per cent, respectively. Sixteen hours after the spraying (i. e., at 8:30 a. m. on July 10), strip Number 4, sprayed with the arsenite of soda solution, had the sprayed leaves burned about 85 per cent. No foliage burning was noted on strips Numbers 1 to 3. Forty - eight hours after the spraying (i. e., at 4:30 p. m. on July 11), the foliage of strip Number 4, sprayed with the sodium arsenite solution, was 100 per cent burned and deserted by the grasshoppers, so no further counts were taken on that strip. The other 3 strips showed no burning injury. Five days after the spraying (i. e., on July 14) strip Number 1, sprayed with Paris green, showed a slight burning, but not enough to injure the alfalfa. No burning was detectable on strips Numbers 2 and 3 on July 14. Altho the sodium arsenite spray unquestionably was most fatal to the grasshoppers, its destructiveness to the alfalfa foliage made it impossible from a practical stand - point, as had, of course, been expected. Of the 3 other arsenicals, the Paris green seemed to give the highest kill combined with no important burning injury, so it was tested further in a final experiment. An entire field of young alfalfa was sprayed with Paris green at the rate of 2 pounds to 50 gallons of water, with 2 pounds of lime and 2 quarts of New Orleans molasses added, beginning at 10:00 a. m. on July 19, a clear warm day with a slight south wind. Just before the spraying was done, Mr. Worley walked across one side of the field and then back on the other side, sweeping up the grass - hoppers in his path with a large hand sweeping net as he went. The number of grasshoppers thus caught in each traversing of the field was counted and recorded, and the results were totaled. As before, 24 hours were allowed for the poison to take effect upon the grasshoppers eating of the sprayed foliage, and on the mornings (between 8:30 and 9:00 a. m.) of the third, fourth, fifth and sixth days after the spraying (i. e., July 21, 22, 23 and 24), Mr. Worley traversed and swept the field in a manner identical with that employed on the date that the field was sprayed, similarly counting, recording and totaling the number of grasshoppers caught. The results of this test may be shown in the following table : Per cent Date July 19 July 21 July 22 July 23 July 24 of Sweeping 12 12 12 12 12 decrease 122 70 64 37 79 11 37 14 19 22 Total 192 101 90 51 41 78.6 From the results of these experiments it is evident that when a field of alfalfa is sprayed with an arsenical solution </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers that will not seriously burn the foliage a mortality of about 73.2 to 86.3 per cent, averaging about 77.9 per cent, may be expected to result. Inasmuch as equally good kills, and fre - quently even better ones, are commonly secured with poisoned bran bait, the answer seems clear that spraying an alfalfa field with arsenicals is not a more effective method than the use of poisoned bait, and nothing would be gained by resort - ing to spraying. Moreover, in spraying alfalfa there is much greater danger of poisoning farm animals than when a poisoned bait is correctly "scattered. In the light of both the 1922 and 1923 experiments, what seems to be the best poisoned bait to use for grasshoppers in the North Platte valley? . The exact answer to this question depends, of course, upon a number of circumstances. The age of the grasshoppers has an important bearing, for if they are preponderatingly or exclusively adult, salt should be included in the bait, while if if they are preponderatingly or exclusively immature, the salt should be omitted, as was shown in the 1922 experiments as published in Bulletin 183 (pp. 17-18). The availability of the ingredients may also make a great difference in the formula to be used, as, for example, in determining the point as to whether dry white arsenic powder or liquid sodium arsenite solution should be used as the poison. Where a com - mercially prepared sodium arsenite solution is readily obtain - able on the local market, at a reasonable price and in the quantity desired, or where mixing plants have been equipped to prepare a home-made solution in quantities by boiling white arsenic powder with sal soda crystals (4, pp. 25-26), the advantages of the sodium arsenite solution as to lower cost and ease of securing an even admixture thru the mash would make its use desirable. But otherwise the always busy farmer will undoubtedly wisely choose to use the white arsenic powder, and thus avoid the laborious task of preparing the home-made sodium arsenite solution. And upon the choice between white arsenic and sodium arsenite will also depend whether or not molasses is added to the bait. In the North Platte valley sugar-beet molasses from the sugar factories should be used, as it is very much cheaper than either New Orleans or black strap molasses. All of the formulae here given have coarse-flaked wheat bran recommended as the base. 1 ■'In 1921 Fluke (2, p. 2) of Wisconsin recommended a mixture of equal parts of bran and sawdust as an alternative for pure bran in grasshopper baits. In 192S Cooley, Parker and Strand (6, pp. 9-10) recommended the use of such a mixture in Montana when bran was very expensive, or of old Cottonwood or pine sawdust alone if bran was unobtainable. In the same year Corkins (7, pp. 9 and 11) recommended for Colorado a mixture of bran and sawdust where the latter was </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 The final recommendations in answer to the very practical question heading this section may, therefore, be presented in the following 4 recommended formulae. Any one of these will make about 60 pounds of poisoned bait, wet weight, or enough to cover between 2 and 3 acres. The cost will be, therefore, from 27 to 35 cents an acre, or somewhat less. Either No. 1. For im- No. 2, For _, « , , . _ , . . mature ffrass- adult Krass- Coarse-naked wheat bran (tree hoppers Cost' hoppers Cost' from shorts) 25 pounds .35 25 pounds 35 White arsenic (!)(. per cent As 2 0:0 1 Vs pounds .24 1 V_ pounds .24 Amyl acetate (technical N'o. 1 grade) % ounce .075 % ounce 075 Salt (any cheap granular gradel 1 pound .02 Water 2 L j gallons.. 2^ gallons.. .665 .685 Or N... II. For im- No. 4. For mature uras. - ndult trrass- Coarse-flaked wheat bran (free hoppers Cost' hoppers Cost' from shorts) 25 pounds .35 Sodium arsenite solution (ft 1 '4 pint. .047 pounds As_0 : , to the call 'm pint .047 25 pounds .35 Amyl acetate (technical N'o. 1 grade) %» ounce .075 % ounce .075 Molasses (sugar-beetl 2 ciuarts .05 2 quarts .05 Salt (any cheap granular grade) 1 pound .02 Water 2 l u gallons 2 '-j gallons .522 .542 rasily obtained and thf production value per acre of the land was low. In 102-1 Pettit (*, p. 4) recommended a pure sawdust bait Tor use in Michigan op the basis of lower cost and supposedly irreater safety. In 102 4 Ruggles and Parker (9. p. 2 ) repeated the Montana recommendation for Minnesota. In 1925 the Wisconsin Station (11. pp. 7-t-**t l recommended a sawdust -sodium ar senile-salt - molasses bait for ireneral use in that state. The Department of Entomology of the Nebraska Agricultural Ex peri men t Station has made no real test of sawdust vs. bran in grasshopper baits, hut in July (10 to 24). 1026. Dawson County Agent Alvah R. Hecht tried! the Mir Mean bait recommended hy Pettit on a farm near Lexinnton. netting the sawdust from a basket factory at that place, and had exceptionally good success with it: better, in fact, than with the bran bait, he count inn 1 K dead trrass hoppers to the square yard where the sawdust was used and only H or 0 dead grasshoppers to the square yard where bran was used, on the third day after the baits were scattered. The consistent superiority of the sawdust bait over the bran bait, however, is its much -greater cheapness in locali - ties where an abundance of free or very cheap sawdust is available. Unfortunately few Nebraska localities have this advantage. The objection to it is that in dry climates it dries out very quickly and is then not as effective as hran. If used, it should be screened, anil substituted for bran by bulk rather than by weight. 1 In computing the cost of the innredients of these formulae, wheat bran has been priced at $1.40 per cwt.. white arsenic at 16 cents a pound, sodium arsenite solution (H pounds arsenious oxid to the gallon) at $l.. r &gt;0 a gallon, amyl acetate (technical No. 1 grade j at 10 cents an ounce, suuar-heet molasses at 10 cents a gallon and salt at 2 cents a pound, these heinir the current retail prices of these materials in the North Platte valley in lit 23. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers It may be interesting to briefly compare the final findings of the Nebraska experiments, as expressed in the above formulae, with the formulae recommended elsewhere as the result of other, and independent, experiments. The formula developed in Montana in 1919, and reported in 1921 by Parker and Seamans (1, p. 138), differs from formulae Number 2 and Number 4, as above recommended for adult grasshoppers, only in the recommendation of 1 pound of Paris green instead of iy_\ pounds of white arsenic or y_, pint of sodium arsenite solution and of 3 ounces of amyl acetate instead of % of an ounce. Following the experimental work of 1920 and 1921 in Montana, as reported by Parker in 1922 (3, pp. 3-6), and of 1922, as reported by Cooley, Parker and Strand in 1923 (6, p. 5), the Montana formula was modified so as to differ from Number 4, as above recommended for adult grasshop - pers, only in the recommendation of 1 pound of Paris green, white arsenic or crude arsenic instead of Vi pint of sodium arsenite solution. The formula recommended for Minnesota in 1924 by Ruggles and Parker (9, p. 2) and by Parker alone (10, p. 27), as the results of experiments conducted in that state in 1923, and the bait used in the demonstration work conducted by Messrs. Lockwood and Udine of the Bureau of Entomology of the U. S. Department of Agriculture in the North Platte valley in the summer of 1923, both differ from Number 2, as above recommended for adult grasshoppers, only in the recommendation of l 1 /^, pounds of crude arsenic instead of V/i pounds of white arsenic, of 1% instead of 1 pound of salt, and in the inclusion of 2 quarts of molasses. The most strongly recommended Colorado formula, one con - taining sodium arsenite solution as the poison (Colorado No. 12), as given by Corkins in 1923 (5, p. 9 and 7, p. 9), as a result of experiments conducted in that state in 1922, is iden - tical with Number 4, as above recommended, except in the trivial difference that it recommends 1*4 pounds instead of 1 pound of salt. Other comparisons might be made, but these are sufficient to show that the general results secured in the Nebraska ex - periments are very similar to those obtained from careful experimentation in other western states. The cost, for materials only, of our four recommended formulae (Nos. 1 to 4) as above given, would be, respectively, $1.11, $1.14, $0.87, and $0.90 for a sack of 100 pounds, wet weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Station, Research Bulletin 41 literature cited 1. Parker, J. R. and Seamans, H. L. Experiments with Grasshopper Baits. Journal of Economic Entomology, xiv, pp. 138-141 (February, 1921). 2. Fluke, C. L., Jr. Poison the Grasshoppers. Circular 135, Exten - sion Service of the Wisconsin College of Agriculture, pp. 2-4 (May, 1921). 3. Parker, J. R. Improvements in the Methods of Preparing and Using Grasshopper Baits. Bulletin 148, Montana Agricultural Experi - ment Station, pp. 3-19 (February, 1922). 4. Swenk, M. H. and Wehr, E. E. Experiments with Poisoned Baits for Grasshoppers. Bulletin 183, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, pp. 2-28 (January, 1923). 5. Corkins, C. L. Sodium Arsenite as a Killing Agent in Grasshop - per Baits. Bulletin 280, Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station, pp. 3-15 (January, 1923). 6. Cooley, R. A., Parker, J. R. and Strand, A. L. Improved Methods of Controlling Grasshoppers. Circular 112, Montana Agricultural Experiment Station, pp. 1-20 (January, 1923). 7. Corkins, C. L. Grasshopper Control in Colorado. Bulletin 287, Colorado Agricultural Experiment Station, pp. 3-19 (June, 1923). 8. Pettit, R. H. Common Pests of Field and Garden Crops. Grass - hoppers. Special Bulletin 132, Michigan Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion, pp. 3-4 (March, 1924). 9. Ruggles, A. G. and Parker, J. R. Circular 17, University of Minnesota Agricultural Extension Division, pp. 1-4 (April, 1924). 10. Parker, J. R. Observations on the Clear-winged Grasshopper. Bulletin 214, Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station, pp. 5-44 (July, 1924). 11. Granovsky, A. A. The Organized Co-operative Campaign Against Grasshoppers in Wisconsin. Journal of Economic Entomology, xviii, pp. 73-83 (February, 1925). 12. Strand, A. L. Leaflet, Montana Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion, pp. 1-4 (May, 1925). </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>