<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Girls' Industrial School</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Girls' Industrial School GENEVA, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">182 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA, NEBRASKA OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES Superintendent Paii. S. McAi lay Mae Hirst Matron Dortiia M. Maxnehs Secretary Maut Donahi e Principal of Schools NON-RESIDENT Joseph Bixby Physician </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 183 GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. GENEVA, NEBRASKA To his Excellency. Honorable Keith Seville, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Com- missioners of State Institutions. Henry denies, Silas A. Holcomb, and Eugene O- Mayficld. Gentlemen: In compliance with law, I submit for your consideration the biennial report of this institution covering the period December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918. The object of this report is to convey to the reader a comprehensive presentation of the policies of the institu - tion in dealing with the inmates and the public in general, the educational, domestic, moral and religious training, finances, general recommendations for future plans, main - tenance and improvements. THE SCHOOI Having so recently come to the Girls' Industrial School as its head, I feel that but little credit is due me for the splendid condition of the school at this time. I found such a degree of interest manifested by all concerned that ab - sence and tardiness was almost unknown. This interest continued to the end of the term, in spite of the fact that the term was finished under Miss Nettie Whitten,,who came to us a stranger to the school and to me, only a month before school closed. Thirty girls finished the work of the eighth grade and presented a very good program together with appropriate commencement exercises to an interested audience in our beautiful auditorium on June 14, 1918. HOME ECONOMICS Home economics covers the art of good housekeeping preparation and cooking of all meals; baking of bread and pastries of all kinds; the making of jellies and preserves; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 184 transformation of vegetables to pickles, kraut, slaw, and relishes; the proper method of making beds; washing and cleaning windows; oiling and polishing floors, woodwork and furniture; sewing by hand and machine; making of skirts, waists, aprons, dresses, gowns, and all household linens, mending, patching, darning, making buttonholes, hemstitching, embroidering, tatting, crocheting, and drawn work, all of which is taught the girls by competent in - structors. RELIGIOUS TRAIMXf The religious training consists of chapel services each Sunday afternoon conducted by the ministers of Geneva. These services are open to the public and we are always pleased to have those who are interested come and visit us. The girls enjoy these sermons and talks to the full - est, and good results are in evidence throughout the week. DAILY ROUTINE Breakfast at seven a. m. ; then bed making, sweeping, dusting, a^d usual household tasks are taken up and dis - posed of by that portion of the girls not in school or em - ployed on any of the details in the forenoon. At 8 :45 a. m. those who go to school, go to the different school rooms for the forenoon session. At 12 noon, dinner; then play for those who go to school in the forenoon ; at 1 p. m. all details, such as laundry, sewing, kitchen, etc., are taken up for the afternoon ; also at 1 p. m. school is in order for those who attend the afternoon session. At 5 p. m., supper; at 6:30 p.m., general assembly of thirty minutes chorus practice; then discussion of daily events; then rest or play until bedtime, 8:30 p.m., at which time all inmates are in bed and the dormitories in darkness. LIBRARY Our library is largely furnished and supplied with good reading matter by the State Library Commission, and the girls greatly enjoy reading these books. In fact, its effects are recognized and highly appreciated by the teachers, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 185 family managers, and all employees, who mingle with or have supervision over the girls: and I fully agree with the former superintendent. Miss McMahon, in asserting that the good results of the library can scarcely be overestimated. RECOMMENDATIONS TO THE LEGISLATURE FOR THE COMING BIENNILM 1 find that a great many people think that our juris - diction over girls who have been committed to our care by any court should extend to the twenty-first birthday as in the case of boys. This I most earnestly recommend. Ref - ormation comes slowly to the girl who has yielded to wayward tendencies, and coming to us. as she always does, lacking in attainments possessed by the girl who has been properly trained at home. I think such a girl should be under government until capable of self-control and self - support. 1 do not mean to say she should remain in the institu - tion until she is twenty-one, but that she should be given the authority and protection of those in charge. Relative to requirements for this institution to be cov - ered by appropriation during the coming session of the Legislature, I desire to make the following recommenda - tions: Furniture and Equipment for proposed hospital build ing, $5000. In order to secure better fire protection than now exists, I would recommend that the water mains be tapped and an independent line run on the east side of the new building to the power house and connected to a fire pump. From the fire pump a four inch pressure line should be connected with two fire hydrants at such points that the building would be adequately protected. The cost of the above improvements would be approximately $1500. I further recommend that two spiral chute fire escapes be provided for the old building. Owing to the height of this building, the cost of these fire escapes will be approximately $2000. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">186 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF For 1800 feet of sewer line for carrying effluent from septic tanks, I recommend an appropriation of $2500. Believing an isolation hospital building to be a necessity here owing to the large number of syphilitic cases con - stantly on treatment, I would recommend the following: That a hospital building be built of suitable size to care for twenty-five or thirty patients, together with nurses, attendants, etc., and would recommend that an appropria - tion of $35,000 be set aside for the purpose of completing and finishing same. For poultry yard and extra poultry houses, I recom - mend an appropriation of $750. Finding the small parcel of land owned by the state in connection with this institution inadequate for the pur - pose to which it is devoted, namely, pasture, hay-land, and garden or truck farming and believing that this will be more apparent as time goes on, and that the demand for greater production will be increasing, I would recommend that not less than forty acres of land be purchased in addition to the seventy owned by the state, and if found possible and practical that the 160 acre farm adjoining us on the north be purchased. CONCLUSION And now, Gentlemen, in conclusion, I desire to express my appreciation for the hearty support and kindly interest at all times manifested by you since my coming to this institution. Respectfully submitted, Paul S. McCaulat, Superintendent. Geneva, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 187 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE INMATES' FUND Not* These are the personal funds of the inmates held in trust by the Institution for these inmates and received and expended for their sole individual benefit PERIOD Debits | Creditt hand April 11. 1918, $2: I Aoril, 19 May, 19 June, 19 $ 26.03 I $ 45.31 i.97 I 168.73 182.68 156.24 .18 58.97 76 94.68 August, l!i Septemb t 123.21 ' 114.60 119.49 ; 75.21 Octobi Mover HI 6.55 I 43.52 £.87 $ 984.80 anee on hand December 1 Note —All monthly statements of this fu ncorrect. Ledger checked April 11, 1918 as npiled from December 1. 1916 to April. 1918, itely as possible with the information avail- and the account commenced ar RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1, 191 ( Jecember 1, 1918 AMOUNTS RECEIVED jENERAL SOURCE Totml Dec. 1. 1916 i Dec. 1, 1917 ! Dae. 1, 1916 in Dec. 1, 1917 ; Dec. 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1918 Hogs 309.85 I $ 376.95 ! $ 686.80 Musical lustrum Cows 646.10 646.10 214.80 60.00 274.80 Calve 52.50 44.50 97.00 Meals and lodging Horses 33.20 55.75 88.95 85.00 85.00 74.84 74.84 Flanrr.'l and h Hay 67.00 | 67.00 Junk 44.77 5.35 5S.12 Excess h; Colt m?rg?ncy cash fund 20.75 15.00 15.00 Cow hide 10.50 10.50 Refund on sippl: Freigh: refund Miscellaneous. 9.68 9.68 6.00 .17 6.17 3.40 2.42 ! 5.82 Total $ 842.02 I t 1296.51 t 2138.53 Ledp </seg>
            <seg id="p008">188 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OK INVENTORY OF LtNDS, BUILDINGS, FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPD/E MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE Note— Total on hand, Dec. 1, 1916, total on hand and produced, total sold, total preserved or transformed, total waste, total disposed of, and total on hand Dec. 1, 1917, is zero in each cas t e hence not shown. No eggs produced. Not*— Total on hand Dec. 1, 1917, total on hand and produced, total sold, total preserved or transformed, total waste, total disposed of, and total on hand Dec. 1, 1918, is zero in each caw, hence not shown. November 30, 1918 Acres Aeres Cultivated Uncultivated Total Esti- i ~ " — — -— — — —^— Acrc~ rn&amp;tcd Garden Farm Orchard Campus Waste at* Value I i " I-and ownwi by institution 21.1 40.7 .2 8 TO ,$15750.00 Land rented by institution icashl Land rented by institution i shares) Total 11.1 I 40.7 2 8 70 I $ 15750.00 i l i i - , ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING , AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Administration buildinf i 40000.00 $ 3360.00 : $ 7846.75 t 51206.75 New building I 50000.00 2100.00 &lt; 9125.00 61225.00 Boiler house 2500.00 8500.00 10000.00 21000.00 Smoke stack 1500.00 1500.00 laundry 35000.00 5000.00 40000.00 Poultry houne 500.00 500.00 Implement house 500.00 700.00 1200.00 Tool shed 100.00 300.00 400.00 Coal house 150.00 150.00 Barn 2500.00 1000.00 3500.00 Ground improvements 6500.00 1600.00 8100.00 Total j $132750.00 * 13960.00 $ 40471.75 $ 1600.00 $ 188781.75 I I I i I DAIRY AND POULTRY PRODUCTS December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1917 i i Total Produced Total Consumed NAME OF PRODUCT 1 1 Measure [ Value Measure Value Milk 58400 lb. $ 2336.00 58400 lb. $ 2336.00 December 1, 1917, to December 1, 1918 I i NAME OP PRODUCT Total Produced Total Consumed ODUCT Measure Value Measure Value 570 das. $187.92 570 dot. j $187.95 65600 lbs. 4100.00 65600 lbs. 4100.0C ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 189 GARDEN PRODUCTS December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1917 Num - ber of Total on Hand Acre NAME OF Total Produced Culti- PRODUCT Total Consumed Dec. 1, 1917 vated Measure Value Measure ; Value | Measure Value Beans 20 bu. | $60.00 6 bu. j 7.50 6 bu. 6.00 IWrx* 6 ! Carrots Cabbage 4H0 lb. 12.00 25 bu. I 11.25 30 bu. ' 45.00 Corn, sweet ta 16 Potatoes 250 bu. J 500.00 350 bu. I $700 00 50 bu. 100.00 Tomauws $741.75 $700.00 Note— Total on hand, Dee. 1, 1916. total on hand and produced, total sold, total preserved or transformed, total waste, and total disposed of, is zero in each case, hence not shown. FARM PRODUCTS December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1917 Num - ber of Total Produced ! Total Consumed Total on Hand Acres NAME OF Culti- PRODUCT vated Dec. 1, 1917 Measure Value Measure Value Measure I Value 10 Hay, alfalfa 37 ton | $590.00 | 12 ton $180.00 25 ton $410.00 1.5 ton 22.50 1.5 ton 22.50 Hay, timothy Pasture 108.00 108.00 2» 1720.50 $288.00 $432.50 Not* — Total on hand Dec. 1, 1916, total on hand and produced, total sold, total preserved or transformed, total waste, and total disposed of, is zero in each ease, hence not shown. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 190 h J r. •3^ ? s § -s •* * 5 I I I = -■- i - ■- I SI y H F u L 3 E . SSSSSSSiiSg s I g I |.8 .8 8 [ * &lt; s i b S5 1 Is V. E ■ = 5 5 f- r 1 = M 2 I I E t go jE-i-E r-.oo U *" Si. 1 J **»'«««§'! | II I fi£ Hi! j If. J It Jjyjiiiiiii i 5 I- ? E - ' I h 'I 1 1 ijtliiJiPi c *o t -3 "2 I x to — 10 .-&gt; »o c- «« — Z : lilSI - - ' "s - s ; </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 191 ORCHARD PRODUCTS December 1, 1917, to December 1, 1918 Num - ber of Acres Culti- Total Produced Totml Consumed NAME OF PRODUCT ated Measure : Value | Measure Value ■h-ri 3 Bu. $9.00 ; 3 Bu. tS-00 $9.00 $9.00 total on hand and produced, total preserved or ised of, and total on hand December 1, 1918, ia Not*— Total on hand, December 1, 1917. I ransformed. total waste, total sold, total dispoi 'ach case, hencs not shown. December 1, 1917 Orchard Product" tablp for Decembe </seg>
            <seg id="p012">192 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF U -5 S »- -N ! a 3 32 3 !Z it :55 :- : = 2 j |i ? s »|S ?j ~ jli'g^i B 1| j §| J • :"— ! , — — x — i — ch / — „ * ] *- o ! « 1 j ! oxqxo P £C ' 1$ | — -r ~ £ — - s ■*.— © mi ■ ! X 3 1 i 2 i -. E «« /. K 5 ; ~- t i .. 5 mnrr ij M :! - — - XI | JJ 1 &gt; ■■• « IS S 'g^S : Ei- « :« 51 ? x ,s I " I I* o i • Tl • - i=g I ■ i ■ : s li I 1 ; ; i I S 1 2 I " ■ S H 1 1 : I S o&gt; To 5 Tio^ « £3 I ' I = = 2 i r 4. -- I 3 Id ::■:!• » I 5; e * I i I *1 i &gt;i* : :w : js i I Sr \§r\ ■■■■■■ c 32 §| &gt;• ? 3 o'xkdead C4 ? ( « 2 a .i i I ! |l|ir5-li 1 1 i{ ; ai j 1 = 1« n &gt; «« 3 a &lt; •J z m i ?; 9S9SS IB ! « i £"?« • gs jg- 8 s j : Illj •■■■■■■■•• I "Si-S. I . .SgSolS Si' |gh|« : : : : : I |i M jljppj| ! b i|fPi| | I I I i Z I * ■S. I , I g gg g I : : : : : | n I II 3 :1* i : : : : : S hi a I S lnlt. u*s* ii Ml I "mm I </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 193 ?i » ! H z z * 5P r-. tea - t-S e- f. •:: z z £?se &gt; ** i E- Z •i z Sf B 5. I . e S ■5 Z .= « • 9 ■ e s Q a S5r 5 3 !j || in »' I - I — IK -&lt; u X &gt; 5.S I S a z 51 MH la •»■ ■ ■ «. E »5 i s I *J ijl-rs y.^ ilii II iStfi ;1 B 5 54 «~ « la* 1. 1 2i jlmml aiiiiji I i il 1 H rll ' t P!^r 8 ; s 31 « iii a &lt; I J| ! &gt;jy~ &gt; 17*: •=^1 s § ?s lis &gt; S : " lib 1 gJS S: 1t !|F I i* |ti p I i P li*|y"|; 1- . §§S :8 S W ji — r I </seg>
            <seg id="p014">194 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE 1 -MOVEMENT OF POPULATION TABLE II AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE III -EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED MOVEMENT For Yemr ending Nov. ;fll, 1917 For Yemr ! ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium F. F - P. Present at beginning of period Admitted: First time Transferred from other institutions Returned from parole 11.-. :i- I 1 107 50 4 115 to I 6 Total* 156 161 210 Discharged: Reached majority Transferred to other institution* Escaped Released to friends or parents Paroled and not returned M 1 8 4 22 4 3 34 It 5 ■ :l* Totala - 49 63 112 Remaining at end of period Average number under care Absent on parole at commencement of or during period, or discharged without returning to insti- tution 107 Ml 4 98 101 34 98 AGE For Year ending Nov. SO. 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Hiennium nder 10 0 and under 12. ... 2 and under 14. 4 and under 16. . .6 and under 18. . . W. C. T. W. C. T. W. C. T. 7 . . .. 7 11 ... It 21 21 2 2 2 2 7. .. . 7 18 18 20 1 21 2 2 2 2 14 14 30 30 41 1 42 r 40 40 I 49 1 50 89 1 90 EDUCATION For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 r. r For Yemr ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium r. r. "rimary st trade Id grade and under Ith grade. ith grade ith grade 'th grade ith grade Ith grade a 8 12 9 40 i i 4 4 4 » 17 10 18 8 20 * 18 6 5 60 90 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 195 TABLE IV NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VI PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED NATIVITY For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30. 1918 Total for Bienniui F._ *■ F. Mebraska 'nited States uthrr than Nebraska 21 11 45 4 .1 64 16 Total native born 32 49 81 jermany, total foreign born 4 4 Unknown 4 1 6 Totals 10 ~nr 5" NATIVITY For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Yetr ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium I I F. nit wl St ales, both parents foreign, both parents Mimed [Tnknown Totals 25 9 6 40 28 5 11 6 13 U 11 18 PARENTAL CONDITION For Year ending Nov. 30. 1917 For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium Both darenu dead Father dead Mother dead Parents living together Parents separated Has step-mother Has step-father Parents divorced Unknown P. F. F. 1 ! IS 2 6 5 3 3 50 1 3 4 11 11 17 14 30 4 « 3 9 10 IS 3 « 5 8 55 105 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p016">196 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII AGE AT DEATH OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VIII VDMISSION FROM DEFECTIVE AND DELINQUENT HOMES AUK For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Y«r rndinn Nov. ;io, Itll Total for Bienniun F. F. r. .hi- at death of father: I'nder 10 years . . 1" and undtT 15 1 5 and over I'nknown Ke at death of mother: I'nder 10 years . . 10 and under 15.. 1 5 and over ! nknown 2 i I I 1 8 I 1 1 n a 3 I 13 8 1 1 Totals ■•i 20 41 CLASS For Year ending Nov. 30. 1H17 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Bienniu F. F. F. Feeble minded : Father Mother Both parent - . . Brother Sister Insane: Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister Intemperate: Father Mother Brother Sister Delinquent: Father Mother Both parents Brothers Sister Unknown 1 ! i 5 1 3 :i 1 u I 1 :i 1 29 1 2 9 10 7 6 ■i ' 5S Totals 40 50 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 197 TABLE IX -COUNTY OF RESIDENCE Or THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM TABLE X -CAUSE FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED COUNTY For Year ending Nov. 30. : 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium All Remaining Nov. 30. 1918 JM '• r. t. I M I. F. T. ' M F. T. M. F. T Adams .... Antelope Brown Box Bun. Burt Custer. . . . Dodce Douglas . . . . Dawes . Hitrhcock Hall Holt Jefferson . . . Johnson KeyaPaha Lancaster . Nemaha Madison Merrick Otoe Phelps Platte Richardson Saline Seotts Bluff Thurston Washington Wayne Webster Totals F - 5 1 i IS 2 1 5 ■i 1 1 1 1 40 ■ F. 1 1 i! T i 4 2 I • 2 1 1 1 1 2 aJ 2 I :i 4 1 2 11 1 1 2 | 1 I 2 I 2 ~90~ F. .i 1 1 1 2 i. 31 2 1 I 1 11 1 2 1 2 :t I ! 4 ;l 2 98 CAUSE Dependency or neflect Delinquent: Unclassified Assault Immorality Ineorrigibility Larceny For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 F. » For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Bieanium F. F. 12 21 M Ifi :j SI 40 1 10 1 2 22 38 13 16 1 a 88 69 50 90 Total delinquents Grand totals I </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 198 K I I] H r TABLE XI— STATISTICS OF PAROLED PUPILS On parole November 30, 1916. Paroled during hicnnium Returned from parole for cause Discharged from parole On parole November 30, 1918 TABLE XII— DIVISION OF LABOR OF ALL PUPILS School, 4 hours per day Home Economics, 4} hours per day Laundry, 4J hours per day Searing room, 4} hours per day Total </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>