<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Several-Purpose Poultry House</title>
               <date value="1919-06">1919-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 57 June, 1919 A Several-Purpose Poultry House H. M. WELLS THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ONE ROOM OF THE SEVERAL-PURPOSE HOUSE CAN BE USED FOR A GOOD FLOCK OF BREEDERS </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A SEVERAL-PURPOSE POULTRY HOUSE By H. M. WELLS, Extension Potltryman A poultry house that can be used for several purposes will constitute a valuable part of the poultry equipment of many Nebraska farms and poultry yards. Plans of such a house are given in this circular. The several-purpose house is adaptable to many conditions and uses; it can be used especially as a brooding or breeding house- but when not used for such purposes it may well be used to house surplus breeding cockerels or laying pullets. This house is also very well adapted for town-lot poultry keeping where the poultry raiser has only a limited space but would like to keep 15 or 20 layers and possibly raise a small number of chicks each season. ESSENTIALS OF A POULTRY HOUSE The essentials of a good practical poultry house are dryness, ventilation without drafts, plenty of sunlight, and simple but convenient fixtures. AS A BROODER HOUSE When the several-purpose house is used as a colony - brooder house the roosts and drooping boards should be re - moved. One room can be used for brooding proper, the brooder stove being placed in this room, the other being used as an exercising room. Coal or kerosene burning colony-brooder stoves are now being very widely used to supply the temperature condition which is necessary for the comfort of the chicks. When the chicks are 10 to 12 weeks old, the colony - brooder stove can be taken out and the roosts put in place. At this time the cockerels should be separated from the pullets and placed in a house and yard by themselves, giving the pullets more room for development. AS A DOUBLE-PEN BREEDING HOUSE This house may also be very well used as a double-pen breeding house. Ten to fifteen breeders can be accommodated in each pen without overcrowding. Better laying poultry and better standard qualities can only be secured by select - ing the best stock each season for breeding purposes. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Extension Service rRONT ELZVflTION FLOOR PLHN ro* COLONY BROODING </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Several-Purpose Poultry House END SECTION r -i I Oroppi itf Boondi I Wbtuts RtimoroU* I ii La £ c ± T\ o .1 J U •/a' /Harm 4? i M \ \ \ \ \ \ * * * 'LOOR PLFIN ro* DOUBLE BREl &gt;//Y&lt;5 Pi </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Extension Service scot* %~*r-o~ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">A Several-Purpose Poultry House 7 ONE ROOM OF THE SEVERAL-PURPOSE HOUSE CAN BE USED FOR BROODING When used as a laying house the partition may be omitted. About 40 hens can then be accommodated. CONSTRUCTION The house may be constructed of hollow tile or lumber. When lumber is used, two-ply patented roofing paper should be placed on the outside of the studding. Drop-siding may then be used to cover this, thus making the building dry and draft proof. The floor may be made of either concrete or wood. To aid in securing dryness in a concrete floor, it is recommended that 8 or 1 0 inches of cinders or coarse crushed rock be used for the foundations of the floor, then 3 inches of concrete, with a finish surface about 2 inches thick. Hollow tile may </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Extension Service also be used for the floor if covered with about 2 inches of rich cement mixture (three parts sand and one part ce - ment). If a wood floor is used the house should be placed on bricks or concrete blocks. This will insure dryness and will keep rats from staying under the building. Concrete or tile floors are not cold if kept covered with 10 or 12 inches of straw or other suitable litter. VENTILATION Good ventilation without floor or overhead drafts is one of the essentials of a good poultry house. The shutter ventilator in the front of the house permits plenty of fresh air to enter without any direct overhead draft. For sum - mer ventilation, a back ventilator is provided. During the summer months the windows may be removed to allow additional ventilation as needed. SUNLIGHT Sunlight and plenty of it in the poultry house is very essential. Sunlight is an excellent germ destroyer, and one of the best disinfectants we have. The house should face toward the south in order to get the greatest amount of sunlight during the winter months. EQUIPMENT AND SIZE OF HOUSE The several-purpose house is 12 by 14 feet with a par - tition and door dividing it into two pens 7 by 12 feet. When used as a brooding house up to 400 chicks can be accom - modated, according to the size of the brooder stove used. The bottom board of the partition is hinged to swing up, providing a large exercising room for the chicks. The dropping boards and roosts should be removable so that they can be put in place when the chicks are 12 weeks old. Two pieces of board 10 by 12 inches fastened together at right angles and placed just back of the chick doors in such a way that the chicks can run in and out of the house, will prevent drafts. All equipment is placed at least 9 inches from the floor, so that every inch of floor space will be available. uo m» </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>