<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Barley as Hog Feed</title>
               <date value="1930-10">1930-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 251 October, 1930 Revised May, 1933 Barley as Hog Feed WM. J. LOEFFEL Department of Animal Husbandry 100% flK| 84% 84% 77°/ . '** ' l UJ I ■SB lull i^ . I^l |u.| l&lt;l lujl luj I^l l&lt;l I" 8 ! ■''I 1° I^l I^l l°l Efficiency of Barley, Based on Pounds of Feed Required fob 100 Pounds of Gain. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF. AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. ItURK, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction , ; 3 Complete Substitution, Barley for Corn 4 Whole barley vs. shelled corn , 4 Soaked whole barley vs. shelled corn 1 Ground barley vs. shelled corn 5 Soaked ground barley vs. shelled corn 7 Partial Substitution, Barley for Corn .• Self-feeding ground barley with corn S Ground barley vs. corn on pasture :... 10 The Preparation of Barley for Hog p'eed { .i 10 Soaking whole barley.. 10 Grinding barley .■ . 12 Fineness of ground barley ... ...... 12 •Feeding soaked ground barley three times daily 13 Damaged Barley .' . 14 Weight per Bushel , 14 The Value of Barley per Bushel ■. 1 '&lt; Quality of Barley-fed Pork 15 Appendix — Complete Data ...-. ■ ....„.-. Literature Cited '. SUMMARY 1. Barley can be wholly .or partially .substituted for c.orn in hog rations. 2. Pigs fed corn gained from 7 to 27 per cent more rapidly than barley-fed pigs. . • • 3. Ground barley was 84 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. 4. Barley appeared to be more palatable than corn, as based on th«_ - daily feed consumption. 5. Self-feeding barley whole pi'oved to be more efficient than hand - feeding soaked whole barley. 6. Grinding barley increased its feeding value 7*i per cent. 7. Soaking ground barley did not increase the rate nor the efficiency of gains. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Barley as Hog Feed WM. J. LOEFFEL The introduction of new varieties of smooth barley and the more extensive use of the combine have increased barley production in Nebraska. This increased production has brought forth so many inquiries regarding the feeding of barley that this summarization of experimental work is presented. Seven dry-lot tests and one on pasture have been carried on by the Nebraska Station since 1918. The dry-lot trials ranged from 55 to 100 days in duration, the average being 77 days. Practically all of these trials were carried on dur - ing the fall, winter, or spring season. One 90-day test on Sudan grass was conducted in 1929.' Objects. — The objects of the investigations were to com - pare barley with corn and to compare various methods of preparing barley as pig feed. Pigs used.- — The pigs used in the tests ranged from 100 to 143- pounds in initial weight, the average being 114 pounds. Feeds used.— -Since other investigators have demonstra - ted the necessity of feeding a protein supplement with barley to secure efficient results, this practice was followed in all tests. Sixty per cent protein tankage was fed to all lots. In the first four trials, the pigs were also given access. to- alfalfa hay in racks. Since the consumption of hay was small, it was included in the summary tables as supplement. The hay used was leafy and of good color. The weight of hay given represents the actual weight consumed, the lots being credited with the portion rejected. -The barley used graded No. 2 and No. 3 feeding barley. Test weights were not- secured except where specifically noted. Since the tests were carried on over a period of years, the barley used probably was a representative cross section of the Nebraska barley crop.- ■ The corn fed graded No. 2 and No. 3. White, mixed and yellow corn were used. Because of the initial weight of the pigs and also because alfalfa hay was fed in several of the trials, it is hardly probable that the color of the corn was of sufficient importance to influence the results. Financial Interpretations. — Changing conditions make costs of gains of little value over extended periods of time For this reason, they have been omitted in this publication </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 i" • ■ ■ •• The amount of feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain is presented. Multiplying these figures by the price of feeds enables one to compute cost of gains for any price condition. Presentation of Data. — Where possible, the various trials have been averaged and summary tables presented. The figures given are weighted averages, by which more signi - ficance is attached to the longer feeding trials and those involving the larger number of pigs. The original data from which all compilations were made are presented in the appendix of this bulletin. COMPLETE SUBSTITUTION, BARLEY FOR CORN Whole Barley vs. Shelled Corn. — In three trials, a direct comparison was made between whole barley and shelled corn. Both grains were self-fed free choice with tankage. In two of the trials, alfalfa hay was provided in racks. The average results ai-e presented in Table 1. The pigs self-fed whole barley consumed more grain and more supplement than those fed corn. In every case, the daily consumption of barley was greater than that of corn. In two trials, the daily intake of supplement was slightly greater with corn. In the third trial, enough more tank - age was consumed with barley to account for the higher consumption of supplement in the average presented. The pigs on corn gained 1.49 pounds a day, while those self-fed whole barley gained 1.26 pounds^a difference of 18 per cent in favor of corn in rate of gain. To produce 100 pounds of gain, 370 pounds of shelled corn were re - quired, while 471 pounds of whole barley were required in the barley-fed group. On the. basis of the grain required, to produce 100 pounds of gain, the whole barley, when self-fed, was 79 per cent as valuable as corn. In other words, 100 pounds of whole barley, when self-fed, were equivalent to 79 pounds of shelled corn. This is only part of the story, however, since the corn-fed pigs required less protein supplement to make 100 pounds of gain and since they gained more rapidly. The results of this summary agree with the results of a trial at Colorado (6), 1 in which smaller gains were secured with whole barley at a higher expenditure of feed per unit of gain. - Soaked Whole Barley vs. Shelled Corn. — A comparison of soaked whole barley with shelled corn is also included in Table 1. The same protein supplements were fed as in 1 Fistnres in parentheses are references to publications listed an pase 20. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Barley as Hog Feed ' Table 1. — Average of three trials I Shelled corn I Whole barley Soaked ' I self-fed I self -fed | whole barley Number of pigs 26 26 26 Average number of. days.... 61 61 61 Average daily ration : Pounds Pounds Pounds Corn 5.51 Barley , 5.93 5.45 S u ppl'ement - .70 .77 .60 Average initial weight 115 115 115 Average final weight 207 193 184 Average gain per head 92 78 69 Average daily gain 1.49 1.26 1.14 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Corn 370 Barley 1 471 476 Supplement 47 61 52 the previous comparison. The shelled corn and supple - ment were self-fed, while the. soaked barley of necessity was hand-fed. In the latter case, the tankage was mixed with the soaked barley just prior to feeding. Although an effort was made to full-feed the lot fed soaked barley, they did not consume as much feed as the self-fed groups. This probably accounts for the daily gain of 1.14 pounds for the soaked barley lot as compared with 1.49 pounds for the shelled-corn groups. In this case, the soaked whole barley proved to be 77 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. Morrison and Bohstedt at Wisconsin (22) also found that pigs full-fed soaked whole barley and tankage did not con - sume as much feed and made smaller and less economical gains than similar pigs fed corn and tankage. Ground Barley vs. Shelled Corn.—^In seven trials, ground barley and a supplement were self-fed in comparison with corn and tankage. Since other workers have shown that it is not advantageous to grind corn for pigs weighing less than 250 pounds, there appeared to be no serious objection to feeding shelled corn in the check lot. Tankage was fed as a supplement to all lots, and alfalfa hay in addition in two trials. The barley in all cases was coarsely ground or cracked. The weighted averages of the results are shown in Table 2. Whenever barley was self-fed either whole or ground, it appeared to be more palatable than corn. The consump - tion of protein supplement varied, in about one-half the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 Table 2. — Average of seven trials _ . . — ' Shelled corn | Ground barley Number of pigs............................. ............. 83 j 83 Average number of days ,76 | 76 Average daily ration: Pounds Pounds Corn 5.99 Ground barley 6.74 Supplement .67 ' .72 Average initial weight . 113 il3 Average final weight: 226 j 220 Average gain per head : 113 | 107 Average daily gain | l."&gt;0 i 1.41 Peed required per 100 pounds gain: Corn : 400 | Ground barley ...... 478 Supplement ;.. . | -1 5 51 cases being greater with ground barley, and in the other cases being greater with the shelled corn : on the average it appeared slightly higher with ground barley. In three of the trials, the corn-fed pigs out-gained the barley-fed pigs, while in the other four cases the reverse was true. Taking an average of all seven trials, the pigs that received corn averaged 1.50 pounds gain a day. while those self - fed ground barley gained only 1.41 pounds. To produce 100 pounds of gain, 400 pounds of 'corn and 45 pounds of supplement were required. To produce a similar gain on ground barley. 478 pounds of .grain and 51 pounds of supplement were fed. In this instance, the ground barley proved to be 84 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. The large majority of- the workers who have compared corn with ground barley secured larger gains with the corn ration (3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 11, 19, 20, 22, 23, 30. 32, 40). In one case (5), ground barley produced larger gains; while in another (15), as good gains were secured with ground barley as with corn. Ferrin and McCarty (9) in a triplicate comparison secured a larger gain with corn. in one case, a larger gain with ground barley in another, and no difference in the third, the average being in favor of corn. Comparing "the amount of grain required to produce 100 pounds of gain, only one worker (5) reported that less ground barley than corn was needed. The lowest effi - ciency for barley reported was 69 per cent (11) and the highest 99 per cent (25). Most investigators found ground barley to vary in efficiency from 80 per cent to 95 per cent </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Barley as Hog Feed of that of. corn (3, 4, 6, 9, 15, 19, 20; 22, 29, 30, 32, 35, 40). .C. D. Smith (28) as early as 1892 pointed out that barley meal, when fed alone, was superior to corn alone. However, when a protein supplement was fed with the two grains, corn was better than ground barley. In practically all of the references cited, a protein supplement was fed. Of special interest is the trial by Snyder (29), since in this case both the corn and barley were ground and fed at the same level (4 per cent). In this case. ground barley proved to be 80 per cent as efficient as corn. Soaked Ground Barley vs. Shelled Corn. — In six tests, soaked ground barley was compared with shelled corn, tankage being fed in all cases and alfalfa hay also in all but two comparisons. The corn and tankage were self-fed. The weights of the soaked barley in this case and through - out this publication represent the weight of the barley be - fore soaking. The barley was soaked from one feeding to the next and the tankage added just before feeding. The average of the six comparisons is given in Table 3. • Table 3. — Average of six comparisons Soaked • ■ ■ Shelled eoi-n ground barley Number of pigs 56 5G Average number of days... :. 77 77 Average daily ration: Pounds \ Pounds Corn .'..,.., C.32 | Ground barley I G.57 Supplement... :... .08 1 .62 Average initial weight I 114 ' 114 Average final weight .-....." 234 218 Average gain per head : 120 104 " Average daily gain . '. . 1.52 | J.-34 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Corn :... : 415 „.&gt; Ground barley .; ...'.....\ 491 Supplement 45 1 46 Once again the average daily consumption of barley proved greater than that of corn, and again the daily gain on barley proved to be less than that secured with coi'n. To produce 100 pounds of gain, "415 pounds of shelled corn and 45 pounds of tankage were required, while 491 pounds of ground barley and 46 pounds of tankage were required in the barley series. Based on the amount of feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain, ground barley, when soaked, proved to be 84 per cent as efficient as corn. Morrison and Bohstedt (22) secured larger gains with corn </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 and tankage than with soaked ground barley and tankage. The soaked ground barley in their trial was 92 per cent as efficient as corn. PARTIAL SUBSTITUTION, BARLEY FOR CORN To detei'mine whether ground barley may not have a higher value when fed in combination with corn, three lots of ten pigs each were fed for 85 days. (For complete data, see Trial C in appendix of this bulletin.) Lot 1 was self - fed corn and tankage;. Lot 2 was hand-fed a full feed of soaked ground barley and tankage ; and Lot 3 was fed soaked ground barley in the morning and shelled corn in the evening. Tankage at the rate of 10 per cent of the total concentrates was mixed with the bai'ley just before feeding. . Here, as in other trials, greater feed consumption was noted where barley .was fed. Lot 1, which received corn as its grain ration, gained 1.32 pounds a day,, while. Lot 3', which received soaked ground barley, gained. 1.17 pounds. Four hundred and forty-five pounds of corn were required to produce 100 pounds of gain as compared with 554 pounds of ground barley, making the efficiency of the ground barley, when soaked, 80 per cent in. this particular trial. In Lot 3, where half the grain was ground barley and half corn, the daily gain was 1.34 pounds, or slightly in excess of the gains of the other two lots. Two hundred and forty pounds of corn and 241 pounds of ground barley, a total of 481 pounds of grain, were required to. produce 100 pounds of gain. The average of the grain required to produce 100 pounds of gain in Lots 1 and 2 is 499 pounds, a figure which might be anticipated to represent the amount of grain required where ground barley and corn in equal portions were fed. The actual figure obtained is only slightly below the calculated one. The efficiency of soaked ground barley, where it was fed as half the grain ration with corn, proved to be 85 per cent, or 5 per cent higher than where soaked ground barley made up the en - tire grain ration. Cooke.(7) also suggested that where both corn and barley are fed greater efficiency is obtained than where either grain is fed alone. Self-feeding Ground Barley with Corn. — In two trials, a ration of shelled corn and ground barley was compared with each grain as the sole grain ration, the same protein feeds being fed to all lots. The average 'results are shown in Table 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Barley as Hog Feed Table 4. — Average of two trials ' Corn and Corn ground Ground • . barley barley Number of pigs 18 18 18 Average number of days... 80 80 80 Average daily ration: Pounds Pounds Pounds Corn: &lt; 7.49 6.57 1 Ground barley! 1 1.73 6.62 ■Supplement •...:.., .63 .59 .74 Average initial weight.... . v ~ 121 121 121 Average final weight 265 268 230 Average gain per head....... 144 147 109 Average daily gain 1.74 1.78 1.33 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Corn ......... ; ... 430 370 Ground barley : 98 497 Supplement -35 .33 56 In previous summaries where both grains were self-fed, the daily consumption of barley was greater than of corn. In one of the trials here summarized, the barley appears to have been quite unpalatable. This depressed the con - sumption below that of corn, and apparently caused the pigs receiving barley as their only grain to fill up on the supplementary feed. The low daily feed intake in the barley lot doubtless accounts for the small gains. The lot receiving corn gained 30 per. cent more rapidly than the barley lot, although, in the general average, lots receiving corn have gained only 7 per cent faster than those self-fed ground barley. While the gains made with barley were not as rapid as with com, they were very economical. Ground barley in this comparison proved to be .87 per cent as efficient as corn, a higher figure than was given in Table 2 where all lots fed in this manner were considered. Doubtless the heavier weights attained by the pigs receiving corn, and corn with barley, in this comparison served to reduce the efficiency of those lots and to increase the apparent effi - ciency of the barley lot, thus causing the two grains to appear more nearly equal in feeding value. This same fac - tor probably also accounts for the small amount of protein supplement required to produce 100 pounds of gain where corn or the combination of corn and barley was fed. The limited consumption of barley where that grain was self -fed with corn is difficult to explain in view of the apparent palatability of barley in the other tests. The </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 feeding of ground barley with the corn slightly increased the daily gain over that secured with corn. In making 100 pounds of gain, 98 pounds of ground barley i*eplaced 60 pounds of corn, which makes the effi - ciency of the barley only 61 per cent as great as that of the com. This is the lowest value determined in this series of tests. Ground Barley vs. Corn on Pasture. — Only one trial is available at this time in which ground barley was com - pared with shelled corn on Sudan grass pasture. Tankage was fed with both grains. The grains were hand-fed, and the pigs permitted to have all they would clean up. The barley used in this particular test was graded as "No. .4 badly stained!' and weighed only 39.5 pounds per bushel. The corn graded No. 2 yellow and weighed 55 pounds to the bushel. The results of this test are given in the ap - pendix in Trial G. In this trial on pasture, the same general tendencies which were noted under dry-lot conditions may be ob - served. Pigs fed corn and tankage gained more rapidly at a lower expenditure of feed than pigs fed ground barley and tankage. Ground barley proved to be 84 per cent as efficient as corn, which is the same value as determined in dry lot. Morrison and Bohstedt (23) found ground barley, when fed on pasture, to be 15 per cent less efficient than corn. Wilson and Wright (35) report that ground barley, when fed with a supplement on pasture, was 86 per cent as good as corn. Both of these values closely approximate that secured in our trial. The latter workers (35, 38) . suggest that ground barley has a higher value for dry-lot feeding than for use on pasture. • . THE PREPARATION OF BARLEY FOR HOG FEED The small size and the hardness of the barley kernel arid the tendency of the pig to eat rapidly cause most feed - ers to agree that some. method of preparing barley is neces - sary. Of the simple prepai'ation methods, soaking and grinding merit consideration. Soaking Whole Barley. — Three trials offer comparisons between whole dry bai'ley self-fed and soaked whole bai'ley hand-fed, tankage being fed in all cases and alfalfa hay in two of the trials. The whole barley was soaked from one feeding to the next. The summarized results are given in Table 5. - </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Barley as Hog Feed Table 5.— Average of three trials Whole barley,) Whole barley, dry I soaked Number of pigs....... :....; 26 . 26 Average number of days... .'.• ,........- 61 61 Average daily ration: Pounds Pounds Barley.......... .......;.... 5.93 5.45 Supplement '.. .: .77 j .60 Average initial -weight .-. 114 114 Average final weight 193 184 Averasc gr.in per head...... ._....,". : 79 70 Average daily gain ,..| 1.26 | . 1.15 Feed required per 100 pounds grain: • ! Barley.!.:..., ': 471 474 Supplement 1 61 | 53 More whole barley and more supplement were consumed daily when these feeds were self-fed than when the barley was soaked. The pigs which were self-fed gained 1.26 pounds a day as compared with 1.15 pounds for those fed soaked whole barley. About the same amount of grain was required to produce 100 pounds of gain in both cases, although slightly more supplement was required where the ration was self -fed. Since larger gains, with no greater expenditure of feed, were secured by self-feeding, it is clear that self-feeding the barley dry is preferable to soak - ing the grain. The question might be raised as to how important a .factor self-feeding was in this comparison. This question is answered by comparing Lots 2, 5, and 8 in Trial H. Lot 2 was self-fed whole barley and tankage and made the largest gains. The barley was used more efficiently in this lot than where the same feeds were hand-fed (Lot 5). Soaking the whole barley produced larger and more effi - cient gains than the same ration hand-fed dry (Lot 8). At the Kentucky station (38), larger and more efficient gains were secured with barley which had been soaked 24 hours. Arnett. (1) states that "dry whole barley produced slower gains than where the barley was soaked," although a year later (2) he concluded that soaking barley was not advantageous. Thompson (30) secured larger but less economical gains with soaked whole barley. Woodman (33) in Great Britain concluded that soaking did not in - crease the rate of gain but did increase the efficiency of the barley. Oliver (24) at Oregon found no difference in rate of gain in three trials, but found 100 pounds of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 soaked whole barley to be equivalent to 90 pounds of whole dry barley. Grinding Barley. — Grinding is a common method of pre - paring barley for feed, but one that requires more labor and equipment than soaking. Three comparisons of whole barley with coarsely ground barley are available These results are summarized in Table 6. Table 6. — Average of three trials i " ■ '. Whole barley Ground barley Number of pigs....... ........;..... " Qg Average number of days. '.. ■"' 66 GG Av^X daily rati ° n: ~~ ~P^ds Pounds-. .^^^:^^^"=±: 6^ 6 -% Average initial weight . fl4 " 1T4 ~ Average final weight "" • o 01 o ,? Average gain per head .' "37 tjV, Average daily gain.....;.. 1.29 I -,1 Feed required per 1Q0 pounds~nain: 1 ~ — '—■ f arle .y-- ' 481 447 Supplement "£ =7 1 • nX — . y " ' I 00 Coarsely ground barley appeJed to bemore palatable than whole barley. Less suppfement was consumed with the ground barley than with whole barley. The piir.s on coarsely ground barley gained 1.51 pounds a dav as com - nn? Z? 1-29 Pounds a day for the pigs on whole barley Only 447 pounds of ground barley and 38 pounds of sup - plement were required to produce 100 pounds of gain while with whole barley, 481 pounds of grain and 57 pounds, of supplement were needed. Based on the savins m gram the ground barley was 7\ ', per cent more valuable than whole barley To be equally as profitable, the cost of grmdmg a bushel of barley, must not exceed 7-i per cent of the cost of barley per bushel. • Seldom does one find such an agreement of results in favor of a practice as in favor of grinding barlev. Vadois inyestigators (1, 2, 4, 7, 12, 22, 23, 24 30) report that * h | feeding value of 'barley frbm 5 to 13 per cent. Hale (16) secured larger but less economir^i gains from ground than from whole barley. economic al Fmeness of Ground Barley.— Trial H reveals that for self - feeding or soaking, finely ground barley (modulus 3 30) was more efficient than coarsely ground barley (modulus </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Barley as Hog Feed 4.02).- Where the grain was self-fed, coarsely ground barley proved to be 8 per cent and finely ground barley 17 per cent more efficient than whole. For hand-feeding dry, coarsely ground barley was 18 per cent more efficient and finely ground barley only 16 per cent more efficient than whole barley. Where the barley was soaked, the coarsely ground barley proved no more efficient and the finely ground barley only 2 per cent more efficient than whole barley. Grinding, therefore, proved most advan - tageous where the grain was hand-fed dry and of least benefit where the grain was soaked. In the case of wheat, grinding is of less advantage where it is self-fed (21). Experiments at the Oregon Station (24) showed coarse grinding to increase the efficiency of barley 9.6 per cent, and fine grinding to improve it 13 per cent. Work at Wisconsin (4) compared moduli of 3.78, 3.27, and 1.99 with whole barley for self-feeding in dry lot. The coarse grinding improved the grain 6 per cent; the medium, 10 per cent; and the fine, 9 per cent over whole barley. While fine grinding may prove more efficient than coarse grinding for certain purposes, one should not lose sight of the fact that fine grinding is more costly because of higher power requirements and reduced grinding capacity. From &amp; dollar-and-cents standpoint, the increased grinding cost may more than offset the increased efficiency of the finer grinding. Soaking Ground Barley. — In five trials, the desirability of feeding soaked ground barley was compared with ground barley self-fed dry. The same supplements were fed in each- case. The summarized results of these trials are shown in Table 7. Soaking the ground barley did induce greater daily grain consumption, but did not increase the daily gain nor the efficiency with which the barley was utilized. At the Okla - homa Station (30), Thompson found that "moistening" ground barley increased the gains but did not increase the efficiency of the barley. Feeding Soaked Ground Barley Three Times Daily. — In all of the trials where soaked ground barley was fed, it was fed twice daily. The question arose whether by supply - ing a third feeding at noon better results could not be secured. This was tried in Trial D (page 17), Lot 7 being 3 The modulus expresses the decree of finenes3 of ground grain. The average modulus of whole barley Is 5.00: for coarsely ground, 4.10; for medium grinding, 3.20; and for finely ground, 2.30. The moduli in this experiment were obtained' through the co-operation of E. It, Lewis of the Department of Agricultural Engi - neering. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 Table 7. — Average of five trials. Ground | Ground barley, dry i barley, soaked. Number of pigs i 48 48 Average number of days.... .. ■.... 78 _ 78 Average daily ration: I'oiuidx Pounds Ground barley.... '..-, ....... &lt;&gt;.7O ■ 7.08 Supplement....^. •'... .70 .57 Average initial weight 114 114 Average final weight .....: :..,.,. 220 I 220 Average gain P&lt;-'r head...-...: 115 . | 115" Average daily gain :.. ..... 1.45 I 1.45 Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Ground barley ,..., '..,. 40:! | . 488 Supplement :. 48 ■] 40 fed twice daily and Lot 8. three times daily. Neither the feed consumption nor the gains were increased by the ad - ditional feeding-, nor were the. gains made any more efficiently. DAMAGED BARLEY In the eastern part of the Corn Belt, some difficulty has been experienced with scab iGibberella mubinetti, Mont., Sacc), a fungus which affects barley, wheat, rye, and oats. Scabby barley kernels are pink- in color. Numerous trials by other experiment stations and the U. S. Department of Agri - culture have shown that if barley is very scabby it is so un - palatable that pigs will not eat it. Such barley can be t.ed to cattle or sheep without harmful results. Since scab is most serious under humid conditions, it is not likely to be much of a factor in Nebraska. Barley which heats in the bin is likely to be unpalatable and lower in feeding value than sound barley. WEIGHT PER BUSHEL The Animal Husbandry Division of the U. S. Department of Agriculture (41) in a dry-lot test compared samples of barley testing 41, 45, and 49 pounds per bushel. Pigs on the heavy barley gained 1.22 pounds a day and required 425 pounds of feed to produce 100 pounds- of gain ; those on the medium-weight barley gained 1.07 pounds a day and made 100 pounds of gain with 485 pounds of feed ; and those on the light barley gained 1.07 pounds at a feed expenditure of 530 pounds for every 100 pounds of gain. The 45-pound barley was 88 per cent and the 41-pound barley 80 per cent as valuable per unit of weight as the 49-pound barley. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Barley as Hog Feed nJ,hL teSt H Wei !- ht .° f barley flu ctuate S from year to year Doubtless this tact accounts for the variations in feeding value noted in the different trials. Test weights of thf barley used were not secured in the early feeding -trials! THE VALUE OF BARLEY PER BUSHEL The feeder. is interested in the price he can afford to nav tor barley with corn at various price levels. Because of differ ence in weight per bushel, direct comparisons cannot be made" Gri&amp; W ". g . ro 7; d ' + is 84 P« cent as valuable as ™orn tin n Th desirable to prepare barley for efficient utiliza - nt ;„•. T\, ot fT dl ? lg must be deducted from the price oi barley. In the iollowing table, the money value of barley Table! 8.— Money value of. barley at various corn-price levels price 5 7oZ "Z S'.!r. $ lP'ii MST»7is ••« • ..■."iffi Value of ground barley 1&gt;0 ° • 1 - 2S 1 - 5 &lt;&gt; 1-75 2.00 U8» er itHndrn"B r cirarBo"c.t ' ' 42 ' G3 ' S4 1 - 05 i- 26 *•« 1.68 Valued* 48!poSna""tJu»hcY " " 48 - 69 I • 00 J - u 1-32 1.53 1-»LJ^J5L^:/: ••• I -13 .23 1 .33 ] .43 .53 . 63 .„ QUALITY OF BARLEY-FED PORK in fhVU.S S y + ? f qU f lity - ° f bai&gt;le y-fed pork was not included Hi the nnestigations herein reported, three references (T iq 27 state that barley-fed pork was found to be firmei and con' tained more lean than corn-fed pork. APPENDIX— COMPLETE DATA Trial A.— Sixtu-day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, October ; - _ ' ' to Dece ™ber 14, 1918 Number^ Ti^. '— i L "g ' ' -","— -,' -^U^ 4 — ' - Lnt !!_l_Lot6^J Ave» S j, n U.Uy raUon": ;, «,«-*/•„?„* | p^ | p^ "^ b t^;:= ;:::;z L ■- 9 :: = ! :::;::;::: =-■ -~~. 6 Ground barley soaked. . : "'TTS 3 - 26 Whole barley soaked ' '■' ' "" "• 9 ' -' Alfalfa &amp;y..ZZZ2I3Z !28 •" ••! -JJ •« "24 Average initial whisht Tu iTT^ iiT 5^ "T^T 25 — AveraitB final weight o?H I igS 2 4 r "? 14 « 143 AveraRc K ain per -head • 90 !"?s '"iS 2 2' 210 2 3'» Average daily gain "-' PiO~i rT5~l i o\ ~ 1°__ 2!_ Feed required per hundred: i — ~ 1 " S1 I 1-18 I _ljil wcicht Kain: Corn 434 J , Whole barley ... Wnc 295 Ground barley Z «sk Ground barley soaked ouu ■;■■■ 215 Whole barley soaked 4J - Tankaue "sS~" "S Vo 5fl 3 -7^r ny = ;: "-±jl_lii 5 Hand-fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 Trial B. — Fifty-five-day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, De - cember 27, 1918, to February 20, 1919 _ _ Z. _ Lot 1 ■ | Lot 2 ' | Lot 3 = 1 Lot 4 a | Lot 5 »" Number of pies 8 8 8 8 8 Average daily ration: Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Corn 4.32 Whole barley .' 4.54 Whole barley soaked (12 hrs.) 3.81 Whole barley soaked (24 hrs.)..... I 3.81 Ground barley soaked „ 3.89 Tankage 53 .40 .38 .38 .39 Alfalfa hay .13 .09 .10 .15 I Average initial weight 103 I 99 ! 103 ! 100 I 99 Average final weight 17:1 ' 152 | 15* 15(1 1 104 Avornco sain per head '. 70 . ! 53 | 55 56 ; 65 Averagedaily gain ~. T. 1.29 | lois j '.'JO | 1-02 I 1.18 Feed required per hundredweight gain : Corn 3»fi | .'. I "... ' Whole barley 472 Whole barley soaked (12 hrs.) 383 . ! Whole barley soaked (24 hrs.).. | . :i.7 1 Ground barley soaked...*. I .- .' ' 329 Tankage II I 42 3S 37 :t:i Alfalfa hay ■■■■■■■■ 10 10 . . | 10 _ 14 13 • Self-fed. 5 Hand-fed. Trial C. — Eighty-five-day dnj-lot hog feeding experiment, April IS, 1919, to July 11, 1919 ■ ■ , Lot 1 ' I Lot 2 • ■ Lot 3 : Number of pigs .....:. I 10 \ 10 10 Average daily ration: Pound* ■ I Pounds ' Pounds Corn : ; .: B.87 ' I (P. M.)3.21 Ground barley soaked _ ] C.4)&lt; (A. M.)».22 Tankage '. ;S4 • .66 .'i4 Alfalfa hay....; , : ; .14 ' .10 I ■ .1- Average initial weight : ."I in 10S .■'. 108 Average final weight '. 22fi : 207 2ls Average gain per head .' 112 99 110 Average daily gain . l.:l2 ' 1.17 ; . 1.34 Feed required per hundredweight gain : Corn : ; , 115 ■ ! 240. Ground barley soaked I 554 241 Tankage II 5fi 48 Alfalfa hay - 10 9 | 9 1 Self-fed. &gt; Hand-fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Barley as. Hog Feed Trial D.— One hundred-day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, November 3, 1919, to February 11, 1920 *^^TT- TT 21 !^' t3 ' l * t4 ' Lot5 ' "*"■ Lot 7.11**. gSSSbS&amp;iOT "-I "•" -KS — ■ fft SS :::::::: :::::::: (twice dnily) Ground barley soaked ~- 22 (three times daily) Hominy feed. ry. -™" 7.21 I If If J 1 | =g "jo; fc£S ISSWSSiz; ngTtST • °» »j o» ■ff-K Averace sain per head Is6 139 f|? "' ?" 260 240 229 Feed required per hundred- ~ j ' ' - 1 - 2 ? weight train : Ground' oariey" 429 T-V »K' 364 322 . Ground barley soaked' 348 7l (twice daily )...„ Ground barley soaked ■ 532 (throe times daily) Hominy feed .„ •"••,-•- 571 Tankage ~~SS ~*ZS ~SZ. *f "5 54 Alfalfa jay ZZZ . 3 6 | 3 | 2 |j B | 23 37 56 1 Self- fed. ' 5 1° § - Hanil-fed. ■ V Barley hand-fed, tankage self-fed. Trial E.— Ninety-four-day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, November 2, 1920, to February 4, W21 Number of p ig . ~ ., Lot 1- | Lot 2- | Lot 3' Average daily ration: .- V • _ 10 . 10 10 Corn ' Pounds Pounds Pounds Ground barley'.."....".;.'".' G ' 37 _ Ground barley soaked........'. '•••'3 Tankage tjj" 6 ' 60 AveraRe'initia'rwciRht — r--'' 1 * '— — dL AvcraKe final weicht ' 12l&gt; 127 127 Averace Kain per head V ■ ? , 238 247 Average difiiy K^n-.^^^Z^ZZZZilZI''.^- ] 41 U1 12 ° Feed reiiuired" per hundredweight train- z^^— ; 1-18 I 1 - 28 Corn Ground barley '."."."."'."".'.'.' Ground barley soaked ' 645 Tankage "" ' --■ 516 ■ — 53 56 3B 1 Self-fed. — ■ ■ 3 Hand-fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 2ni Trial F. — -Seventy-day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, February 18, 1293. to April 24. 1923 Lot I Lot 2 ; Lot 3 ' Lot 4 j Lot 5 I Lot 6 Number of pip:- ~~ 1 r. 15 ' f IB 15 | 15 f 18.- . Averape daily ration. F'tyuniJs Pounds ! Pound* j PovtuJf Pf*i/7tdti Pawnds Yellow com T» - 4 5! ■— j ...:...... | \ ... White corn I * 5.02 : : Mixed corn '.....'. . .... ■ i 5.2« '■ Ground barley .:.._■ ..'.... . 6.J4 .... fi.'jS 6.!-9 Tankape .60 ■' .."6 . .66 .79 .70 .72 Averape initial weigh:.' ~ Til i flfl IIP 111 ill 110 Averape final weicht :. . 215 215. !!&lt;!• "21C 207 . . 213 Average pain per head ...■■ . . 104 106 __ ptP • ll '- '■'" ;flR Averace daiiy pam 1 . A •• ' I ■ *• 1 I.-* 1.45 " ;.. * 1:47 Feed required per hundredv* ;pht j .' - pain: Yellow corn ;;71 1£2 White corn .. . 3PS 192 ■ . Ground barley........... -I5-; 4-1 '■ 46S- 1 , Tarikape '.4V aO_ . 5C .■■&lt; " "&gt;1 All lets pelf-fed. '■Mixed corn ? haii while, half yellow. . ■ Trial G. — Ninety-day hog feeding experiment. June 2S.1929, to September 26, 1929 ' .. ■ .•■ _ ■ r.ot ■. ■ !'.■'■ N'jmber • of r»ips *. n Arc-race daily ration: JVumi&gt; IVicws ■ Corn . . .•.:■:■ Ground barley :.'.. . . : • ■' Tankace Aver.-ipe initial weight ■ ■ ■ Averape. final weipht .* . Average pain per head &gt;- Averape daily pair. . . ■ Feed required per' hundreihvcipht pain: ■ ■ Corn .: ■....: ■...;.; : ... -SSO Ground barley ..;.. ..... iSt Tankace ..——;■■ Both lots full fed by har.tl -.'n Sudan pras*., 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Barley as Hog Feed Trial H. — Sixty-nine day dry-lot hog feeding experiment, November 6, 1932, to January 1U, 1933 — 10 pigs per lot Average daily ration: !• Pounds | Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds ■ Shelled corn , i 5.57 Whole barley ;.. 6.36 5.76 Coarsely ground barley 6.74 Finely ground barley j 7.20 Tankage. .. L . :... .: l .72 1.03 .74 .63 .51 Average initial weight 101.28 I 102.55 102.73 102.95 102.85 Average final weight. 212.17 | 200.72 214.97 233.00 182.41 Average gain i&gt;er head ; 1,10.89 1 98.17 112.24 130.05 79.56 Average daily gain '. ' 1.61 | . 1.42 | 1^63 \- e^_ _ J - ls Feed required per 100 pounds gain: Shelled corn 340 Whole barley : .-. 447 499 Coarsely ground barley '. I „ 415 Finely ground hurley i 382 Tankage .' : 45 ■ 72 . 45 33 44 _ C 1 7 | 8 [ 9~~~1 10~ , egflaS w i ee I ■*?' h^^'handSed^-'- I ™~ ' I »".oy &gt; AveraRC daily ration: . Pounds I Pounds Pounds Pounds Pound* Coarsely cround barley 6.73 ! 7.13 Finely ground barley ! 7.09 7. 67. Whole barley..., j 5.70 Tankairc : .50 | .50_ .49 .50_ Avcnuce initial wciffht i :... 102.93 I- 102.10 102.38 102.50 | 102.62 Averaice final weight 212.5S 216.10 185.57 206.40 '. 215.48 Average sain per head '. 109.65 114.00 83.19 103.90 j 112.86 Average daily train 1.59 1.65 1.21 1.51 | 1.64 Feed required per 100 pounds irain: [ Coarsely irround barley. : 423 j 473 Finely ground barley ■ 429 ! 463 Whole barley •... .V...... I 472 ! Tankaeo :. 31 J 30 41 33 | 30 1 Modulus 1.02. " Modulus a. 30. The barley used graded No. 3 with a test weight of 43.5 pounds. It contained 11.76 per t-ent moisture rind' 6 per cent oats. No. - yellow shelled corn was Ted in Lot 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 251 literature cited (1)1922'. Arnett, C. N. Fattening Pies (21)1931. Loeffcl, Wm. J. Wheat for at the Montana Station. Mont. Sta. Fattening Hogs. Ncbr. Exp. Sta.. Rept., pp. 17-18. Bui. 261. p. 16. (2)1923. Arnett, C. N. Experiments (22)1919. Morrison. F. B., and Boh - with Swine at the Montana Station. stedt, G. Barley for Fattening Hoes. Mont. Sta. Rept., p. 24. Wis. Farmers' Inst.. Bui. 32., pp. (3)1923. Bailey, C. .F. Feeding Ex- 96-103. periments with Swine. Canada Exp. (23)1919. Morrison, F. I!., and Boh- Farms, Fredericton. N. B. Kept., stcdt, G. Barley and Dairy By-pro - pp. 19-22. ■ ducts for Swine Feeding- Record (4)1931. Bohstedt. G., Roche, B. H., of Proceedings, Am. Soc. An. Prod., Fargo, J. M., Rupcl. I: W., and • pp. 93-96. Duffee, F. W. The Effect of Fine- (24)1931. Oliver, A. W. Preparation ness of Grinding Corn and- Barley on of Oats and Barley for Pies. Ore. Their Feeding Value for Pins and Sta., Cir. 104. 7 pages. Dairy Cattle. Record of Proceed- (25)1928. Robison, W. L. Results of ings. Am. Soc. An. Prod., pp. 277- • Livestock Experiments Announced 281. Livestock Day. Ohio Sta., Cir., 16 (B)Brown. G. A. Rations for Growing pages. Fattening Pigs on Pasture. Mich. (26)1899. Shaw. T. Beef Cattle and Acr. Exp. Sta., An. .Husb. Leaflet Swine. Minn. Sta., Bui. 60, pp. 30 - 37. 54. (6)1910. Carlyle, W. L., and Morton. (27)1909. Shepperd. J. H.. and Rich- G. E. Ration Experiments with - ards, W. B. Fattening Trials with Swine. Colo. Sta. Bui. 1G5.. pp. 3-23. Hogs. No. Dak. Sta., Bui. 84, pp. 5 - (7)1897. Cooke, W. W. Feeding Tests 24. . with Barley. Colo. Sta. Bui. 40. (28)1892. Smith, C. D. Corn vs. Bar - (8)1898. Dustan. N. J. R. Agr. Dppt. ley for Pigs. Minn. Sta.. Bui. 22. Univ. Col., Nottingham, and* Mid- ■ PP- 117-126. land Dairy Inst.. Kingston, p. 9. (29)1907. Snydcr. W. P. Growing (9)1925. Fcrrin, E. F., and McCarty, Hogs in Western Nebraska. Ncbr. M. A. Corn and Barley for Finish- Sta.. Bui. 99, pp. 26-26. ing Feeder Pigs. Div. An. Husb., (30)1919. Thompson. C. P. Prelimin- U. of Minn.. Mimeo. Cir. II 19. nry Report on (1) Comparison of (10)1928. Ferrin, E. F.. and McCarty, . Feeds for Fattening- Hogs. (2) Com- M. A. Corn Compared with Barley. parison of Mi-thods of Preparation Div. An. Husb.. U. of Minn.. Mimeo. °' Barley for Hoc Feed. Okla. Sta.. Cir. H 34. Kept., pp. 27-33. (11)1931. Ferrin,. E. F., Peters, W. H., .(31)1920. Thompson. C. P. Swine and Johnson, ' Don. A Comparison Feeding Investigations. Okln. Sta.. of Five Grains as Hog Feeds Div Rept., pp. 24-28, An. Husb., U. of Minn., Mimeo. Cir. .(32)1929. Vaughan. II. W.. Joseph. W. H 48. • E., and Vinke, L. Experiments with (12)1932. Freeman. V.- A. Preliminary Swine. Mont. Sta.. Rept., pp. 64-66. Results from Grinding Barley and 7t - 75 - Wheat for Pigs. Record of Proceed- (33)1925. Woodman. H. K. Maize and ings. Am. Soc. An. Prod.' pp 146- Barley for Pig Feeding. Jour. Min 147. Agr. (Gt. Brit.) 31. 12:1089-1103 (13)1895. Friis, F. Kgl. Vet. Landt (34)1931. Wilson. J. W.. and Wright, Lab.! Landokon Forsog. Copenhagen Turner. Fattening Fall Pigs on p. 199. ' South Dakota Grains. So Dak (14)1899. Goessmann, C. A Ma" , M '"ieo. Rept. Sta.. Seventh Ann. Rept " (35)1931. Wilson. J. W.. and Wricht. (15)192r&gt;. Grimes. ' M. F. Fattening 7 urn , cr ' , BarI&lt;! &gt;" « s " Fattening Feed Rations for Swine. Penn Sta for Cattle and Swine. So. Dak. Sta.. Mimeo. Rept. ' ,o^&gt; Bul ' 2G2 ' :i0 I""-' 1-'* - (16)1931. Hale. Fred. Swine Expeii- (3C) 1? 32 - Wr J Kht - Turner. Fattening ments. Tex. Agr. Exp Sta Mi™,, f,' Ka °," Sma11 Gr &lt;"™- Record of Progress Rept. ' Mlmp "' Proceedings. Am. Soc. An. Prod.. Truckee-Carson Exp. Farm. pp. 21- (39)1927-28. Experiments with Swine. ,,.,"', _ ■ Ore. Sta., Bienn. Rept.. p. 50. (19)1890 Henry W. A. Wis. Sta. (10)1930-31. Progress Report . on Pig f&gt;m?SJS w I""" S 01 "" PP - C3 ' 59 - Feeding at Akron. Colo. U. S. Dept. (20)1929. Hultz, F. S., Reeve, Lew, P., Agr. mill Colo. Exp. Sta: Cooperat - and Wheeler, S. S. The Value of ing. Wyoming Small Grains' for Hogs. (41) Unpublished &lt;lntn from E. Z. Wyo. Exp. Sta., Mimeo. Rept. (Ke- Russell. An. llus. Div., B. A. I.. U. viscl1 ). p. n.'pt. Alt. .. ■ [".Ml </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>