<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick</title>
               <date value="1935-09">1935-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 80 The Utilization of Nitrogen', Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. BLISH, AND F. E. MUSSEHL LINCOLN, NEBRASKA SEPTEMBER, 1935 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY 1. The nitrogen, calcium, and phosphirus content of 127 newly hatched chicks was determined. 2. Thirty newly hatched chicks were ed accurately known amounts of a pood chick mash for 60 days. At the end of thi period nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat were determined for each chick. 3. By means of the comparative slaughter test the retention Of nitrogen was found to be 37.8 per cent, calcium -8.-t per cdnt, and phosphorus 27.3 per cent of the respective elements fed. ■4. The average gain m live weight per gram of nitrogen fed was 12.0 grams. 5. The rate of gain was -11.5 per cent )f the dry matter fed. 6. The coefficient of variability was approximately 5 per cent, except for the calcium figures, which had a coefficient of 8 per cet t. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Utilization of Nitrogen, Calcium, and Phosphorus by the Growing Chick C. W. ACKERSON, M. J. BUSH, AN!) F. E. MUSSEHL Efficient poultry production demands a knowledge of the constituent;, of the ration from the standpoint of proteins, energy, minerals, and vitamins. Studies on the digestibility of protein, fat, and carbohydrate have contributed much information of value, and the fund of knowledge with respect to vitamin requirements is being constantly increased. Data arc also accumulating on several phases of calcium and phosphorus metabolism, chiefly in connection with rickets, osteoporosis, and osteomalacia. The determination of accurate digestion coefficients is beset with difficulties in the case of all animals, but in trials with poultry the addi - tional inconvenience involved in the separation of urinary and fecal matter makes desirable another means of approach to the problem. The formulation of feeding standards for poultry has been based upon several methods of investigation. Briefly stated, these methods include: 1. The determination of the coefficients of digestibility for single feeds and mixtures of feeds (1-5). 2. Growth studies, wherein the growth secured on definite rations is related to the kind and quantity of feed consumed (6, 7). 3. Nitrogen-retention studies, involving the endogenous nitrogen excretion (8, 9). 4. The determination of the net energy requirements of fowls (10. 11). 5. The comparative slaughter test (12, 13). ! Discussions of the advantages and shortcomings of these methods arc readily available in the literature. Work at this station (14), wherein balance studies were carried out in order to determine the biological value of the proteins of cereals, revealed a variation among individuals which was discouragingly high. This variation arose in part from the necessity for using an indirect means of measuring the nitrogen retained by the body. In other words, the bio - logical value of a protein was arrived at by measuring the amount of ingested protein not utilized in its passage through the digestive tract, and after applying a correction for the endogenous nitrogen excretion, it was assumed that the remainder was utilized. The method is theoretically sound, yet it is incapable of proof other than that afforded by a low coefficient of variation in the results secured. In view of the above facts, it seemed desirable to secure information on the value of poultry feeds by means of an approach to the problem involving the chemical analysis of the birds for the purpose of determining the actual gain of nutrients secured during a feeding trial in which the amount of food ingested was accurately known. , \ </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. StA. Research Bulletin 80 METHOD OF H IVESTIGATION The comparative slaughter test (! 7) has as its basis for estimating the initial composition of the test animals, data secured on animals chosen because of their close resemblance to them at the time of starting the trial. Applying this principle to poultry, it is possible to determine the composi - tion of the newly hatched chick witi a small probable error, which may be reduced still further by increasing the number of determinations. The data thus obtained form the basis lor estimating the initial amounts of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus i:ontained in the chicks. At the con - clusion of the trial the test birds are killed, and the amounts of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus in the empiy birds determined. The composition of the gain made by the experimen al chick can be determined with an error, the magnitude of which is th it of the estimate of the initial com - position plus the error of the final analysis. This is merely the principle 01 the well-known slaughter test (17) adapted to chicks. To secure inform uion in addition to that derived from the comparative slaughter test, it is necessary to have quantitative food - consumption records. The ease with which birds can b: fed forcibly is a matter of common knowledge, but when various finely j [round ingredients comprise the mash to be fed, forced feeding is not reafiily made a quantitative procedure. When some years ago commercial feeds of various kinds appeared on the market in pellet form, the most difficult part of the quantitative feeding of young chicks was eliminated. The experimental ration can be made into pellets of a convenient size and weighed amounts fed to individual chicks without loss. To compute the total amount of the various nutrients fed, it is only required that the ration be analyzed. Thus two factors are determiiiable, namely, the amounts of the nutrients consumed and the composition of the bird at the end of the trial. A third factor, that of the in tial composition of the individual, is estimated as previously stated. Frori these data the gain in each of the nutrients from hatching time to any given weight can be ascertained. The amount fed is known, and the percentage of the total retained by the body over the period in question is read ly calculated. This method, with a record of accurate feed consumption by each individual, constitutes a refinement of the comparative slaughter test in that the retention of the nutrients c;m be expressed as a percentage of the total ingested. This represents the average utilization over the period, just as the gain in weight or change in composition represents an average in the slaughter test. It does not take into account the loss of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus in dropped feathers, etc. What is obtained is rhe gain of any element secured fom the amount of the element fed. The gain resulting from this feedirg is a measure of the bird's require - ments for growth over that period «f rime. If it could be determined that this growth is the optimum growth that could be secured in any event, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Utilization ok N, Ca, and P bv Chicks then the requirements could be definitely stated as being the requirements for optimum growth, but such a statement is incapable of ready demon - stration. Chickens lend themselves very well to studies of this sort for the following reasons: (1) it is possible to hand-feed chicks from hatching time to any desired age without loss of feed; (2) chicks increase rapidly in weight, so that marked gains in the various nutrients in the body will be reflectedin short periods of time; (3) they are inexpensive as laboratory subjects, both as regards initial cost and outlay for rations; and (4) their small size, in comparison with other domestic animals, makes an analysis of the entire carcass comparatively easy to carry out. The laboratory tech - nique involved includes the usual planning of the ration and the selection and housing of the chicks, together with their subsequent feeding and care. The ration is mixed as a mash, but to facilitate feeding, and to pre - vent loss in the procedure, it is pelleted in a 5/32-inch die, which pro - duces pellets of suitable size for hand-feeding, baby chicks. These arc screened to remove fine material, leaving only particles which can be readily handled. At the beginning of the experiment, diet bottles containing 150 grams of pelleted feed are assigned to each chick. Feeding tubes are made from glass tubing with a 7 mm. outside and a 5 mm. inside diameter, and 10-20 cm. long, depending on the size of the chick. One end is flared slightly and both ends are fire-polished. The pellets, for the feeding of the indi - vidual are transferred to the tube by means of a V-shaped trough of tin sheeting, 1.5 cm. deep and 25 cm. long, one end of which is closed and the other rounded sufficiently to fit the flared end of the feeding tube. By this means the tubes are readily filled without loss. The filled tube is then carefully pushed down the chick's esophagus, and the pellets expelled into the crop by means of a glass rod. The initial feedings are the most difficult but dexterity in manipulation is acquired with practice. The number of chicks which may be started on experiment at one time is limited by the amount of time available for feeding during the first month of their life, as this operation is time-con - suming. Feeding progresses more rapidly as the chicks grow, but naturally the amount of ration required at each feeding also increases. With careful technique, loss of feed is avoided, but a certain number of casualties among the chicks must be expected during the first week. The chicks are hand-fed two or more times daily during the first three weeks. At three weeks of age it is possible to put them in tall cans where they soon learn to consume the pelleted ration from feeding cups with no possibility of loss. The chicks quickly consume their feed and are replaced in the brooder without delay. By the use of this technique, accurate indi - vidual feed-consumption records are obtained. Fresh tap water is before the birds at all, times. Cod-liver oil to provide an adequate vitamin D level is fed daily by pipette. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. S -a. Research Bulletin 80 At the conclusion of the feeding trial each chick is starved overnight, weighed, and killed by placing in a desiccator and evacuating the air therefrom, which entails no loss ol blood. Chilling the carcass prevents the loss of blood on opening, after which the digestive tract from the proventriculus down (the crop lieing already empty) is removed and emptied. The net body weight of the bird is obtained- following this operation. Nitrogen is determined on the contents of the proventriculus and gizzard, and this amount is deducted from the amount of nitrogen fed. The amount of nitrogen in the remainder of the tract is also determined. The next step consists of the d sintegration of each bird with hydro - chloric acid (sp. gr. 1.18) first in the cold and later on the hot plate. Reakers, their size depending on whether one chick or a group is to be the unit of analysis, are used in the digestion, and acid sufficient to cover the carcass is added. As hydroh sis and disintegration continue, the liberated fat rises to the surface, vhile the rest of the liquid becomes practically homogenous. Chilling t ie sample solidifies the fat so that it may be removed mechanically to another beaker, where it is separated from adherent material by dissolving in successive portions of ether and by removing the ether additions and dissolved fat to a weighed flask by means of a pipette. The ether is dien driven off and the fat brought to constant weight. The portion remaining after extraction of the fat is also freed from ether and returned to the original' i:ontainer. If necessary the solution is concentrated before being made tD volume. Suitable aliquots, ranging from one to 25 per cent of the total, are digested via Kjeldahl. When the digest contains too much nitrogen for the usual distillation, it may be diluted the desired amount and. nitrogen determined on convenient aliquots. From this the total amount of nitrogen in the sample is calcu - lated. To check the possibility oi loss of nitrogen and phosphorus by removal in the fat, 25 grams of fat obtained by the above method were found to contain 0.02 per cent nifogen and 0.03 per cent phosphorus. For a newly hatched chick, the errsr thus incurred in the estimation of total nitrogen and phosphorus is less than a milligram, and for larger birds correspondingly small. A portion of the initial sample (after removal of fat) is oxidized by means of a mixture of nitric and hydrochloric acids to permit the determ - ination of calcium and phosphorus. In addition phosphorus may be run on aliquots of the Kjeldahl digest, mentioned above, to check the prep - aration of the sample by digestion with nitric acid. Nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, md ether extract are determined for each chick and also for the ration fed. With the completion of this work the following information is available for each bird: initial weight, final live weight and net body weight, weight of feed ingested, and the weights of nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat contained at the slaughter weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Utilization of N, Ca, and P by Chicks In addition to this phase of the feeding trial it is necessary to secure data on the composition of baby chicks in order that the gain of each experimental chick may be estimated. For this purpose analyses are made by means of the technique used in the analysis of the chicks at the slaughter weight. As a result it is possible to calculate the total weight of the gain, the weights of nitrogen, phosphorus, and calcium in the gain, the gain as a percentage of the dry matter fed, the gain per unit of nitrogen fed, and the percentage of retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus. Mitchell, Card, and Hamilton (12, 13) carried out comparative slaughter tests involving 95 White Rock and 150 White Leghorn chickens in groups varying in weight from one-half pound to seven pounds. From their data they calculated the daily increments in body weight, dry sub - stance, crude protein, ether extract, ash, calcium, and gross energy of chickens at different body weights. With regard to the application of their data they state (13, page 127), "Their practical use in the formulation of scientific feeding standards must wait upon the satisfactory evaluation of maintenance requirements and requirements for muscular activity, and the satisfactory measurement of the wastage of food in digestion and metabolism." It is with the wastage of food in digestion and metabolism during growth of young chicks that this paper is concerned. The net requirement of matter by chicks of varying ages can be learned from analyses of car - casses of different weights, but knowing them it is still impossible to calculate the exact quantity required because of the unmeasured metabolic losses. It is the purpose of this paper to present the data and conclusions secured in a growth study of chicks in which the net retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus was determined. RESULTS OF ANALYSIS OF NEWLY HATCHED CHICKS In the preliminary experimental work (15) several groups of newly hatched chicks -were killed, individually weighed, and disintegrated with hydrochloric acid so that determinations could be made on aliquots of the resulting solution. With the exception of the first and second groups, each chick slaughtered weighed 37±2 grams. All had been hatched about 24 hours and had received no food. Selections were made on the basis of the weight range of 35 to 39 grams. This range was arbitrarily chosen in an attempt to reduce the individual variability. Sex determinations were not made, nor were the intestinal contents removed. The chicks were killed after weighing, and nitrogen was determined by the modified Kjeldahl method. Calcium and phosphorus were run according to the methods of analysis of the A. O. A. C, following diges - tion with nitric acid. They are reported as elements, not as oxides. Indi - vidual determinations were made on 46 chicks, which showed a mean nitrogen content of 0.94±0.006 gram per chick, with a coefficient of variability of 6.8 per cent. Since these figures showed a low variability, 81 chicks were analyzed in four groups. The results of all the analyses are summarized in Table 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 80 Table 1. — The average compost ion of 127 newly hatched chicks. I Date of I No. in I j ~~ I Phos- j j Ratio i Ether Breed | hatch I group | Weight I N itrogen I phorm | Calcium I Ca:P I extract Grams Gra, i; P. ct. Gram Gram I', ct. Harrcd Rock June 4 7 34 0 9 2.66 0.12 White Leghorn Jan. 15 10 37 0.9) 2.39 0.11 ... ... 6.6 White Leehorr. Feb. 25 14 37 0.91 2.55 0.11 ... ... 7.0 White Leghorn Mar. 25 15 38 0.9 2.62 0.08 0.13 1.7 8.0 White Rock May 18 15 » 36 0.9- 2.60 0.12 0.15 j 1 3 7.2 White Rock May 18 16 » 3fi 0.9 2.58 0.11 0.15 ' 1.3 fi.2 White Leghorn May 25 25 » 37 1.01 2.71 0.13 0.15 1.2 5.8 White Ro:k May 25 25 l 37 0.9 &gt; 2.60 0.1 1 0.15 1.3 8.1 Weighted average 37 OS) ! 2.59 0.11 0.15 1.3 7.0 1 These chicks analyzed in groups. While space does not permit showing the individual analyses of the chicks in Table 1, the fact that variation was not great, coupled with the fact that the figures represent 127 chicks, should make the weighted aver - ages reliable. Furthermore, should ;he error incurred in estimating the initial composition be as great as 10 per cent, even then it would be reflected as less than a one per cent error in the calculation of the gains of a 350-gram chick, as illustrated in Table 2. Table 2. — The relative error in th; estimation of the gains of chicks. I Composition of | Estimated I Composition I 10% | Initial error I 350-gram chick I at 37 gr; ims | of gain I initial error ! as % of gain Grams P. ct. Gra n Grams Gram I', cl. Nitrogen 10.92 '.' 3.12 0."5 9.97 0.095 0.95 Phosphorus 1.93 0.55 0.1 1.82 0.011 0.60. Calcium 2.66 0.76 0.5 2.51 0.015 0.60 It can be readily seen that as the final slaughter weight is increased, the relative error in the calculation jf the gains decreases. This error is also reduced by increasing the nurrber of chicks used at the slaughter weight. The data of Table 1 form the basis for calculating the gain of the chicks by assuming that their initial composition agrees closely with the values found in the table. RESULTS FROM THE EXPERIMENTAL FEEDING To test out this plan of measuring the percentage retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus, 40 White and Barred Rock chicks hatched from pullet eggs were started on a ration which was mixed as follows: Per cent Per cent Yellow cornmeal 36 Meat meal 10 Shorts 20 Alfalfa meal 8 Bran . 10 Dried buttermilk ". 5 Pulverized oats 10 Common salt . . .' 1 Analysis of this mash gave the following results: Per cent Per cent Nitrogen 3.21 Crude fat 4.20 Calcium 0.70 Crude fiber 5.70 Phosphorus 0.81 Ash 6.40 Protein 20.00 Nitrogen-frcc extract 56.50 Moisture 7.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Utilization of N, Ca, and P by Chicks The chicks had not been fed prior to being placed on experiment. They were kept on half-inch-mesh wire under electric hovers at first, but were later placed in two sections of an electrically heated battery brooder for convenience in handling. The wire mesh used permitted the bulk of the droppings to pass through but to reduce coprophagy further the cages were cleaned several times a week. The chicks were housed in a basement room of the Chemistry building. Brooding conditions were good, but 10 chicks did not survive the forced feeding at the outset of the work. Thus 30 chicks were carried through the two months of the feeding trial. The mash was pelleted, using a 5/32-inch die, and fed to the chicks in the manner previously described. During the first three or four weeks each chick was forcibly fed the pelleted ration in approximately the same amount daily. As soon as pos - sible the chicks were trained to take the pellets from a feeding cup in an individual container, usually a tin can of convenient size. After a short period most of the chicks took readily to this procedure, eating their fill in a few moments, so that they could be replaced in the brooder without delay. In this trial the chicks determined their daily consumption, which resulted in varying rates of growth. Each chick was assigned individual diet bottles from which feed was apportioned twice daily, so diat an accurate record of the feed eaten by each chick was maintained with little difficulty. Semi-weekly weighings were made, but the critical weights are the initial and final weights, since their difference constitutes the experi - mental gain. Thus during the trial live-weight and food-consumption records were kept. At the end of the trial the total nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and ether extract of the birds were determined after the removal of the intestinal contents. With the completion of this work the following information had been collected for each bird: initial weight, final live and net body weights, weight of feed ingested, and the weights of nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat contained at the slaughter weight. The initial composition of each chick was calculated from its initial weight and the data found in Table 1. The gain in weight is obviously the difference between the final net body weight and the initial weight. The composition of the gain is the difference between the total nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat as determined at the slaughter weight and the estimated initial content of these nutrients. The amounts of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus fed each chick were calculated from the amounts of feed ingested and the percentage of each in the feed. The amount of nitrogen fed was corrected for the amount which was unused in the pro - ventriculus and gizzard at death, but the calcium and phosphorus figures were not so treated because of the small amount of each involved — only about five milligrams. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 80 From these figures the percentage retention of nitrogen, calcium and phosphorus was calculated by dividing the weight of each nutrient in the gain by the weight of it fed. This resulted in figures expressing for each chick the net retention of each element studied. It is not deemed practical to include all the data collected, liut a summary of the results is given in Tables 3 to 7. These allow com arisons between the males and female* of Lot 1. With the ration fed to he birds of this lot the mean percentage composition of the chicks and the retention of the elements by the chicks did not vary between the sexes. The figures secured possessed low coef - ficients of variability, indicating that the performance of the individual did not vary greatly from that of the mean. _.. Table 3. — Individual data on chicks. Chick I t: "™P""""" of Chick j leu,, C..,np&lt;,si,i,, n „( G,i,, .~ ~ lUlio j |-^~ j_N Ca P | (J:I&gt; "^ fr : c:.,:I&gt; extract •Vo. p. a. i'. a. v.a. ,-.c,. p. „ ,.. „. " ,, c , MALES 2 l» %% "- 31 lM 3U O- 68 0-52 1.31 6 0 2 296 0 -' C&gt; °-56 I-3S .1.01 0.78 0 57 137 77 3 3 .26 M0 03i 1.38 3.36 0.86 Hi 1&lt; 54 1 320 0.82 0.57 1M 3.27 0.86 0 «. M3 65 ' 3.0 0J4 OM 1.37 3.06 0.78 (J .56 ,.39 61 8 3.13 0./2 0.55 1.31 3.18 0.74 0 56 1 31 « 9 2.97 0.72 0.56 1.27 3.01 0.75 o'ss 30 A I: J* "■« °- 3 ' &gt; i» W 0.84 059 .« A 3 3.02 0.78 0.55 1.42 3.06 0.80 0.57 140 6 8 16 -'.01 Q.6P 0.52 1.33 3.04 0 71 0 54 \'i\ l« '! 2 - 85 "-'3 0.55 1.33 2.87 0.74 ojfi 3 s' 5 "3 3.05 0.8fi 0.60 1.43 3.09 0.91 0 64 {.« -4 2/ 3 -- |s us8 0-59 M9 3.56 0.93 0.62 LsO 7J 1' LMALES 1 2.96 0.76 0.55 1.38 3.00 0.79 0 57 M8 10 8 » s s a a is I s 1 ' 1 1 1 I 1 I I i! I £ ■ s a 3 s a | i s s s a a a. s 1 ; : » ,| Mean 3.10 0.76 0.55 1.37 3.15 n.79 0.57 1.37 7 . 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Utilization of N, Ca, and P by Chicks Table 3. — {Continued) Chick I I N«.l»&lt;«y l.iilial I Cain in I Dry I Rate I Gain^T^ I weight I weight wc-ikIii | weight | mailer fed [ of gain | nitrogen fed .Vo. Crams Grams drams Crams Grams P. &lt;;. Grams MALES 1 JM 213 27 186 456 40.8 11.8 24S 239 26 213 496 42 8 12 4 254 243 .13 210 509 41.3 119 295 285 31 254 (-.26 40 6 117 296 286 33 253 595 42.5 123 8 29fi 289 26 263 624 42.1 12 2 9 321 302 30 272 614 44.3 1'8 12 346 321 27 294 666 44 1 12 8 13 346 331 26 305 726 41 0 I2J 16 361 347 28 319 758 42.1 122 '" 365 349 26 323 746 43.3 12 5 22 448 432 41 391 978 40.0 116 2' 58(1 558 42 516 1267 40.7 11.8 FEMALES ■I 287 279 29 250 584 42.8 1 2 4 '• 295 285 26 259 622 41.6 12 1 I" 314 304 ■ 37 267 616 43.3 12 5 11 337 316 34 282 IMS 40.6 11.7 14 ?.53 3il 32 311 755 41.2 119 15 354 344 33 311 740 42.0 12^1 1" 361 348 31 317 738 42.7 12.4 19 360 350 25 325 808 40.2 II 6 20 370 352 4(1 312 772 40.4 11.7 21 440 424 40 384 970 39.6 11.5 23 510 4S9 3S 451 1114 40.5 11.7 24 515 504 36 46H 1159 40.4 11.7 25 525 507 36 471 119(1 39.6 11.5 26 553 539 38 . 501 1218 41.1 11.9 28 596 579 36 543 1408 38.6 11.1 ?9 687 657 37 620 14W 41.4 12.0 30 795 758 34 724 1732 41.8 12.1 Mian 41.5 12.0 Tablu 4. — Nitrogen-retention data. ■ Nitrogen Net Kitnuti-n in chick Chick Nitrogen j in gi7 . zard nXxxogcn N.ir.^n in cluck Nitrogen fci1 contents fcil - I inal | Initial | Gain retained .Vo. Grami Gram Grams Grams Grams Grams P. cl. MALES 1 15.79 0.02 15.77 6.48 0.70 5.78 36.63 2 17.14 0.02 17.12 7.08 0.68 6.40 37.40 \ 17.62 0.03 17.59 7.92 0.86 7.06 40.15 5 21.67 0.01 21.66 9.12 0.81 8.31 38.39 7 20.57 0.01 20.56 8.60 0.86 7.74 37.65 8 21.57 0.02 21.55 9.04 0.68 8.36 38.80 &lt;) 21.22 0.04 21.18 8.96 0.78 8.18 38.63 12 23.05 0.04 23.01 9.28 0.70 8.58 37.28 H 25.10 0.02 25.08 10.00 0.68 9.32 37.17 16 26.22 0.02 26.20 10.44 0.73 9.71 37.06 18 25.81 0.02 25.79 . 9.96 0.68 9.28 36.01 22 33.81 0.02 33.81 13.16 1.07 12.09 35.77 27 43.82 0.03 43.79 19.44 1.09 18.35 41.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 80 Table A.-\-(Continued) 7^Mck N'tfOfcn £'££« nit^ cn Nitrogen in chick j N ~7 comenu fed Final | Initial | Gain retained No. Crams Cram Cram; Grams Crams Grams I', a. f: lmales 4 20.19 0.02 • 20.17 8.25 0.75 7 50 37 15 6 21.51 0.02 21.49 8.68 0.67 8.01 37~24 10 21.31 0.02 21.29 9.31 0.96 8 35 39 19 11 24.04 0.03 24.01 9.84 0.88 8.96 37*29 14 26.13 0.02 26.11 10.28 0.83 9 45 36 19 15 25.61 0.01 25.60 11.08 0.86 10 22 39 92 1" 25.52 0.01 25.51 10.32 0.81 9 51 3730 19 27.96 0.01 27.95 11.60 0.65 10.95 39.18 20 26.70 0.02 26.68 11.80 1.04 10.76 40 33 21 33.55 0.02 33.53 13.60 1.04 12.56 37 46 23 38.52 0.03 38.49 15.30 0.99 14.31 37 18 24 40.09 0.02 40.07 16.32 0.94 15.38 38.39 25 41.15 0.03 41.12 16.00 0.94 15.06 36 63 26 42.15 0.02 42.13 17.40 0.99 16.41 38.95 28 48.73 0.02 48.71 17.96 0.94 17.02 34.95 29 51.84 0.05 51.79 19.64 0.97 18.67 36 04 30 59.90 0.06 59.84 23.24 0.88 22.36 37.36 Mean 37.78 Table 5. — Calcium-retention data. Chick Calcium i Calcium in chick 'y Calcium Fina ' i Initial i GalS retained No. Gram* Craws Cram Grams p c t MALES 1 3.44 1.4L 0.15 1.26 -,0 50 2 3.74 1.82 0.15 1.67 446' 3 3.84 1.95 0.15 1.80 4673 5 4.73 2.33 0.15 2.18 46.18 " 4.49 2.11 0.15 1.96 43.77 8 4.70 2.09 . 0.15 1.94 4124 9 4.63 2.1S: 0.15 2.03 43 91 12 5.03 2.63 0.15 2.47 49'l4 13 5.47 2.5* 0.15 2.44 445-) 16 5.72 2.40 0.15 2.25 39 - 39 18 5.63 2.55 0.15 2.40 4259 22 7.38 3.7 0.15 3.57 4S 37 27 9.56 4.9:i 0.15 4.78 50.08 I EM ALES 4 4.40 2.1!; 0.15 1.97 44.70 6 4.69 2.i; 0.15 2.01 4281 10 4.65 2.0! 0.15 1.87 40 30 11 5.24 2.3i 0.15 2.21 42.06 14 5.70 2.5! 0.15 2.38 41 t,i 15 5.59 2.4 1 0.15 2.29 40 9S 17 5.57 2.3! 0.15 2.16 38 85 19 6.10 2.7? 0.15 2.62 43.04 20 5.82 2.9! 0.15 2.83 48.59 21 ? 7.32 3.6" 0.15 3.52 48.15 23 8.40 3.4! 0.15 3.30 39 29 24 8.74 3.6! • 0.15 3.48 39.80 25 8.97 4.2! 0.15 4.08 45 51 26 9.19 4.1 i 0.15 4.00 43.52 28 10.63 4.5 1 0.15 4.35 40.95 29 11.31 5.i: 0.15 4.96 43.84 30 13.06 5.3 1 0.15 5.23 40.00 Mean 43.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Utilization of N, Ca, and P by Chicks Table 6. — Phosphorus-retention data. Chick Phosphorus Phosphorus in chick Phosphorus Final ' Initial I Gain retained No. Cram! Grams Cram Crams p. ct . MALES 2 ' •■• I™ J-0| 0" 0.97 24.37 ::::::::::::::;::::: $ 1:5? S: g : g» 5 5.47 1.63 0.11 .52 27 - 87 ' 5.15 1.54 oil 1« ,-„ I ■■•• 5.44 1.58 0 47 2703 9 5.35 1.68 0.11 57 ?9?o ; ■ 5.82 1.83 0.11 72 4'ie !:■ •■•■ «-33 1.83 0.11 "72 «••• 6.62 1.81 0.11 • 70 5573 1* ■ "i 1.91 0.11 : 8 o £70 ; : ».54 2.60 0.11 2 49 2919 27 11 ••&gt;« 3.31 0.11 I20 2W2 FEMALES 4 5.10 1.53 0.11 1« 2779 !!:::::::::::::::::::: S 1:11 !:i! I g ' C« 1.81 0.11 1.70 7 §•♦■ 1-83 011 1.72 ?6% I' 7.06 1.91 . 0.11 ISO "&gt;5 57 2" fi.74 2.13 0.11 2.02 3003 Jl ■-« 2.55 0.11 2.44 2885 " 9.72 2.66 0.11 2.55 2621 « 10.12 2.69 0.11 2.58 2548 5 I0-38 '-"I 0.11 2.90 27196 2« 11M 3.04 0.11 2.93 27 50 ;»■■■. 12-30 3.07 0.11 2.9fi 24"o6 2" t- 13.08 3.73 0.11 3.62 2766 30 15.12 3.96 0.11 3.85 TBM Mean 27.26 Table 7. — Summary of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus data. item Seventeen Thirteen All 30 ' Coefficient females males I chicks of variation Per tail I'er cent . Per cent Per cent Kilrigcn in chicks 3.12 3.17 3.10±0.1&lt;!6 4.35 Calcium in chicks 0.76 0.77 0.76+0.0074 7^92 Phosphorus in chicks 0.55 0.56 0.55+0.0037 5.38 Ratio Ca:P in chicks 1.37 1.37 1.37+0.00" 4 13 Nitrogen in Rain 3.17 3.12 3.15+0.185 4.88 Calcium in gain 0.78 0.S0 0.79+0.0081 8.31 I'hosphorut in sain 0.57 0.58 0.57+0.0041 5.79 Ratio Ca:P in sain 1.37 1.38 1.37+0.0065 3.84 Rate of sain 41.05 42.04 41.48+0.167 3.27 O;,in per sram nitrogen 11.88 12.17 12.00+0.055 3.70 Nirroscn retaincJ 37.69 37.91 37.78±0.185 3 98 Calcium retained 42.61 44.39 43.38+0.410 7.71 Phosphorus retained 26.81 27.83 27.26+0.185 5.60 DISCUSSION These figures do not give the biological value of the ration in the sense in which the term is usually interpreted, for the biological value measures the efficiency of conversion of ingested protein to body protein. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acn. Exp Sta. Research Bulletin 80 A schematic diagram of the course of the nitrogen in the body is presented in Figure 1. A factoring of the food nitrogen according to this scheme makes it possible to poirjt out the main differences between various methods of determining the value of feeding stuffs for animals. I | INGESTED NrTROJGEN I' I . UNDIGESTED ■ — — DIGESTED |~ ~1 \p- UNRESORBED I EPIDERMAL I REPRODUCTION I \ | | DETRITUS I | t LACTATION | i 'L—^'^ I sJwVJf^s RESORBED Lj temporary I l I SYNTHESIS^.! _,._. T|SSUEs I 'Tri fl n STORAGE | ■ 1 LJ I ,_||NTESTINAL I I I ,,. 'N^ PECES ~ DETRITUS | 111 7^&gt;. P'l I CIRCULATING N O\ I ilj — j "URINARY ENDOGENOUS NITROGEN PROTEIN \Jv I EXCRETED L_ J TIZTITrTtJ^l URINARY EXOGENOUS NITROGEN -&gt; ■ CATABOLIZED I _J ' I 1 Fie;. 1. — Diagram of Hi course of nitrogen in the body. The usual digestion trial theoretically distinguishes between the undi - gested and digested material; actually in the measured undigested portion is included the unresorbed portion of the material digested as well as the metabolic nitrogen of the feces. |-\s a consequence, the digestion coefficient is in error by these amounts. In the determination of the biological value of proteins it is necessary to ascertain, in a preliminary nit ogen-free feeding period, the endogenous nitrogen excreted in the urine and feces. The animal is then fed a ration containing the protein it is desiicd to test and the total nitrogen excreted in the urine and feces is again determined. The figures obtained in the preliminary period are applied rs corrections in the proper sense and the biological value can then be sta cd. Referring to Figure 1, it is apparent that this method is concerned with the problem of finding the amount of protein which is deposited in tie tissues. This amount is calculated by measuring during two different experimental periods the following nitro - gen fractions: (1) undigested pcrtion, (2) unresorbed portion, (3) protein catabolized, (4) daily loss of cir:ulating protein, and (5) metabolic nitro - gen of the feces. As previously stated, the method is theoretically sound, yet in work with mature hens (9, 14), a high variability in the results led to the use of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Utilization of N, Ca, and P by Chicks a slaughter test based on two direct determinations, namely, the amount of ingested nitrogen and the amount of nitrogen contained in the carcass. Only one trial is involved with each bird, and no assumption is necessary as to the constancy of the endogenous nitrogen excretion of a bird on diets which do and do not provide nitrogen. Naturally this procedure is most readily applied to small birds, as the mechanical work involved is not so great, but it may be extended to adult birds as well. In the work shown in Table 3 one chick was carried to nearly 800 grams without difficulty. In the trials summarized in Table 7 individual analyses were made on each chick in order to test the variability of the results. From the data accumulated during the 60-day feeding trial involving 30 chicks, the composition of the chicks and the gains at the slaughter weights were calculated. Correlating these figures with the intakes of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus yields figures representing the retention of these elements by each bird. These data are presented in Tables 3 to 6 and summarized in Table 7. The agreement in the results is good, as evi - denced by coefficients of variability ranging from 3 to 8 per cent. CONCLUSIONS Under the conditions of the experiment and with the ration fed it is evident that: 1. Forced feeding of the pelleted ration permits accurate control of the food intake of baby chicks. 2. Feeding the ration in pellet form permits the estimation of the .per - centage retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus with a low coef - ficient of variability. 3. The percentage rate of gain and the gain per gram of nitrogen fed approach constant values regardless of differences of 500 grams in gains during a 60-day feeding period. 4. No significant sex differences in the utilization of the nutrients were observed. ' LITERATURE CITED 1. Brown. E. \V. ; 1904. U. S. I). A.. I'.ur. An. Ind. Nul. 56. 2. Kaupp. H. I'., and Ivcj% J. E. 1923. N. C. Aftr. Kxp'. Sta. Tech. Bill. 22. 3. Fraps. G. S. 192H. Tex. Agr. Kxp. Sta. liul. 372. 4. Fraps. C!. S. 1931. Tex. Agr. Kxp. Sta. Bui. 437. 5. Heller. V. G., Morris. L.. and Shirley, H. E. 1930. Poultry Sci. 10:3-9. (&gt;. Titus. H. W.. Jull. M. A., and Hcndricks, \V. A. 1934. Jour. Agr. Res. 48 :S 17-35. 7. Brody, S. 1932'. Mo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 166. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agr. Ex:&gt;. Sta. Research Bulletin 80 8. Mitchell, H. H., and Hamilton, T. S. ■? 1929. The Biochemistry of the Amino Acids, pp. 539-40. The Chemical Cataloc Co., New York. 9. Ackerson, C. \V., Blish, M. J., and Mussehl, F. E. 1930. Poultry Sci. 9:112-32. 10. Mitchell, H. H., and Haines, \V T. 1927. Jour. Agr. Res. 34:927-43. 11. Mitchell, H. H., Card, L. E., and, Haines, W. T. 1927. Jour. Agr. Res. 34:945-60. 12. Mitchell, H. H., Card, L. E., and Hamilton, T. S. 1926. 111. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 278. 13. Mitchell, H. H., Card, L. E., and Hamilton, T. S. 1931. III. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 36J7. 14. Ackerson, C. W., Blish, M. J., arid Mussehl, F. E. 1928. Poultry Sci. 8:1-10. !5. Forty-fifth Annual Report. 1932. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta., p. 31. 16. Forty-sixth Annual Report. 1933. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta., p. 31 j 17. Armsby, H. P. 1917. Nutrition- of Farm Animals, pp. 199-200. The Macmillan Co., New York. [3M] \. ■ '■■ ■ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>