<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Sixteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">V j^ 3". — - C a* a aa S k 2 K 9 C I*— ■ z2 B h i»-^ t—^ — — \ \ J * j* I .' </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA t Sixteenth Biennial Report OK THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble- Minded Youth BEATRICE. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institution* For the Biennium Ending November 30. 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">130 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF RESIDENT OFFICERS EG. Griffiths ma J. Lawrence ;is Werner Superintendent Assistant Physician Steward Susan H. Rai.ey C. P. Underwood Laura Emery Matron Bookkeeper Stenogrspher SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Harriet Schaeffer, Principal Rollings O'Donneix Marguerite Pickett Ada M. Glancy DEPARTMENT HEADS f j.i am Pollock &gt;A Pollock C. Alvoro Boys' Supervisor Girls' Supervisor Supervisor of Boys' Hospit-1 Supervisor of Girls' Hospital Nellie Alvord Martha Dillon Lulu Wernes Lon Wait Sewing Department In Charge of Laundry Chief Engineer KH. Dennehy J. Kaminski Carpenter Painter </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 131 NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE - MINDED YOUTH Beatrice, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehecul, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen : I have the honor to submit herewith the sixteenth biennial report of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, covering the period from December 1, 1914, to November 30, 1916. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT During this period Dr. W. S. Fast had charge of ih institution from December 1, 1914, to February 1, 1916, a which time I took charge and I feel duly thankful to him fo the assistance and advice rendered me in regard to the institu tion affairs at that time. Whatever success has been attainet by the management of this institution has been largely due t wholesome advice and generous support given us by th Governor and the members of the Board. I have also bee fortunate in being surrounded by loyal assistants. THINGS ACCOMPLISHED The erection of the new school building has given us an opportunity to do much more for the children committed to the institution than has ever been done before on account of lack of room and equipment Gymnasium work has been intro - duced and is a very important factor in the training of this class of children, both mentally and physically. Also sloyd work and brush making has been re-established. Manual </seg>
            <seg id="p005">132 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Iining of different kinds is carried on. It is to be remem - ed that the average feeble-minded child, no matter how ch effort is put forth, is never able to go beyond the third or irth grade in literary work. However, the children have ■y decided talents in other directions and it is our belief and •pose, besides developing the children as far as they are e to go in a literary way, to teach them along any line of ational study in which they may show an especial aptitude, laboratory has been established and equipped. We have roduced a new system of keeping records of the children o are committed to this institution by having different ms printed, for physical examination, supervisors' reports, ntal test blanks, laboratory blanks, etc., so that a more •manent record of the condition and progress of each child t enters the institution may be kept. Improving Physical Plant I During the last biennium 80 acres of land have been added that already owned by the State at this place. A dairy barn is now under the course of construction which is the most sanitary that can be erected with its feed department and milking department separate. Milk being one of the most advantageous articles of food for this class of inmates, it is very necessary that we have a dairy barn and a dairy herd which is par excellence. It is also very necessary that dairying be carried on in the most sanitary manner and to this end we are striving in the erection of the new barn. There is, in connection with the barn, a silo in which ensilage is placed for feeding of the cattle. Hay placed here may be stored for the feeding of the dairy herd during the winter A new three-story school building has been erected . The lower floor or basement is devoted to a gymnasium, shop and manual training rooms of different kinds. The first floor has four school rooms, one of them being the girls' industrial room where the classes in art work are held. There is also on this floor a library and music room. The top floor has a beautiful auditorium with a seating capacity for about 750 people. We </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 133 have installed on this floor a motion picture machine and give the children a moving picture show each week which is of great assistance in an educational way and which they enjoy immensely. The income and disposition of the products of the farm, garden, shop, sewing room, etc., are given in detail in tables that follow. PLANS FOR THE FUTURE It seems imperative at the rate the institution has been increasing, if the State is to take care of this unfortunate class of her people, that a great deal of building must of necessity be done in the near future. And it is, beyond a doubt, a well established fact that, to take care of this class of unfortunates and have them properly seggregated, is an economical proced - ure on the part of the State, as it has been well shown that a great deal of our crime is caused by the irresponsibility of the individuals committing them. I recommend that it would be for the best interest of the inmates and the work of the institution to have, in addition to our present medical staff, a medical assistant superinten - dent the same as we have at our other institutions and recom - mend that the salary be the same as at the other institutions, $125 per month. I recommend that we have, in addition to our present corps of teachers, one female and one male teacher — the female teacher for grade work and music and the male teacher to assist in the shop work and special vocations. We have, as the tables will show, at the present time a population of 527 children and a waiting list of 32 children we cannot accept. I recommend that a building for the housing of girls be erected to accommodate from 80 to 100 girls. This is imperative as we are refusing applications of girls on account of lack of room. As the only place where we are able to accommodate the helpless children, of which we now have 18 waiting for admit - tance, I recommend that an addition be made to the hospital. In addition to accommodating this class of children, it could be </seg>
            <seg id="p007">134 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF so arranged that we would have two porches where our cases of tuberculosis could be isolated. It is impossible to do this in this institution at this time and yet, it is really very The dining rooms at present are inadequate to accommo - date the children that are here and the kitchen for children is in a very bad condition. It is next to impossible to keep this kitchen and dining room in first class sanitary condition. Besides, it is badly located. I recommend that a children's dining room with a seating capacity of at least 450 children be erected, modern in every way, with the kitchen, bakery and refrigtrator plant adjacent to it. tAs our heating plant has all the work it can possibly do this time and some parts of it are in great need of repair, ecommend that we secure an appropriation to improve this "t of our equipment. The roofs on some of the buildings are in bad condition and leak a great deal during the rainy season. These roofs have been repaired continually and it is going to be necessary before a great while to renew them. I recommend new roofs for these buildings. fAs we are three miles from the railroad station at Beat - i, the transportation of supplies to the institution, including 1, which is one of the largest items, has become a very per - xing problem. A great deal has been said concerning this, ne have insisted that the railroad switch is the most logical 1 best arrangement that could be effected while others are intaining the paved road would be the best solution. With paving, which the city of Beatrice now has, in connection ;h a paving district that has already been formed and which 1 be paved early in the spring, the paving will be brought within one mile of the institution. As the population of the institution is rapidly increasing and as a large dairy herd is a necessity, it would be very advan - tageous from an economical standpoint, as well as to create more industry for our boys, for us to have more land. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD Or COMMISSION ERS 135 Consonant with the foregoing and the ordinary needs of the institution, I make the following recommendations for appropriations : Salary of Superintendent $ 5,000.00 Salary of Assistant Superintendent 3,000.00 Salary of Assistant Physician 1300.00 Salary of Steward 2,400.00 Salary of Matron 1,200.00 Salary of Chaplain 360.00 Wages of Employees, (includes teachers) 45,000.00 Maintenance 138,503.00 Repairs and Improvements 20,000.00 NEW BUILDINGS, IMPROVEMENTS AND EQUIPMENT New Cottage for Girls $40,000.00 Dininjr Room and Kitchen (Children's) 40,000.00 Addition to Hospital 10,000.00 Furniture and Equipment for New Building 10,000.00 New Improvements to Engine Room, (includes wells) 20,000.00 HEALTH OF INSTITUTION The general health of the population of the institution, as the tables will show, has been exceptionally good during the last biennium. There has been no epidemic of any kind and the death rate has really been lower than one would natu- rally expect with this class of inmates. Respectfully submitted D. G. Griffiths. Superintendent. Beatrice, Xebratka, S'ovember SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">136 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF The following work was done during the biennium by the sewing room and the needle work department of the indus- trial classes : SEWING ROOM New Sewing Mending 25 Aprons, band 410 Aprons 6960 Dresses Aprons Gowns 3821 22 dozen Aprons, work 1 dozen Corset covers 11910 7486 Underskirts Undershirts Drawers 152 pair Curtains 6 Couch covers 183 pair Cases, pillow '- dozen Caps, operating 1670 3673 .3656 Combination drawers 2118 Waists 2 dozen Caps, bakers 738 Corset covers 3 dozen Combination suits 18 Clothes sacks 156 Sweaters 328 Bibs 3 dozen Curtains, sash 1874 pair Hose 120 pair Drawers Bonnets 846 Dresses, every day 52 Dresses, Sunday. Corsets Coats 110 Drawers, combination Overalls, men's and 160 Dresses, made over boys 802 pair Elastics Shirts rlO Gowns, night H dozen Gowns, operating Night shirts Undershirts, men's 30 Mangle covers 12 Mens' shirts and boys' Waists, boys' 42 pair Pants, altered for men 6 Shirt waists 613 Combination drawers. boys' 50 dozen Sanitary napkins 20 dozen Sanitary belts 20 dozen Suits, altered for men 780 • Jackets 194 Camisol Camisoles 192 Coats, men's and 1C2 pair Suspenders, overall boys' 401 180 dozen Sheets Pants 40 6 dozen Sofa pillows 13 dozen Towels, roller Vests 296 Sweaters 184 dozen Towels, hand 3 dozen Table cloths 1639 Drawers 1C69 Hose 12 dozen Table runners 12 dozen Table napkins :so Caps 14 pair Gloves 25 pair Shoes 158 Underwaists 440 Underskirts 65 dozen Bibs 42 pair Shoes for girls 310 pair Blankets 2 dozen Camisoles 204 Window shades, 145 dozen Diapers hemmed 80 Clothes sacks </seg>
            <seg id="p010">■ '5 , -* i J e !^ e J i &gt; &lt;! — ■ ■ £ K B E - I '/ - a ■ -j M-a ■ I F ii V. K &lt;N &gt; . V X , - E £ ■3 - - a - •i 1| C &gt; 3 _^_\.J. £sl &gt;: ".^ I I r v - « </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 137 ART DEPARTMENT 6 Sofa cushions 2 pair Bed room slippers 2 Hand woven pillows 15 pair Curtain fasteners I 3 10 Hand woven rugs Tarn O'Shanters 28 Crotcheted yokes 10 yards Bobbin lace Bath towels, crocheted 15 yards Tatting edge 20^ yards Crotcheted lace 23 Guest towels, crotchet- 24 Raffia and reed baskets ed and tatted 7 Raffia and reed vases Emb. bolster slip 1 1 Raffia pillow 14 pair Emb. pillow cases 5 Emb. sheets 1 Reed tray Emb. sheets 1 Chamois, tatting edge Collar and cuff set 1 1 Crotcheted cap I Drawn work lunch 2 Crotcheted bags cloths 1 Emb. library table 2 Crotcheted lunch cloths scarf. 2 Emb. lunch cloths 1 Piano scarf, emb. 3 Tray cloths 2 Crotcheted jackets 16 Emb. Doilies 2 Crotcheted scarfs 2 pair Wristlets 17 Emb cro. and tatted dresser scarfs 1 pair Knit stockings 30 R&gt; Carpet rags 34 dozen Tea towels 20 Table mats I Handkerchiefs 3 Emb. pin cushions FARM AND GARDEN Following is a list of farm products raised on the institu- tion farm during the years 1915 and 1916, these being con- sumed at the institution 1915 1916 Apples 50 bushels 25 bushels Beans 100 bushels 200 bushels Beets 100 bushels 250 bushels Carrots 50 bushels 150 bushels Cucumbers 200 bushels 125 bushels Cabbage 8000 heads 900 heads Cherries 20 bushels 15 bushels Kraut 16 barrels 7 barrels Lettuce 100 heads 200 heads Corn 2000 bushels 1700 bushels Onions, (green) 500 dozen 500 dozen Onions (dry) 150 bushels 300 bushels Potatoes 2000 bushels 1500 bushels Parsnips 100 bushels 75 bushels Peas 75 bushels 75 bushels Peppers 5 bushels 3 bushels Rhubarb 500 dozen bunches 500 dozen bunches Radishes 200 dozen bunches 200 dozen bunches </seg>
            <seg id="p012">138 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Sweet corn 500 bushels 300 bushels Tomatoes 50 bushels 75 bushels Turnips 400 bushels 100 bushels Alfalfa 175 tons 300 tons Corn in ensilage 14 acres Corn cut into shocks 50 shocks 50 shocks OaU 600 bushels 782 bushels Rye 1C bushels 135 bushels Other hay 25 tons 20 tons Straw, oats and rye 20 tons 15 tons Meat and Milk There has been produced on the farm and slaughtered, cattle and hogs, as follows 1915 1916 Hogs ..._ 52 8724 lbs 48 10111 lbs Cattle 10 3455 lbs 3 2C-55 lbs Calves 5 690 lbs Milk 13794 gallons 16116 gallons Utc Stock 1915 1916 Horse. 9 8 Mules : „ 4 4 Dairy cattle 30 37 Heifers - 15 20 Calve. 12 Bulls 2 2 Sows, (brood) 20 16 Boar 1 l Shoats and gilts 49 80 Colt 1 Fruit and Vegetable* (Canned and Preserved) 1915 1916 1916 Green tomato pickle 9 gallons Green tomato pickle 9 gallons Sliced tomato pickle 38 gallons Green tomato pickle (chop) 210 gallons Green tomato pickle Sliced tomato pickle 38 gallons (chop) 210 gallons Mustard cucumber pickle 48 gallons Mustard cucumber Green tomato pickle Green tomato pickle • sliced) 15 gallons pickle 48 gallons (sliced) 15 gallons Salted cucumber pickle. 300 gallons Salted cucumber pickle. 300 gallons Cucumbars salted 400 gallons Cucumbars salted 400 gallons Kraut 750 gallons Kraut 750 gallons Mince meat 50 gallons Mince meat 50 gallons Mince meat 35 gallons Mince meat 35 gallons Aoples, canned 12 quarts Apples, canned 12 quarts Crabapple jelly 65 quarts Crabapple jelly 65 quarts C.icrries, canned 75 quarts C.icrries, canned 75 quarts Watermelon preserves .. 35 quarts E;ermelon preserves .. 35 quarts bapple preserves 74 quarts bapple pickled 28 quarts Apple and crabapple Apple and crabarpple jelly 20 quarts Crabapple preserves 74 quarts jelly 20 quarts Crabapple pickled 28 quarts Strawberry preserve*.... 48 quarts Strawberry preserve*.... 48 quarts G losebcrries, canned (wild) 74 quarts G -&gt;oseb?rries, canned Kraut 400 gallon* Kraut 400 gallon* (wild) 74 quarts Strawberries gathered Strawberries gathered in June 1182 quarts ADples, canned 292 quarts ADples, canned 292 quarts in June 1182 quarts Peaches, canned 40 quarts Peaches, canned 40 quarts </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 139 TABLE I. MOVEMENT ill POPULATION For Year Fur Year eiiiliiij; ending Total Mi v. .'Mi. Nnv. :v, for Mo V KM K NT f..r tins ■M llieiiniuni xl w. t. m. r. t. m. r. t. I'rest'iit at lieginuiiiK 9t jM'i-io.l Ailinitlvd : ■im ■»* 470 :!4tl £&gt;4 470 For tirst time MmhI from parole sjrnnteil Iwfiire &lt;*ollllliellrelllellt '"f [Mriril 4 4 x 4 4 S Total No loiniHi- re&lt;|lliriu» instilutloiiHl ran Tr«nsf*»rreil to other institutions DM &lt; t! 11 17 Hi IS 4. 1 1'nn IpiI .ir on visit h&lt; ihh and not rfturu^fl iluriligr |»ei'iuil 11 ■ J4 11 ■ M Totnl Hi s .14 SI .V.' 4'.» ST &lt;•! UeniMininu ;it eml nf perlu*l. Axtrii^e iiuuilH*r in institutioi I &gt;iscli;i"^p«l vMl oil | arole l :: '.» 4 13 11 5 ig T.ABLK II. AUK OF THOSE \HMII THi F'or Year Fur Year AGE M. F. T M. r. T. ! SI. F. T Tinier ■ ml i :i s ! 4 n r "•"► ami umler 4."V liver V&lt; 1 1 Totals 32 M) 72 \ 43 20 8J I 75 «) 1H 4i) 72 « -o a 73 m vm Is 282 :»», \-4&gt; +:; ■ C1 X£&gt; 288 «n I MMliMr^fil (i I 5 11 li&gt; 7 IT I -' 1 3 -Tc, J.11 M rm 244 4:14 sou •J4&gt;&gt; ."■&lt;»&lt; j.Vi ir-tt; s 1 rmliiix (MiililiK ToUl X. v. .0. Xi.v. .ill. for Mi HUH ltifiiniiim 1 - :i J | I I I ■ H H ■ : 11 17 9 M .-• I n ir. j 17 M S » s 7 ■ I r, i&lt;) 1:1 ■ j- 7 '■' IK U r&gt; 1"&gt; 16 13 3, I iiml ui &lt;!*• r Mi 10 ami iimler l."V 1". tuwl miilfr is. H .-tiul uiMler H. "J-"i ;ii:i1 uiuler 38... </seg>
            <seg id="p014">140 I \Hl.k III. 11X11 KTATIM OF THOSE \liMI I I t 11 Total*. X! 40 72 j 43 a B 75 * M TABLE IV. EI&gt;1« AT1ON OF THO8E ADMITTED DKATION OK THOSK AI1MITTKI) For Year For Year t-iidiiiL' ending Total Nov. :«&gt;, Nt.v. 30, for 1915 1A16 Blennium For Year For Year cndiiiL' ending Total Nov. :«&gt;. Nov. 30, for BDITATKIN for 1«IS li'ir. Blennium U. F. T. It. F. T. M. F. T. \I F. T. I U. F. I. M. F. T, Abl» to rwid and write 7 ■ 12 ! 8 5 IS 16 10 28 7 5 12 8 5 13 15 10 25 l'u»lile to read and write j 2f. ■ «l 35 15 50 00 50 110 Totals XI 4(1 72 43 » IB IS « 13.1 TABLE V. NATIVITY III THOHE \IIVIITKI) For Year For Year ending- ending MM N&lt;t. 30. X.iv. 3(1. for NATIVITY for 1915 ll'lt: : Biennlum U. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Nebraata » 3X « .77 \~, 54 M » 121 Tnited State*, o»*ict than Nrtira.ka. ._ I S 1 4 I 1 618 2 10 Total native Lorn 32 :e" 71 42 18 «0 74 57 131 &lt;^rmany 1 1 1 3 13 4 Totals !■ 441 72 | 43 20 « 75 00 136 1 For Y*«r f ndfng X&lt;iv. 30. Mi For Year (•tilling Nov. 30, MM Total for Hie mil inn CIVIL RTA-n S M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. 1 M F. T. | M F. T. M. F. T. r SEE i 1 Ml 71 1 « It C 7( » ID 1 1 .... 1 1 1 ...... 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 141 TABLK. VI. l'IKKMA(.l: OF THOME UtMI'l TKI&gt; For Year Kor Y'ear rmllliK ••nilini: •".•ml •-..ml PARENTAGE Ntiv.au, Nov. :«&gt;. for f..r l&lt;tl."&gt; ltil« Blrnninm ltll« Bie:iiiiiini M. F. T. H. 7. tT U. V. T m r. t. I u. r. t. m. v. t. hori - IK :» 37 34 19 50 K ■ 1&lt; IS XI .77 :M 1« SO K 5T&gt; W! Koth iiHtiri' don Kitll foreign , :t i ■» ."■ .1 h x 4 5 3 4 4 » • Mixril In known • 6 1 1 • 1 Totals X! 4&lt;i 7.' 4:t 111 ■ T."&gt; MO 15. Total* TABLK VII. (Ul NTV OK KI-IIH.MK OK THOHK INMII I Kli AND OK THOME IBUnOM AT EMI OK BII.VMI H For Ye«r euiliute For Y'ear All ending Total Kt-uiailiiug CUV STY Not. :*■: Nov. :u&gt;. f..r N..v. :m, IMS l'.ui; HIenuluin 191(5 m. r. t. m. r. t. : m. f. t. :.i. r. t Antelo|«e -.- 1 1 4 4 I S .". 10 !• 1- \(| hi ,ij- I 1 ."&gt; « Boyd - 1 1 1 1 Boone 1 1 J 1 1 -1 3 1 4 Hurt ! 1 11 I SIS &gt; I* SI Butler ! 1 1 — 1 15 2 7 KufTiiln ! I 1 1 ir.-t» Box Mutte ■ 1 1 ! 1111 Brown ! 1 Cherry - 2 1 1 :t :l 4 i • Ch&gt; I 1 11 12 s 1 • Colfax 1 1 - 1 13 14 i 'inning Crd.r I :t 1 4 ('lifter _ ' „ J 2 4 (■ 1H8 _ _ S 3 S Cheyenne ' - ' 1 1 Imwwm _ 1 ... I 2 1 J :t 3 5 h Iiixon _ 1 1 2 1 1 2 4 5 9 Ilmine -' 2 2 2 6 3 8 * — ----■■ m ~ — w I.oucla« .. - « S 14, 13 3 16: W 11 .10 » 3« tl Dawea ! ...- -. 1 2 3 I'akota - - — I™ ! ' 213 Immlv ..._ - ' 1 1 Flllmore I 1 2 I - —- \ 1 12 13 3 Fornaa .._ I — | 1 1 1 13 2 5 Franklin _ - - - 5 16 Frontier - I — - j _ 11 «ai«. __ _ 4 4 1 1 2 1 5 • • i*~a ■ 1 (imiff Giirfleld - - i 1 1 Ciarden — . — . 1 1 1 1 1.1 (irtflfv 11 11 2 ■■ Go»per ' I .- 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">142 TABLE VIL fOlXTY OF KK*II»KN&lt; K. OF THOSE A1»IITTE» AMI OK THOME KKM\I\I\&lt;. AT END OK BIKNMI M — i('oni'ludrd) Ktir Y*«r All For Ywr eiiilinu rmllni: enillmr Total Kfiiuiiiiintf COIXTV S»v. mi. Nov. :X&gt;, fur Xnv. :ill. Ml MM l-.ifiiniiiiii Ml corxrv Nov. 30, i:.i.-, SI. r. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. ,1. K. T. M. I . I. Haatttwa 1 1 1 I 1 1 I I 4 ni'i'i' ' ' _ j i f -i i l :i 3 3 « Mall I j l 2 2 1 2 1 :i 3 3 « Howard i 112 1 II 1 1 ."14 :: T llo»iinl 112 1 1 i 1 •"! 4 :: T Hrw !.,,. ilnrl ill - - JrlTerwin 1 11 1 I I « • » j!.| I M n 1 1 1 1 1 1 .l,,l i ., „ 1 1 1 1 1 1 K ,\ 1 1 1 1 :s :i LaJT?« ..Z." ...I] t 7 1 1 « « 12 1" v:i 4J ||, ,^|,, ... II 0 .. i, l 11 1 1 t t - • • y... ri,.|s ■ 1 1 1 1 4 4 s Mo-rll 1 1 ! 1 1 1 — 1 I;I1 _ 2 2 J 4 It: 14 NTit.-kollx 1 - :i 1 2 :s 4 « in 1 1 1 1 ill 1 - ' '■&gt; !•• Hl.-l|.« 1 .... 1 ; 1 1 VWr,-r 1 1 1 112:: I lattr 1 1 1 11 1 2 ."■ 2 7 !•, U 1 1 1 1 1 I lvrkli:» Ptewaaa i •"• l &lt;s IS-.I Wllltiw 4 4 Kilnrilwin j 1 ■ 3 I 1 1 1 • « I 1 • 1 ,. 1 2 3 I 1 1 1 1 • • H Suniilrn ' 1 1 1 _ 12 4 6 li'ntl 1 1 1111 S-v:ir.| 1 1 | 1 1 2 :'. "&gt; Tlmr»t.ii 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 I n ■|l:i,,.r ! 3 1 4 Tl«:ipmi ....• _ _.... 1 1 Vulley 1 1 ■ 1 1 4 1 Wn.hliwtoii 1 1 I 114 1 Wayne 1 1 I 1111 112 112 1 12 3 s _... n r, i .-, « York 2 2 1 1 I 1 2 ■". I! 8 14 State ..._ _ i 1 1 1 1 1 1 Totiiln _ ■ 4O 72 i 43 20 61, 75 CO 1XS 276 25 C(t l.Vi i 27fl !51 S27 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">&lt; r-i si u _ c 1| Ok s i as p* - ■ IE as u &lt; ' is </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 143 TABLE VIII. HEREDITAKV INKLl KN&lt; K For Year ' For Year emlliiK emlitiK Total HKKKIIITAKY IXK1.I F.XCF. \i v. :u&gt;. Nov. mi, fur llil.*, 11. u: Blenuium M. r. T. M. K. T. M. F. T Hereditary mint &lt;lf»ui«Ml w 7 ■ i". I !» 1&lt; 15 3t 41 ■ i". I &gt; 1« i.-i M 41 Hereditary taint denied Father or' tiioiher feeble-minded Fxtlier or' mother feelile niimletl 10 .1 1.1 !&gt; 4 IS lit !• » 1(1 .'• I.'. -.1 4 It 1!) !' 3t :t :i « 7 7 U) 3 ■ ■J 1 :t i" :t .1 4 4 * l 1 1 a &gt; :« S I 4 Father or mother Insane _ Knttitr or mother In Kane :t :i « 7 7 i II) 3 13 Father nr mother fnteni|»er:;t'&gt; Father or mother Intemperate. l :t i" :t .1 1 4 4 l*ar**iitif l»lm»&lt;l relntlous I'arentH blood relations I . | I I I I I &lt; liriindfnther or era ml mother feeble «;raiHlfnth«r or »rraii(1iiM)th**r taMv - inhxlfd niluileil 1 1 | 1 1 1 l ■.: l l 3 Aunts, iinrles, or MH|bj haMI Aunt*, iim-les, or t-ousiiis iiiMiin l l I - 1 l 2 1 1 I - 1 1 Aii nis, nix-les, or «ou si us fp*-l.lr- -uiiiiilfil An nis, niK'lf s. or rotmiti* fp*-ltlf niiinl***! 1 2 3 4 4- • t 1 12 3 4 4- 5 -' 7 I Krntlier «»r si&lt;*ter fwlile-uiliulwi Brut her or sNter feel»le-iiiin«lei| I I I 3 3 - » I |l I I 4 I I I 3 3 3 Broilier «»r Kist»*r hiHMiir Brother «»r Kister insane .1 1 4 3 3 C 4 » 11 • • • • HI 1» Iitkin wn _ I'ukin \vn 4 7 11 .". 3 M » 1« 1» I AHI.K IX. ( OMIITION Of THOHK 1 1 1 -I II X K( . I- 1 1 For Yf«r For Ye«r eiiiliiiK emlhiK Totn! .Nit. .10, .Nov. 30. for Mi Ml Klrnnion Si. F. T. M. r. T. ' M. F. T. Milf-h ini|irovei) 4 1 5 7 tl i:i 11 7 18 Moderately improved Sliirlitly imprt.vei! 1 1 1 • 3 13 1 4 11 -2 -1 3 S I 11 1 in pro veil Insane - .-. 1 «; 7 1 n 1 S I 2 13 Totals H 4 ■ 1". I H a 13 M TABLE X. &lt; XI -K OF DKATH For Ye«r Fur Year M. F. T. If. F. T. XI. F. T. • til 12134 Apoplexy Iiysentery Kpilepsy 1 1 - - 1 1 N 3 11 3 3 8 S 14 Kxhaustiou from heal lienernl iiifei-tion 1 ...... 1 _ __.. 1 _. . 1 1 1 1 _.... 1 Tnlieri'iilosis. pulmonary Cerebral inflaniM4on TulxTcnlosis. lniliiir\ 112 3 14 1 1 1 1 • 6 3 5 8 1 • 3 14 l'eri'-ardltis Iji Krippr... 1 _._. 1 I ._ _ _..._ 1 _... 1 - 1 1 1 1 Total* 20 i m « 11 17 2C IS 42 CONDITION" AT DISClIAlMiK rndlnx vutliug Total X«t. 30, X»v..vi. for Mi Wl« Kipiiniuni CAl'SE &lt;&gt;K HEATH </seg>
            <seg id="p019">144 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XI. PERIOD OF K»IUKM I IN INST1TITIOV OF THOME WHO DIED IIIHIM, BIENNI1 M For Year For Year end'nir ending Total NYv. :t«». Xov. ». for PERIOD OF RKSinENTK f..r V.tl.-i 1916 Bieniihini 3*. r, t. m f. t. u. r. t \jmm tuan our month 1 1 1 1 1 to 8 niotitlii - • to II months I to 1' yea ri- 1 1 1 1 .! 1 1 i :« 1 4 » 3 S I 6 ."» 11 ll to ."&gt; years. 1 4 6 3 9 to 1(1 years. ■ 1 4 a : « i Eo M ymr». it 30 yearK. ■ 31) NHL 1 _ 12 1 »3 1 4 i i :\ i i i 1 1 1 1 2 Tot.iW 9) 5 as ti 11 17 I 26 lti 42 TABU XII. AGE AT DKATH For Year For Year finiinir cniliui; Totnl X&lt;iv. 30. Not. 30, for I'M.", 1916 Biennium AGK M. r. T. If. F. T. M. K. T. M. r. T. If. F. T. M. K. T l»der 10 t 1 1 ' Si • I 4 I and under IV and under 20.... and under 2B... and under :to. nnrt under 3Ti.. and under 40... and uuder 45— and under 90... I 1 1 III 1 4 ail i si n l it I !&gt; 1 1 tl M 1 11 :i .114 2 13 5 2 7 1 4 18 5 2 7 1 S 5 3 H :: :t -• .-. i 1 3 S 3 H I 1 3 i 2 :t | 1 :s I 1 | I 3 11 4 ."&gt; 1 1 i 1 J - 1 1 1 1 I 1 3 3 1 4 1 1 ' 1 1 1 1 1 1 Totals 30 ■ 28 A 11 17 2)1 1« m </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 145 TABLE Mil AVERJIUF. MUBI.R €&gt;F PAT1ICNTS KMPLOYKD Average Number Employed ■ — Average Per «'eat In Outside Population Kmplojrcd TKItlOD Ward Ward Aggregate M. r. T. M. r. T. M. K. T. M. V T. M. 9. T IMirlni.' year ■Mm Nov. :to. Ml ¥&gt; m •■*&lt; M m l'« 11"&gt; ■' 1» •-••*&gt;&lt;&gt; M 494 44 B During y«ar rndlOK Nov. 30. l!&gt;lrt 4:i m '.« 71 T7 1U' 11&gt;&gt; -7 -•&lt;■-■. 2»&gt; J4.&gt;( S«)H 4« .16 Averages fur t.iennliim 4-.' 50 9l&gt; 75 .V. 110 lit; &lt;, &gt;tn 2K&gt; L'4f. 301 4« M TABLE XIV. Kllll) OF EHri.»YKK8 TO I'ATIKM s TABLE XIV. K\ I in Of EXPI.OYKK!) TO PATIENTH I m r. t m r t NiiiiiIht of pfayitiolanH, inoltnlintc superintendent I lit NuuilM»r of ptiysiriuns, inoltnlintc superintendent 1 1 ■Mia nf ph.vsiriaiiH to patients _ 1 :i"o Ratio nf ith.vsiriaiiH to patients 1 M~*&gt; Niiinl.t-r of iiurwa and wanl attrmlant* (day) ..„ _ _ i » 14 N*uiiil»t»r of nuriteif and ward attendants iday» „ „ 5 9 Itiiti" of «me tn patients 1 :3H Itiiti.. ..f *anie to patientit 1 :3fl Numlier of nurses and ward attendant* (night).. _ 1 5 • Numlier of nurses and ward attendants (nlghti. _ „ 1 5 Untio of siime tn patients 1 :-il Kutio of »nme to patients 1 :*4 Total ilny Mini niulit nurses aud ward attendant* _ _ • 14 Totsil ilay iiik) niu'lit nurses and ward attendants _ _ „ 6 14 W Hiitlii nf same to patients ..._ 1:38 Total nttl&lt;*ern and employees _ 2J 51 Kiitin of same to patients. _ 1 :!•» </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>