<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Board of Health BULLETIN NUMBER TWO JANUARY 8, 1913</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">{ BULLETIN DUMBER VIVO January 8, 1913 OFFICERS OF THE STATE BOARD BOARD OF SECRETARIES H. B. Cummins, President, Seward, Nebraska. E. Arthur Carr, Vice-President, Lincoln, Nebraska. P. F. Dodson, Treasurer, Wilber, Nebraska. C. P. Fall, Secretary, Beatrice, Nebraska. rEX-OFFICIO OFFICERS H. Morehead, Governor. Grant G. Martin, Attorney General. J. E. Delzell, Supt. of Public Instruction. W. H. Wilson, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln, Nebr. The CUflln Printing Company. f^^^^^ University PUca, M«br. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 Nbkaska State Board of Health STATE BOARD OF HEALTH tThe above title in our statute books is used so broadly that confusing to the people of the state, in so far as it in - es not only the Medical Board of Health, but the Pharmacy rd, the Dental Board, the Osteopathy Board, the Veterinary rd, the Pure Food Commission and the Labor Commission. Many letters of inquiry are received by the secretary of one board that belong to the other and for elucidation the fol - lowing information is given; correspondence should be had with the secretaries of the board which for the present time are as follows : C. P. Fall, Secretary State Board of Health, Beatrice, Neb. J. S. Pierce, Secretary Dental Board, Lincoln, Neb. D. J. Killen, Secretary Pharmacy Board, Beatrice, Neb. W. H. Tuck, Secretary Veterinary Board, Weeping Water, W. M. Hill, Secretary Embalmers Board, Hebron, Nebr. C. B. Atzen, Secretary Osteopathic Board, N. Y. Life Bldg., Omaha. QUESTION FREQUENTLY ASKED THE STATE BOARD IThe Secretary is frequently asked for laws, rules and reg - ions of the State Board of Heanh. There are two printed is, regulations for the quarantine, care and disinfection of agious diseases and rules for reporting births and deaths, se printed rules and regulations are, for the most part, in hands of the State Health Inspector, who has the super - m of this part of the work for the State Board of Health, other laws, rules and regulations are, for the most part, in hands of the Secretary and refers mainly to the medical \ regulating the practice of medicine, examinations and procity. IThe Secretary is frequently asked if chiropractors are duly ised in this state. The following opinion on this matter is 1 the Attorney General's office : </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Annual Bulletin No. 2 3 ATTORNEY GENERAL'S OPINION The legislature of Nebraska, in a law enacted in 1891 and in force ever since, has said : I "Any person shall be regarded as practicing medicine hin the meaning of this act who shall operate on, profess to .1, or prescribe for, or otherwise treat, any physical or men - ailment of another." (Cobbey's Annotated Statutes of 1911, tion 9815.) tin two cases which interpret this law, the supreme court apparently answered your question completely. In the of State vs. Buswell, 40 Nebr. 158, the court said that a 3tian science practitioner was violating the law when he ended to treat the physical and mental ailments of people, lout securing a license from the state board of health. The t held in that case : t'The object of the statute establishing a state board of th, etc., is to prevent imposition upon the afflicted by rant and unqualified pretenders to healing power ; and any on not within the exceptions prescribed in said act, and having complied with its requirements as to a certificate shall under any pretense operate on, profess to heal, or cribe for, or otherwise treat any physical or mental ail - t of another, thereby renders himself liable to its pen- In Little vs. State, 60 Nebr. 749, Charles W. Little an osteopath, was prosecuted and convicted of practicing medi - cine without a license. In the decision in that case the court says that it is entirely satisfied with the former decision in the Buswell case. Osteopathy was declared to be the practice of medicine, as defined by the legislature, and before it could be practiced in this state a state license must be secured. The object of the statute, as declared by the court in the Little case, was to regulate the practice of healing, and one who pro - fessed to prescribe, treat, or heal, physical or mental ailments of mankind must secure a state license before he can practice. t Since the decision of the court in the Little case, the letris - re has provided for the examination and licensing of jopaths. (Cobbey's Annotated Statutes of 1911, sec. 9923 section following.) It has been claimed that the practice </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska State Board of Health Practic is similar to that of osteopathy and that the :tor treats ailing patients on the same theory as an i. Some osteopaths have insisted that chiropractors e required to have the qualifications necessary for osteopaths in this state before being permitted to by reason of the similarity in their methods of treat- The advertisement of this chiropractor, enclosed in your letter, states that he makes bone setting a specialty, and that he sets fractures or dislocations. He slates that his price for these treatments is reasonable. This practice is clearly within the letter and the spirit of the definition of practicing medicine in this state. He clearly professes to heal, treat, and operate on people who are suffering from broken bones or dislocations. The fact that he advertises to use neither drugs, knives, rub - bing or massage, and that he calls himself a chiropractor in - stead of a physician is not material. I By professing to heal, and by operating upon ailing per - sons, he is practicing medicine as defined by the laws of this state. Before he can legally practice in this\nanner, he must secure a license from the state board of health. After secur - ing a license and showing his knowledge and efficiency, it is immaterial to the state what school of healing he shall follow. The state has certain educational requirements, and it de - mands knowledge of the human system and of the diseases the flesh is heir to. After having such preparation, and after hav - ing secured such knowledge, and after successfully passing the examination required by the law, a man may practice the art of healing as he chooses, but, before he has attained this proficiency and knowledge, and before he has secured this li - cense, he cannot legally practice the art of healing in this state " RAILROAD SANITATION An effort has been made by the Board to obtain informa - tion from the railroads of the state regarding ice and water supply for drinking purposes used on trains in running through the state. The different railroads were asked to file with this Board the source of the water and ice supply for </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Annual Bulletin No. 2 5 drinking: purposes and have responded promptly and willing - ly to the request. The ice not being used at all times for cool - ing purposes may be the source of considerable danger. It is a well known fact that ice secured from streams is more liable to be free from deleterious germs than ice secured from still water, viz : lakes and ponds. In many of the reports we notice that the ice supply is from lakes and ponds and that railroad companies should be requested to secure their ice used on trains other than for icing refrigerator cars from other sources such as from running streams or manufactured ice. Many localities as well as railroads are obtaining ice from pools and are careless about the water supply for domestic purposes. The water supply in these pools is often times con - taminated with sewage and it is to be hoped that the coming legislature will provide the Board with a Sanitary Engineer which will give the Board necessary information with power to regulate these matters. health conference of the local Boards of Health of the ; would do much to educate the people in sanitary laws. The railroads of the state have shown an unusual willing - ness to comply with reasonable rules and regulations that the Board may adopt as a result of their report now in the hands of the Board, ready for some form of action. TUBERCULOSIS The State undoubtedly needs some legislation along the line of prevention of tuberculosis, as is clearly defined in the following opinion written by the County Attorney of Gage County, the result of a local condition existing in the county at the present time. "Replying to your communication of recent date, in which you say that a child who is now attending a country school in the vicinity of Odell is afflicted with tuberculosis, and in which you ask for an opinion as to whether or not the local board of health of the village of Odell has the power to prevent this child from attending the public school in the school district where it resides with its parents, for the reason that it is so afflicted, will say, that while under the law of Nebraska the local board </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska State Board of Health distance of 5 miles beyond its corporate limits, and a city having a population of from 5,000 to 25,000 may by ordinance confer jurisdiction on its board of health for a distance of 2 miles beyond its corporate limits, the local board of health of a village such as Odell only has jurisdiction within the corporate limits of such village. The country school district to which you refer, being, as I understand it, outside of the corporate limits of the village of Odell, is under the jurisdiction of the County . d of Health, and in the absence of a County Board of Health, it is under the jurisdiction cf the County hoHrd of Supervisors. In case of contagious disease in such school, the same should be reported by the teacher of the school to the County Board of Supervisors. It is then a question for the County Board to determine, after proper investigation, wheth - er the case so reported should be isolated or quarantined. After a careful examination of the law of the state relative to the public health, and the rules and regulations of the State Board of Health, it is my opinion that neither the County Board, or any Board of Health, has the power to legally exclude from the public schools children of school age, for the only reason that they are afflicted with tuberculosis. It is within the power of the legislature to enact a law excluding such children from the public schools, provided that the legislature at the same time makes provision for the separate education of children so afflicted, at the public expense. Such a law would be a wise, and, it seems to me, a necessary provision for the protection of the health of school children. In the case under considera - tion the County Board might require that the afflicted child be isolated in a certain part of the room, while present in attend - ance at school ; that it be required to use a separate drinking cup ; that no other children be permitted to use or handle books, papers, slates and pencils used by it, and that its parents be required to keep it in a clean and neat condition. t Trusting that I have fully answered your questions, and the matter under consideration may be satisfactorily ad - »d, I am, Yours very truly, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Annual Bulletin No. 2 7 rNEED OF VITAL STATISTICS AND THEIR RELA - TION TO PUBLIC HEALTH This country which in most things is a leader among the nations of the earth, has been signally slow in recognizing the need and importance of vital statistics, but little systematic general work having been done along this line until within the past few years, while the system has long been hoary with age in many of the countries of Europe. Happily, however our national government and many of the states have at last awak - ened to the need and desirability of a complete and systematic recording and compilation of all births and deaths. Yet, while this is true, it is also being found true that vast numbers of our people do not at once grasp the reasons for or the im - portance of such work ; having not been educated along those lines they sometimes seem disposed to regard it as a needless innovation interfering with personal and private affairs, when the facts are that the primary need and good is for the indi - vidual, the family, and in a general way the public. Every child born into the world is as much entitled to have a legal and permanent record made of its birth as it is to any other of its birthrights. This may be of immense value to it at some future time in life in the matter of establishing its rights to the inheritance of property, and this is forcibly brought out where the inheritance is to property of a deceased relative in a foreign country ; in fact, in some of those cases the family record, even if there be something of the kind, is wholly inadequate as proof and little short of a certified copy of a birth certificate will suffice. Birth records are valuable in facilitating the establishment of legitimacy, in settling the - child's status as to school age, in exercising the right of suf - frage, the employment of children in factories, the status of the individual's responsibility for crime, exemptions from mili - tary service and jury service, and the settlement of legal diffi - culties generally ; in fact, all along the journey of life one may By W. H. Wilson, M. D., Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska State Board of Health 8 suddenly and unexpectedly be confronted with the need of a certified copy of his birth and which he can only obtain if the legal record has been made of it at the time of birth. The need for and the benefit of birth registration will become more and more apparent and appreciated as it becomes better under - stood and nearer universally adopted. Another time when the individual should be officially re - corded, and that without fail, is when time for him has ended and he must be recorded among the dead, that a proper ac - counting may be made in regard to him. It is becoming very difficult to establish the right to pension of deceased persons without the claimant can produce a certified copy of a standard death certificate of the deceased, and this can only be had with any degree of certainty by requiring the recording- of all deaths. What is true of pension claims applies with equal force in the matter of proofs for insurance claims, in settling per - sonal liability claims, and the adjustment of many legal ques - tions that may arise, all of which require indisputable legal proof of death and which can be often only readily obtained where the state has required the making of a permanent rec - ord of deaths. tThus it seems that it should be apparent to all who will the subject a reasonable amount of thought and study vital statistics, the recording and tabulating of all births deaths, marriages and divorces, constitute the most im - ant events in the history of the race, therefore should elicit hearty co-operation of all in their collection and compila - . A careful analysis of such records will serve as a sub - tial guide to the study of the sociologist in arriving at ething like correct conclusions as to the impelling forces at k among mankind. A study of history gives a knowledge of the general activi - ties of those who have gone before, while vital statistics are an index of the essential changes going on at present and in our midst. A systematic study of which will help to determine causes in relation to effects and moreover when a potent cause is disclosed, a policy of action may more readily be devised which will either enhance or retard such cause. A case in point is that of France, wherein her vital statistics revealed the </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Annual Bulletin No. 2 9 fact that her death rate was equaling and at times even sur - passing the birth rate. The government became alarmed at the findings, recognizing the fact that to permit such conditions to long continue would mean but one thing, namely, the ex - termination of the French people. To avert such a calamity, vigorous efforts are being put forth to lessen the death rate and especially to check the heavy infant mortality; also to encourage the rearing of children. The lives and health of the people are recognized by our greatest leaders as a nation's most valuable asset; how important then that we should zealously safeguard such asset, and as a chief aid to this end how neces - sary to have a ready, reliable record such as vital statistics to refer to, that intelligent information may be had as to the con - dition of this great asset, and yet, how slow have our people been in recognizing this. The medical profession, not only of this country, but of the civilized world, have at last awakened to the fact that it is vastly more beneficial to mankind to prevent disease than to attempt to cure it, and this was forcibly emphasized by the great International Congress on Hygiene and Demography so recently held at Washington, D. C, where large delegations of the foremost medical scientists and sanitarians from some thirty-three leading nations of the earth deliberated for a week on subjects of sanitation, vital statistics and such other ways and means as would tend to prevent disease, suffering and death. In all efforts looking to successfully preventing and combating of disease, it can thus be seen that such efforts may be greatly facilitated by having ready access to complete rec - ords of all births and deaths, the causes of all deaths and the records of contagious and infectious diseases. Indeed, without such records, the worker is almost as handicapped as is the mariner at Sea without a compass, for such records form the basis and point out the way for preventive medicine. A highly important subject, that of infant mortality, is receiving world wide attention at this time. The government of the United States, in keeping with this world wide move - ment, is endeavoring to ascertain through the census bureau and public health service why 300,000 babies die yearly in this country. It is true that the lack of anything like complete rec- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska State Board of Health ords make the foregoing named number really only an esti - mate, but at best the death rate of infants under one year of age in this country is appalling. A complete record would be of great value to the government through the governmental de - partments in the study of this all important subject. Recently an association called the American Association for the Study and Prevention of Infant Mortality has been formed and is actively working in nearly all the large cities of this country. It must be obvious that records of all births and deaths and the cause of deaths would be exceedingly valuable to this associa - tion in making its work most effective. §This article is already becoming too long, but in conclusion hoped that enough has been said to convince those who read it of the need and value of vital statistics. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Annual Bulletin No. 2 11 i 3 ■ : ; 3 i * DH-i«n«a«annn«xg&gt;«oi - i - d o x « M PI •• « ; • « fl • •. 1 1 I I j i i yj r J • ■ — . •c - i c a I i at a; C _ ;■"■"■ " m ~" is J S " s S 5 § § 1 8 i I § s rsTHTSTTa 1 1 M M 1 I j I i n^ S 2 i si-'isiaititlllildllklli* £ CO — _0) 3 I g£ B :5SSSSJSKS?g8-J8S2S8S2 N — — M « -. - « Z -H n m _ 0 31 j ifliiiilliiiiilliilllih &lt;&lt;nnn(sncqnpgnuuuuc)uuouQQQQ </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska State Board of Health | — «0 c oj ■•: t- tr- r &lt;o : n « !•••••• t o r- — ri 1 I I I 4 03 a I ! i : ' ; M "'" r" i r r - - c 5 3 8 iS: H8 « H ! [ • S 5^ ♦» u •" iS" | _' Hi i 1 rn «, ■ 2S|'5S2*"S**'- j^SSS-'a :S?S I o-*-r-*r--*«P!B5r- — &lt;£&gt;-:i- -&gt;oi- r--- n»o :i « m « « — - c. H m — — ;. -•- ! « I s t i is ! m g ; ih : ill"*! m — » &lt;e • a &lt;e t--»&lt;c&lt;co&gt;o-ri~«co&gt;w» &gt;- n n « nc««eir-&lt;c — r-eac — A Mfii-eaoii'- ■om r: n cm: SI vhocoo m ci SS - ■ 3 Sj « h « - - t o t i- • « • » » » " » e '"• - 19 «c-. ni~»oiNOC-r — r: o&gt; rt -r — m ■«■ &gt;O O «■ ■ It 1 t I I I I : I i ft II t It lit ill lit lilt t f t if I ft ff.ffl itil I I f I I I t f I I I t 1 I I I i I ; I : : ■::::::::::::: :i: i i i fitjliiilllitjilliilijj </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Annual Bulletin No. 2 13 ' J i - .c o n tut 6 2 — o z c I - •c m _ i i L_LJ j j S w ";j» ;■; ■•'-' "HF ■ o « « - n &lt;= - « - e I D _ " " -j | s s *■ N Pa - - - „ K « „ :-.,„«■ &lt; _« s i i rniirniiiii ".n i i i L MM 111 111 m I "3 p I l* a " &gt; 5IS* i: '*25*3|2!$"9 WfWi 8 I "a S5""S|S23«g SSg8§s;22gSJ8 J j m I i I i I I I fill i !l | till! ill if If i f Jf </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska State Board of Health j is*s" IT i c. I 5! 8 « | e* j : — C* ; H « CO r -■ a i CO*-iMM» ! « »H W ! '• :«t I i ; i I •&lt; «« *■ m' «■ i 09 ! 10^ j I i 4 c n I I o *-« ei S — — e* Beo : m m n n o : »• ;i o c &lt;s at&gt; n '•&gt; «h ia m &lt;H oe~e &lt;e a~c e~ m*"s&gt; &lt;- I &lt; s -ii I n 1 1 1 1 n" 1 ntrn Mi! : i i M M I I ill! I I I I 1 I i Mill! 2 J S 5 ff g "8 ~S £ S S S 8 § 8 B §5 S SS ~8 8 I I 1 nnHdhMflicfottciaHoiioi-oaio CO 8 -^ 9 — »n Oi O 00 r&gt;, at r- 9 W «* O *- v4 v3 I 1 1 1 ! 1 1 1 i 1 1 1 ! rm I II II s ! &gt;g i ! ! i 1 I ! iilliliiliiliJlillli ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Annual Bulletin No. 2 DEATHS FKOM DEC. 1, 1911 TO DEC. 1, 191!. TvrHriid fever... Smallpox — Measles _ _ Scarlet fever _ Whooping cough „ Diphtheria _ ~ _ Influenza _ „ Dysentery _ Erysipelas Other epidemic diseases. Purulent infection and septichaemia _ Tetanus _ * _ Mycoses - Tuberculosis of the lungs _ _ _ Tuberculous meningitis _ _ Tuberculosis of other organs _ _ Syphilis Cancer of liver, stomach _ Cancer perpitonaeum, intestines, rectum Cancer of female genital organs _ Cancer of the breast - „ _ _ Cancer of other parts Other tumors - - Acute rheumatism _. Chronic rheumatism _ Diabetes _ _ Exophthalmic goitre. Addison's disease. _ Leuchaemia _ _ Anaemia, chlrosis _ „ Alcoholism _ Meningitis _ Locomotor a taxi a „ Other diseases of the spinal cord. _ _ Cerebral hemorrhage, apoplexy _ Softening of the lira in Paralysis without specified cause. General paralysis of the insane Other forms of mental alienation. _ Convulsions Epilepsy Pericarditis ~ - ..., Acute enaocaroius ■ ! </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska State Board or Health DEATHS FROM DEC. 1, 1811 to DEC. 1, 1918— Continued. Organic diseases of the heart _ _ _. — 866 Angina pec tori s 53 Diseases of the arteries. - - 111 Embolism and thrombosis 36 Diseases of the veins, verices, etc _ S Diseases of the lymphatic system _ S Diseases of the nose and throat _ 3 Bronchitis, acute 51 Bronchitis, chronic 37 Bronchopneumonia ~ 161 Pneumonia - - 726 Pleurisv * _ 18 Pulmonary congestion.., 54 Asthma .... _ 64 Pulmonary emphysema _ 5 Diseases of the oesophagus _ _ ". 2 Ulcer of stomach 30 Other diseases of stomach (cancer excepted) : 125 Diarrhoea and enteritis (under 2 years) _... 185 Diarrhoea and enteritis (2 years and over) _ 57 Appendicitis .. . _ 151 Hernia, intestinal obstruction 133 Other diseases of the intestine 1 - 37 Cirrhosis of the liver : 74 Biliary calculi 7 Other diseases of the liver _ _ 105 Diseases of the spleen _ t Simple peritonitis _ 48 Other diseases of the digestive system 6 Acute nephritis 37 B right's disease 535 Other disease of the kidneys and annexa 44 Diseases of the bladder.... _ _ 19 Diseases of the prostate _ 36 Diseases of the uterus (non-cancerous) 27 Cysts and other tumors of the ovary T Salpingitis and other diseases of the female genital organs. 10 Accidents of pregnancy ~ - _________ 50 Puerperal hemorrhage. 26 Other accidents of labor - 34 Puerperal septichaemia _ _ _ 48 Puerperal albuminuria and convulsions _ • Gangrene ' Acute Diseases of the bones (tuerculosis excepted) Congenital debility, icterus, sclerema, etc 1138 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Annual Bulletin No. 2 17 DEATHS PROM DEC. 1, 1911 to DEC. 1, 191»— Continued. Senility •z Suicide by poii -»--- Suicide by hanging _ - 31 Suicide by firearms - Suicide by other means..- — &gt;0 Accidental poisoning 38 Accidental drowning _ 57 Burns _ — Traumatism by firearms _ Traumatism by machines — Traumatism by railways, vehicles, etc_ Injuries by animals - Starvation Excessive cold Excessive heat Lightning Homicides — ~— - • -— - — —— — — . Other external violence ~ No cause Stillborn — Other diseases of the nervous system Ill-defined cause. ~ - Diseases of larynx Other diseases of respiratory system Malaria fever _ Electricity (lightning excepted) Ill-defined organic diseases Encephaltis ~ Other general diseases Stung by swarm of bees _ _ _ Acute poisonings Diseases of the thyreoid body Furuncle Diseases of the skin and annexa DicpacAc of oharvnx •• . — ~ Poisoning by food - — Chorea Disease of ear — Other chronic poi sonings — — Chloroform narcosis. Pellagra — '1 » i 10 ■ 11 ■ 1 - 3 • 1 ■ « </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska State Boakd of Health i | 5 O« ■v*n:i^«o«r-c -^^&gt;9«M««aMMM I I m 1 1 1 1 r i h i 1 1 m ! ill ! i i i i &lt; ill LJ i Mi M II 1 i [ I ill i K ■s s "H r »h M ; ih : x : ■«■ I w* « I 1 X ■H I ] - 1 I I i ! t I I I * i I • w* I I i LJ " " I I" I"* I" J - ill M i rf : j i 5 i i i j I j I j : TTMl I ■ ft s \~~ I" I !** !"" ! !" i : [III a O i ! ~ II i 1 i LJJ III Mi I 1 111 11! f £ I I Ml Mi" : 8 I. I I ;■;■■• i i ■ i i i 1 ! M i j"! 9" " i 122 i i""5 M I HIM 111 II II I S I i ! ! i „ i I II liii;iilt{iiitliifilii </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Annual Bulletin No. 2 19 » g I I J ift *o •• w J 3C SS " i m m m A 2 a 1 •8 S — — cjm ;«««;»(» m — :iH ; n y 'c i a, I I • • I I «4 I I j I •jj;^; |"| i rt ; ! rt i ! rf v4 ) : : : : : I Mil i 1 H^i • i I I I ■8 5 o r" ! "* M 1 i " 1 1 MM |« I ■ ** £ •s 5 : « I • ; h j at mm: 1 j &amp; i ■ | "3 CO M|||||||M| c t • "* ! ! " j : w* rt I I I I I I I I I I I I I I mi mil in l||j||jj]||ljg I i I i MM it]J a a ._ o XXXX , </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 N, State Boabd of Health I "8 a •SMiHOgU I m * {««mr-«&lt;-t««e&gt;M«»&lt;-i i 2 £ " I" I III II I C I H s ii i — — : m ct " *- — e* : : ••:••••: ; : I ! ! : I • i : - | - • | j ft » ;•' I ; „ ; : X J C i ch c. e» I x m • ! ir " : : i - :-. r: - i ||« r-- i : ! : I I i r s s 5 -- ■ m j . r- n ; »h t v4 ; : N H : z a i a •o : : ih o&gt; : ! :ii : : • . o &lt;o i-c « m : H! : g 1 ■8 5 || J i i [I I mm I t-io : ■* " "g :«e PS i I m ** ■ III ■*-■ |s m - -• : a : : : : : : : : : : « • tH : n ei ee ; | w : § : ' iiiiOo: iJSJJliiilllJjlfJisSJi </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Annual Bulletin No. 2 21 V. ■s o I I csomm- ;- | ♦ « - -r r-. m - I OS 1 i ♦ i I I I j I ■ ! | j - ci — — — - « n ti - I | 'S i ■d I 1 1 i i i»" I : :::::: : :::::: i j i « ri N ••«*«•• j j "" * 'X j u a : : *H : i M M I 1 i u -- i ■ 1 I -r ■ m ** j ; « ~ '&lt;-) | f4 I j I I ! § 1 1 i * S ! • j •■ ! i " " S ! g -- x c &amp; . — I S i : :::: i ::;:;:: i 1 I 1 i 1 MM O J ; i i : i i ; 5 n i u ! mi i i i i i ! ! i : i « Me! H </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska State Boakd of Health REPORT OF MARRIAGES— 1911 County Adams Antelope „ _ ________ 1M Banner 2 Blaine _ 9 Boone ______ _ „ .•. 51 Boyd _ 58 Brown „ 80 Buffalo _ SM Burt 83 Butler 107 Cass LSI Cedar 109 Chase _ 29 Cheyenne 113 Clay 112 Colfax 1 91 Cuming _____ 135 Custer _.. 182 Dakota 184 Dawes - 99 Dawson - 117 Deuel 8 Dixon 61 Dodge _ 2S3 Douglas 2132 Dundy 32 Fillmore _ _ 132 Franklin _ 91 Frontier _ _ i 53 Furnas __ __ 58 Gage _ 250 Garfield _ „ 31 Gosper 34 Grant 16 Greeley 63 .-. Hall 319 Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock _ Holt _ Hooker Howard Jefferson _ _. Hamilton 113 Harlan , 96 Hayes _ 15 Hitchcock 31 Holt _ 129 Hooker _ _ 16 Howard , 92 Jefferson _ 169 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Annual Bulletin No. 2 23 Richardson „ 180 lock _ 29 ialine 137 . 137 larpy SO t *** ~— •— — - ~* •*** launders 145 icotts Bluff _ 78 Jeward 136 Sheridan T9 Iherman 71 iioux _ 40 78 m : itanton 74 'hayer 119 33 _ „ 80 /alley _ „ 90 Vashington M Vayne 109 Vebster 99 Vheeler _ _ 8 fork . . 184 74 m » . •0 : Total 11400 REPORT OF MARRIAGES— 1911— Continued Kearney 66 Keith „ » Madison 127 Merriclc 100 Morrill 40 Nance 90 Nemaha 137 Nuckolls 123 Otoe „ _ 180 Pawnee _ 99 Perkins „ 26 Phelps .-.._ 98 Pierce 108 Platte Polk 71 Red Willow 113 teya Paha Cimball Cnox _ „ .ancaster ;. -incoln __ _ : -ogan *oup icPherson </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska State Board of Health » m : — i» : • m s - 6 m n j-4 I v m a a a m ih : : ■» "S pSSSlLUSIQ ? z • a j |HH »• i : N : :e)fH I :M Aaaiinpv • ! -uaipinja • •rinahsaacx ; m « A «tl I ?; A»t»tUO tt tJX ot S ri \ ti^ Ot « -SJX eg is U or- — n b r r o :ooon .- n ci » e i- P a -«JX 01 I ! ■sjX s •sjX z ? I f m ■♦ ih : : m V(l r - 8 5 ;::; e :; i ::::::::,:: ■•llfi : ! : : : :;«): I| S |"J til l.kt^l !s*s •f«i||T]^pQ[T^[WWpf)[ftnnr)Qfjrjrjr\fj 1 ""5*3»"*S*"'"""*3S !.h !H»«t-iat*i«mr4n : n a n h o e »joddns "* j |" | -••« | ; j --- |-- cm « © s :« : t n -■ -« co m !•• CO • CO CO ! ! M W M 9 r* i j««-a«-«««--*«'-*« </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Annual Bulletin No. 2 25 i ! •SJX c» •sjX o» •a en : x R II CO 04 | I c M &gt;o m m t- s? »• « •• 5 -sjx oi a "S -SJA 9 M • N M OD « i-"n h « « i : h : ; a a n n n a &lt;= g ; » « «* --•- j •} • • O s ! oo N Tiua c o : i : i ! ■ : ■ : ■ • : I • • : a : passiuisja Z 5 5~&gt;i i : h h » i i tri«4 : ii ih :»•••&gt; " jaoddns I -uon | ; j j ; j | ssau I • 1 q -ua^unjQ » a ci « | : &lt;-i &lt;o p </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska State Board of Health c I luipuaj passiuisiQ paiUBJQ Suipuaj " r r" i i £ i j " j ; js j is - j pn j^ssa"*"- 1 "* 2 t s - " 2 *' * « s Xjajjnpy TeTS I I n m i &lt;o t&gt; « : : m « m P«r 1 | : : ! : : i E I c 1 I UOI}J3S3Q uoddns ■uox 14 M 4 « « h : j" S - : « : i SS3U • : f« n h « h : h oo * Mi! ill f •• •« n » m i «- X»i9ruo l.r-11-": •sjX st : ; ** ■ •* i •«JX ot • • • ! ■ llllii m M! rt I •«JX S2 I ** • I • ■• ii ia rt iHiHiirt ■o tax ot --- - --- !--■- |S % •SJX S 11 j-«8» ■ °° |* ••aXj - O c &lt;r. c&gt; — - - -r g c - jS N I-*" -T-n •a ; ra : ! 5 ; ! I I i D 8 M M MM i i 1 ! i i I ■III ! j I ' I I I I I I I • •-oo«-g«S«.5c5i=o2c»5;oSt i </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Annual Bulletin No. 2 27 &lt;5 I_ passiiusiQ P C I : : : . l | • ■ Z | ♦ • ♦ t- :- W m«»-,, ■« _ -_; _ _ * £ UOti-I3S3Q ! Me. «;. at ~ m ~ - i-c:^ ssau (3 , -ua^unjQ 5 io oti«ci««ocrt-i-rMrt ra i AjianjQ •sja Bt W : rt i M r&lt; ; : « •sjX Of I MO : IH M m *h ih vh m w m i •SJA •sja' s « O « — N * C ! &lt;C C^ C) 00 « 00 «5 — « — — ct T 'SJA r M M •^"11 i ■ !« ' ! I M | j i 'J I ' I I I |« j« ■• ■• l ]!■«« « et : - - , 1 *** "° : •" *" *° i j~« '■ « &lt;o h h » n T~?T"w uotfdM " ; " • " " ---'—-*-- | - j "o -uo\- I v ! : i Cl a M on « » n f: n :i !• «44 A Ax t « SJA t . , </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nbkaska State Board of Health I • ■ : - Suipuaj » — a — 'o passiuisiQ PSSSILUSIQ * ----- o&gt; a Xjai[npv i i **** a — i 5 s uoi;jas3Q "° rt " I c r i I SS9U • 1 I I • I . j j j-j _ - r. B 9 -. O 5 ■ jjijMi E a -. ■saX « 9 E a a IJX OX °° " :i n - o M I ! •saX S j " | - ■ S •sjX g rt c •t"n 111; MM i ! ; i c i liifij ! 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Annual Bulletin No. 2 29 DIVORCES— 1911 County Adams _ 48 Antelope 16 Blaine ' 2 Boone _ 4 Box Butte 12 Boyd 10 Brown .... 14 Buffalo 53 Burt , 10 Butler 15 Cass 24 Cedar 4 Chase _ 3 Cherry „ 11 Dundy ,. 3 9 3 3 11 6 3 1 Hall 39. Hamilton „ _ &gt; jo Harlan 10 Hayes .. 1 Hitchcock 4 Holt _ 22 Howard „ _ _ u Jefferson .. lg 'heyenne Hay !olfax 'uming _ _ 'uster ... )akota )awes )awson _ )euel Hxon )odge _ )ouglas .._ _ _ ! lllmore 'ranklin Von tier "urn as rage 1-arden _ _ _ rarfield rosper „ ireeley </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska State Board of Health 30 REPORT OF MARRIAGES— 1911— Continued Johnson ♦ KcArncv - ...— ■ . lft Keith Kimball 4 Knox _ 13 Merrick — - 4 Mnrrill 4 Xancc 2 n 6 0 T 10 n 4 II Richardson _ 14 Rock _ 7 Saline _ _ 19 Sarpy _ _ 16 Saunders _ 22 Scotts Bluff !... 12 Seward _ 15 Sheridan _. 16 Sherman 6 Sioux ; 6 Stanton 5 Thayer 12 Washington 4 Wavne B Webster .._ 11 .in coin - - ■: /Ogan ~ &gt;oup -.- ladison ~ i &gt;toe - - 'awnee Vrkins : •helps *ierce — •lattt _„ _ &gt;olk _ _ „ j_j Tt*:n </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 SUMMARY REPORT OF VITAL STATISTICS FOR 1912. "Total number of deaths r, Total number of births Total number male children Total number of female children Tota number of white children M563 Total number of colored children SUMMARY REPORT OF MARRIAGES AND DIVORCES FOR 1911 Total number of marriages Total number of divorce suits .._. CAUSE FOR DIVORCE NATURE OF DECREE Number of divorces granted Number of divorces dismissed 186 Number of divorce pending - - - "783 dren 12914 5 Nonsupport _ — Desertion .. ~~_~~.«_~~-«~_— «~~«~«~~ Adultery _ _ i LENGTH OF MARRIAGE Under two years. Between two years and five years Between five years and ten years Between ten years and twenty-five years Between twenty-five years and forty years. Between forty years and forty-fiveyears Not ffiven „_______________ ! </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>