<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00032.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00032.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Board of Health BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN k Published &lt;juarterly at the ortiif ot the Seen'tary af the Board, Sewani. Nebraska, tered aw second claa* matter, February tith, 1914, at the Poatofnce, jeward, Nebraska, under of July lrith. 1914. NO. 1 VOLUME .' TMl Bulletin will be MM bn to any pcnaa within the siatf upon rcijucMt 1' F. DOD8ON, M. D., President, Wilber E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Vie.-Presideni, Lincoln C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., Treasurer, Falls City H. B. CUMMINS, If. D., Secretary. Sewar.l BOARD OF HEALTH JOHN H MOREHEAD, Governor A. (). THOMAS, Supt. Pub. Instr. \V. H. WILSON, If. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln WM. F. WILD, M. D., Director Bacteriological Laboratory. Lincoln WHEN IN DOUBT In case of doubt as to the disease as to whether it is infectious or contagious always be on the safe side and isolate the patient and caution other members of the family. More cases of diphtheria, scarlet fever and in - fectious diseases are caused from the doubtful cases than there are from the more malignant. JANUARY, 1915 SECRETARIES WILLIS E. RKED, Atty. General </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ANNOUNCEMENT The annual convention of the League of Nebraska Municipalities will be held at Lincoln February 10 and 11, with headquarters and sessions at the Lindell Hotel, Twelfth and M streets. The program will open Wednesday at 10 A. M. with an address of welcome by Mayor Frank C. Zehrung, of Lincoln. Response and annual address by Senator George F. Wolz, of Fremont. The afternoon program and that for the 11th will cover municipal problems in relation to streets, sewers. water, lighting, sanitation and important legislative measures before the Legislature. The evening program for the 10th will be held as a joint session at the Lincoln Hotel with the Board of Health officers. Each city, town and village is requested to send at least two delegates whether the municipality is a mem her of the League or not. Tome and see the work we are doing. R. C. OZMAN. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">OFFI ( 'KRS The annual conference of state and local boards of health will be held in the banquet room of the Lincoln Hotel, Lincoln, Nebr., February 10 and 11. As there is to be joint meeting part of the time between the Nebraska State Municipal League and the Health Board and as the joint committee of the program has not yet met, we will be unable to publish the program for this meeting; however, it will be a very interesting one. as you will see by the Municipal League' 8 subjects. I The joint session will undoubtedly take up the suit : of new legislation pertaining to health and sanita 1, and the question of state sanitary survey will be en up and considered fully. iAt our last meeting in 1913 there was a great in - &gt;st taken in the subjects and the discussions entered » by so many that we were unable to complete our gram and the discussions were limited to a few ten. We intend this year to have fewer subjects and I give greater time to their consideration. (No town or village in this state can afford to not send 'presentative to this meeting. We i-ecominend to the uicipalities to pay the expenses of delegates and the rotary will issue certificates to those who attend the i days' session, stating that they had attended the &gt;ting, and recommend that the expenses for the same 1"We have the promise of some of the best sanitarians he country to be with us and take part in the program. Some delegates at our last meeting expressed the opinion that it was well worth the time and expense to hear the lecture of Mr. Brooks and see his moving pic - ture illustrations of sewers and sewage disposal. IThe Board is very anxious to see a large attendance we are contemplating some extensive work along itary lines and would like the opinion of the men in field. H. B. OITMMINS. Secretarv. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska State Board of Health Office of Secretary Seward. Nebr, January 1, 1915. tn H. Morehead, Governor. Lincoln, Nebr. Dear Governor: At the meeting of the Secretaries of i State Hoard of Health December 9, 1914, the Secre y was requested to prepare the following report and miit to you for your consideration, also one to be sent the Attorney (Jeneral and Superintendent of Public traction. Complying with the same I he» leave to submit the following recommendations and plans. Very truly yours, If. !'». (TMMINS, Sec'y, Board of Secretaries of the State Hoard of Health. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 To the Honorable John II. Morehead (Governor, The State Board of Health and all others concerned: Ebeg leave to submit, as requested, the following re - al to changes which should be made in our health L These recomniendations are baaed partly upon ex perience and partly upon information as in the regulation • &gt;f these matters in other Mates. The greatest weakness of our system is the tact that the Health Department has no executive head. The Board proper is composed of state officers already over burdened with other duties and who have no technical knowledge of health or sanitation in a scientific sense. The constitution should he amended to provide either for a Board of Health or a Health Commissioner who should serve a term of from four to eight years and re ceive a proper salary, and on whom should be placed the responsibility for the enforcement of health laws. Until such an amendment can be submitted, or if the same be not practicable, the only thing to do is to try to collate the duties which relate to health and sanitation and effect a reorganization of the state's departments and bureaus so as to bring them under one head so far afi may be. II should suggest that the law be amended so as to ate the office of Health Commissioner, who would be x&gt;inted by the Board of Secretaries and act as their iretary, also as custodian of the records, who should o be State Registrar of Vital Statistics, with charge work in that department, and who should direct the rk of the department and in fine be the executive head far as may be under such laws as could be adopted. Subordinated to him should be a corps of inspectors, who should include a competent sanitary engineer. Such number of inspectors should be apj&gt;ointed as could do the work effectively. I would place under this depart ment for inspection all matters relating to health and sanitation. This would include water supply, sewerage disposal, the sanitation of hotels and factories, such in- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 spections as affect the labor laws with regard to health, the matter of pure food, dairies and drags, and all mat ters which require expert knowledge of bacteriology and biology. In no other way can intelligent work be done along these lines. I Co-ordinated to this body would be the laboratorv . ch should have a competent bacteriologist and also a mist, with necessary assistants. These would be nee iry to complement the work of the inspectors. How - r, if the laboratory was well equipped and furnished re would be no need of any other laboratory, either in state house or at any institution, as this general oratory could do all the work. Similarly the corps of assistants referred to could do practically all the work along the lines of inspection now done, and would eliminate considerable duplication. They could go into a town, and make proper reports and it would not be long before the people would take an interest in these matters and would want their towns to stand well. Tt would be more a matter of education than of laying foundations for prosecutions. The pure food law occasionally costs a man in this state a few dollars, but the fair man must admit that it has done little prac - tical good. By taking all lines together, securing the co - operation of local officers, and making the ratings of towns public, it would be a matter of pride with a town to stand well, and we should secure some local assistance in enforcing these laws, whereas now we get very little. The Health Commissioner would direct these surveys, also additional and local inspections where necessary, preserve in proper form the results and publish them as a report. IThe adoption of the above would take over most of work of the Pure Food, the Hotel and the Labor nmissioner. Their other duties could then be con - dated into one department and a great practical sav made. Also, the laws would be intelligently enforced, ch ought to be worth something. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The above also practically merge* the Secretary of the Board of Secretaries with the premni Health In - spector. This should be done. There is no need for both Fnspections u to epidemics and diseases can j'.ist as well be made under the new system as the old. I would also suggest that the Health Commissioner should act as Sec - retary for the Board proper as well as the Secretaries and should maintain an office in Lincoln. This would make it a permanent projw)sition, put the Board proper and the advisory Board in close touch and be of great benefit. The Board of Secretaries would still retain then original functions, including the examination of appli - cants, the regulation of practitioners and the like. I think the above would result in placing Nebraska among those progressive states which give some atten - tion to sanitaiy matters. As it is, and it will be so until we make some change, we are ranked among the trailers, and this will continue until we get it fixed so that we have an effective head and something to work on The .state's health should be as important as its pocket-hook. It is to the individual. It should be to the state. Respectfully submitted. H. B. OUMMTNS. Secretarv. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 STATE SANITARY SURVEY tin order to accomplish the best results in sanitation 1 public health work, accurate information must bo 1 as to the conditions that exist in the state relating the subject. The most important things to be oom - ered in this connection are: 1. The water supply. Ts it safe and sufficient in quantity? 12. Is there a sewer system? Is it adequate to meet demands ? 3. Is the food free from contamination? E. Are the authorities exercising due diligence in pro ncr the citizens from infectious and eontagiouR dis It tThe only way that such information can be obtained I arranged so as to be on a working basis is by means a state sanitary survey. This has been thoroughly iionstrated by our best health officers in the states ere the boards of health have accomplished the most id and have given the best satisfaction. We can possibly give the best idea as to what i - meant by a sanitary survey from the following proposed cards, outlining the different headings under which the investigations will be taken up. The word "survey" means to inspect or take a view of; to view with atten tion; hence the object of this survey is to take a view or inspect the state as to its sanitary or health conditions, — to note and record the conditions in the different parts of the state for present, as well as future, use, — to ascer - tain where changes are needed in order to comply with rules and regulations that are necessary to protect the health and lives of the people, and to maintain a aui table recognition by other communities. The details of the survey are indicated in the following: </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Sanitary Survey of Towns Town Oountv Date Population Mayor Health Officer Sanitary Inspector Food Inspector Source of Water Supply (ref ) Topography (ref Drainage I Sewerage Stream Pollution Type of Closets Generally Disposal of Night Soil . . . Cess Pools Water Tight Method of Cleaning Garbage Collection (ref Garbage Disposal At House Ultimate Streets (ref ) Cleanliness Drainage Trash Cans Isolation Hospital for Infectious Diseases </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Remarks- (Use Back of Card.) GRADE— EXCELLENT GOOD FAIR POOR BAD Notice s?i ven </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Inspection of Bakeries, Confectioneries and Ice Cream Factories Name of Owner Date &lt; 'it v or Town County Registration Number Building (ref ) Floors, Walls, Ceilings, Woodwork (ref ) Storage Rooins, Back Rooms. Yard (ref ) T.ight and Ventilation (ref ) Screens (ref ) Flies ) Handling of Goods (ref ) Employees (ref ) "Water Supply (ref ) Plumbing and Drainage (ref ) Toilets. Style A.B.C.D.E. Cups and Towels (ref ) </seg>
            <seg id="p012">GRADR— EXCELLENT GOOD FAIR POOR BAD Notice given </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Inspections of Hotels and Restaurants Xanic of ( timer Name of Place City or Town County Date Classification Dininjr Room— Floors. Walls and Ceiling (ref ) Shelves and Tables (ref ) Table Covers and Napkins (ref Light and Ventilation (ref ) Classes Cups, Saucers, Plates, etc. (rof ) Flies Kitchen — (ref Floor Wai I- and Ceilings Shelves. Tables and Sinks Ventilation and Light Washing and Rinsing of Dishes and Tableware (ref....) Flies Refrigerator (ref ) </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Sleeping Rooms Garbage (ref ) Screens (ref ) ) Cups and Towels (ref ) Drinking Water (ref ) Toilets (ref Style A.B.C.D Remarks— (Use Back of Card.) GRADE— EXCELLENT GOOD FAIR POOR BAD Notice given </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 H NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEAI/1 Inspection of Public Buildings Town Countv Date Building Floors (ref ) Method of Cleaning Walls and Ceilings (ref ) Appearance Method of Cleaning Ktilation (ref it (ref ) \ Spittoons (ref ) Cleanliness Disinfectants Used Anti-Spitting Signs Drinking Cup Signs Common Drinking Cup (ref ) Drinking Water Lavatory (ref ) Closets (ref ).: Stvle A.B.C.D.E Is Toilet Paper Provided Kining of Closets (ref hod'.. ) Krels (ref ) ter Supply (ref ) </seg>
            <seg id="p016">II Grounds Around Building Drainage. Remarks — Use Back of Card.) t\DE— EXCELLENT GOOD FAIR POOR BAD ice given </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 To conduct a work of this kind, and to have the work done properly and effectually, it will require the aid of one versed in sanitary engineering. It will also require the aid of a chemist, a bacteriologist and a number of in - spectors. The latter the state already employs. Tli*' sanitary engineer would be inspector of water supply and sewerage disposal and the work that he would perform would be along the line of engineering, etc. This would be the only change that would be required in the working force. Tt would also necessitate a larger office force than we have in the State Board of Health at the present time: but, by consolidating the Departments of Pure Food, Hotel Commissioner, and relieving the Labor Commis - sioner of that part pertaining to the sanitation of fac - tories and child labor, etc., and combining the offices of the above, the work could be done with a less fore*. In fact, concentration would be economical and far more effectual. For instance, take the Department of Hotel Commissioner; their duties being to inspect hotels and restaurants as to their sanitary conditions pertaining to public health and the dissemination of disease, it is ap - parent to those who understand this work that to be effectual in that department, — taking it in all its phases, — would require the same class of inspectors to do effect - ual work as would be required to make any and all the inspections and ratings that our plan covers. We ask for some space to explain the cards to show how this plan will work out. For instance, on the card under sanitary survey of towns under the subject of water supply you will find the prefix f ref ) in parenthesis, which is simply placed there to call your attention to what will he placed in the same space on the cards when completed. There will be formulated laws, rules and standards for each of the different headings, which will be published in book form for the use of local health officers, inspectors and the local boards of health. The instructions pertain - ing to this subject will be numbered and the number will V. J % % ■ * M M M- MM X^ ' * 1 LI V 1 &amp; * I II r^J^X la f | I ' I lit </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 face under the heading ''Source of Water Supply" will included depth, surroundings, possibility of pollution I the condition of wells as to the chemical and bacte - logical analysis. Under the head of "Topography" 1 be instructions concerning the lay of the ground, inage and relation to pollution. The same reference [ instructions will be given regarding all other sub - bs. This book will be known as the Sanitary Code. I In the inspection of hotels, dairies, groceries, bakeries, it markets, slaughter houses, drug stores, etc., we will e as an illustration "bakeries," and would refer to &gt;rs, walls, ceilings, wookwork, storage rooms, back ms, yard, light and ventilation. You will find a num - of references in these, and there will possibly be ee of four paragraphs under one heading; but full in - lctions will be given in the Sanitary Code as deemed essary for the carrying on of such work. I After a thorough examination of the above, a card 1 be given to the proprietor showing the standing as whether his grade is excellent, good, fair, poor or bad. this scoring he will be able to understand wherein he iefective and where improvement is needed. On the ;k of the card will be space for instructions explaining desires of the health department, in order that his e can be raised if needed, thus giving him a notice ap what is expected, and the length of time he will be en to bring it up to the required standard. If he is *ible to that standard, he will be rated as excellent good; but, if below that, the necessity for his correct : the existing conditions will be explained, and the ad - ltage of raising the rating will be fully explained. After the entire town is inspected and the work is compiled the city or village is given a similar card show - ing where changes should be made, and the local board of health is requested through their health officer to notify the State Board of Health when their ratings should be advanced. There will be no complaints filed or action tfilcPn on flnv of tlioso conditions unless it is flxypiiT*6nt </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 that it should be corrected at once in order to protect the health of the citizens. We do not advise that tlio ratings of the town be published for a year or two, or, at least, not unless it was thought advisable by the state author - ities after thorough consideration of the matter. But the ratings of the towns and of the different business places coming under inspection and the condition of each town or village will be on file in the office of the Secretary of the State Board of Health and it will be the duty of the Secretary to inform the municipal authorities of th&lt; j exact conditions existing and to see that these conditions are brought up to the proper standing. The benefits that will be derived from this survey will be from an educational standpoint, as it is very apparent to those who have had experience in these matters that the unhealthy and unsanitary condition of cities and villages are more or less due to ignorance and prejudice along sanitary lines. When a town or village is shown wherein they are defective in sanitary matters as com - pared with other towns and villages civic and individual pride will stimulate a desire to correct these conditions and is more satisfactory in accomplishing results than to compel such action by legal proceedings. The above, together with correct morbidity and mor tality statistics and report of births, will indicate as to whether sanitation pays. It will demonstrate in a few years whether there is more sickness and deaths in a town that is giving proper attention to its water supply, meat market, dairies, etc., and whose board of health and health officers are exercising due diligence in protecting the citizens from infectious and contagious diseases, than one that is not. We believe what has been said will indicate clearly the object and plan of the proposed survey. We wish to give special credit to Oscar Dowling, M. D., of Louisiana, for priority in this work in the recommending and estab - lishing the first work of this kind and what has proved a &lt;rreat benefit to his people. We have received letters </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 from different ones, Dr. Burkett, secretary of the State Board of Health of Michigan, recommending this; also recommendations from different states that are in favor of combining these departments under one head and plac - ing them under the control of the board of health com - posed of men who are competent to act on these matters. tOur reason for asking that part of the Labor Commis - ler's duties pertaining to sanitation of factories ami Id labor, etc., can best be explained by the following ort (in part), as probably no one is more familiar than )r. B. S. Warren in these matters and his recommenda - is should carry weight: I In Public Health Reports for May 29, 1914, Dr. B. S. rren, of the United States Public Health Service, and itary adviser to the United States Commission on In itrial Relations, has a very stimulating and instructive icle on Industrial Conditions and Their Relation to blic Health. In introducing the subject he says that the study of methods for the prevention of disease, estigators have found that many of their problems industrial and economic and that success in disease (vention very largely depends upon the proper adjust - nt of the industrial relations of employer and em - yee upon a basis that will permit both to live accord - : to hygienic standards. I In order to bring about this adjustment and bring wrerful aid to those influences already working for in - strial betterment, the public health forces should co prate heartily. Often it is found that the effects of in - strial conditions extend to entire communities and are a large part indirectly responsible for slum districts, ey dwellers, and low standard of living. From current blished reports it is easily to be seen that industrial nditions particularly relating to industrial hygiene and aitation, are not what they should be. The author believes that in order to make any head - way in disease prevention in the industries, the following </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Annual Bulletin No. 1 21 1. Hours of labor which do not cause excessive fatigue or cause damage to any part of the body. Kl. Regular employment at a wage sufficient to meet cost of hygienic living and insure against sickness or &gt;r physical disability. 3. Sanitary environment in the place of employment. 4. Education as to methods of hygienic living and the importance of such living. I He does not place the responsibility for existing eon - ions of environment entirely upon the worker. One mot always choose his own environment. This will itinued to be true, especially in the unskilled groups, long as the supply of laborers is greater than the de - nd, and the competition for employment makes it pos - le for the employer to fix the terms of employment, e responsibility must rest mainly on the employer, but j state must do its part. The following list of hygienic luirements, outlined according to where the respond ity lies, seems to be of sufficient value to quote entire: 1. Wages. (a) Adequate to maintain the employees as to 1 1 ) proper food, (2) clothing, (3) hours for rest and recrea tion, and thereby maintain an efficient and healthy mind and body. (b) Increase or promotions according to length of service to provide for family and increase in family. (c) Adequate to save for old age or pay for old-airf pension. 2. Place of employment. (a) General sanitary condition?, (1) proper heating. (2) proper humidity, (3) proper lighting, (4) no over crowding, (5) proper ventilation (6) proper cleaning, (7) clean water supply. (b) Removal of dust, gases, and fumes. (c) Safeguarding against accidents. t(d) Equipment necessary for personal hygiene: (1) hing facilities, (2) toilets, (3) rest rooms, (4) lock - etc. A. Employers' Responsibility </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 3. Mental and physical energy expended. (a) Hours of labor: (1) length of work day. (2) over - time, (3) night work. |(b) Fatigue: (1) rest, recreation, and sleep necessarv waste and restore body cells prior to begin g day's work, (2) posture, speed of work or attention uired, which causes unusual strain to be eliminated ere practical, or adequate rest periods to be allowed, monotony of occupation as cause of fatigue. t\ge and sex of employees. No child labor under 14 years. rompensation for sickness and accident incident lu employment. 6. Regular employment in so far as practicable 7. Prompt medical and surgical aid. (a) Sanitary inspections. 1(b) Elimination in an equitable manner of the men y and physically unfit. Bjntributor to sick insurance fund, ducation of employees. (a) Prevention of disease. (b) Prevention of accidents. (c) Special rules for dangerous processes. B. Employees' Responsibility 1. Home environment. »(a) General sanitary condition as to (1) heating. (2) lidity, (3) lighting, (4) overcrowding, (5) ventilation, cleanliness, (7) clean water supply. (b) Special sanitary condition. (c) Personal hygiene: obtain proper (1) food, (2) clothing, (3) bathing, (4) rest, (5) recreation and avoid - ance of dissipation. 2. Places of recreation. (a) General sanitary conditions. (b) Special sanitary condition. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Regular employment. (a) Seek employment. (b) Prompt attendance. 4. Procuring medical and surgical relief in case of sick ness or accidents. 5. Contribution to sick insurance fund. 6. Education. (a) Prevention of sickness. (b) Prevention of accidents. (c) Special rules for dangerous processes. (d) Study to increase efficiency and fitness for pro motion or increase in pay. C. State Responsibility. 1. Housing — home, shops, places of amusements, etc. (a^ Sanitary building regulations. (b) Licensing of dangerous trades. (c) Sanitary inspections. (d) Special regulations governing sanitation. (e) Personal hygiene requirements. 2. Regulations of hours of labor. (a) Day and night, to prevent exhaustion. (b) No child labor under 14 years. (c) Overtime to be eliminated where practicable. 3. Minimum wage scale. 4. Medical supervision. (a) Free hospitals for indigent?. (b) Dispensaries for indi gents. (c) Regulations governing medical attendance in cer tain industries. 5. Pure- food regulations. 6. Pure water supply. 7. Special measures to prevent diseases. 8. Regulations of social insurance or compulsory sick and old age insurance. 9. Education of those concerned. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 VITAL STATISTICS In submitting our annual report, we take this oppor tunity of publicly thanking the physicians, undertakers, county judges, clerks of district courts, and local regis trars who by their filing and reports have made this re j)ort possible. The report relative to marriages and di - vorces is, we believe, complete, representing every trans - action of the kind taken place in the state for the period herein covered. It is with a degree of regret that we can not say as much of the births and deaths, for, in our opin - ion, the reporting of all births and deaths to the depart ment is of vastly greater importance than the reporting of the former, for marriages and divorces are already subjects of record in the various counties and judicial dis - tricts of the state, while such is not the case with births and deaths. Because of this we wish to emphasize if possible, the importance of making returns of every birth and death occnring in the state. It is true that the de partment is getting as nearly complete returns of births and deaths as the average state in the Union; but this is not enough and does not satisfy us, as we wish to and should be getting them all and would get all of them if every person officiating at a birth and all who serve as undertakers fully realized the importance and did their duty to their patrons in this respect. Also, if the public would awake to the need of having all births and deaths recorded and require the persons serving them in such ways comply with the law, and make the legal filings, then would our vital statistics be complete. That every child coming into the world is entitled to have a legal, permanent record made of the date of its birth and a few other pertinent facts relative thereto i« so evident that it should not need argument, it being the fir-4 and great event of one's existence, would seem to be sufficient reason for the making of such records. This being admitted, then it would seem to follow that the attending obstetrician is the most suitable person to Til 3) 1\ f* KliOtl TPPHm ' Vi PTlf*** 1 1 1 O 1 Qtt Vl Qc Y"hl qaa/^ 4-V\o f^Tl'far gr)i"1 1 1 1 n i\ • in ii i u hvV * ' "v law Ilttg |_McH_trU til" lllll^V dll ' 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 responsibility on such persons, and he or she who neglects it has not only violated the law, but has failed in duty to the child and its parents, and the parents should in all cases exact this duty of the attendant. Legal records of births are highly advantageous in legal transactions of diverse kinds, as in property rights, questions of legiti imacy, school attendance, the exercise of the electiw franchise, marriage, etc. Also in the commercial world, as in the employment of child labor, and the securing of employment in various industries in the large industrial centers. Birth being the first great event of one's career, death is the last, and, like the first, should have a public record made of it, that a proper accounting may be made of the individual and the cause and manner of his demise Death certificates are of exceeding importance and con venience in the proving of various kinds of business an.l commercial transactions, and no dotibt the requirement by the state, of the filing of death certificates, is a deter - rent to crime. Lastly, we only suggest at the immense valu* 3 of vital statistics as a guide in preventive medicine, and trust that this brief summary and the appended statistics will tend to stimulate more prompt and com plete returns. DEATHS BY COUNTIES From December 1. 1913. to December 1. 1914 Adams 280 Butler 123 Antelope 94 Cass 190 Arthur 1 Banner 1 Chase 14 Blaine 5 Cherry 50 Boone 84 Chevenne 29 Box Butte 57 Clav 129 Bovd 4 fi Colfax 87 Brown 28 Cuming 109 Buffalo 245 Custer 142 Cedar 91 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Dawes 53 Madison 202 Dawson 96 Merrick 60 Deuel 16 Morrill U Dixon 89 Nance 47 Dodge 244 Nemalia 84 Douglas 2,424 Nuckolls 100 Dundy 34 Otoe 192 Fillniore 114 Pawnee 80 Franklin 76 Perkins 5 Frontier 35 Phelps 92 Furnas 104 Pierce 89 Gage 296 Pbitte 209 Garden 23 Polk 86 Garfield 13 Red Willow 9:: Gosper 20 Richardson 196 Grant 11 Rock 18 Greelev 46 Saline 116 Hall 289 Sarpy 26 Hamilton 94 Saunders 173 Harlan 59 Scott's Bluff 91 Hayes 7 Seward 144 Hitchcock 21 Sheridan 48 Holt 109 Sherman 52 Hooker 2 Sioux 5 Howard 76 Stanton 51 Jefferson 125 Thaver 114 .Johnson Johnson 64 64 Thomas •1 Kearnev 76 Keamey 76 Thurston . Thurston 112 Keith 22 Keith 22 Valley Valley 75 Keya Palia 11 Washimrt-m Keya Palia 11 Washiniit'in 104 Kimball 7 Kimball 7 Wayne Wavne 62 Knox 116 Knox 116 Webster ... Webster 95 Lancaster 888 Lancaster 888 Wheeler Wheeler 10 Lincoln 100 York Lincoln 100 York 140 Logan 6 Logan 6 Loup 6 Total L&lt;mp 6 Total 10,735 MePherson 3 McPherson 3 CAUSES OF DEATHS, 1914 89 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Smallpox 4 4 Measles ti Scarlet fever 54 Whooping cough 42 Diphtheria 118 Influenza Cholera nostras 1 Dysentery 33 Erysipelas 17 Other epidemic diseases 4 Purulent infection and septic aemia 99 Tetanus o Mvcoses 1 Tuberculosis of the lungs 358 Tuberculosis meningitis 32 ... Pott 's disease 1 Tuberculosis of other organs 112 Syphilis 8 Gonococcus infection 1 Cancer of liver, stomach 287 Cancer peritonaeum, intestines, rectum 76 Cancer of female genital organs fil ( lancer of the breast :}7 Cancer of other parts 211 ( )ther tumors 21 Acute rheumatism 16 Chronic rheumatism 12 Diabetes 156 Exophthalmic goitre 12 Addison's disease 2 Leucaemia 15 Anaemia, chlorosis 81 Alcoholism 16 Meningitis 97 Looomotor ataxia 11 Other diseases of the spinal cord 20 Cerebral haemorrhage, apoplexy .")&lt;;»; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Paralysis without specified cause 216 (it'Tieral paralysis of the insane 72 Other forms of mental alienation 19 Convulsions 54 Epilepsy 39 Pericarditis S Acute endocarditis 39 Organic diseases of the heart 1,039 Angina pectoris 4 v Diseases of the arteries 187 Embolism and thrombosis 67 Diseases of the veins, varices, haemorrhoids, etc . . 2 Diseases of the lymphatic system i i Haemorrhage, other diseases of the circulatory sys tern 11 Diseases of the nose and throat J Diseases of the ear 1 Diseases of the pharynx .', Diseases of the larynx 7 Bronchitis, acute 40 Bronchitis, chronic 40 Broncho pneumonia 14.'» Pneumonia 707 Pleurisy 22 Pulmonary congestion 55 A &gt;t lima 36 Pulmonary emphysema 11 1 &gt;i&lt;eases of the oesophagus 1 Ulcer of the stomach 37 Other diseases of the stomach (cancer excepted) . . 93 Diarrhoea and enteritis (under 2 years) 203 Diarrhoea and enteritis (2 years and over) 109 Appendicitis and typhlitis 113 Hernia, intestinal obstruction 114 Other diseases of the intestines 52 Acute yellow atrophy of the liver 5 Cirrhosis of the liver 77 Biliarv calculi :!4 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 &lt; H .her diseases of the liver 54 I )iseaBes of the s[&gt;leen 1 Simple peritonitis 151 &lt; tther diseases of the digestive system 6 Acute nephritis 312 Bright 's disease .'U2 &lt; tther diseases of the kidneys ami annexa 14 I &gt;iseases of the bladder 48 Diseases of the prostate 31 Diseases of the uterus (noncancerous) 6 ( 'ysts and other tumors of the ovary 8 Bpingitis and other diseases of the female genital rgans 1 Accidents of pregnancy i;i Puerporal haemorrhage 15 Other accidents of labor 8 Puerperal septicaemia 26 Puerperal albuminuria and convulsions 1*» &lt; Jangrene 4'2 Diseases of the bones (tuberculosis exeepted) ... 1 Congenital debility, etc 1,040 SeniHty 589 Suicide by poison Suicide by hanging ::."&gt; Suicide by firearms ti(i Suicide by other means 1C Accidental poisoning 17 Accidental drowning 69 Burns 50 Trnumatism by firearms 52 Tranmatism by machines 15 Traumatism by railways, vehicles, etc 74 Injuries by animals 4 Starvation 1 Excessive cold 2 Excessive heat 8 1 1 ll 1 1 11 —^ ................................ ... -L17 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Other external violence 238 No cause 69 Cause of death not specified or ill defined 77 Hi-defined organic disease 44 Other diseases of the respiratory system .*&gt; Other general diseases 2;: Electricity (lightning excepted) 10 Neuralgia and neuritis 7 Poisoning by food f&gt; Ptomaine poisoning 4 1 ntestinal parasites 1 Other diseases of the skin 3 •&gt; Hodgkin's disease 11 Other acute poisonings 1 Diseases of the nervous system 14 Jaundice 1 Absorption of deleterious gases (conflagration ex- cepted 15 Hydrophobia 2 ftrnve's disease 6 Chorea 3 Diseases of the thyroid body 2 Pellegra 5 r. Poliomyelitis 2 Encephalitis 11 Fracture (cause not specified) 1 Calculi of urinary passages 1 Anthrax 1 Diseases of the joints 1 Cancer and other malignant tumors of other organs not specified \ Congenital malformation 1 Still births 499 Total 10,735 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">3, Tabula :ed Re Dt f Bird is by Counties fo - port oi t the Year End! rcetnbc ■ 1, 1 »I3. to December 1. 1914. Counties - I — ~ C 5 • j ■ 0 i S B I! =S &gt; B X 09 ■ z m I Blaine Brown Franklin Frontier .... Furnas 251 154 14 188 39 96 98 279 163 167 173 200 50 77 64 14S 136 164 302 70 70 208 26 107 265 2,097 50 148 134 HI 123 294 40 36 66 23 96 235 149 121 38 32 192 13 108 174 112 99 53 247 KHt 18 137 43 89 74 202 137 175 166 190 36 73 49 168 126 174 273 63 69 144 21 121 264 1,878 34 127 136 104 98 286 50 39 52 19 76 213 142 112 35 34 181 17 77 185 102 100 29 497 273 32 325 82 185 172 481 300 342 339 389 86 150 113 316 262 337 575 133 139 352 47 228 529 3,917 84 275 271 215 321 .580 90 75 118 42 172 448 291 233 73 66 373 30 185 359 214 199 82 1 I ' 419 249 30 286 76 165 166 446 267 294 308 362 84 147 103 284 233 303 560 125 131 338 47 208 485 2.641 79 241 251 200 212 560 83 71 109 37 155 414 278 231 69 59 348 28 163 336 198 178 75 44 13 1 17 3 7 1 15 7 8 12 15 1 I 4 10 14 24 3 1 6 3 18 3 1 16 2 5 2 6 22 8 11 9 5 2 2 3 2 2 4 2 1 l 2 1 2 1 6 It. 11 6 2 3 ' 14 7 1 1 3 n 3 5 6 6 1 I 1 1 2 4 1 | 2 1 1 11 2 1 •&gt; 7 i 5 I i 58 S 17 202 1 10 13 11 5 14 6 I S 1 9 13 310 2 11 7 3 1 89 1 4 9 197 1 2 4 536 7 3 2 T 1 1 3 3 1 Hayes Hitchcock . JpffcrsoD .... i\C1iD 28 4 1 1 2 9 3 9 1 1 3 4 1 12 2 2 14 •-' 1 2 3 2 7 1 1 3 1 2 2 4 1 2 4 ■ 2 4 16 12 7 I 2 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 &gt;ulated Report of Birtl December 1. 1913. t&lt; is by Counties for the Year Ending December 1. 1914 — Concluded. Counties '— 31 iff 8 c 5 •p I 3 I r. C 1.1 I 1 " ■ M x 1 c = I — Kimball ... Lancaster. . Pawuop 1 crKins .... Red Willow. Scotts BJuflF. Washington. 33 12 190 992 168 26 12 236 125 44 111 140 173 227 117 16 130 168 282 143 109 273 38 185 50 215 115 178 101 125 5 103 172 s 138 120 119 138 167 24 220 25 6 214 887 149 25 14 256 114 56 115 152 149 193 118 8 m 139 244 116 112 225 28 188 44 215 (tx 1M 78 113 S 107 165 5 133 127 134 105 135 24 197 58 18 404 1,872 317 51 26 492 239 100 226 292 322 420 235 24 226 307 525 259 221 497 66 373 &lt;« 430 209 3M 179 238 IS 210 337 13 219 247 2.53 243 302 48 415 7 ' 1 .J7 18 356 1 ,553 an 51 26 431 222 94 205 287 298 398 221 24 203 276 453 244 207 491 62 330 S7 364 193 317 162 211 11 185 310 13 237 218 231 214 282 47 400 23 131 2 41 4 2 i a 8 14 8 6 20 24 4 6 6 1 13 3 23 S 12 5 5 1 16 155 8 12 7 •t 6 14 5 17 5 13 11 6 i 2 1 1 a i •&gt; 1 14 a 7 2 1 a 2 i l 2 H I i I 4 3 1 24 8 1 3 7 1 5 4 3 1 24 I 3 i 1 1 13 20 1 7 2 &gt; 52 14 5 10 21 9 10 7 10 7 3 1 1 1 a i 2 3 II i 2 3 2 ■ 3 V Total . . 12,779 14,002 be.653 128 r23,425 11,073 I 353 950 211 K3O6 Males 302 Females; 304 Pair. ( 5 Males &lt;&gt; Whit I 1 Female: 2 Sets 608 White, 498 American, 110 Foreijpi c, 6 P'oreiRii. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 DIVORCE REPORTS, 191:5 Counties Number Counties Number Hitchcock 1 Adams 4&lt;&gt; TTolt 25 Antelope 19 Hooker 1 Banner 2 ■' Howard 10 Blaine -&gt; Jefferson 2G Boone 9 i Johnson 3 Hox Butte 4" Kearnev !l Bovd fi Koith Brown Brown 13 13 Buffalo 50 Kimball ■ ) Buff ale. 50 Knox 17 Knox 17 Burt n Lancaster 297 Lancaster 297 Butler Lincoln 17 Lincoln 17 Cass U Ix&gt;gan .") Logan ( 'edar &lt;• &gt; &gt; I»up J- Clicrrv 28 Cherry 88 ( 'heyenne 16 Madison 42 Madison 42 ( 'heyenne 16 Merrick 10 Merrick 10 Clay 6 Morrill P Colfax 6 i Nance 6 Nance 6 Chiming 11 Chiming 11 Neraaha 22 ( 'uster 31 Custer 31 Xuckolls 19 Nuckolls 19 Dawes l'» Dawes 19 Otoe 23 Dawson 17 Dawson 17 Pawnee 8 Pawnee 8 Dixon 5 Dixon 5 r. Perkins 2 Doiisje 47 Dodsre 47 Phelps 12 Douglas 63.') Douglas 63.') Pierce 12 Dandy 2 Dundv 5 Platte 17 Fillmore 18 Filhnore 18 Polk 9 Franklin 13 Pranklin 12 Red Willow . . ...... 24 Red Willow 24 Frontier 9 Frontier 9 Richardson 17 Richardson 17 Furnns 15 Pumas 15 Rock 12 Gage 32 Qage 32 Saline 20 Garden 4 Garden 4 Sarpy 12 GarfMd 9, (Jarfield 9, Saunder.^ 20 Ciosjier 6 Gosper 6 Scotts Bluff 14 Scotts Bluff 14 Greeley 2 Greelev 2 Seward 20 Hall 60 Sheridan 1 fi Sheridan 1 fi Hamilton . 11 Hamilton . 11 Sherman 2 Sherman o Harlan 11 Harlan 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 i -po ! oa -a ■ •« — m eo— • M ■ ■ ■ COO ■ M*r &gt;tc . ; :3R : ■ — iiui r~« : : : ot— •&lt;&gt;• • ■*■ — — -«5 • ia iii :"* : : : : p : ,jq IT&lt; Cl — C&lt;3 «w— ~; — — Cl TO — — — I •a "5 V ■ ■ . . ■ *r " 1 1 M " c&lt;; 1 1 : ~&lt;— : . . m — : —» ; •g n : : - : ; : : n : 3 X : : : ' : ' : " ' ? «• "" .' • — — • • • e* cc ■ • ' 0 t £ '•»-« • - m x I m o - : . «n ■ ••-; « -i s ?: - o o n m MNi.- i -g coco ;-«*- *m ■ -1- — *»■ — • mm- -*r» : — ■ — f ~: 3 . . : : . : : n : : H : : : : : : : : : s -r a I I 5 c 5. g = S5 5i en • ; — n • — m ** ■ ; ; -c M ; 1] : : : : : :-s* — ;g ;- K »- xi ; ■.•:■.■..:■.::■. : : ■ : ■. t ■.:::•.::: 3D . . . - . ...... .... . ....... s • • S3 : : : : : • :::::::::::::::::: '"S I I 1 a 9 .22 r--* ■ • "t— o ' — ' mm ' ■ 10 ■ t^. » •;*» — — ~ ihijiijininnniih-iriihf" £ r : rt " s • i -g m '— ■ 'W • — -&lt; " ■ ■ — w — ~ ■ • — — ■ -rocs •«« — n £ , ; ; ; . . : .' : : : 00 ; Xt ■■■■■■■ ■■■■■■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ : E I 3|- ; ; :• ; :• :• : : ■ •" _Li:.-:.;iiii:iiii; 1 X| : .; : : : : n : 1 fj SO — : &lt;N C&lt;5 -• ■* to CH . N ;t^CC ' « N « — C&lt;5 .' t~ O» — •♦C* — ?«IC : : : • -„ ;N« 2 -.^ s u SlB «MXO««r. 22 ON S g .S» W "2 •^ • ::•.: • ■ ■ &lt;n • ■ ■ : . ■ •* ■ . '. — — : ■ • 2 :•• i . : • &amp; : •::::: ; : : : : : : : . ' " : . : 6 itlll^ll^iliyllilillflill^ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 E a u "5 ". ■r ■_ 0 pM ■ M ■ Cl ■ ■ ic • •^f : — -« n »r is. — : us l-X -( 3 |U1 — w oo c s; *c »r ;i-/. s. -c ri ■* « © Tf -r i^ c -r. - •- re cr- 1 - -1- -•- 3 &amp; ! ■ • : .^it •S :- : :« : 3 • • • Hi : : : : ■ ri I ' n a c D I ~oJ ■ ; : : ' • ! M I- M - K M « N n - ?1 X n ri i-icnri c I 3 ■§ m . — — ic ~i ■ r&lt; ■ m ; e*n • K i : : : : : -coo — — I 5 I * j : : : — -xl — | m ; — « — ■ '■ • -""S ~\ .O« 2 5 ■ e | : : :.: • : : : : \ : | : j : : : \ w :::::::::::::::::: B j | u 0 % : : ' : ■ ; M ■«!&gt;! ■_ — — • ■* m M ; — — — ci "; co m 1 :•'! ! 1 1 i • ! 53 :::::::: ■ :— eo &gt;, ,2j ■«« •iOfO)M-"N-NMfiOM ■ * &gt;O OS M - r» M l- f n &gt;C f M j6 x ■ • o ■« ■ -co ; • — • r) ■ • « O N ; ; «.■; ■ 3 — © : • • ; — ' .' .' in — .' ; ; — .' ' 5- 9 I ■' -" «5 &lt;M ■— — &lt; e m .' — «; -r «&gt; w o 5b c^ cc ; ss *x — ■ o t-H : : . K T - . 'mmmm ; ; co ■«■ irj M .' re M — — -r ■ f M : - : : * - : e* : — — i - — ; — . ;«■&gt;•/: -.o re ?io:r~co — .' — c-i *r M x o 05 f ! ' — c^ ■ ; t ; . — 1 ■a : i '■ J ' : = '■ % c 6 := -Sd i 8-s : '■ *£ '• ■' </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 2 pas o - ia :«m* ; - rere-i^. j H4 . : :^, | w . : ., u O " ~ - re - - ,- ;WM4 ; — re re m ■* : — •»■ ■ • mm ;- ; ; ju ; ;H- ;|| £\ ■ : : PI : : : : i- : T-:l" X 3 ■ Bd : ■ P I I ."= . - re ri -. -r rc ~, re - -r re ~i m « iriM-t I -^ 0. :m : ■ i- -t n -r ~i re m m ■ — — '--^ '. -j., ■ a : • • ' : : ; : ; : Ii I 9 = B *Z I M M — M i- ~1 ' • M — • — ; re — ; M — ro re 33 m 1 — q I | 5 a : : : : : : : Minn I 0 • a. I &lt;z m ci « ; m e« cs *c : : : MM— ; 10 ■ 'C &gt;oroe&gt;&gt; • I eg ■8 I : a! • np 1 0 liiJ Mi ii 1 re T r. S| :"" :::: : I:::::;) ;~ s j I : m — re m re m ! : — re ; r- — ! : — m : — ' m ; -* w I ' - ?&gt; e - 1&gt; -t m i- m n - m « - ■»).,-_. tc ' m e* &lt;o to © • : . « ■ . — '? m re — &gt;r: remi-r- — — re .' oc ■»»• &gt;c ro — ; I Nex^itxti-Mtcoc-rM ;m-*x .'bwsno p&lt; i\ &gt; j »~ — — s I I iiii!jiji;il:Mj:M^;|Mi jigs -11 : «^l---s-il Jlsl-^lsi • ZItt£333lfilJlj£i^&amp;3J£E2 » </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Counties Number Counties Number Wayne 12 Th aver 16 Webster 16 Thomas i York 12 Tlmrston 52 Vallev 6 Total 2.150 Washington 16 REPORTS , 1913 .marriage Counties Number Counties Number Adams 249 Frontier 56 Antelope 138 Furnas 00 Banner 11 Gage 269 Blaine 10 Garden Boon* 103 (iarhVId Box Butte 1H ( ioSjX'f 30 Bovd 67 Grani 12 Brown 64 Greeley 52 Buffalo 204 Hall 278 Hurt 85 Hamilton 9&lt;i Butler 118 Har'nn 81) Cans 121 Haves Cedar 117 Hitchcock 36 Chase 01 Holt 130 ..&gt; Hooker 15 Chevenne 132 1 1 o ward 82 Clay 105 Jefferson 185 Colfax 83 Johnson 94 &lt; Wing 110 Kearnev 7'! Custer 178 Keith Dakota 213 Keya Paha 21 Dawes 99 Kimball 4 1 -! Dawson 112 Knox 154 Dene] 14 Lancaster 972 Dixon 71 Lincoln 181 Dodge 256 Douglas 2.473 Logan 30 fxrap 24 Dundv 44 McPherson 13 Filhnore 114 Madison 175 Merriek «7 Ll..... T-K.j fJP </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Counties Number Counties Number Counties Number Counties Number Morrill 58 Morrill 58 Seotts Bluff 130 Seotts Bluff 130 Nance 67 Nance 67 Seward 136 Seward 136 Xemaha 121 Xcmaha 121 Sheridan 61 Sheridan 61 Xuckolls 123 Xuekolls 123 Sherman 61 Sherman 61 Otoe 180 Otoe 180 Sioux 39 Sioux 39 Pawnee 87 Pawnee 87 Stanton 66 Stanton 66 Perkins 15 Perkins 15 Thaver 144 Thayer 144 Phelpa 104 Phelps 104 Thomas 28 Thomas 28 Pierce 96 Pieroe 96 Thurston 76 Thurston 76 Platte 219 Platte 219 Vallev 67 Polk 67 IN. Ik 67 Washington 107 Washington 107 Red Willow 146 Red Willow 146 Wavne 109 Wayne 109 Richardson 178 Richardson 178 Webster 10o Webster 103 Wheeler 6 Wheeler 6 Rock 51 Rock 51 York 150 Saline 158 Saline 158 Barpy 143 B«rpy 143 Saunders 141 Total 12,157 Total 12,157 Kaunders 141 SIM MARY REPORT OF VITAL STATISTICS FOR 1914 Total number of deaths 10,735 Total number of births 26,781 Total number of male children 12,779 Total number of female children 14,002 Total number of white children 26,653 Total number of colored children 128 Summary of Marriages and Divorces for 1913 Total number of marriages 12,157 Total number of divorce suits 2,159 Drunkenness 221 Non-support 392 I desertion 452 ( anse for Divorce ( Vnelty 97n </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Anm'al Bulletin No. 1 39 Length of Marriage I' I nder two \ ears &lt; &lt; - --■) Between two years and five years 60.'! Between five years and ten years 486 Between ten years and twenty-five years 207 I 'x-t ween twentv-five yean and fortv vears 25 Between forty years and forty-five years •&gt; Tnknown 64 Xatnre of Decree Number of divorces granted 1,577 Number of divorces dismissed 280 Somber of divorces pending 302 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>