<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00007">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00007</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
The University of Nebraska 

BULLETIN 

or thi 

AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION 

or 

NEBRASKA 

VOL. XIV. AimcLB II. 

T7u Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. 

Br T. L. Lton. 

Distributed April 4, 1902 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
OF 

NEBRASKA 

THE GOVERNING BOARD 

E. ?. FORELL, President, Kearney 
GEO. F. KENOWEK, Wisner 

tN C. RICH, Omaha 
L. TEETERS, Lincoln 
CALKINS, Kearney 
ERNST, Lincoln 

THE STATION OFFICERS 

§ BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman 
LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist 
DALES, M. Ph.. Financial Secretary 

WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk 

THE WORKING STAFF 

A. T. Peters, D. V. M.. Animal Pathologist 
Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist 
Hudson H. Nicholson, M. A., Chemist 
A. L. Haecker. B. Sc., Dairy Husbandman 
Lawrence Bkl'nek, B. Sc., Entomologist 
Ebwin H. Bakbouk. Ph. D., Geologist 
R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist 
0. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer 
G. D. Swezet, M. A., Meteorologist 
A. T. Wiancko, B. Sc., Assistant Agriculturist 
H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman 
J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 
Hknkt B. Slade, B. A , Assistant Chemist 
S. W. Perin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm 

(tm| MCCNTt OF THE UMIVEHSITt) </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. 

By T. L. Lyon. 

Ee present northern limit of winter wheat production in the 
i-Missouri region lies in the State of Nebraska, thus limithe 
output to a portion only of the arable land in the State, 
spring wheat region protruding south from the Dakotas 
laps the winter wheat region to some extent, and thus 
?r wheat and spring wheat are raised side by side. 

The chief condition that discourages winter wheat production 
in northern Nebraska is the dry, cold, winter weather. 
Spring wheat suffers from a number of adverse conditions, due 
mainly to its late ripening. This habit increases the liability 
to injury from chinch bug and grasshopper depredations, and 
especially to injury from dry, hot weather. 

Winter wheat as a crop for Nebraska has enormous possibilities. 
Not only are the large yields of this wheat such as to 
recommend its culture to the farmers of the State, but the quality 
of Nebraska winter wheat gives it a high standing among 
buyers and consumers. The conditions of climate that produce 
a milling wheat of superior excellence are found in the region 
of country bordering on the semi-arid. It is worthy of note 
that the great spring wheat producing region borders on the 
semi-arid belt in the north, while the region that is fast becoming 
the center of winter wheat production occupies a similar 
position' farther south. It is very noticeable that the quality 
of hardness in wheat improves as its culture approaches the 
semi-arid belt. Its advantage over spring wheat is evident in 
its larger yield, when not winterkilled, in its comparative freedom 
from insect depredations, and in the protection it affords 
the soil during a considerable portion of the year. All these 
considerations make it highly desirable to improve our winter 
wheat in hardiness and quality, so as to extend its growth more 
widely throughout the State and to increase its productiveness. 
Improvement in hardiness may be looked for either by the in- 

BULL. 72, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XIV., ART. II. </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
4 

troduction of hardy varieties, by rendering hardier by selection 
varieties already grown, or by a combination of these processes. 
Improvement in quality and productiveness is to besought 
in careful culture, fertile soil and rational selection of 

To these ends this Station has tested, during the last five 
years, one hundred and eighteen varieties of winter wheat, 
many of which are foreign varieties, chiefly from eastern Russia. 
These tests have thus far resulted in selecting a few 
American varieties as especially suited to Nebraska by reason 
of their hardiness. Two of these, Turkish Red, a bearded 
wheat, and Big Frame, a smooth wheat, have been pushed north 
and west by distributing packages of twenty pounds of seed to 
each of nearly four hundred persons living north of the Platte 
river, or west of the 100th meridian. Reports from these attempts 
have been very encouraging, the great majority of 
trials having been successful. 

A number of Russian varieties have shown themselves to be 
very hardy, and it is possible that some of these will furnish 
the foundation tor varieties adapted to the northern portion of 
the State. These Russian wheats are generally late maturing 
sorts, which is a considerable disadvantage in southern Nebraska, 
but farther north this quality is less objectionable, and 
when a variety is sufficiently hardy to endure the winters its 
advantage over spring wheat is proportional lo the difference 
in the time of ripening. 

Wheats from different sections of the country have shown 
decidedly different qualities when sown here from seed of the 
same variety grown at the Experiment Station. Seed from 
more humid regions, but from approximately the same latitude, 
matured later and did not yield so well as native seed, while 
seed from central Kansas matured earlier, and yielded slightly 
better than native seed. The relative hardiness of these alien 
wheats has not been thoroughly tested, there having been but 
two severe winters since they have been grown here. In the 
winter of 1896-97 and again in 1898-99, Turkey wheat from 
Kansas winterkilled almost completely, while Turkish Red 
RIowa and Nebraska survived the winter creditably. Judgrom 
this it would not always be safe to use Kansas-grown </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

TEST OF VARIETIES. 

S &gt;arge number of varieties of winter wheat have been tested 
ig the past five years. Most of these varieties have been 
n first in small amounts to test their hardiness, and later 
ey showed unusual hardiness and if the seed available 
ed they were tested on a larger scale. In all, 118 variebave 
been tested, of which a very small number have 
mstrated their ability to pass successfully through severe 
?rs. Whatever may be the productiveness of a variety, its 
ilness in the long run will depend upon its hardiness; con?ntly 
it must demonstrate its ability to live through win)f 
at least average severity to entitle it to a further tort. 

TESTS DURING 1896-97 

Table I. shows the record of the test for the winter of 1896-97. 
All varieties were planted with a press drill September 

22 or 23. 

TABLE I. 

VARIETY SEED GROWN IN EFFECT OF 
WINTER 
Turkey Bed Iowa Partly killed 
Red May Kansas Entirely killed. . 
White Track Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Emporium Kansas Entirely killed .. 
Bearded Monarch . . Kansas Entirely killed . . 
Dallas Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Extra Early Oakley Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Disaell Kansas Entirely killed .. 
Deitz Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Democrat Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Farquhar Kansas Entirely killed .. 
Early Red Clawson. Kansas Entirely killed .. 
Tbeias. Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Lancaster Kansas Entirely killed .. 
Gold Medal Kansas Entirely killed . 
Rudy Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Velvet Chaff Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Ramsey Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Fulcaster Kansas Entirely killed.. 
Diehl Egyptian ... Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Big English Kansas Entirely killed. . 
Diehl Mediterranean Kansas Entirely killed . . 
Tasmanian Red . . . . Kansas Entirely killed .. 

HELD PI 
ACRE 
13 bushels </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 


Boyer Kansas 

Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 

Jones' Winter Fife. Kansas. 

Fultz Kansas 

Penquit's Velvet 
Chaff Kansas 

Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 

German Emperor. . Kansas. 

Buckeye Kansas 

Valley Kansas 

Big Frame Kansas 

Partly killed.. . . 18.5 bushels 
Entirely killed 

Turkey Kansas 

Currell Kansas 

Partly killed. ... 96 bushels 
Entirely killed 

Zimmerman Kansas 

Andrews' So. 4. ... Kansas. 

Entirely killed. 
Entirely killed. 

Seneca Chief Kansas 

Dawson's Golden 

Chaff Canada 

Entirely killed. 

The winter of 1896-97 was a 

severe one on winter wheat. 

The ground was bare of snow .most of the time, which produced 
a condition too severe for even the Canadian wheat. Most of 
the wheats had been grown in Kansas for at least one year before 
this test, which would perhaps make them more susceptible 
to the cold. It will be noticed that there was Turkish Red 
or Turkey wheat from Iowa and Kansas, and that the Kansas 

seed killed out entirely. 

TESTS DURING 1897-98. 

During the winter 1897-98, only Turkish Red, Big Frame and 

Currell varieties were grown. They were drilled in September 

14 and yielded as follows 

TABLE II. 


PER ACRB 

Turkish Red 21.4 

BigFrame 18J 

Curivll 18.1 

The wheats did not winterkill, but were badly infested with 
chinch bugs, which occasioned the low yields. Owing to this 
fact the significance of the test as far as yields are concerned 

TESTS DURING 1898-99. 

Re fall of 1898 a very considerable number of varieties of 
wheat were sown. These wheats were supplied through 
A. Carleton, Cefrealist of the U. S. Department of Agri- </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

culture. The seed planted had been grown for at least one year 

in Kansas, but many of them were of Russian origin. In the 

table of results, under the head of "origin", is given,so far as 

known, the place where the seed was grown previous to its 

life in Kansas. The amount of seed of each was too small to 

permit of an accurate estimate of the rate of yield. The winter 

was the most severe experienced in this region since records 

have been kept by the U. S. Weather J3ureau. The seed was 

drilled by hand on September 20. 

TABLE III. 

VARIETY ORIGIN EFFECT OT 

ORIGIN 

WINTER 

Ghirka Winter Russia. Province of Kharkov. .. Partly killed. 

harvested 

No name ... Entirely killed 

No name Jones, Newark, NY Entirely killed 

Early Arcadian Jones, Newark, N. Y Entirely killed 

Pedigree Early Gene- 

see Giant Entirely killed 

Jones' Winter Fife Jones, Newark. N. Y Entirely killed 

Golden Cross Jones, Newark, N. Y Kntirely killed 

Standard Jones, Newark, N. Y Kutirely killed 

Eariy White Leader. . Jones, Newark, N. Y Entirely killed 

Surprise Jones, Newark, N. Y Kntirely killed 

Early Bed Clawson . . . Jones, Newark, N. Y • Entirely killed 

Bearded Winter Southeast Russia. Entirely killed 

Dattel America Entirely killed 

Bordeaux France Entirely killed 

Genealogic White Russia Entirely killed 

Pulavka Russia Entirely killed 

Champion Russia Entirely killed 

Vyssoko-LitoTsk Poland Entiiely killed 

Swedish Russia .. Entirely killed 

Egyptian Russia Entirely killed 

Theiss Orlora Entirely killed 

Champlain Russia. Knt rely killed 

Chiddam de Mars Russia. Entirely killed 

h( D'Arblay's 1 
\ Hungarian, }¦ Australia Entirely killed 
( Improved Fife \ 

Boyer Entirely killed 

Clawson Entirely killed 

¦D'Eautomne ] 
Sdtt' Entire.ykn.ed 
from Australia J 

Early May Entirely killed </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 


American New Mexico Entirely killed 

Banatka Southwest Russia Entirely killed 

Pringle's No. 5 New Mexico Entirely killed 

Nigger Kansas Entirely killed 

Walker Kansas Entirely killed 

Russian Hard New Mexico Entirely killed 

Gold Drop Entirely killed 

Theiss Kursk, Russia Entirely killod 

Budapest Hungary Entirely killed 

Crimean Crimea Entirely killed 

Triticam — American Entirely killed 

Darnma Japan Entirely killed 

Nashi India Entirely killed 

Farquhar Entirely killed 

Don Podolia, Russia Entirely killed 

Arnold's Hybrid Kansas Entirely killed 

Canadian Wonder. ... Kansas Entirely killed 

Big English Entirely killed 

Coryell Entirely killed 

Buckeye Kansas Entirely killed 

China Red New Mexico Entirely killed 

Fuliz Kansas Entirely killed 

White Kalinovka Entirely killed 

Tangarotto Italy Entirely killed 

California Walker Entirely killed 

Quartz New Mexico Entirely killed 

Red Bearded Russia. Entirely killed 

Long Berry Kansas Entirely killed 

Mennonite New Mexico Entirely killed 

German Amber Entirely killed 

Zimmerman Kansas Entirely killed 

Early Ripe New Mexico Entirely killed 

Earnhardt New Mexico Entirely killed 

Daruma Entirely killed 

Turkey Missouri Entirely killed 

Red Winter Samara, Russia Entirely killed 

Red Winter Poltava, Russia Entirely killed 

Russian English America Entirely killed 

Genealogic Red Russia... Entirely killed 

Golden Premium New Mexico Entirely killed 

China White New Mexico Entirely killed 

Prolifero Italy..... Entirely killed 

¦D'Arblay's T 
Hungarian, 
Improved Fife, V Entirely killed 
on French 
Early White J 

Alsace Entirely killed 

Vyssoko-Litovsk Russia Entirely killed </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
9 

Gliirka Winter Russia Partly killed. 

harvest.-.) 

Xx Russia Partly killed. 

harvested 

Theiss Entirely killed 

Crimean Entirely killed 

Re. I Winter Entirely killed 

Re. 1 Bearded Entirely killed 

Turkish Red and Big Frame varieties were sown on a larger 

scale. Chinch bug depredations cut down the yields of these 

to a great extent, and the damage not being uniform entirely 

destroyed the value of the test. 

Drilled September 20. 

VARIETY 

BUSHELS PER 
ACBE 

Turkish Red 28 5 

Big Frame 15 5 

TEST DURING 1899-1900. 

During the winter of 1899-1900 the test of varieties was con- 

tinued. Many of those planted the preceding year were again 

tested, seed from the same source being used, except the six 

varieties that produced seed. Of these the new seed was used. 

As only small quantities of seed were available it was not at- 

tempted to determine the yield per acre. All varieties were 

planted on September 8 

TABLE IV. 

VARIETY EFFECT OF RUST LODGED DATE OF 

WINTER RIPENING 

Egyptian Entirely killed 

Theiss Entirely killed 

Chaniplain Entirely killed 

Chiddam de Mars Entirely killed 

Pringle's No. 5 Partly killed. ... Much.. None.. July 8 

Russian Hard Uninjured Much . None.. June 80 

Crimean Uninjured Much.. None.. June X 

Nashi. : Partly killed Little.. None.. June SB 

Farquhar Entirely killed 

Zimmerman Partly killed Little.. None.. June 88 

(From) Jones, Newark, 
NY Partly killed Little.. None.. July 8 

GoldMedal Entirely killed 

Seneca Chief Entirely killed 

Big English Entirely killed </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


Jones' Winter Fife. ... Entirely killed. 

Bed May Entirely killed 

Early Genesee Giant.. Entirely killed. 

Ghirka Winter Uninjured Little.. None.. July 7 

Early Arcadia Entirely killed 

Dattel Entirely killed 

Bordeaux Entirely killed 

Genealogic White Entirely killed 

Pulavka Entirely killed 

Champion Entirely killed 

Vyitoko-Litovsk Entirely killed 

Swedish Entirely killed 

Ghirka Winter Partly killed. ... Little.. None.. July 

Yx Uninjured Much.. None.. July 

The U. S. Department of Agriculture sent to be tested four 

varieties of Hungarian winter wheat. The followiner state- 

ment regarding is^made* in Inventory No. S.^Section of 

Seed and Plant Introduction. 

"This shipment comprises four of the* best known of the 

Hungarian hard winter wheats. These wheats are the quali- 

from which the higher grades of flour are made at Buda- 

pest. Hungary is about the only European country which ex- 

ports flour, and therefore comes into competition with America 

in this commodity. Experts on the stock exchange at Buda- 

pest claim that some of the Hungarian hard winter wheats pro- 

duce a better grade of flour than do the best American wheats. 

This, however, is doubtful. These varieties are worthy of 

careful trial wherever the winters are mild enough to permit 

of the growth of winter wheats. Of the varieties included in 

this shipment the Banat and Theim are the best known. Both 

varieties have a large quantity of gluten of a high quality. It 

is doubtful whether the names applied to Hungarian wheats, 

such as Thews and Banat, really represent distinct varieties of 

wheats. They are rather to be considered as indicating the lo- 

cality from which the wheat was obtained, and these numbers 

may consist of a mixture of varieties. They probably differ 

somewhat in different localities." 

These wheats were planted in the same way as the above, 

but owing to their late arrival not until October 27, 

TABLE v. 

VARIETY ErrECT OF BUST LODGED DATE OF 

WINTEK RIPENING 

Weissenburg Nearly ail killed. Little.. Partly. July 

Banat Nearly all killed. Little.. None.. July 7 

Theiss Nearly all killed. Little.. None.. July 7 

Pester Boden Entirely killed </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

The late planting placed these wheats at a disadvantage as 
far as the effect of winter was concerned. 

During the same winter several other varieties were tested 
on a larger scale, among these being the Turkish Red, Big 
Frame and Currell, which had proven so hardy in previous 
years. Quite a large acreage of these was grown to furnish 
seed for the co-operative tests by residents in the northern and 
western portions of the State. A few varieties were received 
from the U. S Department of Agriculture, which on account 
of the fact that they had been successfully grown in Russia 
under cttpatic conditions somewhat similar to those of this 
region were considered deserving of a careful test here. They 
were drilled in September 11. The results were as follows: 

TABLE VI. 

VARIETT 

RUST 

LODGED DATE OF HELD PER 

RIPENING AI'RE 

Turkish Red Little... 

None June 27. 33 bushels 

Big Frame . . . . , Little 

None June 26. 34 bushels 

Currell Little.. 

None.... June 26. 25 bushel* 

Yaro6l»T' Little.. 

None July 2. 22 bushels 

Yaroslar 2 Little 

None.... July 2. 26 bushels 

Banat* Killed out entirely during the winter. 

Sandomir* Little None July 2. 18 bushels 

i From the government of YaroalaT. 
'From tbe government of St. Petersburg. 

'From Russia, but Introduced there from Hungary. 
• Winterkilled to some extent. 

TESTS DURING 1900-1901 

Ethe fall of 1900 only those varieties were planted that had 
ved the winter of 1899-1900. The number was thus cut 
very considerably, but no variety was discarded until 
two years' trial. The quantity of seed was still too small 
rmit of determining the yield per acre. All were planted 

TABLE VII. 

VARIETY 

EFFECT OF 

RUST LODGED DATE OF 

RIPENING 

WINTER 

Pringle's No. 5 Uninjured Little.. None.. June J7 

Russian Hard Uninjured Mueh.. Badly. June J» </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 

The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat 

Crimean Uninjured Much.. Badly. June 29 

Nashi Uninjured Some.. Slightly Jane 37 

Zimmerman Uninjured Little. . None. . Jane 27 

¦ Jones, Newark, 
V Uninjured Little.. None.. June 29 

Ghirka Winter Uninjured Little.. None.. June 20 

Gbirka Winter Uninjured Little.. None.. Jane 29 

Tz Uninjured Little. None.. JomM 

Some other winter wheats received from the U. S. Depart- 

ment of Agriculture were tested. These were all of foreign 

origin and had not been grown here before except three of the 

Hungarian wheats, of which the home-grown seed was planted 

at this time, but of the Pester Boden variety that killed out 

completely during the winter of 1899-1900 the original seed 


Extremely hot weather at time of ripening caused the wheats 

harvested this year and especially the later ones to reach the 

cutting stage prematurely. They have, therefore, not changed 

as greatly in time of ripening as would be indicated by the rec- 

ords. They were planted September 17. 

TABLE VIII. 

VARIETY EFFECT OF RD8T LODGED DATE OK 

WINTER KIPEMNK 

Weiaeenburg Uninjured Little.. Slightly June 29 

Banat Uninjured Little.. Slightly June &gt;7 

Theiss Uninjured Little.. None. . June 39 

Pester Boden Uninjured Little.. None. . . Jane 29 

Steinwedel Entirely killed 

Budapest Uninjured None.. None... Jane 27 

Early Baart Entirely killed 

King'sEarly Entirely killed •. 

Canning Downs Entirely killed 

Pootung Uninjured None.. None... June 21 

Other varieties were sown on larger plots and the yields as- 


TABLE IX. 

VARIETY RLST LODGED DATE OF . YIELD PER 

RIPENING ACRE 

Turkish Red Little None June 96 89 bushels 

Big Frame Little None June 24 84 bushels 

Currell Little None June 24 23 bushels 

Yaroslav 1 Little None July 1 80 bushels 

Yaroalav* Little... None July 1 28 bushels 

B«ifrw ir Little None July 1 18 bushels 

i From the government of Y»rosl»T. </seg>


            <seg id="p013">
13 

A quite extensive and fairly accurate test of the comparative 
merits of the Turkish Red and Big Frame varieties was made 
for the northern and western portions of the State by the distribution 
of seed of these two varieties in those regions. By 
taking only those counties in which both varieties were grown 
and comparing the total results for each variety we have a 
comparatively fair method of comparison, the weak point being 
the fact that each variety was tested by a different person and 
hence there is no assurance that the conditions were the same, 
but it is expected that the large number of tests will largely 
counterbalance this source of error. 

The subjoined table of results is made up from the results 
of tests of each variety in the following counties : Antelope, 
Boone, Buffalo, Burt, Cedar, Colfax, Cuming, Custer, Dawson, 
Deuel, Dixon, Dodge, Garfield, Greeley, Holt, Howard. Merrick, 
Pierce, Platte, Stanton, Valley. 

table x. 

NUMBER OF NUMBER PER CENT AVERAGE VIELP 

VARIETT TE8TS WINTER- WINTE - PER ACRE 

KILLED KILLED IN BUSHELS 

Turkish Red 59 7 12.0 21.5 

Big Frame 104 10 9.6 18.2 

These figures would indicate that the Big Frame wheat was 
somewhat hardier, but that the Turkish Red was more prolific. 

A comparison of these results with those obtained at the Station 
through a period of five years shows a pretty close agreement 
as far as yield is concerned. 

TABLE XI. 

VARIETY YIELD IN BUSHELS PER ACRE 

1897 1808 1899 1900 1901 Avenge 

Turkish Red 12 31.4 88.8 88 80 »l 

Big Frame 18.5 13.5 15.5 84 84 .'8 1 

Currell »6 16.1 .... 95 38 184 

TESTS OF WHEATS IN NORTHERN AND WESTERN NEBRASKA. 

In the fall of 1900, three hundred and sixty-seven samples of 
wheats of the Big Frame and Turkish Red varieties were sent </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. 

Sies living north of the Platte river or west of the 100th 
in. Each experimenter received twenty pounds of 
and agreed to plant and care for it, threshing it sepafrom 
his other grain, and to report upon the following 
connected with its growth. 

¦ Sown on upland or bottom land? 
Depth to water? 

3. Nature of soil, i. e., clay, gumbo, loam, sandy loam, or 

4. Nature of subsoil? 

¦ Is there any alkali present? 
Is the soil light or heavy? 

¦ Method of preparing the soil for this crop? 
Depth of plowing (if plowed)? 

¦ Previous crop? 
Date of sowing? 

I Amount of seed per acre? 
Good or poor stand in fall? 

¦ Protection by windbreak or snow during winter? 
Condition in spring? 

15. Date of ripening? 

¦ Did it rust, smut, or lodge? 
Date of cutting? 

18. Yield of threshed grain per acre? 

P Comparison with other varieties raised by you or in 
vicinity? 

20. Remarks. 

The nuinber of reports available for use in computing results 
from these tests was 194. The accompanying table shows the 
number of tests, the number of cases in which the wheat was 
destroyed by winterkilling, and the average yield per acre for 
each variety in each county in which the tests were made. 
Plantings later than October 1 were not included among the 
list of losses by winterkilling, but the omissions from^this 
cause were very few. Average yieldsjper acre were found'by 
dividing the sum of all yields reported for any variety^in a 
county by the n amber of such reports. </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
15 

TABLE 

XII 


COUNTY VARIETY OF WINTER- TIBLD PEB 

TESTS KILLED ACRB 

Antelope Turkish Red I 1 24 

&gt; 

Big Frame 6 1 17 

Boone Turkish Red 8 0 2» 

Big Frame 3 0 » 

Boyd Big Frame 1 0 

Brown Big Frame 1 0 

Buffalo Turkish Red 3 1 

Big Frame 18 0 14 

Bort Turkish Red I 0 ¦ 
Big Frame 1 0 * 

Big Frame 1 0 *J 

Cedar Turkish Red 3 1 9 

Cedar Turkish Red 3 1 9 

Big Frame 2 0 1 

Big Frame 2 0 18 

Cheyenne Big Frame 1 0 -&gt;&lt;) 

Cheyenne Big Frame 1 0 -» 

Colfax Turkish Red 3 0 
Big Frame 7 0 3 

Colfax Turkish Red 3 0 ¦ 

Big Frame 7 0 37 

Cuming Turkish Red 1 0 
Big Frame 3 0 I 

Cuming Turkish Red 1 0 

Big Frame 3 0 J"&gt; 

Caster . . Turkish Red 6 1 87 

Caster . . Turkish Red 6 1 -'7 

Big Frame 18 4 8 

Big Frame 18 4 81 

Dawson Turkish Red 9 1 87 

Dawson Turkish Red 9 1 87 

Big Frame 11 0 .' 

Big Frame 11 0 .&gt;.' 

Deuel Turkish Red 1 0 
Big Frame 1 0 

Big Frame 1 0 

Dixon Turkish Red 1 0 87 

Dixon Turkish Red 1 0 27 

Big Frame 1 0 

Big Frame 1 0 8 

Dodge Turkish Red 4 0 1» 
Big Frame I 3 I 

Dodge Turkish Red 4 0 1» 

Big Frame I 2 *2 

Douglas Big Frame 4 1 84 

Douglas Big Frame 4 1 24 

Dandy Big Frame 1 0 

Dandy Big Frame 1 0 4 

Furnas Big Frame '-' 0 

Garfield Turkish Red 3 1 • 

Big Frame 3 0 10 

Greeley Turkish Red 1 0 -»0 

Big Frame S 2 18 

Hall Big Frame 8 0 18 

Hayes Big Frame 1 o 

Hitchcock Big Frame 2 0 

Holt Turkish Red 1 0 

Big Frame 4 0 10 

Howard Turkish Red 5 0 .'4 

Big Frame 4 0 IS 

Knox Bisr Frame 8 0 18 

Loup Big Frame 1 0 20 

Madison Big Frame 1 0 ¦ </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 


Merrick Turkish Red 

I 

M 

0 

Big Frame 8 0 18 

Pierce Turkish Red 1 0 16 

Big Frame. . . . 

¦&gt; 

0 

U 

Plstte Turkish Red 4 0 27 

Big Frame. 

H 

0 

M 

Redwillow Big Frame 

1 

1 

Sheridan Big Frame 1 0 

Sherman Big Frame 

I 

0 

I 

Sioux Big Frame. 

1 

0 

N 

Stanton Turkish Red 1 0 

Big Frame . . 1 0 

Vallev Turkish Red. . 

I 

1 

U 

Big Frame. 

I 

1 

in 

Washington Big Frame 1 0 

Total 1M 19 

The distribution of winter wheat was made with two objects 
in view, namely, to help ascertain the possibilities of winter 
wheat culture in thut portion of the State lying north of the 
Platte river and that lying west of the 100th meridian, and also 
to encourage experimental attempts to raise winter wheat in 
those regions. 

The latter object is being attained in a very marked degree, 
as practically all those who made the test are planting the seed 
again this year. In addition, large numbers of farmers have 
planted wheat this year for the first time. There is great danger 
that the industry will receive a setback should the winter 
prove a severe one resulting in the loss of large areas of wheat. 
The adaptation of winter wheat to parts of that region cannot 
&amp; accomplished at once and should not be attempted on a 
;e scale by single individuals with the belief that they have 
id a sure crop for all seasons. 

As far as the attempt to gauge the possibilities of winter 
wheat growing is concerned, that cannot be determined by one 
year's test, but something has been learned, and a beginning 
has been made by furnishing the Station with a corps of competent 
volunteer experimenters who are provided with winter 
wheat of known origin, and who are disposed to continue its 
culture. In time, the results obtained by these persons will 
throw much light on the subject. 

The results of the first winter, as shown in the table, are </seg>


            <seg id="p017">
17 

very encouraging. Of the 194 tests reported, there were only 
nineteen cases of complete loss by winterkilling. Some of 
these were doubtless due to lack of moisture in the fall. Tests 
were made in thirty-eight counties north of the Platte river or 
west of the 100th meridian. In only one county was there a 
complete failure, and in that county only one trial was made. 

IMPROVEMENT BY ADAPTATION. 

Undoubtedly the ideal winter wheat for Nebraska is yet to be 
developed. Whether some of the varieties now in use, like the 
"Turkish Red", will form the basis for the improved wheat 
or whether some of the Russian wheats will be found best 
adapted to this region cannot be foretold. It seems probable 
that varieties of somewhat different characteristics will be required 
in different portions of the State. The northern portion 
will require a hardier variety than the southern, and the 
western a more strongly drought-resistant variety than the 
eastern. Early maturity is a desirable characteristic everywhere, 
but becomes of more importance as wheat culture proceeds 
southward and westward. 

That much can be done towards adapting some of the commonly-grown 
varieties to portions of the State not generally 
considered in the winter wheat area has already been demonstrated. 
One of the most promising varieties for this purpose 
is the so-called Turkey Red or Turkish Red or Turkey. The 
three names doubtless represent a wheat of the same local origin, 
namely, the Crimea. It is grown extensively in Iowa, 
Kansas and Nebraska, and even farther east. As its original 
habitat resembles in some climatic conditions the trans-Missouri 
country, the characteristics that favored it in the Crimea 
have made it useful here. It has, however, exhibited ouite a 
tendency towards variation, and in the different regions in 
which it has been cultivated shows markedly different habits 
of growth. An experiment designed to show the difference between 
representative samples of this variety from different sections 
of the country was carried on at this Station in 1899-1900 
and in 1900-01. Turkish Red seed wheat was obtained from the 
Ohio Experiment Station in eastern Ohio, the Iowa Station in 
central Iowa, and through the Kansas Station there was obtain- </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 


ed a sample from central Kansas. These samples and one of 
Turkish Red wheat that had been grown at this Station for 
three years vrere sown on contiguous plots of land. The record 
of growth shows a great difference in the habits of these 
four strains of what was without doubt originally the same variety 
of wheat. That the Nebraska and Iowa seed were originally 
the same is certain, for the Nebraska seed had been obtained 
from the Iowa Station three years before. 

TABLE XIII. 

Kansas Nebraska Iowa Ohio 

Yield of grain per acre.. 29.1 bu. 27.5 bu. 
Weight of grain per bu.. 64.2 lbs. 62.2 lbs. 

22.8 bu. 23 1l.il 
56.91bs. 58.91bs 

Ee winter of 1899-1900 was a very favorable one here for 
&gt;r wheat and a comparison of the stand in fall and spring 
ed that there was no appreciable loss from winterkilling. 

The Iowa and Ohio wheats rusted and lodged badly, while 
the Nebraska and Kansas wheats did not suffer in this way. 
The Kansas wheat ripened a little earlier than the Nebraska 
and both of these before the Iowa and Ohio wheats. There 
was eight days difference between the earliest and latest ripening 
grain. The yield and weight of grain seemed to depend 
upon early ripening. 

All of these differences in growth of wheat from different 
States, but of the same variety, denote a ready tendency towards 
variation which enables the plant to adapt itself to its 
new environment. 

The possibility of adapting a variety of winter wheat to regions 
of more severe winters is thus indicated. Such adaptation 
has actually been going on for a number of years, which 
may in some measure account for the fact that winter wheat is 
now being grown in portions of Nebraska where twenty years 
ago it was considered an impossible crop. Wheat planted in 
a locality where the winter weather is more severe than that 

Date of sowing 
Stand in fall 
Stand in spring 
Date of ripening 

SKED 
Sept. 9 
Good 
Good 
None 
Very little 
June 25 

Sept. 9 
Good 
Good 
None 
Very little 
June 27 

SKEIl 
Sept. 9 
Good 
Good 
Badly 
Much 
July 2 

Milch </seg>


            <seg id="p019">
19 

to which it has been accustomed will ordinarily winterkill 
more or less. This may be enough to produce a practical failure 
of the crop or it may not, but the plants that do survive 
may become the basis of a hardier strain of wheat and the more 
severe the season the more valuable for seed are the plants 
that are left. This should be borne in mind when one is in the 
act of deciding whether to plow up in the sprinsr a field of 
winter wheat that has been badly winterkilled. Consider 
whether you can get seed that has survived such weather when 
you come to sow next fall. 

THE SOURCE OF SEED SUPPLY 

Eher point brought out by this experiment is the fact 
e locality from which seed is brought will make a very 
lifference in the success of the crop the first year. The 
ice in the latitude of the various localities from which 
the wheats were brought was not great, but there was considerable 
difference in the amount of annual rainfall in these regions. 


Etie winter hardiness of the plants cannot be said to have 
1 tested, as the winter was a very favorable one and all 
e through successfully. The characteristics that produced 
differences in yield were, time of ripening, ability to withid 
rust, to r«main erect, and possibility to utilize economicthe 
available moisture in the soil. 

The wheats from more humid regions were obviously at a 
disadvantage, and this is undoubtedly worth considering when 
purchasing seed wheat. Whether on the other hand there is 
an advantage in bringing seed from regions of less rainfall has 
not been demonstrated. 

rOVEMENT OF WHEAT BY SELECTING LARGE, HEAVY 
KERNELS FOR SEED. 

In 1896 the Nebraska Experiment Station began an attempt 
to improve the quality and yield of wheat by selecting for seed 
kernels of more than average specific gravity. To select these 
kernels and separate them from the lighter ones a solution of 
calcium chloride in water was used. The solution was suffi- </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 


ciently dense so that when the grain was thrown upon it about 
half of the kernels floated and the other half sank. Those 
that floated were, of course, the light kernels and those that 
sank were the heavy. This method of separation accomplished 
the desired object, but was slow and cumbersome. An attempt 
was then made to use an ordinary seed fanning mill for the 
purpose, but it was found difficult to get a sufficient wind velocity 
to make an equal separation of the grain. After repeated 
attempts to get the plan on a practical basis a machine was discovered 
that was originally intended for a different purpose 
but which accomplished the separation satisfactorily and rapidly 
and which after undergoing some modifications is now being 
manufactured especially for this purpose. Another machine 
is now manufactured that is claimed to accomplish the 
same end. 

The machine operates by directing upwards a current of air, 
the velocity of which can be regulated. Into this current the 
grain is directed. The result is that the heavy kernels and the 
large kernels fall, and the light and small kernels are driven 
out. The separation thus accomplished is somewhat different 
from that effected by a solution, the difference being that the 
latter separates the kernels entirely according to their specific 
gravity while with the air blast a large kernel of a certain 
specific gravity might descend with the heavy kernels, when 
if it were smaller although of the same specific gravity it would 
be blown out. 

The number of light kernels that descend on account of their 
large size is relatively small owing to the fact that large kernels 
are as a rule of higher specific gravity than small. The 
following test was made to determine the relation between the 
size of wheat kernels and their specific gravity. An average 
lot of wheat was nearly equally divided by means of two sieves 
into three portions representing medium, small and large kernels. 
Each of these portions was then thrown upon solutions 
of the same specific gravity, and the proportion by weight 
that floated, or light seed, and the proportion that sank, or 
heavy seed, was determined. </seg>


            <seg id="p021">
21 

TABLE 

XIV. 

LKiHT, KATIil 

CKAMS , HEAVY: 1MB 
I1.M 1 : 1.29 

Smmll 

Medium 9.62. 

10.7N 1 : 1.1* 

Large 11.96. 

8.04 1 : 0.87 

The weight of light kernels 

among the small was nearly 

twice that of light kernels among the large seeds 

¦ring the last two years a number of experiments have 
made to ascertain the effect of this practical selection of 
, heavy seed upon the yield and quality. 

In the fall of 1899 a quantity of Turkish Red winter wheat 
grown at the Station and cleaned in the fanning mill was separated 
by the air current into two approximately equal portions. 
Each of these oortions was again run through the air 
current. Of the heavy portion the heavy kernels obtained on 
second treatment were retained and designated ''Heavy 
wheat". Of the light portion the light kernels obtained on 
second treatment were retained and designated "Light 
wheat". These were planted on adjacant plots of land and beside 
them was planted the same variety of wheat but not treated 
otherwise than being cleaned in the fanning mill. The 
yields were as follows : 

TABLE XV 

YIELD 1-EK ACBE 

KIND OF SEED 

Heavy 29.5 bushels 

27. 5 bushels 


Light 28.0 bushels 

In the fall of 1900 a sample of the crop grown as "Heavy 
wheat" was separated into approximately equal parts by the 
air current, and th« heavier portion again separated, the 
heavier portion being retained and called "Heavy wheat." 
The crop grown as "Light wheat" was similarly separated, 
but the lighter portion was retained in each case. This was 
called "Light wheat". The two portions thus secured were 
planted on adjacant plots of land, as was also some of the 
wheat grown from the "Ordinary wheat" which seed was not 
treated except to clean with the fanning mill. The yields in 
1901 were as follows : 

KIND OF SKED HEAVY, 
UK A MS </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


TABLE XVI. 

KIND Or 8EED 

TIELD PER ACRE 

Heavy 29.3 bushels 

Ordinary 26.0 bushels 


26.7 bushels 

In order to verify the experiment with Turkish Red wheat a 

similar test was made both years with the variety known as 

Big Frame. The method of procedure was exactly the same 

as that above recorded. The yields in 1900 were as follows : 

TABLE 

XVII. 

KIM&gt; OK HD 

YIELD PER ACRE 

H.-avv 

25.1 bushels 


23.8 bushels 

Light 20.5 bushels 

The yields in 1901 were: 

TABLE XVIII 

KIND OF SEED YIELD PEK ACRE 

Heavy 27.7 bi; 
Ordinary 25.8 bushels 

Light 21.2 bushels 

The average yields for both varieties for each of the two 

years is as follows : 

TABLE XIX. 

YIELD IN TIELD IN 

1900 1901 

Heavy 27 3 bushels 28.5 bushels 

Ordinary 26.7 bushels 25.9 bushels 

Light- 21.8 bushels 23.9 bushels 

This shows an actual improvement from one year to the 

other in the yield of wheat and a still larger relative increase 

as compared with the ordinary seed. 

This is a rational method for improving the yield and quality 

of wheat, especially when used as auxiliary to selection and 

breeding of individual plants. It offers the farmer a simple 

and practical method for improving his seed. It will be givnn 

a continued trial at this Station, and an attempt will be made 

to determine what proportion of the wheat it is desirable to 

discard on account of lightness and smallness of kernel. </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat 

23 

Summary. 

Ejthe'l 18^ varieties of winter wheat tested during the last 
years, Turkish Red and Big Frame have — hardiness and 
I considered — been the best. 

In 194 tests of these two varieties during 1900-1901 in counties 
north of the Platte river or west of the 100th meridian, Turkish 
Bed yielded better, but Big Frame proved to be somewhat 

Of the 194 tests in the region above described, there were 
nineteen cases of complete loss by winterkilline. 

Eae Russian varieties of wheat tested indicate great hardiand 
promise well for fche northern portion of the State, 
ially if they can be made to mature earlier. 

Ee selection of large, heavy kernels for seed resulted, on 
whole, in increasing substantially the yield over seed 
.t not so selected. 

Wheats of the same variety, but grown in different portions 
of the country, when grown side by side showed much difference 
in their habits of growth, which were greatly to the disadvantage 
of the seed grown east of the Missouri river. 

Bi tendency shown by these alien wheats to adapt themi 
to local conditions when grown here for a number of 
encourages the hope that Nebraska-grown seed may beadapted 
to all arable portions of the State. 

The yields of these wheats were nearly proportional to their 
tendency to early maturity. 

Ksas-grown seed matured earliest and yielded best, but 
y winterkilled when Nebraska- and Iowa-grown seed of 
ne variety passed the winter successfully. 

Accepted for publication February 12, 1902. 

Errata 

Yx should read Red Winter on pp. 9, 10, 12. 
Red Winter should read Yx on p. 9. </seg>


         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>