<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Beef Production</title>
               <date value="1919-09">1919-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 174 Sqriember, 1919 Beef Production H. J. GRAMLICH HIGH GAINER IN LOT 3 This steer gained 486 pounds in 130 days on a ration of gi ound corn, ground alfalfa and cottonseed cake. AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION BULLETIN 173 ■n and one part of oil meal, and the average lamb will take in the neighborhood of 1.75 pounds of corn and about .5 pound of oil meal. The hay consumed is negligible, usually running about .33 pound daily. To ascertain the advisability and economy of the above method of feeding, lot 8 in this trial was fed practically as indicated above. The lambs in this lot were marketed at the end of 40 days, owing to their high degree of condition at that time. By comparing these lambs with those in lot 1, fed on straight corn and alfalfa in the usual manner, and with those in lot 5, fed on corn and oil meal together with alfalfa hay, we find a consider - ably greater daily gain in these self-feeder lambs, their gain being slightly over .5 pound. "We find a daily feed consumption of 1.33 pounds of corn, 1.05 pounds of oil meal and .35 pound of prairie hay, showing that the hay consumption is very low in contrast to that consumed in the other two lots and the oil meal con - sumption runs very high. The feed required to produce one pound of gain is shown to be 2.65 pounds of corn, 2.09 pounds of oil meal and .72 pound of prairie hay. a total of 5.46 pounds, which contains a considerably higher percentage of grain con - centrate than was consumed in lot 1 or lot 5. The proportion of grain and concentrate to hay in these three lots is of interest In the self-feeder lot, 6.6 pounds of grain were consumed to each pound of hay. In lot 1, 1.32 pounds of grain to each pound of hay, and in lot 5, 1.33 pounds of grain to one pound of hay. The cost of 100 pounds of gain under this method of feeding was found to be $7.34 which is almost $2 per hundred higher than that of any of the other lots fed in this experiment. The profit is as a result somewhat less, being but $1.45. From this trial it will be seen that while the above method has an advantage in the fattening of the lambs quickly, it is not as economical as the other methods of feeding outlined and it is not to be recommended un - less a man is desirous of putting a high degree of finish upon his lambs in a very short time. Subsequent trials to the one given here and the experience of practical feeders has shown that the lambs fed in this manner for a period exceeding 50 days are subject to sudden death possibly from apoplexy due to the exceed - ingly large amount of protein in their ration. Tn this trial there was no sickness and no lambs went off feed and the 28 head at the close of the test were carrying a uniformly high degree of finish. [8 M] </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY I. The addition of 1.71 pounds of cottonseed nut cake to a corn and alfalfa ration failed to increase the rate of daily gain, but did increase the feed required per pound gain by .80 pound and the cost of 100 pounds of gain by $2.16. It also decreased the profit $2.C5 per steer. (Lots 1 and 2.) II. The grinding of corn and alfalfa when fed in conjunc - tion with cottonseed nut cake gave a .32 pound per day larger gain at a materially reduced cost per 100 pounds gain, namely $2.08, and increased the profit per head from $5.56 to $11. It also reduced the pork produced per steer from 42.6 pounds to 28.9 pounds. (Lots 2 and 3.) III. The feeding of snapped corn, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa hay in comparison to shelled corn, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa hay gave a slightly greater daily gain and a $5 cheaper cost per 100 pounds of gain. The feeding of the snapped corn gave, exclusive of pork, a profit of $13.87, in comparison to $1.26 loss where shelled corn was fed; and inclusive of pork, a profit of $10.85 in comparison to $5.56. (Lots 2 and 4.) IV. The feeding of a heavy silage ration did not produce as much finish as the feeding of corn in conjunction with cot - tonseed nut cake and alfalfa, but did result in considerable fleshing and a market price which left a margin of profit. The margin of profit per steer amounted to $1.49, in spite of the fact that the sales price was $1 per 100 pounds less than where the steers received a heavy feed of corn. (Lots 2 and 5.) </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bci,i.etin 174 Feed cost per steer Returns $170.09 $168.78 $177.16 $167.19 $144.18 Value of pork per steer (•• 16cj $6.22! $6.82 $4.62 $5.98 **$3.17 Profit, including pork, per steer 8.21 5.56 11.00 19.85 7.05 Shrink in transit, lbs. per steer 28 IS 13 18 50 Dressing percentage, cold 60.69J 57.29 59.85 59.27 58.48 'Shelled corn substituted for snapped corn during last 22 days, since snapped corn w.is no longer available. "The pigs in this lot received shelled corn, the value of which has been deducted. April 1 to April 8 1.05 4.47 4.09 3.60 2.57 Interest (a 7 f ; 2.1f&gt; 2.20 2.18 2.17 2.18 Cost of marketing 2.25 2.25 2.25 2.25 2.25 Total cost (168.10 $170.04 $170.78 $153.32 $140.30 Value per cwt., Omaha $14.50 $14.50 $14.85 $14.50 ~~ $13.50 Omaha weights 1,173 1,164 1,193 1,153 1,068 Profits, exclusive of pork $1.99 —$1.26 $6.38 $13.87 $3.88 Pounds pork per steer 38.9 42.6 28.9 37.4 45.8 ANl.E ii mm (try of a. 'ots Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Lot 5 Number in lot 10 10 10 10 10 Ground Corn corn Snapped Silage Corn Cotton- Cotton- corn* Cotton- RATION Alfalfa seed nut seed cake Cotton- seed nut cake Ground seedcake cake Alfalfa alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight 835.5 837.7 831.5 825.0 830.0 Average final weight 1,195.3 1,170.3 1,203.0 1,168.5 1,115.5 Average gain 359.8 332.6 372.5 343.5 285.5 Average daily gain 2.77 2.56 2.87 2.64 2.20 Average daily ration Corn 18.12 16.56 17.66 *3.54 Snapped corn 16.27 Cottonseed 1.71 1.54 2.09 3.8 Alfalfa 11.75 11.51 8.96 8.12 2.18 Silage 52.05 Feed required per pound gain Com 6.54 6.47 6.15 *1.34 Snapped corn 6.16 Cottonseed .67 .54 .79 1.73 Alfalfa 4.24 4.5 3.12 3.08 .99 Silage 23.66 Cost per 100 pounds gain . ... $21.65 $23.81 $21.73 $18.81 $18.26 Cost per 100 pounds gain Initial cost per steer (« $9.78 $81.71 $81.93 $81.32 $80.69 $81.17 Feed cost per steer 77.90 79.19 80.94 64.61 52.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Beef Production 5 ONE HUNDRED THIRTY DAY CATTLE FEED ING EXPERIMENT, NOVEMBER 22, 1917, TO APRIL 1, 1918 Cattle feeding has gone thru a period of marked changes during the past several years. Methods of feeding which were popular and justifiable a few years ago have been cast aside and others have appeared to supplant them. The practice of feeding heavy cattle followed extensively in the past is no longer to be recommended, on account of changed conditions. The feeding of good cattle has even received a rather severe jolt because of the fact that, due to the war and other outside influences, the market for common cattle has been so good that men feeding this class have actually made larger profits than those who handled good cattle. This is undoubtedly of temporary duration, and when conditions become normal again it is likely that good cattle can be fed as profitably as ever. At the present time the world is facing a rather serious crisis as regards not only the meat supply but likewise the grain supply. There is, without doubt, a big shortage of wheat. To take the place of part of this wheat a great deal of corn, barley, oats and other grains are being used for human consumption. These grains are milled and after such parts as can be used for human consumption have been extracted a certain amount of by-product remains which is prepared and sold for stock - feeding purposes. _ r — t The cattle feeder is urged to produce more beef. At the same time he is being urged to limit his corn feeding, in order that corn may be available for human consumption. As one means of overcoming the grain shortage it has been suggested that heavy steers which formerly were taken out as feeders in the fall be allowed to go to slaughter without finishing on grain. Another suggestion offered was that of feeding less grain and more roughness and by-products. The cattle in the experiment reported in this bulletin were handled in several different ways with the object of ascertain - ing the cheapest possible manner of making beef and at the same time producing the greatest quantity in a given time. CATTLE USED The cattle used in this test were Nebraska grown, originating in the sand hills of Cherry county. They were mostly of Shorthorn and Polled Durham breeding and weighed at the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 time purchased 803 pounds. They were a trifle uneven in size. due to the fact that a portion were well-grown yearlings and the others short 2-year-olds. Their cost on the Omaha market was $9.65. They were allowed to graze in one lot until put on test November 22. At this time their average weight was 830 pounds and the cost into the test was $9.78 per 100 pounds. They proved to be of a very quiet disposition and well adapted in this respect for experimental purposes, as the numerous visitors seemed to bother them very little. TREATMENT PREVIOUS TO EXPERIMENT The cattle were allowed to run in a 15-acre bluegrass pasture from November 3 to November 21. They were fed alfalfa hay once a day in addition. At the opening of the experiment they were divided into five lots of ten each. They were not started on their respective rations until November 22, which was the second of the three initial weigh days. Consequently they carried a uniform fill at the time the test started. RATIONS FED Lot 1. Shelled corn, alfalfa hay. Lot 2. Shelled corn, cottonseed nut cake, alfalfa hay. Lot 3. Ground corn, cottonseed nut cake, ground alfalfa hay. Lot 4. Snapped corn, cottonseed nut cake, alfalfa hay. Lot 5. Corn silage, cottonseed nut cake, alfalfa hay. FEEDS USED The corn used in this experiment was of a fair grade. It is charged to the cattle at $1.40 per bushel. It would have graded upon the market as No. 5 and the price which is charged for it is if anything a shade high, quality considered. The snapped corn fed in lot 4 was of a grade much inferior to the shelled corn fed, it being corn which would not have matured and which was relatively light. It is charged at $1.50 per hundred, which was more than market price for snapped corn of such grade during the period of the experiment. The cottonseed nut cake was of the 37 to 39 per cent protein grade and was in a very hard nut form. The steers did not seem to relish this cake as well as usual, there seeming to be quite a large percentage of hull. The alfalfa hay was of a fair grade. The silage was made from corn which yielded at the rate of five bushels to the ton. It is charged at $10 per ton. The feeds are charged as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Beek Production 7 PIGS USED In this test it was deemed advisable to run only as many pigs as would follow the cattle and gain reasonably well. As the grain ration was increased more pigs were added. After the cattle were on full feed the number of pigs used was: 8 in lot 1. 7 in lot 2. 5 in lot 3, 0 in lot 4, and 4 in lot 5. No additional feed of any kind was allowed the pigs with the exception of those in lot 5. These were given a total of ten pounds of corn per day. This was deemed necessary inas - much as the cattle were receiving no corn in their ration. This corn was charged against the pigs at $1.40 per bushel and the, same deducted from the pork gain made in this lot. FEED YARDS AND EQUIPMENT The cattle weiv fed in lots 21 feet wide and 110 feet long with an open shed at the north end of each, the shed space amounting to 3(50 square feet. The hay racks were under the sheds while the grain bunks were in the open. The floor of the shed was concrete, while most of the lot was unpaved. AVater was kept before the cattle at all times. No heating device was used for this. As the experimental yards were located at the main barn a great many visitors saw these cattle while on test and every day several persons were out in the pens looking over the steers. In spite of this the cattle made a uniformly good gain for the 130-day test. WEATHER CONDITIONS During the time of this experiment, November 22, 1017. to April 1, 1918, the weather was good for feeding purposes, it being a comparatively open winter with but one or two snows and storms. A number of spells of very severe cold weather occurred, but they did not seem to affect the cattle materially. On several occasions the thermometer reached 20 degrees below zero. March was a comparatively warm month and the cattle had shed off quite nicely by the close of the experiment. Shelled corn $ 1.40 per bushel Snapped corn 1.50 per cwt. Cottonseed nut cake 60.00 per ton Alfalfa hay 25.00 per ton Milage 10.00 per ton </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bili-etjx 174 CORN AND ALFALFA HAY VERSUS CORN, ALFALFA HAY AND COTTONSEED NUT CAKE. Lots 1 and 2 Table 2 — Lota 1 and 2 Lot 1 Lot 2 Number in lot 10 10 Corn Cottonseed nut cake Alfalfa Corn Alfalfa RATION Average initial weight . . Average final weight. . . . Average gain Average daily gain . . Average daily ration Corn Snapped corn Cottonseed Alfalfa Silage Feed required per pound gain Corn Snapped corn Cottonseed Alfalfa Silage 6.47 .67 4.5 Cost per 100 pounds gain . $23.81 Initial cost per steer &lt;S $9.78 Feed cost per steer $81.93 79.19 Feed cost per steer, April 1 to April 8 Interest % 1% 4.47 2.19 2.20 Cost of marketing . 2.25 2.25 Total cost. $168.10 $170.04 Value per cwt., Omaha $14.50 1,173 $14.50 1,164 $168.78 Omaha weights Returns $170.09 Profite, exclusive of pork 1.99 —1.26 Pounds pork per steer 38.9 42.6 Value of pork per steer (a 16c $6.22 $6.82 Profit, including pork, per steer $8.21 $5.5t. Shrink in transit, pounds per steer Dressing percentage, cold 28 13 60.69 57.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Beef Production 9 Thru a series of years experimental work conducted at this station has tended to show that a corn and alfalfa ration pro - duced as economical a gain as any ration used, and at the same time a very satisfactory gain. Thinking that the high price, together with the comparatively low quality, of the corn this LOT 1— CORN AND ALFALFA The steers in this lot gained 2.77 pounds daily upon a ration of 8.12 pounds of corn and 11.75 pounds of alfalfa, at a cost per 100 pounds gain of $21.65. The profit per steer was $8.21. year might cause this ration to be somewhat less economical than one in which a protein supplement was supplied, it was deemed advisable to feed one lot cottonseed nut cake in con - junction with corn and alfalfa. This ration was assigned to lot 2. During the first part of the experimental period the steers in lot 2 made a very unsatisfactory gain. They consumed vir - tually as much feed as did those in lot 1, but did not show the gain and furthermore evidenced no apparent cause for this lack of gain. As the experiment progressed they displayed considerable improvement. At the close they were still behind lot 1 in daily rate of gain, the figures being 2.77 pounds in lot 1 and 2.56 pounds in lot 2. The plan was to keep these two lots consuming approximately the same total amount of feed daily, lot 2 to receive 10 per </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 cent of its grain ration in the form of cottonseed nut cake. The daily ration holds very close between these two lots, it being 19.12 pounds of corn in lot 1 compared to 10.56 pounds of corn and 1.71 pounds of cottonseed nut cake in lot 2. The alfalfa hay consumption was virtually the same, being slightly less than 12 pounds daily in both cases. LOT 2— CORN, COTTONSEED NUT CAKE, AND ALFALFA These steers gained 2.56 pounds daily or 21 pound less than those in lot 1, which did not receive cottonseed cake. The cost of 100 pounds gain was $23.81, which is 2.16 higher than that in lot 1. The profit per steer was $5.56. As the cattle in lot 2 consumed slightly more feed per daj than did those in lot 1 and at the same time made slightly less gain, it therefore of necessity required more feed in lot 2 to produce one pound of gain than in lot 1. The corn consump - tion per one pound of gain is almost the same, it being .07 pound greater in lot 1, namely 6.54 pounds in contrast to 6.47 pounds in lot 2. The alfalfa consumed is slightly greater in lot 2, it being 4.50 pounds in contrast to 4.24 pounds in lot 1. The cottonseed nut cake amounts to .67 pound in lot 2. From this it is noticeable that the steers in lot 2 required to produce 1 pound of gain, .07 pound less of corn, but .26 pound more of alfalfa, in addition to .67 pound of cottonseed cake. Hence the total feed required in lot 2 amounted to 11.64 pounds for 1 pound of gain, in contrast to 10.78 pounds in lot 1. Due to </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Beef Production 11 thi.s rather more extravagant usage of feed in making gain? the cost of the gain on lot 2 must run quite a little higher. Figuring corn at $1.40 a bushel and alfalfa at $25 a ton, the gain on lot 1 cost $21.65, in contrast to $23.81 in lot 2, which is the most expensive gaining group of the experiment. The total feed consumed amounts to $77.90 and in lot 2 to $79.19. This causes the total cost per steer when marketed to be $1.94 more in lot 2. Both groups sold for $14.50, indicating that the cottonseed nut cake did not increase the finish on the lot 2 steers. Exclusive of pork, the profit on the steers in lot 1 is $1.99, while in lot 2 there is a loss of $1.26. There is slightly more pork produced per steer in lot 2, the amount here being 42.6 pounds in contrast to 38.9 pounds in lot 1. This approximates .33 pound of pork produced per steer daily in both lots. Valuing this pork at 16 cents per pound, there is a credit per steer of $6.23 for lot 1 and $6.82 for lot 2. Added to the profit or loss above, the profit in the two lots amounts to $8.21 in lot 1 and $5.56 in lot 2, a differ - ence of $2.65 in favor of the cattle which did not receive cot - tonseed nut cake. From this trial it would seem that the addition of the cot - tonseed nut cake to a corn and alfalfa ration was not justified with prices as they were at the time of the experiment. It might be stated that the cattle did not seem to relish the nut cake, often leaving considerable of it in their bunks. In previous years, cattle relished this cake very much. The steers were made ready for shipping to market by cutting down the corn ration and substituting oats during the day previous to shipping; likewise prairie hay was substi - tuted for alfalfa. As a result they did not shrink excessively in transit, those in lot 1 losing 28 pounds and those in lot 2 but 13 pounds. The dressing percentage is 3.4 per cent greater in lot 1. This is a rather wide margin in favor of lot 1. They shrank somewhat more in transit and this would account for a part of the spread. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 12 IS THE GRINDING OF CORN AND ALFALFA HAY JUSTIFIED WHEN FED IN CONJUNCTION WITH COTTONSEED NUT CAKE? Lots 2 and 3 Table 3— Lots 2 and 3 Lot 2 Lot 3 Number in lot 10 10 Corn Ground corn Cottonseed Cottonseed RATION nut cake cake Alfalfa Ground alfalfa Average initial weight 837.7 831.5 Average final weight 1,170.3 1.203.0 Average gain. 332.6 372.5 Average daily gain 2.56 2.87 Average daily rations Corn 16.56 17.66 Snapped corn Cottonseed 1.71 1.54 Alfalfa 11.51 8.96 Silage. Feed required per pound gain Corn 6.47 6.15 Snapped corn Cottonseed .67 .54 Alfalfa 4.5 3.12 Silage $21.73 $81.32 80.94 4.0 V 2.18 2.25 $170.78 $14.85 1,193 $177.16 6.3s 28.9 $4.62 Profit, including pork, per steer $5.56 $11.00 Shrink in transit, pounds per steer 13 13 Dressing percentage, cold 57.29 59.85 Cost per 100 pounds gain Cost per 100 pounds gain $23.81 Initial cost per steer (a $9.78 Feed cost per steer Feed cost per steer, April 1 to April 8 Interest (u 7% Cost of marketing $81.93 79.19 4.47 2.20 2.25 Total cost. $170.04 Value per cwt., Omaha Omaha weights Returns Profits, exclusive of pork $14.50 1,164 $168.78 —1.26 r 42.6 $6.82 Pounds pork, per steer Value of pork per steer ((?, 16c </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Beef Production' 13 Grinders of all sorts have been invented during recent years. These have been used in preparing feeds for both fattening and breeding animals. Their inventors have worked on the theory that by grinding, a certain amount of waste in feeding can be eliminated. The animals can be induced to eat more feed and a greater and more economical gain will accrue. The experimental work which has been conducted in past years has tended to show that the labor cost of grinding has not been offset by the added gains secured, due, undoubtedly, in part at least, to the relatively cheap prices of the feeds. With war prices in existence, it was thought that it might prove en- LOT 3— GROUND CORN, COTTONSEED CAKE, AND GROUND ALFALFA This was the high gaining lot, namely 2.87 pounds per steer daily. This was also the high selling lot and the high profit lot of the entire trial. As compared with lot 2, the grinding of corn and alfalfa increased the daily gain .31 pound, decreased the cost of 100 pounds gain by $2.08 and increased the appraisal from $14.50 to $14.85, due to greater finish carried by the steers in this lot. The profit per steer was $11 tircly justifiable to use the grinder in preparing both the grain and the hay for cattle. Lot 3 was used to test this method. The corn was run thru a coarse grinder, rather more of a cracker, while the alfalfa was run thru a machine which reduced it to lengths approximating one-half inch. These two feeds were mixed together with the cottonseed nut cake and fed to the steers in lot 3. Lot 2 received shelled corn and cot - tonseed nut cake in the bunks and whole alfalfa hay in the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 rack, lot 3 of course receiving no other roughness than the ground alfalfa. The ground feed lot gained 2.87 pounds daily while lot 2 gained but 2.56 pounds, the difference being .31 pound. This is quite a margin in favor of lot 3, and this added gain must without doubt be attributed to the method of feeding. The daily ration consisted of slightly more corn in lot 3, the amount being 17.66 pounds compared to 16.56 pounds in lot 2. The cottonseed nut cake was slightly less, being 1.71 pounds in lot 2 and only 1.54 pounds in lot 3, while the alfalfa was considerably less in lot 3, amounting to slightly less than 9 pounds, whereas lot 2 consumed 11.51 pounds. The cattle in lot 3 were relatively efficient gainers, using 6.15 pounds of corn, whereas those in lot 2 used 6.47 pounds. Likewise, as regards the cottonseed nut cake, but .54 pound was required in lot 3, whereas in lot 2, .67 pound was required. It took but 3.12 pounds of alfalfa hay in lot 3, whereas in lot 2 it took 4.5 pounds. Totaling up the feed required to produce one pound of gain the cattle on ground feed consumed a total of but 9.81 pounds whereas those on whole corn and hay ate 11.64 pounds. The ratio of the increased grain and increased roughness is consistent and the grinding actually saved 1.6 pounds of feed. As a result of the smaller amount of feed required to produce one pound of gain the cattle on ground feed produced one hundred pounds of gain at a cost of $21.73 whereas those on whole feed, in lot 2, produced their gain at a cost of $23.81, a difference of $2.08. In ascertaining this cost of gain a charge of 4 cents per bushel is made for grinding the corn and $3 per ton for grinding the alfalfa hay. These are the customary prices for such services at most mills. Owing to the greater feed consumption in lot 3, each steer in the two lots at the close of the experiment cost $170.04 and $170.78 respectively. The cattle on the ground feed not only made a greater gain but showed more finish and as a result sold on the market at $14.85 in contrast to $14.50, the sales price of the cattle in lot 2. Disregarding the pork, the steers in lot 2 show a loss of $1.26 per head, whereas those in lot 3 show a profit of $6.38. Upon examining the record sheets it is noted that the pigs following the whole corn cattle produced considerably more pork per steer, which would be expected as the ground corn cattle undoubtedly made better use of their feed. The pork produced per steer in lot 2 amounted to 42.6 pounds and in lot 3 to 28.9 pounds. The value of this pork at 16 cents per pound </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Beef Production 1 15 gives a credit of $6.82 to the steers in lot 2 and a credit of $4.62 to those in lot 3. Added to the profit and loss mentioned above, in lot 2 a profit was made of $5.56 per steer and in lot 3 a profit of $11.00. In other words, the grinding of corn and alfalfa doubled the profit in this trial. Both lots shrank 13 pounds per steer in transit and the dressing percentage showed 2.56 per cent greater in lot 3 than in lot 2. In conclusion it would seem that the factors which must of necessity determine the justifiability of grinding are: First, the availability of labor and equipment; second, the relative price of the feeds in question ; and third, the relative availability of the feeds. Last winter, alfalfa was very scarce in many feeding sections and it was not so much a matter of the price, as it was having it at all. Hence by grinding many feeders were able to make their supply go farther. On a basis of the figures obtained above it is quite readily noticeable that the grinding was justifiable and that a considerably higher price could have been paid for the grinding of both the hay and corn and the steers would still have made as much profit as those in lot 2. Many feeders have adopted the practice of using a silage cutter to prepare their alfalfa hay for steers. In most instances they do not grind the corn, but merely mix the cut hay with the corn and other feeds in the bunks. CAN SNAPPED CORN BE ECONOMICALLY SUBSTITUTED FOR SHELLED CORN WHEN FED IN CONJUNCTION WITH COTTONSEED NUT CAKE AND ALFALFA HAY? Lots 2 and 4 It has been the practice of many feeders to start their cattle on snapped corn early in the fall, continue them on this ration until the supply is exhausted, and then finish them on shelled corn. Most feeders have considered that cattle do well when handled in this way, altho no data have been available cover - ing the subject. The advantages of the method are twofold: Assuming that the cattle do better, it must be remembered that by feeding snapped corn a great many husks and parts of cob are consumed by the cattle which would otherwise go to waste. Furthermore this husk is taken from the field early and pre - served so that it is quite appetizing to the cattle during the winter months, whereas if left in the field the husk not only becomes very coarse and woody, but likewise unpalatable, due to exposure to the elements. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bui.ijctix 174 Table 4 — Lots 2 and 4 Lot 2 Lor 4 Number in lot 10 10 Corn Snapped corn Cottonseed Cottonseed RATION nut cake rut cake Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight 837.7 825 Average final weight 1,170.3 1,168.5 Average gain 332.6 343.5 Average daily gain 2.56 2.64 Average daily ration Corn 16.56 3.54 Snapped corn 16.27 Cottonseed 1.71 2.09 Alfalfa 11.51 8.12 Silage Feed required per pound gain Corn 6.47 1.34" Snapped corn 6.16 Cottonseed .67 .79 Alfalfa 4.5 3.0S Silage. Cost per 100 pounds gain $23.81 $18.81 Initial cost per steer (a $9.78 81.93 80.69 Feed cost per steer 79.19 64.61 Feed cost per steer, April 1 to April 8 4.47 3.60 Interest at 7% 2.20 2.17 *"**'»*-*"' •»• ■ /V I — --U -. 1 * Cost of marketing 2.25 2.25 Total cost $170.04 $153.32 Value per cwt., at Omaha $14.50 $14.50 Omaha weights 1,164 1,153 1,164 1,153 Returns 168.78 167.19 Profits, exclusive of pork — 1.26 13!87 Pounds pork per steer 42.6 37.4 42.6 37.4 Value of pork per steer @ 16c $6.82 $5!96 Profit, including pork, per steer 5.56 19.85 Pounds shrink per steer 13 18 13 18 Dressing percentage, cold 57.29 59.27 Shelled corn substituted for snapped corn during last 22 days, since snapped corn wa no longer available. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HREF PkoDICTIOX 17 Lot 4 was started on snapped corn and kept thereon the first 10* days of the experiment. In conjunction they received ap - proximately 10 per cent of the ration in the form of cotton - seed nut cake and all of the alfalfa hay they wished. Compare corn, cottonseed nut cake and days of the trial, which was n supply was exhausted, the •helled corn. Some little time 5 before the supply of snapped this lot with lot 2. fed on shelled alfalfa hay. During: the last 22 the period after the snapped cor cattle in lot 4 had a full feed of )■ was taken to accustom them to this corn was completely exhausted. — __ rr _^ As a result there wa no LOT 4— SNAPPED CORN, COTTONSEED NUT CAKE, AXD ALFALFA The feeding of snapped corn in cont cottonseed cake and alfalfa, increased th&lt; 100 pounds gain $5, and increased the prc ist to shelled corn (lot 2), in addition to daily gain slightly, decreased the cost of it per steer from $5.56 to $19.85. digestive trouhle following the change and the cattle remained on full feed. The ration consumed daily by the cattle in this lot amounted to 19.5 pounds of snapped corn during the first 108 days and 20 pounds of shelled corn during the last 22 days, in contrast to lfi.56 pounds of shelled corn per day, the average thru the trial in lot 2. A number of tests were made on the snapped corn and it was found that each 100 pounds of snapped corn contained 75 pounds of shelled corn. Consequently, during the first 108 days the cattle in lot 4 actually consumed per head daily 14.G3 pounds of corn, figured on a shelled corn basis. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 The steers in lot 4 made a somewhat greater gain than those in lot 2 ? the daily gain being 2.56 pounds in lot 2 and 2.64 pounds in lot 4, on snapped corn. The cost of 100 pounds of gain is materially lower in lot 4, due doubtless to the fact that the snapped corn was a relatively cheap feed and that upon this ration the steers showed a very efficient gain. The cost amounts to $23.81 in lot 2 and $18.81 in lot 4, a difference of $5 per hundred. Owing to the fact that the ration in lot 4 cost con - siderably less than in lot 2, the feed cost for the duration of the experiment amounts to $64.41 in lot 4, in contrast to a feed cost of $79.19 in lot 2. The cattle in these two pens were appraised at the same value, $14.50 per hundred, and when sold, irrespective of pork gains, there was a loss of $1.26 in lot 2 in contrast to a profit of $13.87 in lot 4. The amount of pork produced per steer was 42.6 pounds in lot 2 in contrast to 37.4 pounds in lot 4, a difference of 5.2 pounds in favor of the lot where the steers had shelled corn. Crediting this pork at 16 cents per pound, the actual profit per steer is $5.56 in lot 2 and $19.85 in lot 4. Incidentally, lot 2 shows the least profit and lot 4 the largest profit of the entire test. The steers in lot 4 shrank 18 pounds in transit and their dressing percentage was 59.27 per cent or 2 per cent better than that of lot 2, which lost 13 pounds in transit. From this test it would seem that the use of snapped corn during the season of the year when it can be fed to advantage is a very economical practice. Cattle thrive on snapped corn, because of its bulkiness and the fact that in itself it makes up a well proportioned feed, carrying sufficient bulk to meet the animal's cravings. Furthermore, considering that the husks are largely wasted in the field, when they can be put to so good a use as this and show so satisfactory a gain, the practice deserves consideration. CAN BEEF BE MADE WITHOUT CORN? Lots 2 and 5 In order to meet war time emergencies it was deemed advis - able to keep one lot of cattle on a ration which did not contain corn or other grain. Lot 5 was, therefore, placed on a heavy feed of silage, being allowed all they would consume together with 4 pounds of cottonseed nut cake per day and what alfalfa hay they wished. These cattle relished the cottonseed nut cake very much and seemed to eat it much better than did the cattle in lots 2, 3 and 4. The ration consumed per day in this pen amounted to 52 pounds of silage, 3.8 pounds of cottonseed nut cake and 2.18 pounds of alfalfa hay. At the first of the expert- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Beef Production 19 Table 5 — Lota 2 and 5 Lot 2 Lot 5 Number in lot 10 1(1 Corn Cottonseed nut cake Alfalfa Silage Cottonseed nut cake Alfalfa RATION Average initial weight Average final weight. . Average gain Average daily gain . Average daily ration Corn Snapped corn Cottonseed Alfalfa Silage Feed required per pound gain Corn Snapped corn Cottonseed . . Alfalfa Silage Cost per 100 pounds gain. . Initial cost per steer (« $9.78 Feed cost per steer Feed cost per steer, April 1 to April 8 Interest (a 7','r 4.47 2.57 2.20 2.18 Cost of marketing 2.25 2.25 Total cost $170.04 $140.30 Value per cwt., Omaha. . Omaha weights $14.50 1,164 $13.50 1,068 Returns $168.78 —1.26 $144.18 Profits, exclusive of pork Pounds pork, per steer . . 3.88 42.6 45.8 Value of pork, per steer (n 16c Stf.vj $3.17* Profit, including pork, per steer $5.56 $7.05 Shrink in transit, pounds per steer . Dressing percentage, cold 13 50 57.29 68.48 The pigs in this lot received shelled corn, the value }f which has been deducted </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 174 ment these cattle consumed as much as GO pounds of silage daily. However, the consumption was reduced toward the latter part and 50 pounds was as much as they would take at the time the experiment closed. The alfalfa consumption was very light, but remained consistently at 2 pounds per day thru - out the entire trial, altho they had all of this they cared for at all times after they had learned to eat the silage. CI &gt;^ LOT 5— SILAGE, COTTONSEED CAKE, AND ALFALFA The feeding of a ration of 52.05 pounds silage, 2.18 pounds alfalfa and 3.8 pounds cottonseed cake resulted in a gain of 2.2 pounds per steer daily. This gain cost $18.26 per 100 pounds and was the cheapest gain of the trial. These steers lacked finish and consequently sold for hut $13.50 per hundred pounds with the resultant cutting of profits to $7.05. The gain made by these cattle was 2.2 pounds in comparison with 2.56 pounds by lot 2, the pen which had a full feed of corn, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa hay. Owing to the rela - tive economy of the ration fed the steers in lot 5 their gain cost but $18.26 per 100 pounds. In producing each pound of gain they consumed 1.73 pounds of cottonseed nut cake, .99 pound of alfalfa hay and 23.66 pounds of silage, in contrast to 0.47 pounds of corn, .67 pound of cottonseed nut cake and 4.5 pounds of alfalfa in lot 2. Hence there was a very much larger proportion of roughness in the feed consumed in lot 5 and a reduction of over $5 in the cost of producing 100 pounds of gain. Exclusive of pork, the cattle in lot 5 show a profit of </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Beef Production 21 $3.88 in contrast to a loss of $1.26 in lot 2. The pork pro - duced per steer in lot 5 runs somewhat higher than in lot 2 rhis is due, however, to the fact that each of the hogs following the steers in lot 5 received 2.5 pounds of corn per day during the entire experiment. After deducting the cost of this corn from the pork gains there is a net value of $3.17 for the pork per steer in lot 5. This added to the figure above gives $7.05 profit per steer, in contrast to $5.5C&gt; profit in lot 2. Hence, there was an increased profit of $1.40 from the cattle fed a heavy feed of silage, cottonseed nut cake and alfalfa with - out corn. The cattle in lot 5 shrank heavily and looked very uneven on the market. Their shrink amounted to 50 pound's per head. Due to their uneven, rough appearance on the market they were subjected to a rather severe discrimination and sold for $13.50 per hundred, in contrast to $14.50 for the cattle in lot 2. Had the steers in lot 5 brought a price commensurate with that brought by those in lot 2 there would have been a larger margin of profit in their favor. Their dressing percentage, following so heavy a shrink, amounted to 58.48 per cent, which is 1.1!) per cent higher tJian that of the cattle in lot 2. Had they shrank the same in transit as lot 2 they would have dressed approximately 3 per cent lower than they did, or almost 2 per cent lower than the cattle in lot 2. noM] </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 EBRA8KA ] ExPKKiiiENT Station Bulletin 8. S 338 8 § fl 3 3 n l~ OJ T -» L- 00 ' inn ooaox q*«oo 3 s N N N ■&lt;t --reo us ao O1C4C4 OtO&gt;Q 3S3 J UUCQO 00C4 00 ins 00 00 00 *0 I 5 S. S S 3 « S£3 "*l "*. ' 'Hi 2SS 00 00 M .5 B tart 5S5 222 t-C-t- ! t-' t-* t-" s 3 t i. 3 U3 00 8- £g£ 22§ L - _ go 'ooocoo — — — in | I • x » S2S t-r-t- I I oi &gt;o w«n cococd »H — — — — f-4r4*4 ===^^ == — == — === . q t^ ocoo) is « tot-'x * " x «i t-* 322 1 - •"8 ■fl" U5 U3 t O U5 j» 00 lO O&gt; -H 5§S U3t&gt;00 t i- in n j. tt Tf iq oq q ' ia is (d SS5 s. 5 « — X iO tO 00 ■^"C-NOJtO Tf -j. iq 30 — SS5 fricoco S i =— 9 IS — — — ""! "*? "^! ass si d -t HfHH — 8 1 ~ 1 "S § •&gt; . 8. 2 s s s « — — 1 TTt-NAt- 2SS i 3 — — CQtOtO ■^f -^qcooo — — — &gt; f *0 I § 1 5 OBOt-; lOUSio "*c-e4os w -T -f «O 00 i-« *- t-i « s n ? s s 2S2 j -rr-Xiiiw -.* -^ -* t- q 0103 09 ONOCJ in o&gt; t-_ to I I -3 8. S 04 O oieicj i; «*iqoo© HHf- sag oidb i 1&gt;« s 2"3 — — ' i 8=5 ; it g "sirs — gg^— — la ■—- S^-ofel • bSS ■ |s* : • 3 b8 3 Ss IS 3 1 I I a | </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>