<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1933</title>
               <date value="1933-02-01">1933-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-SIXTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA asd .Presented to the- Governor February 1, 1933 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMIT! AL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Forty-sixth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. W. W. Burr. . February 1, 1933. Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Mr. W. W. Burr, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Forty-sixth An - nual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Charles W. Bryan, Lincoln, February 1, 1933. . Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Marion A. Shaw, David City, President Term expires January 1935 * RED A. Marsh, Archer Term expires January, 1935 Jlarl Cline, Lincoln ......Term expires Januarv, 1937 Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha Term expires January, 1937 Stanley D. Long, Cowles : Tei^n expires January, 1939 Frank J. Taylor, St. Paul .....Term expires January, 1939 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Chancellor L. E. GUNDERSONi 1 Finance Secretary THE SiATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc, Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF C. W. Ackerson, Ph.D., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry M. A. Alexander, M.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry Arthur Anderson, M.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy Aj. E. Barager, M.Sc, Research Assistant in Home Economics M. J. BlisH, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemistry (Chairman) E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. in E.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) E. M. Brouse, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Valentine M. Ruth Clark, Ph.D., Associate in Home Economics H. P. Davis, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Associate in Dairy Husbandry H. C. Filley, A.M., Rural Economics (Chairman) A. L. Frolik, M.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy R W. Goss, Ph.D., Associate in Plant Pathology H. 3. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) I.'L, Hathaway, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry Harold Hedges, A.M., Assistant in Rural Economics J. A. Holden,- B.Sc, Supt. Expci-imental Station, Mitchell Nelson E. Jodon, ;i B.Sc, Research Assistant in Agronomy, North Platte F. D. Keim, Ph.D., Agronomy (Chairman) T; A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy E. B. Lewis, B.Sc. in A.E.; Assistant in Agricultural Engineei-ing . W. J. Loeffel, M.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry \V. E. Lyness, B.Sc in Agr., Assistant in Agronomy C. B. McGrath, D.V.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene R. F. Morgan, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry F. E. Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) J. F.Olney, D.V.M., M.S., Assistant in Animal Pathology G! L. Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman) John F. Pospisil, Supt. Box Butte Experiment Farm, Alliance J. C. Russel, M.Sc, Associate in Agronomy Rudolph Sandstedt, M.Sc, Analyst Edna B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant in Home Economics Ll B. Snyder, M.S., Assistant in Riu-al Economics \y. P. Snydek, M.S., Supt. Experimental Substation, North Platte Coit A. Suneson,- 4 ' M.Sc, Research Assistant in Agronomy M_H. Swenk, A.M., Entomology (Chairman) ' 1 lly an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15. 1809. the Stutc Treasurer became cx-officio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1. 1899. I 2 Detailed from the Office of Western Irrigation AKriculture. 1 Detailed from Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases, United States Department of Afrriculture, Waphington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">H M Tylda^P^ n C " /«?'*""" &gt; * »''''«&lt; Husbandry L VAvvliw'n^ Vr c' i4 . M ! s ' a ' lf '» P'o»l Pathology H E w!f' K LY?M sf- A"™? . Fetology and Hy a lne (Chairman) Hnw •■« I 'c Sc " /lssls '« i " '« Agronomy LVS" 0 - MiSc. m Horticulture Don B Whelan, M.Sc, 4s«ist&lt;int m Entomology W W*vS ANSI $&amp;"■*«**»***• (Chairman) W. W. Yocum A.M., As«s*n.n/ m Horticulture ■ i^. L.. iCOOK,' B.Sc, Agronomist, North Platte ' ' i ■ . ■-: ■.'■;-/.■■ CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal and Governor's Certificate &gt; The Station Staff Introduction , Agricultural Engineering.'. Animal Diseases '"'."■ '• I| Dairy Husbandry' ""'. :■ ,-. • ' Field Crops and Soils Fruits and Vegetables '...'... """'" '- Home Economics ■■■■•- Insect Control [ ;'■. "' " Livestock Feeding ' ™ Milling and Baking... .;.. 2 \ Plant Diseases 2ti Potatoes ; - 27 Poultry &#132;'■■'-' '^ZZ:'Zl - 2 ° Rural Economics.. ""'""" ' ' ■ " '"" 31 State Serum Plant 3 North Platte Substation.. """ ""■ 35 Scottsbluff Substation 36 Valentine Substation "V - 40 Box Butte Substation .Z.ZZ. : V 42 Changes in Staff 44 Legislation ..ZZ....... A i Additional Lands, Buildings, and Equipment " tt Publications of the Last Fiscal Year : * Financial Reports r 45 47 ;-t ■ ■ A«JgISSS? &amp;n^ e . Cro " 3 — Diaeascs. Unite, Stale, Dopart m ont of cultu^^shVnTtonTD? ° C f "** LaDd ™™H™. Unite,, States Department of A K ri- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Forty-sixth Annual Report This report is a record of progress in investigations, of changes in staff, and of improvements, publications, and re - ceipts and expenditures of the Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1932. The reports from the substations extend to January 1, 1933. The funds for carrying on the work are derived from federal and state appropriations and from cash receipts. This report does not designate the particular funds under which each project is carried. For convenience the projects are grouped as to subject matter. The financial report has been prepared by the Finance Secretary and is given at the end. During the year the financial depression has grown steadily worse. The almost unprecedented low prices and exchange values of farm commodities have made it exceedingly difficult for farmers to carry on. In an attempt "to overcome these conditions the farmers have scrutinized more carefully than ever before every factor that increases the cost of production or overhead. The demand upon the Experiment Station for assistance has been greater than in any preceding year. Members of both the Experiment Station and Agricultural Extension staffs have attempted to take care of these requests, and report a keener interest in information and demonstra - tion than in years of normal prosperity. The difficulties of meeting obligations have brought forward the whole matter of taxation. Believing that this question is vital to all the people,- and particularly to farmers, the University of Nebraska is preparing and the Experiment Station is publishing a series of twelve tax circulars. It is hoped that a study of the whole question of taxation will lead to an equitable solution. These circulars are available through the College of Agriculture. Since the publication is an extra burden on the station, a charge of five cents per circular is being made. The resources of the station have been somewhat curtailed by reduced appropriations and to a much larger extent through a falling off of the cash income because of the low prices of agricultural products. This has necessitated econ - omies and changes in program but the fundamental lines of research have been continued. It is felt that the information gained from their solution will be invaluable in the adjust - ment of agriculture to whatever conditions arise as we emerge from the present depression. A list of the publications issued by the station during the past is given later in the report. The bulletins and circulars </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station issued are available to any citizen of the state by writing the Agricultural Experiment Station, Lincoln, Nebi-aska. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Nebraska Tractor Tests.— This work is done under the Nebraska Tractor Testing Law. During the past year 14 tractors from nine manufacturers were tested. Three of the general-purpose type were tested on the low-grade fuel dis - tillate, eight on gasoline, and three on kerosene. Five of the 14 were of the crawler type and seven were general-purpose tractors. Bulletin 277 will summarize tests up to January, lJoo. Wind-driven Electric Plants for Farm Use. — This project has been completed and the data are being prepared for pub - lication; The conclusion is drawn that the uncertainty of steady wind, the necessity of large storage capacity, and high investment cost will limit electrical service from such plants. Pump Irrigation.— A portable unit for measuring the effic - iency _of irrigation wells and equipment was Used for the first time in the field. 'Work was also done in connection with the United States Geological Survey and the Division of Conser - vation and Survey of the University of Nebraska on the action of ground water. This work will be continued. A manu - script summarizing results to date is being prepared for pub - lication. :• The Use of Electric Power on Nebraska Farms. — The field work is practically concluded. A bulletin on the consumption and uses of electricity on Nebraska farms is in process, sum - marizing the data obtained through the co-operation of farm - ers in the project. Electi'icallij Operated Refrigerators for Farm Use. Data and observations on project farms, are to.be included in the general bulletin mentioned. Further laboratory studies have been made on milk coolers and or the household cabinets. Some commercial experimental coolers have been under ob - servation. Data on kind and amount of water circulation with limited equipment and temperature curves have been and still are being obtained. In the household-cabinet study the effect of different-shaped alcoves on two types of cabinets under controlled conditions was observed. A report of this will be ready by fall. Circula - tion of air was materially restricted when the cabinets were enclosed too closely, causing large consumption of electric "energy. The work will be continued. • The Use of Small Motors on the Farm. — In co-operation with the Department of Animal Husbandry, a study is being </seg>
            <seg id="p007">■ • Forty-sixth Annual Report made of the costs of processing standing corn into fodder or ensilage, the cost being figured on a per-ton and a per-acre basis. A study is also being made of the use of small motors in the grinding of feeds. This embraces the fine and coarse grinding and some observations of the different types of grinders. . . Methods of^ Cooling Milk on the Farm and Their Effect on Quality. — This project is co-operative between the Depart - ments of Agricultural Engineering and Dairy Husbandry. Data on cooling with various amounts and temperatures of water, and by use of different equipment have been obtained. The data obtained have been published as Experiment Station Bulletin No. 266. The project will be closed. ANIMAL DISEASES The Pathogenicity as xoell as Antigenic and Biologic Prop - erties of the Organisms Belonging to the Hemorrhagic Septi - cemia Group. — The experimental phases are practically com - pleted. There now remain an analysis of the data and prep - aration for publication. The Influence of Environment on Poultry Morbidity". — A study of the epizootologic behavior of six poultry diseases was continued under controlled environment. These were bacil - lary white diarrhea, blackhead (turkeys), tuberculosis, fowl cholera, coccidiosis, and fowl typhus, all of economic im - portance in Nebraska. For each disease there are two lots. In one the soil is covered with about one foot of coarse gravel. The watering and feeding apparatus are also arranged to promote sanita - tion. In the other lot no attempt is made to obtain sanitary conditions. The experiment was originally designed to discover whether or not environment plays a part in the dissemination of the bacillary white diarrhea among adult fowls. Thus far, no concrete evidence has been found on this point. On the other hand, the frequent serological examination of fowls revealed a high degree of irregularity in the reactions and in the per - sistence of the latter. Significant although circumstantial evidence came to light which indicates that the eating of one another's eggs may explain this phenomenon. This phase is now being studied. The turkey lots showed that environmental % (soil) infection is the largest if not the only factor of practical importance in . the spread of blackhead. Hence, it must be possible to create an environment for turkeys in which blackhead can not spread or even in which the disease is impossible. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Thus far no strikingly conclusive results have been obtained m the tuberculosis lots, probably on account of the insidious slowjy spreading character of. the disease. The experiment with fowl cholera is practicallv concluded It showed that while the environmental factor can not be entirely denied, it is most conspicuously overshadowed by the great promptness and extreme virulence of direct-contact ex - posures.. The influence of healthy carriers was also recognized as ail important factor in keeping the infection sequence in - tact in the two flocks. In other words the infection is much more apt to find a reservoir in living, apparently healthv towls than in the soil and other parts of the environment ' I he results in the coccidiosis lots have thus far not per - mitted concrete conclusions. It was found to be difficult to induce outbreaks of fowl typhus. In the. one which became established, it was evident that mere sanitary control measures were very effective in prophylaxis, the losses in the lot under sanitarv'cohtrol being only one-tenth of those in the lot where no attempt at sanita - tion was made. . ' The project is being continued and the work is gradually yielding results capable of being applied/in the practice' of poultry husbandry. Laboratory Diagnosis and Examination of Specimens.— This project takes care of the specimens that come to the De - partment of Animal Pathology and Hygiene for examination and diagnosis. During the -year 6,287 specimens were ex amined. '■'■■■■•:■ DAIRY HUSBANDRY The Principles of Ice Cream Making .—The study of the factors affecting the composition of an ice cream' mix was continued. In preparing a mix, the amount .of each ingredient necessary to produce a final product of definite percentage composition is calculated. In practice, despite accurate cal - culations and supposedly accurate means of determining the percentage composition of each ingredient, there is a defic - iency, particularly of fat, in the finished product. The varia - "?" °£ fat 24 samples of commercial ice cream as compared with the calculated fat content of the mix was ±0 8337 per cent. In 20 of the 24 samples the fat as reported bv the manu - facturer averaged 0.8082 per cent higher than that found bv analysis. In order to find out where the losses occur a series of samples were taken at different stages of the processing and freezing of the mix and after hardening the ice cream It was found for instance that in eight comparisons the per - centage of fat in the frozen ice cream was lower than the per- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Forty-sixth Annual Report centage of fat in the mix. Smaller variations occurred when the frozen, ice cream samples were from a second rather than a first batch, frozen. Samples from the top and bottom of a live-gallon can of ice cream, held. at 0° F. for five days with a parchment cover, showed a constant variation in fat per - centage, with the sample from the top of the can having the highest percentage of fat. No appreciable variation in the percentage of fat was found between samples from the top and the bottom of a ten-gallon can of mix held for 24 hours at 40 c F. All fat determinations were made by the Mojon - nier procedure. A further study of the Nebraska procedure (Experiment Station Bulletin 246) for the determination of the fat. in ice cream was made in order to eliminate if possible the charred material that occasionally occurs at the base of the fat column of the finished test. A modification of the proportion of in - gredients in the reagents has given better results than the pro - portions-originally proposed. Studies of' "Fat Soluble A" as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds, Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey and Guernsey. — This work was continued in a study of the effect of stand - ardization; of biitterf at upon the vitamin A content of the milk. It was found that separated milk contains very little vitamin A.. The study indicates that when milk is standardized by the addition of separated milk the vitamin A content is lnwered. Factors Affecting the Quality of Fluid Milk as Shown by the b'ut Test . Sediment Teat, and Bacteria Count. — During the year a report of the data obtained during the past seven years under this project was published as Experiment Station Bul - letin 270. Growth of Dairy Cattle. — The monthly weighing, measur - ing, and photographing of more than 100 head of cattle has been continued. One phase, the influence of pregnancy upon the gain in weight of dairy cows, is being prepared for pub - lication. Studies of the age of cow and age of bull upon the number of services required for conception are being com - pleted. The study indicates that young sires are much more efficient than older bulls. Methods of Practical Control avd Economic Effect of Con - tagions Abortion upon a Dairy Herd. — This project was started in an attempt to obtain a herd free from Bang's dis - ease as indicated by the agglutination test. The dilutions used are 1:25, 1:50, 1.100, and 1:250, and the entire herd is tested at three-month intervals. A separate group of build - ings and yards is provided for the animals considered in- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station fected. The infected herd has contained a total of 48 cows since it was established but now only two are left 1 ; of which one is negative in reaction. There has been but one reactor since March, 1929, a heifer that reacted during March, 1931, and was disposed of. In order to obtain some idea of how premises once occupied by infected animals may be made safe for non-infected ones, some of the barns and lots formerly occupied by the infected herd were cleaned and disinfected, and then allowed to lie idle for about two and one-half months. The top six inches of soil was removed from the lots, they were thoroughly treated with quick lime, and new dirt was hauled in. This group has oc - cupied these barns and lots for one year and have neither aborted nor become positive to the agglutination test. Studies have been made on the effect of feeding sprouted oats as a cure for temporary sterility, but sufficient data have not yet been accumulated. The Vitamin Content of Field-cured and Artificially Cured Hay. — In co-operation with the Dairy Bureau of the U. S. D. A., this woi'k was continued in a study of the vitamin E con - tent of field-cured and of artificially cured alfalfa. This study was made by comparing the number of litters produced by groups of female rats which received graded quantities of either field-cured or ai'tificially cured alfalfa as their source of vitamin E. It was concluded that the artificial drying of. alfalfa tended to preserve its vitamin E content to a greater degree. than did field curing. The results have been published in Research Bulletin No. 62. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS Corn Improvement through Inbreeding and Hybridization. — Special effort is being directed toward the development of recombinations of selfed lines which will prove attractive and profitable for farm use. Outstanding selfed lines developed by a number of other states have been tested in various hybrid combinations for their suitability under Nebraska conditions. Some have proved well suited and are being used, as seed stocks. Twelve hundred new selfed lines are now in the second generation of inbreeding. In the principal yield test, 135 experimental hybrids, including local and out-of-state single and double crosses, were compared with seven commer - cial hybrids and 20 farmers' varieties. The entire group of 135 hybrids averaged 7 per cent higher yield than Hogue Yellow Dent, which ihas been grown at the Experiment Station for the last 30 years. The 30 most productive hybrids aver - aged 43 per cent greater grain yield than the Hogue. The average yields of the seven commercial hybrids, 30 highest </seg>
            <seg id="p011">■ • Forty-sixth Annual Report experimental hybrids, and 20 farmers' varieties were 25 bushels, 42.1 bushels, and 25.6 bushels per acre, respectively. In addition to high yield many of the better hybrids are especially lodge resistant. Miscellaneous Cultural Practices Involved in Grmving the Corn Crop. — That phase of this project dealing with uniform distribution of plants in the field is ready for publication after 14 years' investigation. It is evident that extreme uni - formity of stand is not essential for maximum yield. The uneven stands represented by (1) alternating 2 and 4 plant hills, (2) alternating 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 plant hills, and (3) alternating 1, 3, and 5 plant hills averaged 50.0 bushels per acre,' compared with 49.9 bushels for a uniform stand of 3 plants per hill. The plant population produced in the irreg - ular stands was but slightly more variable in plant develop - ment than in case of the uniform stands. Soil moisture studies and root excavations in the corn field indicate that a corn plant draws heavily upon the soil mois - ture under these Experiment Station conditions to a lateral distance of 3.5 feet from the corn row and to a depth of 5 feet. Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies with Small Grains. — The new Nebraska Crimean se - lection which has been named "Cheyenne" yielded most among all standard hard red winter varieties which are suit - able for recommendation in this state. Other outstanding qualities cf this variety are lodge resistance and shatter re - sistance, which are desirable characters for combine harvest where wheat must often stand long after it is ripe. During the four-year period, 1928-1931, Cheyenne has yielded 39.8 bushels, compared with several standard varieties as follows: Nebraska No. 60, 37.5; Crimean 1435, 37.6; Kanred, 36.5; Turkey. 36.2; and Kharkof, 37.0. Cheyenne also was the top variety as averaged for the four stations: North Platte, Alli - ance, Valentine, and Lincoln. Several new Nebraska bunt - resistant Turkey wheat selections continue to be of great in - terest and possible value. They have proved almost com - pletely resistant to local bunt during six years in control in - oculation tests, and have yielded fully as well as Nebraska No. 60, Turkey, and Kanred. Several of these newer bunt-re - sistant Turkey selections appear also to possess a striking re - sistance to Hessian fly. Work with winter wheat is co - operative with the Division of Cereal Crops of the U. S. D. A. Selection work with the Burt variety of oats, which began in 1920, has resulted in the isolation and determination of superior lines. This variety has yielded 4 bushels better than the popular standard Kherson variety as an average for 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station years. In turn, the most productive new Burt selection has surpassed the original by 13 per cent during a three-year period. Two of these Burt selections are highly resistant to stem rust as well as high in yield. Two others are very re - sistant to smut. A number of oat hybrids have been made and are being tested for both smut and stem-rust resistance. They have given evidence of marked practical resistance. Smooth-bearded varieties of barley continue very at - ti'active and are being extensively grown. Compared with Common Six-row, the following bushel yields are an average for the last two years: Common Six-row 32.7, Comfort 43.9, Glabron 47.2, Ezond 48.2, and. Spartan 50.7. Trebi has been the most productive of the rough-bearded varieties and gave a comparative yield of 45.2 bushels! The above list would seem to include the most attractive varieties now available for Nebraska conditions. Although Marquis was recognized for many years as the most productive spring wheat variety for Nebraska condi - tions, it has been surpassed during the last five years by a number of varieties as follows: Marquis 16.5 bu.. Garnet 19.5 bu., Kearney 18.5 bu.. Progress 18.5 bu., Java 19.5 bu., and Ceres 19.2 bu. Nebraska farmers are now growing Ceres as a certified crop. . During a number of years the yields of winter wheat have been reduced almost proportional to the percentage of infec - tion with stinking smut in Experiment Station tests. Popper carbonate applied at 2 1/ : &gt; to 3 ounces per bushel of seed con - tinues to be the. most practical treatment for this disease. For the respective planting dates of March 19. March 31, April 10, and April 21, during a number of years, the rela - tive yields of spring wheat were 107, 100, 93, and 05 per cent; oats 104, 100, 91, and 85 per cent, and barley 90. 100, 103, and 94 per cent. Forage Crop Investigations. — The alfalfa - improvement phases of this work are co-operative with the Division of Forage Crops and Diseases of the U. S. Department of Agri - culture. In a test of alfalfa varieties which has continued for nine years, the following average acre yields in tons of r-uved forage have been obtained: Cossack 3.72, Baltic 3.68, Hardi - stan 3.45, Grimm 3.43. Nebraska Common 3.29, Provence F. P. I. No. 43886 (Kaw) 3.21, Turkestan 3.14, Canadian Var - iegated 2.98, and Sand Lucern 2.35: Of these, Turkestan and Hardistan have maintained the best stands, because of superior resistance to wilt. '•..'•■ Of 30 varieties in another test, which. has been under way for three years, Grimm, Ladak, and Northern Common have </seg>
            <seg id="p013">. Forty-sixth Annual Report been consistently high in yield, while strains from South Africa, Italy, France, Arizona, and California have proved unadapted to Nebraska conditions. While these and more re - cent plantings indicate superiority in the yield of Cossack and Grimm over Hardistan and Common, it is evident from these and outlying tests that the former are more susceptible to wilt. For this reason the latter two should be recommended for localities where wilt is prevalent. Owing to its superior cold and wilt endurance, Hardistan has been distributed to farmers and is now being grown as a certified seed crop. A new phase of the alfalfa program is the planting of a rather extensive nursery containing open pollinated and first, second, and third generations of selfed lines from several hundred promising wilt- and cold-resistant selections. This is part of: a broad program for alfalfa improvement through breeding and selection, certain phases of which are co - operative with the Department of Plant Pathology. A 'state-wide study of the effects of alfalfa on subsoil mois - ture depletion and, in turn, the effect of this upon the alfalfa yields has been completed and is being prepared for publica - tion. The effect of such, subsoil-moisture depletion on yield may be well illustrated by the nine-year performance record of Hardistan alfalfa at the Agronomy Farm. Although the stand has continued satisfactory throughout the period, the acre yield of cured forage averaged 4.27 tons during the first live years and only 2.42 tons during the last four. New seed - ings of alfalfa on land previously in alfalfa have yielded ap - proximately one-half the tonnage of alfalfa grown on land never before in this crop. The Relation of the Characteristics, Commercial Grade, and Market Value of Alfalfa Hay to Curing, Stacking, and Baling Practices.-r-In co-operation with the Hay, Feed, and Seed Division of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, a detailed study has been made of the haymaking practices as carried on in the.Platte valley between Kearney and Cozad. The results have led to the plan of the control operation of a 200-acre alfalfa meadow at Lincoln. This will be inaugurated in the spring of 1933. The chief object will be to study the causes and prevention of hay .spoilage in the stack, and to develop superior hay-management practices. Crop Rotati&lt;s)i and Fertilizer Experiments. — These experi - ments comprise a series of 184 one-tenth-acre plats at the Agronomy Farm and have now continued for eleven years. The season of 1931 was very favorable for wheat and oats but not for corn. The average yields in bushels per acre of un - treated plats were: wheat 41.5, oats 51.2, corn 20. It was </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the seventh season of phosphate deficiency on wheat and the sixth of nitrogen deficiency on oats. In 1931 the average in - crease creditable to 100 pounds per acre of superphosphate on wheat was 6.5 bushels. The. average increase creditable to 100 pounds of sodium nitrate fertilizer on oats was about 22 bushels. Manure applications gave average increases of 1G.7 and 19.3 bushels per acre on wheat and oats respectively, ob - viously on account of the phosphorus content for the one crop and the nitrogen content for the other. These are the largest seasonal increases ever obtained and are decidedly above the average for the entire period of these tests. For the eleventh time potash treatments failed to show benefit on any crop. Corn and alfalfa were not consistently benefited by any treat - ment. The Relation of Weather, Cultural Practice*, and Soil Con - ditions to Nitrification in'Nebraskq Soils. — Three field appli - cations of Calurea were made to wheat in Phelps, Knox, and York counties, with some increase in yield. The project will be continued. Factors Which Affect the Tilth of Soils. — Tbe work of the year has been in connection with an elaborate set of field ex - periments located on a farm near Rogers, Dodge county, Ne - braska. The soil is an alkali phase of Lamoure srlty clay loam that is unproductive on account of extremely poor tilth rather than saline toxicity. One hundred and twenty-eight plats are involved. The treatments include sulfur, lime, gypsum, manure, and treble superphosphate at various rates, singly and in combination. The applications were made in the soring of 1931. No increases in crop yields were obtained the lirst year, partly because of drouth but mainly because ot* slowness of physical improvement. A slight benefit to implement per - formance was observed from a five-ton lime application to corn. In the spring of 1932 physical benefits were observed as follows: Gypsum — 4 tons per acre. Outstanding. Even the worst spots wore mellow after dashing rains. A two-ton application save similar but less conspicuous results. Sulfur — 1,500 pounds per acre. Distinct improvement generally but not marked on the worst spots. Seven' hundred and fifty pounds per acre gave but slight improvement. Lime — 5 tons per acre. A faint improvement, but negligible on the worst spots. Manure — 10 to 20 tons per acre. No trace of benefit. Treble superphosphate — up to 500 pounds per acre. No trace of benefit. • Profile studies in the field revealed an abundance of gypsum and lime in the subsoil within reach of certain kinds of deep- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-sixth Annual Report tillage machinery. Laboratory studies are being made on ex - changeable base, permeability, plasticity, shrinkage, and other characteristics involved in tilth. ' Phosphate Fertilizer for the irrigated Sections of Eastern Nebraska. — This project includes a field study pf the usage of phosphate fertilizer and also laboratory investigations on soil phosphorus, in co-operation with the Division of Soil Fertility of the Bureau of Chemistry and Soils, Department of Agri - culture. The field work of the past year has included experi - ments on the common crops throughout the North Platte river territory from North Platte westward, and experiments on sugar beets mainly in Scottsbluff county. The fei'tilizer used has been treble superphosphate. Significant responses have been obtained on first bottom and low bench soil types' generally throughout the territory and also on high bench soils that are calcareous in the surface. Responses have not been obtained on soils that are non-cal - careous in the surface, or on soils generally that have been consistently and heavily treated with barnyard manure. Increases on responsive soils have ranged from 2 to 12 tons per acre of beets, 0.5 to 2.5 tons per acre of alfalfa hay, and 10 to 50 bushels per acre of barley. .A single test gave increases of 70 and 145 bushels per acre on two varieties of potatoes. •First-year residual effects of 23 to 38: bushels of increase in barley have been observed. One experiment that is being repeated at several points deals with the rate and time of application of phosphate to alfalfa and the relative magnitude of effects the first, second, and third years. The work of the first two seasons indicates that the heavier applications give largest increases per acre but the lighter the application the greater the increase per unit of fertilizer. For the two-year period, an application of 70 pounds' of treble superphosphate per acre has given prac - tically twice' the increase per pound that has been obtained from a 200-pound application. The results of the first two years' work are being pi-epared for publication. FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Priming Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. — For the past year this work has been confined to apple pruning. One-half of the Jonathan and Winesap trees set five years ago were removed for growth measurements and other observations. Some were heavily and some lightly pruned at transplanting, with little or no later pruning. Heavy pruning at transplant - ing time resulted in greater height, trunk diameter, and weight than the light pruning. The heavy pruning also gave fewer scaffold limbs and a larger number of twigs, or potential </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station fruiting parts. There appeared to be no difference in the number of fruit buds. In a comparison of several methods and dates of pruning there was no significant difference in growth or fruit production of the filler apple varieties in the Union orchard. ■ Fruit Breeding.— This work was continued in a study of new varieties of strawberries, gooseberries, and plums. The past year also afforded an opportunity for observing the varietal differences in resistance to low temperatures of various standard and new varieties. Orchard Culture.— The 1931 crop was the first large one harvested from the cultural blocks in the Union Orchard. . There was little difference in yield from the trees in clover sod, permanent sod, and cultivated legume blocks; but the yield was slightly less than from comparable trees in the fil er blodk. The tree, growth has been greatest under cultiva - tion and least in the filler block. One very noticeable effect which could be traced directly to overstimulation due to cultivation was the prevalence of fire blight in the Jonathans. Infection became quite general in early July, particularly in the clean-cultivated section. Blighted twigs were cut from 10 trees in J-his block and from 10 trees in the adjoining filler plat. The 'twigs were counted and measured later with the results indicated. Ay. number Total length blighted twigs (feet) Cultivated, block 6C.1.4 !;00.i) Filler 8.2 1.7 Because of erosion the clean-culture block will be discon - tinued and some cover crop will be utilized to protect the soil. The soil-management work with grapes was continued arid records taken as to yield and growth of plants under various treatments. The results correspond with those given for. previous, years. Vegetable Experimentation— Variety Trials ami Cultural Tests.- — Supplemental irrigation with six of the more im - portant vegetables increased the yields from 30 to 100 per cent. Applications of one ; inch of supplemental water per week seemed the most desirable. Irrigation practically doubled the yield of early tomatoes up to September 1. and for the entire season increased the yield approximately 30 per cent. Asparagus experiments have been continued as in former years. The plats originally planted with large crowns are still continuing to be the most productive. The longer period of cutting appears to result in a larger yield the following </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forty-sixth Annual Report year. Shallow-planted plats are yielding more than deep - planted. Straw- and manure-mulched plats are producing very late and unsatisfactory crops. The application of com - mon salt causes the soil to become deflocculated and puddled, so that run-off is greater and yields are reduced. A number of the standard varieties of spinach were planted to determine how long they will persist in the vegetative con - dition. Extremes of more than three weeks were observed. The Savoy and Bloomsdale varieties fruited rather early, while the Victoria, Viroflay, and especially the Prince of Den - mark persisted much longer in spite of the excessive heat and long days during June. Some preliminary tests were made in a study of head-lettuce production. Under a paper mulch large growth was obtained but heads were not formed. Under a straw mulch the growth was less,' but firm heads were obtained. The plants in culti - vated plats were intermediate between these two in leafmess and head formation. . ■ [ . Experiments with tomatoes on the loess hills south of Ne - braska City, where^ithe canning of tomatoes is an established industry, were conducted in conjunction with the Otoe Food Products Company';. Applications of 100 pounds of treble superphosphate resulted in an increase in yield of 20 per cent or approximately two to three tons per acre. Manure and phosphate together increased the yield only slightly more. Most of these increases were due to the production of more tomatoes early in the season. The fertilized plats set fruit during very hot weather when other plats failed to do so. Ap - plications of phosphate in excess of 100 pounds per acre did not result in higher yields. Applications of nitrate of soda at .the time of fruit development indicate that further investi - gation along this line is desirable- Fruit Stuck Investigation. — One-half of the trees in the top - worked orchard were removed because of crowding. The roots were excavated several feet in every direction from the trunk so that the type of rooting could be observed and photo - graphed. All of the Virginia Crab root systems were quite similar iin having coarse roots extending laterally rather close to the surface, no matter what scion variety was budded into the scaffold branches. Hibernal root systems also had coarse roots but these extended downward more than Virginia Crab and showed a slight tap root development* Orchard Spraying. — During the year various kinds and strengths of fungicides were tested for control of apple scab and for damage from burning. Liquid lime-sulfur as it has been used in the past has caused considerable burning of fruit and foliage. It is believed that this injury may be reduced. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The test of fungicides for control of both apple scab and frog-eye or black-rot is being continued. Both diseases ap - peared quite serious during 1932. The value of pink spray as a control measure has already been demonstrated. This spring, because of a great deal of wet weather when the trees were coming into leaf, very few received -the pink spray, and as a result an early and severe infection of scab developed. Experimental, spraying of cherries at Nebraska City for control of leaf spot failed to yield results in 1931. Very little leaf spot developed so that the foliage on unsprayed check trees remained just as healthy as on trees receiving three applications of lime-sulfur. The Effect of Packing and Storing on the Keeping Quality of Apples. — Six varieties of apples were packed in baskets, both round bottom and tub type, and in boxes. In some of the containers shredded oiled paper was used and in others oiled wraps. The fruit was placed in storage at a temperature of 32° to 33° F. Certain packages . were removed for observa - tion at intervals of approximately one month, beginning No - vember 1 and running, for certain varieties, up to May 1 as the last date of removal. Data were obtained on several factors that affect quality. There was considerable varietal difference in the shrinkage, being greater with Winesap and Blacktwig and less with De - licious. As to the effect of packing, the fruit wrapped in oiled paper and packed in boxes had the least shrinkage and the tub baskets with no paper the greatest amount. The percent - age of cuts and rots did not vary greatly either with varietal or package differences. Rots caused by stem punctures were more frequent in the Jonathan than in other varieties. The percentage of storage scald varied with the variety and also with the package. Virginia Beauty, Missouri, King David, Jonathan, and Delicious showed little or no scald at any removal date in any of the packages. Winesap and Stay - man showed some scald at the later dates while Grimes, Black - twig, and York showed severe scald after a period in storage. Not much scald was found on any variety before February 1 except with Grimes, where it began to show January 1. Oiled paper, used either as wraps or as shredded packing, was effective in lessening the amount of scald but did not eliminate it entirely. A part of the fruit from the Union Fruit Farm was packed at the orchard and some brought to Lincoln for packing. The results did not seem to justify the practice of using a packing shed located a considerable distance from the producing point. The Root System of Apple Trees. — This project was inar.g - ui-ated during the past year to determine the effect of various </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Forty-sixth Annual Report cropping systems upon apple tree root development. A num - ber of trees of various varieties were planted last spring and are receiving different cultural treatments. The root systems will be excavated after one, two, or three years' growth. HOME ECONOMICS The Family History and Standards of Living of Farm Families in Selected Districts of Nebraska.— In the first year of this work, 80 co-operating homemakers enrolled and 59 completed the records. In the second year, now under way, there are 99 in the three counties, Cass, Fillmore, and Buffalo. The project will be continued for another year. Electric Cooking Stoves. — This project is planned to study the speed, thermal efficiency, and cost of operation of different types of electric stoves. Five standard stoves are under in - vestigation. The experimental phases of the work are divided into three groups: (1) the efficiency of the surface units and the determination of the proper utensil, (2) the de - termination of oven efficiency, which includes preheating, oven losses, distribution of oven temperature, and the rate of cool - ing, and (3) the measurement of temperatures over the entire stove. Tests on surface units have been divided into five parts, namely: the unit started cold with the cover on the utensil; the unit hot when the utensil, with the cover on, is placed on the unit; the unit hot with the cover off the utensil; and pro - longed boiling tests, one with the unit cold and the other with the unit hot at the time the utensil is placed on the unit. To determine the output, the time-temperature curves of the in - put tests are approached as nearly as possible with a calrod unit as an immersion heater. The utensils vary in size and kind of material. The quantity of water used has been 4,, 3, 2, and 1 pounds for each unit. The research work on the efficiency of the surface units has largely been completed. The study of oven efficiency is well under way. Satisfactory methods for recording the distribution of temperature and the output will be worked out. It is probable that the project will be completed during the coming year. Factors Affecting the Performance of Kerosene Stoves.- — This work was continued in a study of the effect of construc - tional details of the burner and framework on performance. The research has been completed and the data are ready for* publication. The project will be closed. INSECT CONTROL Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. — In - vestigations in connection with the control of the Hessian fly </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station by means of delayed sowing of the winter wheat were con - tinued to supplement and check the studies made in 1923, 1924, 1925, and. 1930. These studies will be completed for publication following one or two additional years' work. They show that by maintaining one or two field-observation stations to determine the emergence of the main fall brood of the fly from day to day, and adjusting these findings to the latitude, elevation, and summer and fall precipitation in the various fly-infested localities, it is possible to announce fly-safe dates of wheat sowing in advance with a high degree of accuracy. A survey to determine the area of Hessian-fly infestation was made in the fall of 1931. With the completion of an insectary, a study of the life histories and possible control of several other insects, notably the imported cabbage worm, egg-plant flea beetle, cherry slug, box elder plant bug and several species of common ants, was begun. Grasshopper Control. — Following the extensive damage by grasshoppers and drouth in Nebraska in the summer of 19:31. a grasshopper egg survey was made that fall between Sep - tember 10 and November 19, during which 91 Nebraska counties were surveyed, and the location and intensity of threatened damage for 1932 in all parts of the state was de - termined. The results were studied in relation to fhe weather conditions that had prevailed in 1930 and 1931. The egg - laying habits of the destructive species were studied both out - of-doors and in the insectary, and the matter of winter sur - vival of grasshopper eggs was given special attention. This woi-k served as a basis for recommendations on grasshopper control during the spring and early summer of 1932. The Distribution, Life History, and Means of Control of the Cutxcorms Attacking Corn in Nebraska.— This project was continued with satisfactory progress. A portion dealing with life histories requires accumulation of data over a long period. A Brood Study of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Ne - braska.—rln 1931 the fourth year of. an intensive study of the life history of the codling moth in Nebraska was completed. The weather conditions in the fall of 1930 sent the hibernating larvae into the winter in a condition favoring a heavy sur - vival. High mean temperatures during January and Feb - ruary of 1931 with copious rainfall and high humidity in March caused extremely early pupation and emergence of the spring brood of .moths. Developmental conditions for the pupae of the spring brood during May were not as favorable as usual, delaying the emergence of the spring brood of moths somewhat. First-brood larvae began hatching on June 2, but hatching was slow, probably because of the very high June </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-sixth Annual Report temperatures, so that the crest of hatching did not occur until June 20.- First cover sprays applied shortly after the first hatching of tirst-brood larvae were therefore too early. Continued, high temperatures shortened the pupal period of the first brood, bringing out the moths early in July. The flight of these moths ended very early, on August 21, and this short and intense season for the first brood of the codling moth was the outstanding feature of its 1931 life history. The first larvae of the second brood hatched on July 16, and the crest of hatching occurred on July 27, about the normal time. The evidence of the four years of work indicates that second cover sprays are to be applied during the last week in July except where the rainfall and humidity in that month are exceedingly low. Second-brood pupation began early, on August 5, and very high September temperatures reduced the percentage of second-brood larvae entering dormancy and in - creased the number pupating, thus producing an earlier and much stronger flight of second-brood moths than had obtained in any of the preceding three seasons. In 1931, for the first time during these studies, the third brood of larvae, which was in evidence from August 30 on, would have been strong enough to have justified a cover spray early in September, were the problem of spray residues not to have been con - sidered. LIVESTOCK FEEDING . Wintering Rations for Stock Calves. — Eight lots of 14 steer - calves each were used for the third trial in a wintering ex - periment, devoted primarily to a study of the use of the corn plant in the form -of corn silage and ground corn fodder. On an acre basis corn silage proved to be 15 per cent more efficient than ground corn fodder. On the basis of dry matter, ensilage produced 9 per cent more gain than ground corn fodder. Both feeds proved to be palatable and there was practically no weigh-back. Calves did not seem to tire of the ground fodder. Corn silage supplemented with one pound of cottonseed. cake produced 379 steer-day rations per acre and 85 per cent as much gain as a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Three hundred and forty-five steer-day rations were obtained from one acre of ground corn fodder supple - mented with alfalfa in contrast to only 164 from an acre of corn when fed as a full ration of shelled grain and alfalfa. Silage supplemented with one pound of cake per day gave 14 per cent greater gain than silage supplemented with two pounds of alfalfa, and at current prices the cost was 10 per cent less. One pound of cottonseed cake gave 8 per cent greater gain than two pounds of alfalfa when fed with ground corn fodder. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Lot 1 — shelled corn Lot 2— shelled corn K ( clacked wheat •;,, Lot 3— she ed com ',., crucked wheat &gt;■■ Lot 4— shelled corn, './cracked wheat »4 Lot 5— cracked wheat :; ,, cracked barley ', . ■ All lots consumed approximately the same amount of (rrain The feeding of wheat in amounts of one-foiu-th to Le-hlf v the grain ration gave results equal both in rate of S and efficiency to a corn ration. Feeding as much a&lt; t nVe ' ,,' wheat produced no harmful effectsfbut the caftte^wSe Srde, to keep oh lull teed and gained more sWnvlv. The 1 , rS e v nig barley responded favorably. The bulkiness of tffis' Sin S&amp;^SJSh 7 P astu . re .. cl -°P! « parted fn the s „ h'g f Wo^. through co-operation of the Departments of Agmnomv and Animal Husbandry. Twehfv aci-ps nf ]•.,„ w« i J Records are being kept on a check lot on | ermanen l-^s' The results will be compiled on a steer-day basis Forage 'Crops for Ho,,*.— Eight lots of thirteen 7S noun, I Pigs .each were fed different grain rations i, a ! 0- h n ' ti All lots had access to sudan grass and received ttfnkaS •.&lt; ,' ■ supplement. In this te^t- whole wheat proved tS £ K cent as efficient as corn. Tins is lower than he averse of previous tests. The gain produced per day was? Sselv </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-sixth Annual Report ground wheat 1.64 pounds, finely ground wheat 1.47 pounds, finely ground soaked wheat 1.55 pounds, corn 1.52 pounds, and whole wheat 1.51 pounds. In efficiency the rank was corn, coarsely ground wheat, finely ground wheat, coarsely ground soaked wheat, and finely ground soaked wheat. The wheat - fed pigs consumed slightly less tankage than those receiving .corn. The more finely ground wheat was less palatable than the coarsely ground. Fine grinding requires more power; hence there is a double advantage in coarse grinding. There was no advantage from soaking. Ground rye was materially less palatable than wheat. Pigs receiving rye gained only 1.29 pounds daily. They lacked finish and bloom at the close of the test. Ground soybeans made an unsatisfactory supple - ment to corn. The feed consumption was light, the gain was only 0.82 pound daily, and efficiency was low. Driiry By-products as Hog Feed. — Four lots of 113-pound pigs were fed 80 days on shelled corn supplemented with (1) tankage. (2) skim milk, (S) skim-milk (half feed) and tank - age, and (4). powdered skim milk. A full feed of skim milk increased, the total feed consumption and the daily gains. Substitution of tankage for part of the skim milk lowered the daily gain by 0.19 pound and slightly increased the cost. Powdered skim milk produced 0.42 pound less gain daily than a full leed of .skim milk and increased the cost per hundred pounds. Powdered skim milk proved to be as efficient as tankage. . The Utilization of Wheat and Rye as Hag Feed. — Five lots, cadi containing 10 pigs weighing 113 pounds, were fed dif - ferent" fattening rations for 80 days in dry lot. l'ifc.l required to produce 100 pounds of ••uin I f'i it i i Coarsely . Kintiy i r , . eain ! s-livll..! Whole-. Bro ui.d rfouml • Ground TankoKO { iorn _ »■:&lt;«■:■ t whe-.t . _ whl-at 1 r &gt; c ' l.h.&lt;: lj&gt;*. l.l&gt;*. l.l'.i. ' /.(«•.. ■ l.h.i. 1 1.11 -110 I '.. ' 41 • 2' 1.73 4511 ..:... , 30 ;i 1.79 ...... :;&lt;). r ) 28 4 '1.81 ■ .:..: 382 28 . 5 1.40' 205 _••••••_. __O^_ 2Q. r ) 1 o") Because of the greater cost involved in fine grinding, there was no resultant advantage although it produced the greatest gains. The feeding of equal parts of ground rye and shelled corn resulted in the production of 100 pounds of gain with less grain and a somewhat lower cost. To produce 100 pounds of gain oii .whole wheat required 19 pounds more grain but 11 pounds less tankage than where corn was used. All wheat lots gained more rapidly than those on corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lots of 104-pound fall pigs were started on test Februn rv 8 ;j2 J ed . 7 5.day 8 . All lots received corn. The variable* con sisted of mixtures of protein supplements of plant origin with tankage constituting the base in all cases. Cottonseed me - fa u ? r a e ii c ir al&gt; soybe f n me^' and c °™ SS \\eie used. In all cases, mixed supplements incited greater consumption ot corn and increased daily gains The h chest nprl y f in v L81 P° u " ds - was obtained where a mixture it •&gt; parts tankage, 1 part linseed meal, and 1 part a fa f Ll rZnT d f *? ai l ka P a !?" e prodllced 1 51 PoS of S The lesults of this test indicate clearly that there is an advant-iLc in mixing protein supplements for hogs. There not onfvwfs an mcrease in daily gain but likewise some savfn?^ corn re - quired to produce 100 pounds of gain. The several sSSntel ments proved to be similar in replacement value PR \u^ Ct0^'L Affectinu the Qualit V (md Payability of Meat —A study of. the carcasses produced by hogs fed on corn and t-ink S^'nT 0 ' heat t , anka « e - grou » d ™ and tankage an J coin and soybeans disclosed considerable variation in firm - carcassS' 0U Thn Wh f *, ***** Vye produced tliL&gt; fl™S carcasses Those fed on corn and tankage were not quite so hrm, while thecorn and soybean carcasses were vc'v soft Refractive indices were determined on back-fat samples' L,kp y n P C .f ngS l Ch - eCk With '» radin S s made in the coolers 1 v Wl tv cfita ti fl ins Wei ; e l^ sed for C00kin^ tests *' 1(i Palatal bihty data. The flavor ot the lean of the wheat-fed pork w-as most pronounced and desirable. .That from the rve-fed lot was rated lowest in desirability. There was a very slight variation in tenderness of the samples. The soybean pork w &lt; most juicy and had the richest flavor l»mh o a P air . ed - indi . vidua .l lamb-feeding experiment, eight .ewe lambs of simnar breeding -were used. The rations all in - fnstfn^ 11 / 11^ 1^ 1^ Gr ? und s °y bea "s were added in one mstance and cottonseed meal in another. Observations were made on the basis of uniformity of feed consumption, thrift ot lambs, and complete carcass and meat-cooking studies Sov - beans proved to be distinctly unpalatable, and resulted in a marked softening of the fat Feeding Wheat to Lambs.— ln a study to determine the rela - tive palatabihty of ground corn and ground wheat when mixed with alfalfa hay and fed to lambs, ground corn pro" duced a : larger daily gain but required 12 pounds more of grain and 11 pounds more of alfalfa to produce 100 pounds of gam In a third lot. lambs were permitted to have free choice of ground corn and ground alfalfa in one feeder and </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-sixth Annual Report ground wheat and ground alfalfa in another. The ground - wheat mixture proved to be somewhat more palatable, as the average daily consumption of this was 0.79 pound, whereas that of the corn and alfalfa mixture was only 0.64. These lambs gained slightly less than those in. the other two lots, but made somewhat more efficient use of the grain. Production of Market Lambs from Aged Western Eives. — Three lots, each containing 33 ewes, were bred for the pro - duction of early lambs. The lot which received a heavy grain ration both before and after lambing gained 48 pounds. The ewes receiving no grain before lambing and a heavy ration after gained 35 pounds, while those receiving no grain either before or after lambing gained 20 pounds. Thus the grain feeding resulted in a substantial increase in weight. On March 12, when the lambs were started on test, the average weights by lots were 22, 21, and 19 pounds. They were marketed 94 days later weighing 77, 75,. and 68 pounds. The ewes fed heavily on grain not only gained more but produced heavier lambs which sold to better advantage. As in the other trials, the full-fed ewes were evaluated the highest. The Value of Protein Supplements in Lamb-feeding Ra - tions.—A study of the relative value of cottonseed meal, lin - seed fneal, and corn gluten meal as protein supplements when fed alone and in combinations with corn and alfalfa was con - tinued. Results checked quite well with the first trial with the exception that cottonseed meal failed to show an advantage either when fed as the sole supplement or in the mixtures. Lambs fed on corn and alfalfa gained 0.&amp;71 pound daily. The greatest daily gain, 0.398 pound, was produced where corn gluten meal supplemented the corn and alfalfa. Corn and alfalfa produced the cheapest gains. All lots were evaluated the same; consequently there was no financial advantage from the addition of the protein supplements but there was from the standpoint of palatability. Market Lambs from Late-bred Eives. — Further work was done on market-lamb production from late-bred western ewes. The lambs from the late-bred ewes of the previous year's trial were finished. All ran with the dams on sudan-grass pasture from May 7 until July 28. During this period the 46 head produced an average gain of 40 pounds. Sixteen were then marketed weighing 75 pounds and sold for $7.25 per hundred pounds. They consumed a daily ration of 1.17 pounds of corn. The remainder were fed on pasture until October 27. They were marketed at an average weight of 81 pounds and sold at $6.00 per hundred. This trial indicated that it may be well to have lambs of sufficient size and finish to market by . midsummer. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station MILLING AND BAKING Preparation and Study of the Cereal Glutelins —Work the per cent alcoS '* of 1 met . h ?dS A .have been found useful for this type acid and T2I fdSSS? ti r\ (1) nJi. eutraIization of the ace *' factors "that JflW S, S3 l S - u There are ' however, several iactors that affect the amount, the composition and the nhvs i~ R r ,°P erties of , the glutenin fraction, chief among which S silV flf kfn? T^ I 2 ? il ind Of salt ' &lt; 8 &gt; conc7nti«oS perature! a (ethyl ° r met M), -and (3) tem - inJ".mnn" h £? e i. affpI ? e 1 additJ onal information bear- S? nnTtL ! establishment of optimum conditions for the Reparation of the various protein fractions. One of the chief SSpS C f a + ? bee " tO u find a Set of conditions under whS ttn in or? 0 ? m . a y &gt; prepared with a minimum of altera - tion in original physical properties. Among the more im - portant findings with regard to glutenin are the folio wing: ;i; fi^ e " the "glutenin fraction" is precipitated by neutral, uation (at suitable temperature) of the acetic a-id-alcohol dispersion (either in 60 per cent methyl or 60 per cent etlu ™n fV* he ?. omeS rai ? idly "denatured" to the extent that i can not be redispersed in dilute acetic acid. This is a decided disadvantage in that redispersion is highly desiASe fS pur - poses of purification and identification h™ Wher \ tn ! glutenin fraction is precipitated bv the addi - tion of neutral salts, but without neutralization of the acetic acid, lower temperatures are required in ethyl alcoholic dS- EeTngcomXblfe" 6 " * U8ed ' conditions nriiS??t at^f atiOn , ?f glu . tenin invariably occurs when it is Sermon hvt^ r ° n irV S - PerS1 i &gt;n ! 5 methyl alcohol-acetic acid dis - persion by the addition of salts. tm?A o T !? e USe^ ° i P°{ assium sulfate as the precipitating salt wWho X ard i d « n 1 a ! urati 9. n of the glutenin regardless of 2? the alcohol is methyl or ethyl, the denaturation being more rapid in methyl than in ethyl alcohol. pr,f; * ne + ?6t ° f co " diti ons has been- found in which the glut - enin fraction can be precipitated without denaturation, or at any rate with a minimum of denaturation, for it may be re - peatedly redispersed and reprecipitated. This involves the </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-sixth Annual Report use of sodium chloride in acetic acid-ethyl alcohol dispersion at about 11° C. This procedure apparently offers decided ad - vantages over all others that have been studied, and it will be used as the basis for further work. ' Standardization of Methods for Experimental Baking Pro - cedure.— The : assignment of the American Association of Cereal Chemists' Baking Research Fellow to this laboratory was discussed in last year's report. The fellowship term ex - pired during the past year, and comprehensive reports have been organized and published. These studies indicate the manner in which numerous factors, individually and in var - ious combinations, operate in affecting (1) characteristics of the experimental loaf, and (2) variability of results. The project is now closed. A report of a comprehensive study of "Some Effects of Varying Sugar Concentration in Bread Dough on Fermentation By-products and Fermentation Toler - ance" is in press. Flour Enzyme Studies. — Serving in the capacity of Asso - ciate Referee on the Diastatic Value of Flour for the Associa - tion of Official Agricultural Chemists, the writer has devoted considerable time and effort to a systematic study of flour diastatic activity, its quantitative estimation, and its signif - icance. Two papers dealing with these and related matters . have been submitted for publication. These and studies of a similar character are being carried forward under a new project assignment, "Enzymes of Wheat and Flour as Related to Flour Grade and Baking Characteristics." PLANT DISEASES The Pathological and Physiological Aspects of Alfalfa Fail - ures in Nebraska.— Several phases of this project are being carried on, a part of the work in co-operation with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Winter Injury and Cold Resistance. — Out of these studies a method has been developed for testing the cold resistance of alfalfa seedlings under controlled conditions. It is a useful tool, not only for determining cold resistance within a short period of time (8 weeks), but also in selecting hardier indi - viduals. During the past year three publications dealing with the different aspects of this phase have been published, and a fourth manuscript prepared lor publication. Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt. — During the past two years many hundreds of alfalfas, collected for the most part by Mr. Westover. of the Forage Crops Office in most of the alfalfa-growing regions of the world, have been tested for susceptibility to wilt. At present approximately 30,000 plants </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station which proved resistant to wS 2nd raid A Y* "° W in , ha " d The a Nat n u°;i o?t .'"-SdSSfa the' Hell Iarge number °' studied and it has been louml hat * na - T Y of Wilt has bee " with anatomical atrScfure To th- re^ lsta " ce can be tied up added studies of the metaholilm th s '."Y^tigation has been istry of healthv and creased nSn^ yS1O t L° S /;, and ™i««cheiif - of the pathogenesis ot ! bacterial tint Zl . the , e " t . ire history. and likewise productive resistant to cold and wilt tetion to moisture-hSg cScSv S" iV" "j 6 llisease in re " of development of the S pK V,' gS »»M°J »'«ee to susceptibility? y ° lorm wound cork tissue different^eTo'/scat ZnAur^™" 1^* isolated &amp;™» </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-sixth Annual Report Detailed records of scab and Fusarium wilt in all of the rotation plots at the Box Butte Experiment Farm and in var - ious cultural experiments at the same location have required considerable time but significant differences probably will not be found until the experiments have been continued several more years. Up to date the rotation experiments have shown great variations in the occurrence of scab in different replica - ations of similar rotations, the only consistent difference being in the large amount of scab in the continuous potato plats. These variations clearly indicate the necessity for a detailed study of the many complex factors influencing the activities of the micro-organisms in the soil. ■ While some study has been made of the number and types of micro-organisms oc - curring in these soils the work has been greatly handicapped by the lack of local laboratory facilities. The new laboratory building at the Box Butte Experiment Farm is being equipped at the present time and this phase of the work will receive move attention during the coming year. The Cherry. Leaf Spot Disease Caused bij Coccomyces hiemaliSi — This project, in co-operation with the Department of Horticulture, has been confined to a study of spraying mot hods for control of the disease. Owing to weather con - ditions last summer the disease was not serious in the experi - mental orchard at Nebraska City and no significant differences were obtained by the various spray schedules. • Wilt a&gt;id Die-back of the Elm hi Nel)7-aska. — The occur - rence of an important new fungus disease of the elm has been established by surveys, isolations, and infection studies. A master's-degree thesis by P. R. Frink, entitled "A Study of the Wilt and Die-back Diseases of Elm in Eastern Nebraska", has been completed. POTATOES 'Potato Selection for Seed Purposes. — Several phases of this project were continued. Strain Tests. — The number of tuber lines of Triumph pota - toes was reduced and the amount of stock of each strain was increased. The strains have been separated on the basis of the vegetative vigor, which causes a difference in the time of maturity of the plant. Eight selected strains, varying from extremely shoi't-season to extremely long-season types, were planted in comparative trial plats on four different dates at Alliance in 1931. Trials of the same strains have been conducted at Scottsbluff under irrigation with both early and late planting and early and late harvesting. Other trials have been carried on under irrigation and on dry land at North Platte and also at Lincoln. In addi- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. tion, a standard set of tests harvested on two different dates at each of the trial points have been conducted in co-operation with experimenters in Texas, Louisiana, Alabama, Florida, Mississippi, Arkansas, and Missouri. Because of the variation in the conditions at various places and the seasonal peculi - arities, it is not yet advisable to formulate conclusions con - cerning these various strains. It appears, however, that the difference in total yield is much less than the 'appearance of the strains in the field would lead one to expect. Production of Foundation Tuber-indexed Stock. — This work is being diminished because the need is no longer great. Several thousand tubers from tuber lines are indexed each winter and are increased at the Alliance experiment farm for dissemination. The acreage of certified seed potatoes now being planted in western Nebraska from stock indexed at one time is well over 5,000. Seed Potato Production in Eastern and Central Nebraska, — These studies are carried on with disease-free stocks. Results continue to indicate that when diseases are eliminated from the seed, and when the variation in the maturity and conse - quent duration of the dormant period are recognized, satis - factory seed potatoes can be produced in these localities. Disease control is more difficult under irrigation than in the unirrigated areas. Experiments in Potato Planting. — The details in general represent no departure from the results af former years. Shallow planting is desirable provided the soil can be man - aged in such a way that the pieces will not dry out. Planting large seed pieces far apart is not quite so good as planting the same total weight of smaller pieces closer to - gether. A Study of Degeneracy in Seed-potato Stocks.— This was continued in a study of the effect, of time of planting and harvesting, and a comparison of seed, from irrigated ami dry - land districts. Time of Planting and Harvesting. — Late planting continues to produce potatoes of the best market quality as •measured by type, color, and freedom from disease, but because of imma-. turity they lose more weight in. storage. When planted the following season the results were essentially the same as in former years, there being no significant difference in the pro - ductivity of the different stocks. Their value in this respect depends largely upon the time the seed potatoes of different maturities are planted during the second year. Irrigated vs. Dry-land-grown Seed. — This project has been carried on to a small extent with trials in Nebraska anil in the southern states. In the absence of virus disease it is </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-sixth Annual Report ■ difficult to distinguish any difference between the seed from the two sources. There appears to be more shrinkage in the case of the irrigated seed during shipment. At Scottsblutf potatoes from various irrigated rotation plats were grown in comparative trial plats the following year to determine the possible effect of the different soil conditions and to make a comparison of these irrigated stocks with the dry-iand stock of the same line. Differences were found but in no consistent direction and of no significance.: Conclusions as to this phase are being withheld until the experiment can be conducted tor another year. POULTRY ''Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Fading: — -This project is ' co-operative between the Depart - ments of 'Chemistry. 'and Poultry. The comparative slaughter - te?t method discussed in last year's report was applied to Heavy-breed '"chicks on a standard complete ration containing -() per cent picteiri. i he data secured in previous work, in - volving the analyses of 06 newly hatched chicks, have indi - cated the percentages of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus, respectively, in the chicks at the start of the feeding trial. The composition of newly hatched chicks hiving been es - tablished, oO chicks were fed individually. in such a manner that the feed consumption over a two-months period was ac - curately known. At the end of the period each chick was analyzed for nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and fat. The composition of the feed was also determined. Knowing the . amount of each nutrient in each bird at the slaughter weight, and the estimated composition of each chick at the beginning pf the test, together with quantity of each nutrient consumed, it was possible to calculate the percentage ot retention for nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus. ■ ; ' The following values were obtained in feeding 30 chicks ior 60 (lavs on the standard ration : Percentage retained •Nutrient ; ; of amount fed ■Phosphorus ■ ■ 2 '- 4 ± °- 17 These data show that the method will permit the estimation of the percentage of retention of food nutrients with far greater dependability and less individual variation than can be hoped for with the methods involving analysis of excreta. Although it is laborious and time-consuming,; the higher de - gree of precision appears to justify its use inj nutritional in - vestigations with birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station A full report of this work is in preparation, and studies now in progress involve the effect of increased calcium in the ration, on the percentage of retention of each nutrient. Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. — This project is co-operative between the Departments of Poultry Hus - bandry arid Chemistry. During the past year a series of ex - periments to determine the antirachitic value of sardine oil for growing chicks was conducted. Comparisons were made with a sample of cod-liver oil which previous experiments had indicated would prevent rickets when fed at one-fourth per cent levels added to a standard basal ration. Bone-ash and growth-rate data are believed to justify the following conclusions : one-eighth per cent of sardine oil did not contribute sufficient of the antirachitic factor to promote normal calcification. One-half per cent, however, produced normal calcification. No improvements in calcification or growth rate were obtained by increasing the sardine-oil level about one-half per cent. Previous work at this station indicated a significant dif - ference in the growth-promoting value for chicks of dried buttermilk and dried skim milk when fed at the same 'protein level.' Differences in the vitamin B complex values, lactic acid,. and lactose levels appear to offer the best leads for an ex - planation of the difference in growth-promoting value of the two products. During the past year a series of experiments was conducted to obtain further information. An experiment in which low-acid dried buttermilk u;is compared, with high-acid buttermilk indicated a slight ad - vantage for the latter. The probable error of the difference in growth rate of the two lots, however, is just a little less than one-third the observed difference, indicating that further work should be done with larger numbers of individuals. The nutritive value of lactose as compared with starch, dextrin, and sucrose was also determined. Twelve per cent of each was added to a basal ration complete for all known nutritional essentials. The growth rates of 56 chicks in each of the lots in which the carbohydrate (12 per cent) was the only variable were not significantly different. Research chiefly with rats has indicated that lactose may influence nutrition through an alteration of the pH of the material in the digestive tvact. The pH of the material in the digestive tract of each of twelve birds from the starch, dex - trin, sucrose, and lactose lots was determined. No significant differences were observed. The effect of modifying the calcium-phosphorus ratio of a standard ration for growing chicks, when optimum, condi - tions for calcium and phosphorus assimilation are provided, </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Forty-sixth Annual Report was studied. The basal ration used (4-F) contained 0.88 per cent calcium and 0.79 per cent phosphorus. This was mod - ified by adding precipitated calcium carbonate to provide a Ca:P ratio ot' 2:1. No improvement in calcification was ob - served. The same ration was modified by the addition of phosphorus-contributing salts (dibasic sodium phosphate, monobasic sodium phosphate, and monobasic ammonium phosphate respectively) to produce the ratio of one part calcium to two parts phosphorus. The growth rate on the high-phosphorus rations was suboptimum, but the ash content of the bones was normal. Inheritance of Egg Production. — This project was con - tinued in a study of the effect of line-breeding and outcrossing on fertility, hatchability, vigor, and egg production. While some interesting figures have been obtained, the data are not sufficient for conclusions. Turkey Production. — A study was made of factors affecting the hatchability of turkey eggs. Preliminary to a study of the effect- of humidity on normal turkey embryonic development, the weight loss of 300 eggs of approximately, the same size (80-90 grams) hatched in the same cabinet incubator was ob - served On the twenty-fourth day eggs varied in their weight loss from 9.61 per cent to 26.29 per cent of the original weight. No correlation was observed between the weight of poults at 56 days after hatching and the weight loss experienced during the first 24 days of incubation. RURAL ECONOMICS Cost of Producing Farm Crops. — This work is carried on in co-operation with farmers. Rooks are furnished for the keep - ing of accurate records of costs. During the calendar year 1931, 151 records were completed on the cost of growing wheat, 264 on the cost of growing corn, and 67 on the cost of operating either a tractor or a corn-picker. For the current calendar year, 731 records are being kept. The major part of the co-operating farmers live in- Phelps, Fillmore, Chey - enne. Saunders, Cass, Perkins, Thurston,: and Douglas counties. ■ : The farmer keeps a record of his hours of labor and of his other costs on forms furnished by the College of Agriculture. At the close of the season the records are tabulated at the college. ..Farm Organization and Farm Costs. — This project utilizes the farm account book for obtaining information upon the relative profit obtained under different systems of organizing the farm business in the various areas of the state. Many of the farmers who keep a farm record book keep cost-of-pro - duction records upon one or two crops. A total of 819 farm </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station account books were summarized for 1931. More than 1,300 have been placed with co-operating farmers for 1932. Nebraska Farm Land Prices. — Work under this project is divided into three parts. The first study is a history of farm land prices from 1860 to 1931. The consideration involved in nearly every transfer by warranty deed has been secured for eleven Nebraska counties. The tabulation of the records has been completed and will be prepared for publication. The second phase is the study of farm mortgages and land prices in York county for the past sixty years. All data have been collected and tabulated, and will be prepared for publi - cation following the publication of Part I. The third division of the project compares the assessed and sales value of Nebraska farm land for the years 1921-1931. The size of the farm is one of the factors that apparently affects the relationship between the assessed and sales value. It is hoped that publication upon this part of the project can be made during 1933. Cost of Marketing Corn and Wheat in Nebraska by Dif - ferent Methods. — The financial and operating cost data for farmers' elevators for the past year have been procured and added to the several years' records already obtained. Analysis has given evidence of the influence of such factors as volume of business, side lines, use of labor, and use of equipment on operating costs and financial results. The complete data per - mit an insight into the financial progress of farmers' elevators since 1918. Data on car-lot shipments of the principal grains and kinds of livestock from selected shipping points in the state are being collected and tabulated. It is hoped to determine dif - ferences in the seasonal movement of these products from the various parts of the state, the year-to-year variations in such movement, and the reason for such differences and variations. Transporting Livestock to Market.— -This project involves a comparative study of transportation of livestock by train and by truck. It takes into consideration not only the cost but the effect on the livestock shipped. The field studies have been completed and the material is being prepared for pub - lication. , Economic Studies in Prices, Volume of Production, and Purchasing Power of Farm Products. — Data upon prices paid farmers for corn, wheat, oats, hogs, butterfat, eggs, and po - tatoes at different Nebraska points from January, 1895, to December, 1931, have been obtained. The prices vary widely during the period, but purchasing power varies even more widely. The data are being analyzed and the findings will probably be published soon. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">. Forty-sixth Annual Report i -..■■■; state serum plant There was considerable hog cholera in the state in August, September, and October. The plant experienced no difficulty in filling all orders promptly and kept a supply of serum in storage for an emergency. It continued the policy of buying serum subject to retest and of manufacturing virus. Because of the fluctuating demand, the plant purchased some virus to meet, emergencies. Clear concentrated serum Retailed at 65 cents and blood serum at 55 cents per hundred c.c. until April 1, when the prices were reduced to 50 and 45, respectively. On the same date virus was reduced from I 1 /* to 1 cent per c.c. Following is a report of the serum and virus sales by ' months, and a statement showing the financial status at the close of the year 1932. It shows total assets of approximately S7.000 less than a year ago. This reduction in assets is due to the lowering of the inventory price of the serum on hand. Cubic centimeters Serum on hand January 1, 1932 6,403,275 Serum purchased and delivered during 1932........ ....'. 7,587,075 Total serum • handled for year 13,990,350 Seiu m and virus sold bv months: Serum Virus . . : c.c. c.c. January 117,125 7,965 February •-• 56,500 4,130 March ' : 62,000 4,035 (Vpril 319,650 20,970 Mav 563,075 47,720 June 1,149,300 90,035 j u lv 664,200 49,325 fVueust ...."■ 1,796,575 128,295 September 1,226,775 75,240 October • 522,075 35,030 November 255,225 i 17,260 December 242,475 18,480 Total sold 6,974,975- 498,485 Used by plant... : 40,375 4,500 Total \ 7,015,350 502,985 •" Serum on hand January 1, 1933 .;.... 6,975,000 c.c. Total gross sales ■ $36,210,38 Money collected and receipted for 39,713.64 Cash' balance on hand January 1, 1932, according j to report of bursar , | 2n Serum stock value , , 2 Mln nn Accounts due and miscellaneous stock 4uu.uu Total assets :...„..„...: - $99,346.51 Pifis used in i-etesting serum and making virus '. 4bO Number of orders for year i •■ 2,926 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station north platte substation The work of the North Platte Substation has been con - ducted in the usual manner throughout the year. A severe hail storm on August 5 damaged crops, young trees, and shrubs, and caused an expense of $3,000 to repair roofs. Agronomy. — Conditions were unfavorable, and the dry - land yields were among the poorest in the history of the station. The preceding year, 1931, was one of the driest on record. Except on fallow there was no available subsoil mois - ture at the beginning: of the 1932 season. ■ Total precipitation in 1932 was close to normal. Its efficiency was, however, very low on account of wide departures from normal distribution and a high proportion of rains falling in torrential showers with heavy run-off and little penetration into the subsoil. Hail on June 11 caused some injury to small grain and the hail August 5 caused the heaviest loss in crops in the history of the station. Dry-land Crop Rotations and Tillarjc Methods. — The crop? rotation and tillage-method studies in co-operation with the U. S. Division of Dry Land Agriculture have completed their twenty-sixth year. Unusual results in 1932 were the com - plete loss of winter wheat, the excellent response of spring - seeded grains to the fallow treatment, and very low yields of row crops as a result of drouth and hail injury. On cropped land there was no moisture for the germination of winter wheat. On fallow, although there was a good .supply of mois - ture at lower depths, the upper soil was too dry for winter wheat to become established. All tillage preparations- were reseeded with spring wheat. Spring wheat, oats, and barley after fallow produced yields of 25.5, 40.9, and 29.0 bushels per acre respectively. These yields were four to six times greater than the yields on land cropped the previous year, and close to the long-time averages of these crops after fallow. The yield differences that usually result from differences in crop sequences and between tillage practices other than fallow were reduced to insignificant amounts by the severe moisture shortage. Spring-grain yields after corn exceeded those after small grain by slight amounts. Yields after fall plowing usually exceed those after spring plowing but in most cases the reverse was true for the season. Results from the crop-rotation and tillage-methods studies for the 25-year period from 1907 to 1931 have been summarized and will be published. Crop Improvement. — The crop-improvement work is com - pleting the ninth year of co-operation with the U. S. Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases. On account of the unfavorable </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Forty-sixth Annual Report ; ■ ■ . - _ ' ' . ■ i season, yields were low and the differences ; between crop varieties less than usual. The average yield of 20 varieties of winter wheat was 8.2 bushels per acre on fallow. The highest yield was 10.7 bushels from Kharkof. '&lt; Nebraska 60, which is' usually one of the better-yielding varieties, produced 9.7. Oro, which is promising on account of its resistance to bunt, yielded 9.4 bushels. Yields of spring wheat following corn ranged from 4.0 to 11.0 bushels per acre, the high yield being from Ceres, which has been the leading variety in these tests for the past several years. The second-highest yield, from Kubanka durum, was 2.5 bushels per acre below that of Ceres. Yields of 17 varieties of barley after corn ranged from 3.1 to 11.1 bushels per acre, with Trebi as the; high-yielding variety. Comfort, the most promising of the! smooth-awned varieties at this station, occupied twelfth place; this year with a yield of only 5.6 bushels per acre. The high yield of lo varieties of oats after corn was 16.2 bushels per acre, made by both Iowar and Fulghum. Iowar has been among the leading varieties since the beginning of the tests. Varietal and breeding test plats of corn were so severely injured by hail that no results were secured. ! The work will be continued next year from remnant seed saved from pre - vious years. Pump Irrigation. — During the season of 1932 the pump was operated on 61 days for a total of 524.25 hours. Water was applied from one to four times on 107 acres. The average rate of discharge of the pump was 1,112 gallons per minute, or 2 48 acre inches per hour. A total of 108 acre feet was pumped This required 9,291 kilowatt-hours of electricity or 17 7'' kilowatt-hours per hour. The cost of ;electricity was slightly less than four cents per kilowatt-hour, or approxi - mately 70 cents per hour, or 28.22 cents per acre inch or §3.39 per acre foot. . ., . Owing to the damage clone by the hail, it was not possible to secure accurate figures on the profit per acre due to the irrigation. However, there was a fair margin of profit from the water applied by pump irrigation to potatoes and alfalfa. The charges for irrigating include an overhead charge cover - ing interest upkeep, and depreciation on the plant and operat - ing expense of the motor and pump, and man labor in dis - tributing the water. The results confirm the conclusion of former. years, that water may be lifted to a height of 50 feet or more profitably for irrigating potatoes, corn, and alfalfa under conditions such as exist at the North Platte Substation. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Horses. — Satisfactory progress has teen made with the Percheron breeding herd. There is a ready demand for breeding animals. There are now in the herd seven mares of breeding age, three fillies, and two stallion colts. Com, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves. — Five lots of twelve Hereford steer. calves were fed for a period of 194 days on grain rations of shelled corn, ground wheat, ground rye, a mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and ground wheat, and a mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and ground rye. Alfalfa hay was fed to all lots. Data secured check with the 1930 results which were published in Experiment Station Bulletin No. 263. The experiments in fattening calves on wheat and rye indi - cate that either of these grains may replace corn to a con - siderable extent or entirely with favorable results. However, it is well to feed the rye or wheat early in the fattening period or to mix them with corn throughout and to finish on corn alone. Creep-feeding Calves. — The effect of feeding grain to calves while running with their dams on pasture is being studied. How or when grain may be fed most profitably and how the calves may be handled to the best advantage after weaning have not yet been fully determined. The calves from the 1931 creep-feeding project were full-fed shelled corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot after weaning. The steer calves fed grain under range conditions before weaning made more rapid gains in the feed lot than similar calves that had not been creep-fed. The creep-fed calves also sold for more money and returned a greater profit than calves not creep-fed. Heifer calves fed grain under range conditions before weaning showed no advantage in the feed lot in comparison with .sim - ilar calves not fed before weaning. The work will bo con - tinued until dependable results have been obtained. The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle. — The third year's work has been completed and the data are being pre - pared for publication. The three years' work indicate that the full feeding of yearling heifers on alfalfa pasture is a practical method of beef production. Hogs. — Studies on the feeding value of rye compared with corn for fattening hogs have been made during the past year. Data secured indicate that on pasture ground rye is from 80 to 85 per cent as valuable as shelled corn for fattening hogs when fed with tankage. Hogs fed whole rye under the same conditions gained as rapidly as hogs fed ground rye but re - quired approximately one-eighth more rye and one-eighth more tankage per unit of gain. Rye has not proved satisfac- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-sixth Annual Report tory-as the sole grain for fattening hogs in a dry lot even when fed With a mixed protein supplement containing choice alfalfa. ■ Sheep.— -A flock of grade Rambouillet ewes is being main- - tained as a farm flock. Hampshire and Southdown rams have been used to sire market lambs. Data ; on the cost of maintaining such a flock and on the returns from it are being secured. Corn; Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs. — Five lots of western lambs were fed grain rations of shelled corn, whole wheat, whole rye, and a mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and whole rye. Alfalfa hay ■was fed to all lots. This year's results indicate that wheat and rye have a value pound for pound of from 85 to 90 per cent of that of corn for fatten - ing lambs when fed with alfalfa hay. Three lots of lambs were self-fed ground shelled corn, ground wheat, and ground rye, the grain being mixed with ground alfalfa. In each case the self-fed lambs ate more grain and gained more rapidly than the lambs hand-fed the -comparable ration. The self-fed lambs required approximately as much grain and somewhat less hay per 100 pounds of gain than, the hand-fed lots. Poultry. — The station maintains flocks of White Leghorns and Buff Orpington chickens and of Mammoth Bronze turkeys as demonstration flocks. Holstein Dairy Herd. — The effort during the year has been to improve the quality rather than to increase the number. Several of the least desirable cows were marketed. There has been a fairly ready sale for all bulls produced, although at re - duced prices. The Advanced Registry Association reported during the year twelve butterfat records above 640 pounds, three above 800 pounds. An attempt is being made to develop and test all daughters of each herd bull. The results show that the effects of sires are very marked. A careful study of the butterfat records of the daughters of the several sires used in this herd indicates that measuring the value of a sire by the records of his immature daughters may lead to serious error. Horticulture. — Former work has been continued. Several thousand pine transplants were set in the canyon sites. Those planted a few years ago in the more favorable places are making rapid growth. Austrian and Scotch pines are the most promising. Many of the Jack pine planted 15 to 25 years ago have died after reaching a height of approximately 20 feet. They were planted in hard rather than sandy soil </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION ttJ^rfwi^SfejSS^ °" in -oration with dug • • A larf?e acreage of potatoes was not iiSIiliP _______ j-mn^uro I «-»"~ | A.fn.fa ' "SS™ . fiX". Potatoes (bit.) U4 R~ ~~orr~-~ ,, ■ alfulfa .1. pa^ur«-d Sugar beets (£'}""' 79 2 ??n "7 -.1 :312 -° ' "••"••" Corn rt«.;... 180 -•'•" - 18 ' 8 ' ir '-« Oats (hu). . ■ il-2 -;;•- 50.0 ■ wheat r6u.;.::::::::z J£J &lt;0 -' g| sii 5^ </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Forty-sixth Annual Report tided advantage over late planting. In two of the years shallow planting was better than deep planting because of the wetness of the spring. In the dry year, deep planting was better.' . • The work with potatoes was continued. A: five-year com - parison shows that irrigated seed is equally as good as dry - land seed when both are disease-free. The data also indicate that with disease-free seed the cropping system does not in - fluence the -quality of the potatoes for seed purposes. In the varietal study of barley, Trebi and Comfort gave the highest yields. . i Horticulture.— Work was begun a year ago to determine the possibilities of vegetable production . in the valley, and con - sisted largely of variety testing. This year, in addition, studies of small fruits have been undertaken. The vegetables include spinach, peas, beans, sweet corn, cabbage, egg plant, peppers, tomatoes, and onions. The small fruits include rasp - berries, blackberries, and strawberries. Lamb Feeding. — During the year a three-year feeding ex - periment with 13 lots of 25 lambs each was completed. The lambs averaged 58.5 pounds and were fed for a period of 110 days. The rations were primarily local feeds. All lots re - ceived alfalfa hay, and this was supplemented in various com - binations with corn, beet pulp, barley, beet tops, and cotton - seed cake. The average gain per lamb varied from 17.4 on a ration of four pounds of corn, 28 pounds of pulp, and alfalfa hay. to 40 pounds where 16 pounds of corn, 16 pounds of pulp, 6 pounds of cake, and beet tops were fed, in addition to the alfalfa hay. The loss in the tirst case was three cents per lamb and in the second case there was a profit of $1.50 per lamb. These results correspond with the results obtained in the two pre - vious years. The three years' results will be prepared for publication. ; : . Beef Cai res:— Four lots of eight steers each were fed for a period of 186 days. The steers weighed approximately 1,050 pounds each when put in the feed lot. Each lot received as much corn silage and alfalfa hay as they would clean up, and one pound of cottonseed cake per head per day. In addition they were fed 15 pounds of different grain mixtures per head. The lot receiving corn and wheat in equal parts gained 370 pounds per head ; where corn, wheat, and barley were fed in equal parts, the gain was 366 pounds per head; wheat and barley in equal parts gave a gain of 373 pounds per head ; and wheat and dry pulp gave a gain of 392 pounds per head. No trouble developed in any of the lots. When the steers were </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station on full grain ration, it was necessary to cut down the amount of alfalfa hay, especially where wheat and barley were fed, so that the steers would clean up the grain. Dairying. — The study of the effect of nutrition on milk and butter production has been continued. The cows are divided into two lots. One lot receives roughage only — alfalfa hay, corn silage, and summer pasture. The other lot receives grain in addition to the roughage. The cows receiving grain pro - duced more miik and more butterfat, but the cost per unit of production was higher than where no grain was fed. The grain keeps the cows in better condition and they produce larger calves, but from a dollars-and-cents standpoint, the profit is less. The returns per dollar of feed consumed were $2.11 where grain was fed and $2.62 where grain was not fed. The feed cost per hundred pounds of milk was 63 cents where grain was fed and 49 cents where roughage alone was fed. The feed cost per pound of butterfat was: with grain, 18.7 cents; without grain, 14.7. The production in milk was ap - proximately 180 pounds more, and in butterfat 7 pounds more per month where grain was fed. Hogs. — The station maintains a herd of breeding sows. The pigs raised are used in carrying on various experimental pas - turing and feeding projects. Poultry. — The flock is kept purely for demonstration. An accurate record of feed cost and production is kept. Two hundred and seventy-three hens were kept in the flock and gave a return of $371.26 above feed cost. The average selling price of eggs was 15.7 cents per dozen. The feed cost was approximately nine cents per dozen, and the total cost 11.1 cents. VALENTINE SUBSTATION Agronomy. — Weather conditions were unfavorable for crop production at the substation, but on the hard table land good yields were obtained. A comparative yield test of corn seed from 12 local farmers showed a difference of 4.5 bushels in yield. Seed from either 100 miles east or west yielded less than the average of the local varieties. The test indicates that most of the farmers are selecting a well-adapted type of seed. The yield of "cattle corn" hardly warrants the enthusiasm being shown for this variety. This station is co-operating with the U. S. Department of Agriculture in testing a number of winter wheat varieties. In 1931 S. D. No. 4300 ranked first, Nebr. 50 second, and Kharkof 1442 third. The smooth-bearded varieties of barley have been outyielding the common and are gaining in popu - larity with the farmers. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Forty-sixth Annual Report; A ten-year average yield of amber cane seeded at the rates of four and six pecks per acre showed an 18 per cent increase in tonnage from the heavier seeding. This was sufficient to compensate for the additional seed ; besides, a better quality of hay was produced. Beef Cattle. — The year 1931 closed five years' work on the value of various supplements to prairie hay in wintering calves that are to be grazed the following summer. In all trials rations that produced the largest wintei 1 gain were fol - lowed by the smallest summer gain. However, the advantage of wintering well more" than offset the difference in summer gain and in the majority of cases returned a profit above the cost of supplement. The optimum winter gain for calves that are to be turned on grass in the spring is approximately one pound per day. In using cottonseed cake as a supplement the feeding of one pound per. day has proved most profitable. The following supplements produced practically the same gain as three-quarters of a pound of cottonseed cake: two pounds oats, two pounds ground barley, one pound corn plus one-half pound cake. When used in a wintering ration, corn, barley, and oats show a different relative value than when used for fattening. Oats rank first and corn last. Dairy Cattle.— The herd of purebred Holsteins continues to make progress in production records. In the 1932 Herd Im - provement Registry the Valentine herd heads the list in Class "C" with an average of 12,753 pounds of milk and 464.6 pounds of butterfat. The highest record within the herd was 18,160 pounds of milk and 657.2 pounds of butterfat made by a senior two-year-old. While the production" of the herd has increased the percentage of fat has decreased from 3.9 to 3.6 per cent, largely because of the influence of- a certain sire. Turkeys. — The use of a light at night and the placing of low roosts in the brooder house before the poults were two weeks old prevented death loss from crowding and lessened the evening labor and worry of the caretaker. Good fertility was obtained from flock-mating three toms with forty hens. Both fertility and hatchability decrease as the laying season advances. Fertility dropped from 97.5 per I cent in April to 92 per cent in June and hatchability from 75 per cent to 40 per cent. Meadcnu liwestigation. — Very little seeding was done the past season because of lack of moisture. The water table was lower than normal this summer with the result that consider - able clover on marginal land died. i </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station box butte substation During the summer of 1931 there was little rainfall, only 7.56 inches from April to October. The temperature was high during the summer months. The winter of 1931-82 was unfavorable for winter wheat and practically all fields winter - killed and had to be replanted with spring grains. The rotation experiments including 144 one-tenth-acre plats have not been continued long enough to justify any con - clusions as to either yields or disease. Increased yields of potatoes were obtained following fallow and corn. In addition to the rotation experiments, which are under the direction of the superintendent," considerable work was' carried on by the Deppartments of Horticulture. Plant Path - ology, and Agronomy, the- latter also co-operating with the United States Department of Agriculture in the use of uni - form nurseries for wheat bunt, winter injury, and varietal yield studies. Agronomic investigations included variety tests of small grains, corn, sorghum, and beans. The yield of all grains was relatively poor and all winter wheat With the exception of one replication had to be replanted with spring wheat. The horticultural investigations with potatoes involved some 10 to 12 acres and included strain tests, cultural experiments, planting time, time and depth of plowing, and other more technical studies. Plant-disease studies were con fined to the soil-borne dis - eases of potatoes and included about seven one-tenth-acre plots in which the effect of previous crops and treatments on the percentage of disease and on the development of soil micro-organisms was studied. In addition to the investigational work the farm is also used for the increase of pure, disease-free aeml of proved varieties of small grains and tuber-unit indexed lines of. potatoes for distribution to the farmers of western Nebraska. During the spring of 1932 the Box Butte County Commis - sioners erected a laboratory building, which provides' two small laboratories and an office. One laboratory has been fully equipped by the Plant Pathology Department and cer - tain essential phases of work can now be carried on that have heretofore been impossible. CHANGES IN STAFF Dr. M. Ruth Clark was on leave during the latter half of the year. Mr. A. E. Barager was continued during the entire year for research work in Home Economics projects. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Forty-sixth Annual Report legislation There was no legislation affecting the work of the Experi - ment Station during the year.. ADDITIONAL LAND. BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT Animal Husbandry Hall, which was damaged by fire last year, was repaired. The building was made lireproof throughout at a cost of approximately $27,000. Plans have been completed for building a fireproof seed house and crops laboratory. PUBLICATIONS OF THE LAST FISCAL YEAR The publications of the station for the fiscal year covered by this report are as follows: '■Forty-fifth Annual Report, presented to the Governor February 1, 1932. 2,000 copies. BULLETINS No' 259 Alfalfa Molasses Meal for Fattening Lambs. A. D. Weber and H. D. Fox. August, .1931. 5,000 copies. : No 200. The Cause and Prevention of Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes. ■ ■!■!■ '\Vcriier, August, 1931. (5.000 copies. .No. 2G1, Wheat for Fattening Hogs.' Wm. J. Loeffei. October, 1931. ■ 10,000 copies. ' • .''.;'-_ No 2G2 Length of Feeding Period and Plane of Nutrition as Factors in Lamb Feeding. A. D. Weber, Wm. J. Loeffei, and Matilda Peters. October, 1931. 5,000. copies. . ! ,, , T No: 203, Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves. Marvel L. Baker. October, 1031. 5,000 copies. • . No "'G4 Housing -Hid H&lt;Hise Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms. ■ J. O.'Rankin, November, 1931. 3,00.0 copies. No 2C5, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1921-1931, Board of Tractor lest Engineers. January, i932. 3,500 copies. No. 260, Cpoling Milk on Nebraska Farms. P. A. Downs and E. B. I ewis Jiiiuiaiv. 1932. 5,000 copies. ' T , , ' t-. No. 207, A Summary of the Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes. .1. O. Rankin and Eleanor H. Hinman. January, 1932. .5,000 "'xt' ofig Lamb Feeding Experiments with Grains and Dried Beet Pulp.. James A. ' H olden. March, .1932. 3,000 copies No. 209, Hatching Turkey Eggs. F. E. Mussehl. April, 1932, 8,000 C "no!'270, A Seven Year Study of a Milk Supply. P. A. Downs. April, 1! 'no. D 271, Pumi) Irrigation and Water Table Studies. Harry E. No. \t2, Cereal Variety Experiments at North Platte. N. E. Jodon. June, 1932. 5,000 copies. RESEARCH BULLETINS No 57 The Effect of Maturity and the Ethylene Chlorhydrin Seed Treatment on the Dormancy of Triumph Potatoes. H. O. Werner. August, 1931. 3,000 copies. ■ _v No 58, Studies of Rickets in Swine. Wm. J. Loeffei, R. R. Thalman, F. C.'. Olson, and F. A. Olson. August, 1931. 4,000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station No. 59, The Influence of Number of Daily Milkings on '.he Production of Dairy Cows. R. F. Morgan and H. P. Davis. September, 1931. 3,000 copies. No. 60, Studies of Prairie Hay in North Central Nebraska. F. D. Keim, A. L. Frolik, and G. \V. Beadle. March, 1932. 3,000 copies. CIRCULARS No. 43, The University Fruit Farm. C. C. Wiggans. September, 1931. 3,500 copies. I TECHNICAL PAPERS Blish, M. J., and Merritt, P. P. Report of Activities of A. A. C. C. Research Fellowship. Cereal Chem. 8:267-292. July, 1931. Blish, M. J. Report on Experimental Baking Tests. Jour. Assoc. Official Agi\ Chemists 14:494-500. November, 1931. Blish, M. J. Report on Glutenin in Flour. Jour. Assoc. Official Apr. Chemists 14:484-485. November, 1931. Goodding, T. H., and Kiesselbach, T. A. The Adaptation of Corn to Upland Soils. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. Vol. 23, No. 11., November, 1931. Kiesselbach, T. A., and Anderson, Arthur. Quality of Alfalfa Flay in Relation to Curing Practice. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui." 235. April. 1931. Kiesselbach, T. A., and Leonard, Warren H. The Effect of Pollen Source upon the Grain Yield of Corn. Jour. Amer. Soc. Apron. Vol. 24, No. 7. July, 1932. Kiesselbach, T. A. Some Problems of Corn Production in Nebraska. 23d Annual Report Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc. 1932. Leonard, Warren H:, and Kiesselbach, T. A. The Effect of the Re - moval of Tassels on the Yield of Corn. Jour. Amer. Assoc. Agron. Vol. 24, No. 7. 1932. Merritt, P. P., Blish, M. J., and Sandstedt, R. M. Report of Activities of A. A. C. C. Baking Research Fellowship. Cereal Chem. &lt;): 175-238. May, 1932. Mussehl, F. E., and Ackerson, C. W. Tho Growth Promoting: Value of Yeast Added to Certain Chick Rations. Poultry Sci. Vol. X, No. 6. September, 1932. Mussehl, F. E., and Ackerson, C. W. The Growth Promoting Values of Dried Buttermilk, Dried Skimmilk, and Dried Whey for Chicks. Poultry Sci. Vol. XI, No. 2. March, 1932. Peltier, G. L. Control Equipment for the Study of Hardiness in Crop Plants. Jour, of Agr. Research 43:177-182. 1931. Peltier, G. L., and Tysdal, H. M. Hardiness Studies with Two-year - old Alfalfa Plants. Jour, of Agr. Research 43:931r956. 1931. Peltier, G. L., and Tysdal, H.- M. A Method for the Determination of Comparative- Hardiness in Seedling Alfalfas by Controlled Hardening and Artificial Freezing. Jour, of Agr. Research 43:429-444. 1932. Reichart, E. L. Some Developments in the Commercial Manufacture of Cream Chetse. The Milk Dealer. July, 1932. ■ Swenk, M. H. Codling Moth Investigations for 1931. 1932 Report of the Nebr. State Horticultural Society. Skidmore, L. V. Leticocyinxpnn xmithi Infection in Turkeys and Its Transmission by Simnlnim occidcntnle. 7th Annual Meeting of Am. Soc. Parasitologists. Jour, of Parasitology Vol. 18,. p. 130. 1931. Skidmore, L.. V. . Tvichostrongylus cohtbiformis {T. instability) in the Jack Rabbit (Lepiis califoi-nicits melanatis) . Jour. A. V. M. A. Vol. 80, N. S. 33, pp. 800-801. 1932. Van Es, L. The Tubercle Bacillus in Man arid Animals. Jour, of Out - door Life Vol. .29, pp. 146-152. 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 Forty-sixth Annual Report Van Es, L. The Principles of Animal Hygiene and Preventive Veter - inary Medicine, pp. I-X, 1-7G8 (John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York). April, 1-932. Wiggans, C. C. Vineyard Soil Management Experiments. Annual Report Nebr: Hort. Soc, pp. 18-25. 1931. ; THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June :JO, 1932, under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total \ ?15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries...* ■ $15,000.00 Total | ?15,000.00 ADAMS FUND I Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of .Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 3(3, 1932, under act of Congress, approved March 10, 1906. Total $15,000.00 Expenditures For salaries..... 515,000.00 Total '. $15,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January &lt;*., 1933. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station purnell fund Receipti Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for. the fiscal year ended June 30, 1932, under act of Congress approved Feb - ruary 24, 1925. Total $60,000.00 Expenditures SALARIES Regular .-. S38.04C.73 Temporary 2,920.41 Total : S40.9C7.M SUPPLIES Office supplies S 185.44 Laboratory supplies...: - 1,787.40 Educational and recreational 108.28 Feeding stuffs , 3,541.39 Agricultural supplies 239.16 Total .' . S5.SC1.C7 EXPENSE Office expense and postage S 39.5-J Freight, express, and drayage :&gt;8.9'.t Water, heat, light, and power.. 1:05 Public printing and advertising 632.52 . • Traveling expense 2,542.73 Rentals 441. 1C Special and temporary services 5,330.26 Miscellaneous 01.25 Total ..' $ 9,1 1 7.50 REPAIRS .-.'.■ - . Lands '. 9 215.4H Equipment • 317.74 Total : ~ ~S 683.28 EQUIPMENT -. Furniture and fixtures S 317.71 Apparatus (labor and equipment) 386.30 . . Machinery : : 76,59 Books, magazines, etc . 51.65 Total ' ? 832.25 LANDS AND BUILDINGS : Land improvements........ . $ ( 186,36 Original construction '. 2,501.85 Total S 2.C88.21 Grand Total . $60,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 6, 1933. -. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Forty-sixth Annual Report financial statement Statement of expenditures for the - Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1932 (ex - clusive of Federal funds), including expenditures for central station at Lincoln, and substations at North Platte, Scottsbluff, Valentine, Union, and Alliance. SALARIES AND WAGES Regular .' : $82,120.29 Temporary '. • 5,097.37 . Total ~587.217.GG SUPPLIES Office supplies...; 9 9G7.27 Laboratory supplies ; ■•• -1,885.20 ■ Fuel (coal) ■• 1,641.22 Food stuffs 1,775.67 Educational and recreational 180.91 Janitor and barn' supplies : , 418.19 Feeding stuffs 26,733.84 Agricultural supplies 8,666.05 Total ■■■ $45,268.35 EXPENSE; • „ P ._ Office expense and postage § 9o2.&lt;4 Freight, express and drayage 1,342.99 Water, heat, light, power and fuel 5,139.22 Public printing, advertising and photography ••• 3;151.44 Traveling expense 2,162.39 Rentals ■,. 259.50 Special and temporary services , 31,057.7o Miscellaneous 1^062.55 Total •• S45.128.56 V Building ■ ■ •••? 2i233.71 Lands • - 425.55 Equipment 6,935.57 Total - $ 9,594.83 EQUIPMENT . 'r.rnr ' Furniture and fixtures .....$ 646. &lt;6 Apparatus, labor and equipment 2,925.72 Livestock 14,044.04 Machinery 5,243.81 - Books 265.20 Total $23,125.53 LANDS AND BUILDINGS \ •.■■!- V Land purchase § S2, Sn Land improvement " 1&gt; "["jg^" Original construction 3, A ■■ Additions and improvements 74^.00 Total $ 3,740.33 Grand Total $214,075.26 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, \ L- E. GUNDERSON. January 6, 1933. ' Finance Secretary. iiyjMi </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>