<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Cooperation</title>
               <date value="1915-06-16">1915-06-16</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. Jl. r The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. COOPERATION By H. C. Filley Distributed June 16, 1915, ► E i_r uaTORS i.1 nr*"Mt1Uf T^lit.t-5 ............ * ri 4- CooP(RMT&gt;ut S-TOWC9 t C oo»Kf(ATt we CmjwMH...... 3 c i^ncE iii^... rs LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. Distributed in Furtherance of the Purpose of the Cooperatlre Agri cultural Extension Work Provided for in the Act of Congress of May 8 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD THE REGENT! OF THE UNIVERSITY HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, President. Vail. HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN. Davey. HONORABLE JOHN E MILLER. Lincoln. THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY. Ph. D., LL. D E. A. BURNETT. B. Be., Dean, C Chum i ll&lt; liege of Agncult niriil sttitmn J. S. DALES. M. Ph.. financial f EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF C. W. Pugmlby, B. Sc., Director A. E. Anderson. A. B.. Farm Dewfnstration II *Mabki. D.\mki..n, B. Sc. Huhk Imula Hi thaii Pktkismpn, liiiii\' mill llirls' Clubs. Emma Reei&gt; Davisson, Wmmeu't Clubs. Frank C. Dkan. A. B.. Agricultural Editor. THE EXTENSION COUNCIL E. Mbm Wii.cox, Ph. D., Agricultural lUittni F. W. Upson, Ph. D.. Agricultural C*emi*tr\ L. W. Chask, M. E.. A. E., Agriniltiiral Emi E. A. BUBNETT, B. Sc, Anmuil H iisbmnlrii. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathnlogii. 1. H. Frakdsfis, M. S. A., Dairy Hiisbandiii. Lawrkxce Bki'.nki:. B. Sc, Entomology. ' I Kill T. A. Kikssklbach. A. M., Experimental A§ H. C. PlLUtY, A. M., Farm Miiiiikji mint. nt R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture P. B. Barker, A. M., Instructional Afronomp G. A. Loxei.ami. A. M., Meteorology. H. E. BiiADKinii. A. B., Principal, Hchirol ut Agricutt Resigned. W. J. Mobkjll, M. Foil., Forestry. Alice M. Loomis, A. M., Homr kvnn </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTEXTS. l-AUK K :&gt; Kuclidalc principles of coojieration 5 Nebraska cooperative law 1 &lt; (lisiacles to cooperation in Nebraska 8 Stale constitution 8 State constitution &amp; Limitations of cooperative law " Limitations of cooperative law !&gt; llijjli par value of shares 10 llijjh par value of shares 10 Forma of cooperal ion 10 Forma of cooperai ion 10 l'l-odiict ion 11 l't-odiict ion 11 Kxchange labor 11 Kxchange labor 11 ( low test in}; 11 ( low test in}; 11 Count v (lenioustrator or agricultural agent 12 County demonstrator or agricultural agent 12 Manufacture 12 Manufacture 12 Creameries 1- ( dreameries 12 Laiindries 14 Laundries 14 Purchase 14 Purchase 14 Rochdale st&lt;»res 14 Kochdale stores 14 Articles of incorporation for cooperative mercantile coinnanv IK company in By-laws of the cooperative mercantile company 17 Marketing 19 &lt; irain elevator 19 Vrticles of incorporation for cooperative grain com 1!l pany Bv-lawg of the farmers" grain company 21 Cooperative skipping associations 23 Kjij; circle 24 Cooperative sale of fruit 25 I'hf management and the manager 21 Some I nisi ness principles 28 Cooperative literature 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">COOPERATION. The Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station receives many letter each yew eoneeraiag cooperatiou aud cooperative enter - prises. This bulletiu is writ leu as an answer to such inquiries. It contains a discussion of the principles of cooperation, laws governing cooperation, and examples of cooperative concerns en - gaged in business in Nebraska. Cooperation is a word which is sometimes used in a very broad sense to mean any united effort, but in an economic sense its meaning is limited to that united effort which complies with cer - tain well-established principles. While we have had a great many so-called "cooperative companies" in Nebraska, comparatively few of them have been truly cooperative in the restricted meaning of the term. It should occasion no surprise that true cooperation is not more common, since it has been only about To years since the first cooperative association, governed by principles which we now consider fundamental, was organized. ROCHDALE PRINCIPLES OF COOPERATION. In 1844, 27 overworked and underpaid weavers at Rochdale, Kuglaud, agreed to contribute weekly from their scanty earnings until sufficient capital had been secured to operate a cooperative store. The store opened a year later, with a capital of f 140 and a membership of 28. It was successful from the outset, and many similar stores were soon started. The principles utilized by these men in conducting their busi - ness have since come to be recognized as the fundamentals of true cooperation. In brief they are as follows: 1. Each member is given one vote and but one, regardless of investment or shares held. 2. The dividend on shares is limited to current interest rates and is considered simply as interest upon capital invested and not as profit. 3. Profits are divided in proportion to patronage. EXTENSION BUL. NO. 31, AGE. KXP. 8TATION OF NEBB. BY H. C. FILLEY. INTRODUCTION. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Cooperation. The first principle given is diametrically opposed to the com - mon rule in stock companies which bases the voting power upon money invested. In a cooperative enterprise the members are equal, and men, not money, do the voting. In other words, it is an industrial democracy, and each member, rich or poor, has an equal share in the management. The second principle recognizes capital as a servant, not a master. It receives a fair wage for the work it does, the same as any other employee. The third fundamental principle is not thought of in the ordi - nary stock company. It recognise! the fact that the profits of any concern come from the men who furnish the business. All expense, including a fair rate &lt;&gt;f interest on capital invested, must first be deducted from the gross profit. Conservative companies usually set aside a part of the net profit for a reserve fund, and another part for education. The remainder is divided among the patrons in proportion to the business which each furnished to the company. A common practice of cooperative companies in apportioning dividends is to pay members of the association at just twice the rate which is paid to nonmembers. The payment of the dividend to the uonineniber is a very effective method of arguing the eco - nomic advantage of cooperation. The payment of larger divi - dends to members makes membership very desirable, and this in turn is an aid in building up the business. Sometimes the non - inembers do not receive their dividend in cash, but as a partial payment upon stock. This is an added incentive for them to become members. A cooperative organization might follow the principles al - ready given, and yet not be successful. The members should live in a restricted area. It is best if all are acquainted, as strangers are prone to have little confidence in one another, and coopera - tion requires the highest confidence. If a productive society, the members should be interested in the same products ; if a purchase society, they should be interested in the same class of purchases. The members should be doing the same kind of work and meeting the same demands. The stockholders in a cooperative elevator should be men who raise grain; in an apple growers' association should be men who grow apples; and in .1 fanners' telephone com - pany should lte farmers who need about the same class of tele - phone service. The members must lie directly interested in the success of the company, or else the company will soon cease to be successful. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Cooperation. 7 NEBRASKA COOPERATIVE LAW. The legislature of 1911 passed a law providing for the incor - poration of cooperative companies. Previous to that time a company which wished to operate under cooperative principles was compelled to incorporate as an ordinary stock company. In the following extract from the Nebraska Cooperative Law (Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913), the features which dis tinguish it from the old corporation law are indicated by italics: Section 733. "For the purpose of this article, the words 'co - operative company, corporation or association' are defined to mean a company, corporation or association which authorizes the distribution of its earnings in part, or wholly, on the basis of. or in proportion to the amount of property bought from or sold to members, or of labor performed, or other service rendered to the corporation: Provided, nothing in this article shall be con - strued as in any way conflicting with or repealing any law relat - ing to building and loan associations or installment investment companies." Section 734. "'Any number of persons, not less than 25, may be associated and incorporated for the cooperative transaction of any lawful business, including the construction of canals, rail ways, irrigation ditches, bridges, and other works of internal improvements." Section 735. "Every cooperative corporation as such has ]&gt;ower : First — To have succession by its corporate name ''Second — to sue and to be sued, to complain and to defend in courts of law and equity; "Third — to make and to use a common seal, and alter same at pleasure; "Fourth — to hold personal estate, and all such real estate as may be necessary for the legitimate business of the corporation ; "Fifth — to regulate and limit the right of stockholders to transfer their stock: "Sixth — to appoint such subordinate officers and agents as the business of the corporation shall require, and to allow them suitable condensation therefor; "Seventh— to make bi/ lairx for the management of its affairs, and to provide therein the terms and limitations of stock owner - ship, and for the distribution of Us earnings." Section 73fi. "The powers enumerated in the preceding sec - tion shall vest in every cooperative corporation in this state, whether the same be formed without, or by legislative enactment, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Cooperation. although they may not be specified in its charter or in its articles of association." Section 737. This section of the law prescribes that the in - corporation fees shall be the same amounts as those provided for like capitalization of general corporations, and provides a means for cooperative corporations or associations already or - ganized to obtain the same legal recognition as those organized under the cooperative law. OBSTACLES TO COOPERATION IN NEBRASKA. The Nebraska constitution interposes a serious tho not un - surmountable obstacle to true cooperation. Section 5 of Article XI6 requires that: "The Legislature shall provide by law that in all elections for directors or managers of incorporated companies, every stock - holder shall [have] the right to vote in person or proxy, for the number of shares of stock owned by him, for as many persons as there are directors or managers to be elected, or to cumulate said shares and give one candidate as many votes as the number of directors multiplied by the number of his shares of stock, shall equal, or to distribute them upon the same principle among as many candidates as he shall think fit, and such directors or managers shall not be elected in any other manner." This makes it impossible for cooperative organizations to en force the "one man, one vote" rule. Many companies by mutual consent of the members have adopted such a rule. In case of dis - agreement, however, it could not be enforced, as it has no legal standing. A constitutional amendment is necessary to guarantee to members of cooperative organizations full security in their voting rights. The constitutional obstacle is in part avoided by that pro - vision of the cooperative law which allows an organization to limit the number of shares which one man may hold. This prac - tically precludes any small number of men from gaining control of a cooperative organization. A second obstacle to true cooperation is found in the law itself. Section 733 limits the payment of the patronage dividend to members. This dividend helps draw business and acquaints all the patrons with the advantages of membership. As non - members ordinarily receive only one-half the patronage dividend given members, they usually become members in order to double their dividends. House Roll 73, thirty-fourth session of the Nebraska legisla ture (1915), provided that Section 733 of the cooperative law be amended to read as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Cooperation. 9 "Section 7:13. For the purpose of this article the words 'co - operative company, corporation or association" are defined to mean a company, corporation or association which authorizes the distribution of its earnings, in part or wholly, on the basis of or in proportion to the amount of property bought from or sold to members, or to members and other customers, or of labor per - formed or other service rendered to the corporation ; Provided, nothing in this article shall be construed as in any way conflict iug with or repealing uny law relating to building and loan asso - ciations or installment investment companies." The italics indicate the suggested change. Protection would still be given to cooperators who preferred to limit the distribu tion to members, and at the same time associations which so de - sired could extend the privilege of participating in the earnings to nonmembers. This bill passed the House by a practically unanimous vote, but died in the hands of the Senate sifting committee. This obvious defect in the law need not, however, work any nrioM hardship upon cooperative companies. It is possible for a company to estimate the patronage dividend payable to a non - ineiiilMT and sot this aside as part payment upon a share of stock. This unpaid dividend remains as a part of the working capital &lt;&gt;f the company and increases its assets by just that amount. Whenever the accruing unpaid patronage dividend of any mm - member equals the value of a share of stock, the stock is issued to him. No dividend is paid to a nonmember, as the issuing of the stock makes him a member. When the patronage dividend earned is large a uonmember will usually pay the balance due on the share in order to secure the advantages of membership. He doubles the rate of future dividends at a very small cost, and obtains a vote in the electing of directors. The Nebraska "Blue Sky" law of 1913 requires that "The par value of all stocks sold or offered for sale must be one hundred dollars," (Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913, Section 80G). The object of this provision of the law is to protect innocent investor* from purchasing worthless stock. Selling stock at from f 1 to f 10 a share has enabled professional promoters to obtain nun dreds of thousands of dollars from small investors. The purpose of the law is therefore commendable, but it has, nevertheless, worked a hardship upon Nebraska cooperative companies. In order to sell stock in a cooperative company it is usually necessary that the shares have a par value of not more than $25 or $50 each. The men who subscribe for the stock are not capi - talists. Even if stock of a higher par value can be sold, the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Cooperation. results would not be satisfactory. Ownership would be central ized in a few men, whereas the aim in all cooperative companies is to reach the greatest j&gt;ossible number. Section 7K8 of the law makes several exemptions to the fore - going rule, among them "sales of stock in Nebraska corporations already in existence, and in Nebraska corporations hereafter created, but which have been in existence one year or more at the time of such sale." Therefore, any Nebraska company which was organized one year previous to the date this law went into effect, July 17, 19K5, can sell its stock without regard to par value. Companies which organize now must place their pur value at $100 if they wish to sell stock within one year after their organization and incorpora - tion. If they are willing to wait one year after organization be - fore selling stork. Ihey may place any par value u|m&gt;u it that they wish. They may hold their preliminary meetings and solicit sub - scriptions of stock at the par value decided upon. The soliciting should be continued, not only until sufficient subscriptions are received to make it possible i ( , organize the company, but until the promoters are sni-e i hat everyone has had an opportunity to subscribe who would be likely to wish membership. The list of proposed stockholders with the amount of stock which each pro - poses to take should then Ik* submitted to the Special Examiner for the Nebraska Slate Railway &lt; 'oinmission, Lincoln, Nebr.. for his approval. No objection will he made b} - the Railway Com mission to the fin mat ion of a Farmers' Cooperative Company, and it may Ik- organized as heretofore. The company may begin business at once, and one year later may sell stock. According to the secretary of the Nebraska Fanners' Co o|H'iative Grain and Live Stock Association, — "The only effect the •Hlue Sky' law will have on the business of a company organized in this way is that the company cannot sell any stock for one year after organization and incorporation unless the shares are made $100. but if the community has been thoroly canvassed Im - fore organization, it is hardly likely that more stock would In - sold for a year at least, so this feature is really no handicap. This plan of organization exempts the company from the operation of the law, because it actually makes all stockholders original iu - eorporators, and no stock is sold after the incorporation. After one year of oj&gt;eratiou, the stock can be sold without restrictions." FORMS OF COOPERATION. Four main lines of cooperation will be discussed in this bul letin, — production, manufacture, buying, and selling. Coopera </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Cooperation. 11 tive enterprise is by m means limited to these four divisions. In Nebraska, cooperative fire insurance is well develojied, there be - ing over $31 5,000,000 of risks in force in the fanners' mutual insurance companies of the State in 1014. Cooperative telephone companies have been developed in many localities. In Nebraska, many of the early rural lines were owned by small stock com - panies which have since been absorbed by stronger competitors. In many European countries, cooperative banking or credit is one of the most important forms of cooperation. It has been widely agitated in this country for the past few years, and will undoubtedly be fostered by both State and national laws. The Extension Service hojK-s to issue a bulletin ujion this subject at some future time. There is in every community considerable cooperation in pro - duction without an organization. The exchange of labor in shell - ing and threshing, and the occasional joint ownership of farm implements and breeding stock are true cooperation. Where any considerable number of men are concerned and where a definile understanding is required, an organization is essential. A cow testing association is a good example of a cooperative productive organization. Every farmer knows that there is a wide variation in the amount of milk and butter fat produced by individual cows during a year. Very few farmers know how much milk or butter fat each one of their cows is producing, or which cows of the herd are returning to them the greatest profit. Comparatively few men have a knowledge of cow testing, and few of those with such knowledge can do the work as econom - ically as a specialist, wko devotes all his time to the work. The association hires a trained man who tests cows for all the mem - bers. Probably the best number of Bdoben for a cow testing asso - ciation is 26. This gives the tester one day's work a month at the house of each member. The tester would determine not only the amount of butter fat produced by each cow per annum, but the cost of production. A dairy herd might produce fairly well and yet return no profit. High priced feed and labor, a large invest - ment in cattle and buildings, and poor methods of marketing the product may cause even good cows to be milked at a loss. Many herds which show a profit would show a larger profit if the low producers were sold. Tow testing associations have almost in - variably resulted in the weeding out of the poorer cows and a consequent increase in the profits of the herds. Members of the Douglas County (Nebraska) Cow Testing As- rROlilXTION </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Cooperation. sociation sold nearly a hundred of their poorest cows before their first year's records were completed, and many others were sold soon afterward. Because of this weeding out process, it is thought "that the productive capacity of the average herd be - longing to members of this association was raised at least 50 pounds butter fat per cow, as a direct result of the first year's work of this testing association." A herd composed of the 10 most profitable cows in the association would have yielded a profit of more than S1.000 a year, while a herd composed of the 10 least profitable cows would have yielded less than $60 profit a year. Bulletin No. 12!) of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station gives the results of one year's work of the Association. Denmark, with less Ilian a fourth of the area of Nebraska, had. in 1911. 530 cow tenting associations. The first one was formed in 1895. Evidently they aid the Danes in getting results. Altho land is much higher in price in Denmark than in Nebraska and a part of their feed is imported from this country, they are able to compete successfully against us in the English butter market. The work of the county demonstrators or agricultural agents is cooperative in the restricted meaning of the term. The farm ers of a county unite in hiring a man who can give tlieni help in production and distribution. The "one man, one vote" rule has always been adhered to by the associations having demonstrators, irrespective of the size of individual contributions. The demon strator works first for the members of the association, and mav spend the time not demanded by them in working for mmmem hers. MANUFACTURE Cooperative manufacture is really only one phase of coopera - tive production. We speak of the farmer as a producer and not as a manufacturer, altho if a part of his work were carried on in a building devoted exclusively to that |i«p«t it would be classed as manufacturing. On the other hand, all labor which results in the production of useful goods is productive labor, no matter whether the labor be performed on a farm or in a factory. Separating milk or churning butter in the house is as essentially a manufacturing process as if performed in a creamery, yet in or dinary conversation we make a distinction. Perhaps a cooperative creamery is the most typical example of cooperative manufacture. Tn 1911, according to the records of the Dairy Division of the United States Department of Agri culture, 33.6 per cent of the creameries and 9.8 f&gt;er cent of the cheese factories in the United States were organized by the farmers as cooperative institutions, and the number has increased </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Cooperation. 13 since that time. In Minnesota there were 608 cooperative cream - eries in litlO; in Wisconsin, 347; in Iowa, 313; in New York, 118; in Michigan, 101, and a lesser number in many other States. In Denmark the fitst cooperative dairy was established in 1882. By 1909 there were 1,157 cooperative dairies to which was brought the milk or cream from 86 per cent of the farmers of Denmark and from 83 per cent of the cows. Four-fifths of the butter made in Denmark is the product of cooperative creameries, and in addition these companies sell annually whole milk to the value of $6,400,000. England is the largest purchaser of Danish butter, and 98 pounds out of every KM) are shipped direct by the creameries thru their exjHirt federations. Denmark is only one of several European countries where i peratire dairies and creameries are thriving. In 1909 there were :!.. r &gt;00 in Germany, 2,000 in Switzerland, 400 in Finland, 400 in Ireland, and a considerable number in many other countries. Several factors are essential to the successful operation of a cooj)erative creamery. 1. There must be brought to the creamery enough butter fat to keep the manager and machinery busy. According to common estimates, this should be not less than 100,000 pounds annually, representing the product from about 600 "average" cows. The familiar saying that "in cooking a rabbit, the first step is to catch the rabbit" applies here with particular force. In organizing a coo|&gt;erative creamery, cows should be counted and cream pledged as a preliminary step. L'. The creamery should be capitalized at its true valuation. This means that the equipment should be purchased from a re - sponsible company. A creamery promoter is not working from altruistic motives. His services may double the cost of the creamery. The manager should be competent. 4. The company should be organized cooperatively. Failures have been common among creameries organized by producers, and by far the most common cause of failure is that they have been organized as an ordinary corporation instead of being organized cooperatively. In the ordinary corporation the profits are distributed as dividends on stock held, but the co - operative company, after allowing a low rate of interest upon stock, distributes its profits in proportion to the amount of cream purchased of the various members. Farmers' creamery companies organized as corporations will continue to record a high percent - age of failures because the producers will not be loyal to a con - cern in which the stockholder gets the profit, altho he may not contribute any of the cream. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Cooperation. One of the functions of the cooperative creamery is I lie marki-i iug of the batter, and no small part of the success of the ci-canuM-v depends upon the manager's ability as a salesman. It is to be noticed that creameries, whether private, corporate, or coopera - tive, usually have no trouble in selling butter at a better price than the farmer can obtain for his product. The cooperative laundry operated in connection wiili a ereaw ery has been tried at Chat field. Minn., and proved successful. The work of machinery is often cheaper than the work of man, or woman either, and the passing of "wash day" will relieve farm life of one of its hardest tasks. The Ifochdale stores, the organization of which has already been discussed, stand out as the most conspicuous examples of Fig. 1. — Farmers' cr&lt;&gt;:imcrv. Kivcrton. Nebr rTK&lt;HASK. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Cooperation. 15 successful cooperative purchasing. Their principles have heeu followed with success in nearly every European country and in America, while many so-called "cooperative stores" organized an ordinary corporations have failed. In many instances goods have been purchased cooperatively of local merchants with profit to both seller and buyer. The merchant could make a low price because of selling in quantity ami baring his capital invested for only a short time. In Great Hriraiu in 1!)12 there were more than 1,400 coopera - tive purchase societies, with an aggregate membership of 2,81(5, - 006. The head of every fourth family in the United Kingdom is a member of a cooperative organization. "The sales of the retail societies affiliated with the British Union were in I!tl2 $:M»2,280, - 4!K). the share capital ?17."5,71:S,455, and profits |5!».787,110." The Right Relationship League of Minneapolis. Minn., has been active in starting cooperative stores. It never assists in urbanizing a company unless a large uuniber of members are willing to cooperate, and never adds to the number of stores in a town if it is possible to buy out an existing tirni. A study of the auditor's reports of these companies is very interesting. Manx of them turn their capital three to six times during the ear. Tlie net profit on sales is usually small, yet the capital is rapidly that a good dividend on stock could lie paid if the members wished. Only a nominal interest is allowed on shares of stock, and the remaining surplus is distributed ano&amp;fc customers, company members receiving dividends at twice the rate of uouincnibers. Each member has one vote regardless of stock held. In Nebraska, a number of cooperative stores have lieen formed within the past two years. The majority of these stores have been promoted by the Farmers' Union. The members seem to lie enthusiastic over results secured. The following constitution is modeled largely after one now in use by the Farmers' Union Mercantile Association at Hardy, Xebr. The constitution should always be as brief as possible and still comply with the legal requirements, as any amendment re - quires a change in the articles of incorporation. The by-laws are easily amended and should contain the working rules of the or - ganisation. Lack of space prevents more than mentioning the most important pointi which they should cover: </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Cooperation. COOPERATIVE MERCANTILE COMPANY ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION. rKEA.MHl.E. We, (names of incorporators) , do hereby associate ourselves together into a cooperative society under the laws of the State of Nebraska and do hereby adopt these Articles of Incorporation. ARTICLE I. The name of this corporation shall be Cooperative Mercantile Company. ARTICLE II. The principal place of business and office shall be Nebraska. ARTICLE III. The business of this corporation shall be the buying and sell ing for itself or on commission of all kinds of goods, wares, uier chandise, products of field, forest, and mine, such as grain, hay. roots, fruits, live stock and their products, lumber, cement, brick, lime, and other building material, coal, and implements; the pur- chase, sale, or lease of such real estate as may be of use to the corporation; the borrowing of money for use of the corporation. and the giving of security for the same ARTICLE IV. This association shall continue for a period of ninety nine years from , 191 . . ARTICLE V. The amount of capital stock shall be fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000), to be divided into fifteen hundred (1500) shares of ten dollars ($10) each, of which shares at least 50 per cent must be sold and paid for before any merchandise shall be bought or sold. ARTICLE VI. The debts of this association shall never exceed one-third of the total paid-up capital. ARTICLE VII. If there are any surplus earnings of this corporation after paying all expenses and setting aside a reasonable amount for depreciation, the board of directors may declare a dividend of 6 per cent per annum upon the par value of the paid-up capital stock. The board of directors with the approval of a majority of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Cooperation. 17 ilu- stockholders may apportion, as a patronage dividend, any surplus remaining after the payment of the stock dividend, and such division shall be made according to the by-laws of said cor - poration hereinafter adopted. ARTICLE VIH. Section 1. The business of the company shall be conducted by a board of six directors who shall be selected at an annual meeting of the company. At the first election two shall be elected for a term of one year, two for a term of two years, and two for a term of three years, and thereafter two shall be elected annually. Section 2. The directors shall elect from their own number a I nvsideut, vice president, and treasurer. They shall also elect a secretary, who must be a stockholder, but who need not be a director. ARTICLE IX. Section 1. A majority of votes cast at any election of direc - tors and officers shall elect, and those so elected shall serve until their successors are elected and have qualified. Section 2. Vacancies shall be filled by the president with the concurrence of the other directors until the time of the annual meeting, when the vacancy shall be filled by election in the usual manner. Section 3. Until the annual stockholders' meeting the follow - ing persons shall serve as directors and officers: (Names of directors and officers.) BY-LAWS OF THE . COOPERATIVE MERCANTILE COMPANY. Lack of space prevents giving by-laws in full. The following points should be covered : 1. Duties of officers. Bonding of officers and employers. Date of annual meeting. 4. Provision for special meeting. 5. Method of electing directors. ti. Members necessary to constitute a quorum. 7. Who may hold stock. ( For a farmers' company this may be limited to those engaged in agricultural production, and for a city consumers' league, residence in the city might be made es - sential.) 8. Rules for transfer of stock. These should provide not only for ordinary sale but for the company taking up the stock of men who remove from the community. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Cooperation. !). Amount of stock which one member may hold. This should lie made a small enough amount that a few men cannot obtain control of the company. 10. Division of profits. Ordinarily dividends should l»e de dared separately upon goods sold to members and produce pur - chased of members. Some companies also declare a labor divi - dend. Some provision should also be made for payment of dividends to nonstockholders. The following provision is copied from the by-laws of the coopeiative association at Hardy. Nebr. : "Nonstockholders, eligible for membership, and stockholders who have not fully paid for at least one share of stock, shall receive dividends at one-half the rate of stockholder* in good standing, and the half (i/^) dividend shall Ik&lt; held by the associa - tion as a payment on a share of stock until one share is fully paid. If such nonstockholder shall neglect to comply with the require - ments for membership within sixty (60) days [after] declaration of this dividend, such dividend shall revert to the surplus fund of the association." 11. All merchandise sold by this assomiou shall be paid for in cash or its equivalent and at a uniform price. Fig. 2.— Cooperative store, Hardy. \&gt; -l&gt;r </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Cooperation. 19 12. The director* shall audit the hooks of tin' association at regular intervals, and access to the hooks of the secretary and : reasurer shall not be denied any stockholder at reasonable times. 13. Amendinenrs to constitution. It. Amendments to by-laws. ir&gt;. Uules of order MAUKETINC Cooperative grain marketing has develo|&gt;ed rapidly in the Middle West during recent years. In December, 1!M4. there were "_'■_'• farmers' elevator companies in Nebraska, operating 2'V.) ele - \;iiors. The average invest nient per company was S&gt;S,800 iu round number*, making a total investment of more than *2. 000, 000. The average annual business exceeds 138,000,000. The majority of these companies are not cooperative in the restricted meaning of the term, heinj; simply ordinary stock cor - porations owned by a large number of farmers. The companies organised previous to the enactment of the cooperative law in 1 !H 1 necessarily incorporated under the law jfoverning ordinary profit corporations. They seem to have been well satisfied with re - sults attained, as few of them have thus far taken the trouble to change their articles of incorporation and become cooperative. Nearly all of the newer companies are, however, truly cooperative, and their success will doubtless influence many of the older com - panies ultimately to become truly cooj&gt;erative. The following constitution for a cooperative elevator is copied, with the exception of a few minor changes and abbreviations. roni a model furnished by the secretary of the Nebraska Farm is' Graiu and Live Stock Association. Several elevators an &gt;perating successfully at present under a constitution and by aws practically identical with this: FARMERS' COOPERATIVE GRAIN COMPANY OF NEBRASKA. ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION. Know All Mkn by Tiiksk Presents: That we. niaincx of incorporator$) , have associated ourselves together for the purpose of forming and becoatfajg a corporation under the cooperative laws of the State of Nebraska, and for that purpose do hereby adopt these Articles of Incorporation: AltTH'LE 1. The name of this corporation shall be Farmers' Cooperative Grain Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Cooperation. ARTICLE II. The principal place of transacting the business of this cor- poration shall be at , County, Nebraska. ARTICLE III. The business of this corporation shall be the buying and sell - ing for itself or on commission, as well as that of handling and shipping, grain, farm produce, coal, live stock, and farm supplies; to purchase, hold, or lease real estate or other property for the use of the corporation in conducting its business; to direct, own. control, lease, or operate grain elevators, warehouses, storehouses, and other buildings and to acquire property in any terminal mar kets necessary in conducting said business; to purchase and to hold stock in other corporations ; to borrow money ; to make, execute, and deliver conveyances and to secure the same; and to do, perform, and carry on the aforesaid business in the State af Nebraska. ARTICLE IV. The authorized capital stock of this corporation shall be twenty-five thousand dollars (*2."i.0&lt;)0) divided into five hundred (500) shares of fifty dollars ($50) each, which stock shall be fully paid up when issued and shall be nonassessable. ARTICLB V. The term of the existence of this corporation, shall commence on the day of , A. D. 101. ., and the same shall continue for a term of fifty (M) years from said date unless sooner dissolved by a majority of the stockholders or by operation of law. ARTICLE VI. The highest amount of indebtedness or liability to which this corporation may at any time subject itself shall be sixty (60) per cent of its paid-up capital stock. ARTICLE VII. Stockholders of this corporation may sell or pledge their stock to each other, within the limitations of these articles of incorpora - tion, but no stockholder may sell or pledge his stock to another not a stockholder nor to another stockholder of this corporation whom these articles of incorporation would not allow additional stock, until he first shall have offered the same to this corpora - tion at a price not to exceed the asset value of said stock as shown by the books of the corporation. Such offer shall be in writing and shall be filed with the secretary of the corporation, and if </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Cooperation. 21 such offer be not accepted within thirty (30) days from the date of the filing of the same, then said stock may be sold to anyone as provided in the by-laws of this corporation to be hereinafter adopted, except that in no case may any individual hold or own, either directly or indirectly, more than fonr (4) shares of said stock, and no stock shall be transferred on the books of this cor - poration unless these articles of incorporation and the by-laws of this corporation have been complied with. ARTICLE VIII. If there are any surplus earnings of this corporation after paying all expenses and setting aside a reasonable amount for depreciation, the board of directors may declare a dividend of five (5) per cent per annum upon the par value of the paid-up capital stock. The board of directors with the approval of a ma - jority of the stockholders may apportion, as a patronage dividend, any surplus remaining after the payment of the stock dividend, and such division shall be made according to the by-laws of said corporation hereinafter adopted. ARTICLE IX. The business of this corporation shall be conducted by the following board of five directors until the first annual meeting as provided by its by-laws: (names of directors, stating which shall serve as president, vice president, and treasurer). article x. These articles may Ik? amended by a two-thirds vote of the stockholders at any regular meeting, or at any special meeting called for that purpose, provided a notice of the meeting and a copy of the proposed amendment be mailed to each stockholder's last known post office address at least ten (10) days prior to the date of such annual or special meeting. SIGNATURES OK INCORl'ORATORS. Signatures should be witnessed before a notary public and his seal attached to the articles of incorporation. BY-LAWS OF THE FARMERS 1 GRAIN COMPANY. The constitution should be brief and contain only the essential legal requirements, as the State law provides (Section 574, Re - vised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913) every change "shall be recorded and published in the same manner as the original articles are required by law." </seg>
            <seg id="p022">■ Cooperation. The by-laws should provide the majority of the ruled for the management of the organisation. Rules upon the following points are cnmntiiil and others may be added as desired : 1. Who may hold stock. 2. Kules for transfer of stock. :{. Date of annual meeting. 4. Provision for upecial meeting Fig. %.— 'Con|&gt;er:itivc (lev ittor. Hampton, Xebr 5. Provision for the company taking up the slock of any iiiein l&gt;er removing from the community. t&gt;. Method of electing officers. 7. Members necessary to constitute a quorum 8. Duties of officers. !). Division of profiis. 10. Maintenance fee — the levying of a fee to provide for the running expenses of the company upon all grain sold by members to other grain dealers. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Coo/n ration. 23 i 11. Amendment of by-laws. 12. Order of business. 13. Rules of order. COOPERATIVE SHIPPING ASSOCIATIONS. Live slock is sometimes sold thru the cooperative elevator company, and wed law by cooperative shipping associations. I'sually only a small capital is required to run such an associa - tion. Often a certain day in the week is agreed ujxm as the regular shipping day. The members who have stock to ship notify the manager. He orders cars and attends to the details of shipping. Often the stock belonging to several men is shipped in Fig. 4. — Cream station at dishing, Nebr. one car. The stock of each shipper is sold separately, and the manager turns the proceed* over to him, less the necessary ship - ping and selling expense and a small fee which pays the running expense of the association. As only a small part of the manager's time is required, his salary is likewise small. The Fanners' Business Association at Arapahoe, Nebr., has mi shares of stock, declares do dividends, and has no salaried offi - cers. According to the secretary, "Au entrance fee of fl for membership and a weighing charge furnish sufficient money to keep the yards, sheds, office, and water supply in fine condition." The manager is paid a small fee by the owners of the stock which is sold. In many communities where not enough cream is produced to keep even a small creamery busy, one finds three or more cream receiving stations. Each station necessarily requires a competent </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Cooperation. man and a room equipped for receiving and testing cream. One station could usually do the work at greatly reduced expense. Cream shipping associations have been formed in several lo - calities for the purpose of increasing the price offered for butter fat by doing away with duplicate cream receiving stations. Altho their utility in decreasing expense cannot be questioned, yet in some instances they have not met with a ready response from the large creameries. The Cooperative Cream Buying Association at Cushiug, Nebr., operates a successful station of this type. The plan of organiza - tion is very simple. About 50 farmers contributed $1 each toward the purchase of station supplies and the starting of the company. Their cream is sold to the highest bidder, on a yearly contract, using the New York butter market us a basis. A definite price cannot, of coarse, be named, but the company bids to pay within so much of the New York price for butter, using the market on a certain day in the week as the basis. Ac - cording to reports received, this plan has given entire satisfaction for three years. The cooperative marketing of eggs requires little capital or labor, and secures for the members a higher price for their prod - uct. Formerly, practically all eggs were sold "case count" at a uniform price without regard to age, size, color, cleanliness, fer tility, or condition. Since the passage of our pure food laws, the candling of eggs at the time of purchase has become more ami more common. A visit to the candling room of a wholesale egg house will, however, convince the most optimistic that there is room for improvement in the condition of the eggs marketed. We have made a big advance in the past five years, yet the candler still finds many "blood rings," "seconds," and "spots." These decrease the price which the country merchant receives for the eggs, and that, of course, means that the producer recives a lower price than if all the eggs were guaranteed to be good. The careful producer, therefore, loses a cent or two on each dozen of eggs, while the careless producer receives more for his eggs than they are worth. The cooperative egg circle discriminates against the purveyor of stale eggs instead of in his favor. The egg circle is formed to bring about an improvement in the quality of eggs marketed and consequently an improvement in price. The cost of membership in such an association is always small, usually not more than 25 cents. Each member is furnished a rubber stamp which is used in marketing all eggs sold by him. The stamp gives the date, the THE EUli CIBCLE. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Cooperation. 25 number or brand of the circle, and a serial number for the pro - ducer. The eggs are sold by the manager at a premium above market price, because the purchaser knows just what he is get - ting. If an egg does not come up to standard, the seller is easily located by the number. The first offense usually means a fine, and the second expulsion from the circle. Some of the common requirements of the members are as fol - lows: 1. Eggs gathered twice a day and no egg more than eight days old to be delivered to manager. 2. Eggs to be of uniform size Eggs to be clean. 4. Eggs to be kept in a cool, dry place 5. Eggs stamped, and no stamped egg sold except thru the manager. 6. When put up in cartons it is usually required that white eggs be separated from the brown, and the cartons so marked. In some circles the manager collects the eggs at regular inter - vals, but more often they are delivered to him. Sometimes a creamery man acts as manager, as the handling of eggs combines readily with the butter business. There will seldom be any diffi - culty in finding a manager or a market for the product. The chief difficulty to surmount is the old problem of doing something in a way different from the one to which we have been accustomed. COOPERATIVE SALE OF FRUIT. Cooperative marketing has been very successfully utilized by the fruit growers' associations of the Western States. For ex - ample, during the winter of 1913-14, California oranges could be purchased at Lincoln and Omaha fruit stands cheaper than could home grown apples. That is, the California grower by means of his cooperative association was able to overcome the handicaps of high priced land and labor, expensive fertilizer, freight and re - frigerator car charges, and undersell us in our market. Nebraska orchardists have never been averse to entering their apples in competition with apples grown either East or West, and the premiums won have well rewarded their confidence. The truth is that the climate and loess soil of the counties bordering on the Missouri River seem to be particularly adapted to apple culture, while home orchards in almost all parts of the State have proved satisfactory. Our fruit has won its high standing because of flavor, texture, and keeping qualities, altho sometimes smaller and less highly colored than apples from other regions. Discriminating buyers realize, however, that size and color do not affect the eating qualities of an apple. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Cooperation. Despite all the advantages of home grown fruit, many apples from Colorado, the Pacific Northwest, and New York are sold each year in Nebraska and other Missouri Valley States. Why can the orchardist of Oregon or Washington after raising apple* on high priced land pay 50 cents per bushel freight besides re - frigeration charges and niiirket liis fruit at top prices in a region which grows a better product? The western orchardists use co - operative methods in growing and distributing fruit. — the ma jority of Nebraska's orchardists work independently. As a result of uniform methods of culture, grading, and packing, only good fruit is shipped, and a standard of excellence is established. In the past, each Nebraska grower has set his own standard, and as a result wormy, inferior fruit has found its way to market to the detriment of our apple industry. The Central Fruit Grower*' Association, with headquarter* at Nebraska City, is now (1915) in its third season. Among tin rules adopted by the association are the following: "Uniform Methods: All fruit will be packed under grades and rules established by the association and must be passed upon I \ association inspectors. Itefore the brand is placed on the package which guarantees the pack." "Care of Orchards: One of the first requirements for member ship in the association is up-to-date orchard management. Only growers who spray thoroly are eligible." The by-laws provide that, with certain exceptions. "The asso ciation shall have the exclusive right to market all the graded fruit * * * grown by its members." "All dividends declared by this association shall be issued pro rata to the memlters of the association, l&gt;ased upon the proceeds arising from the sale of the fruit of each member of this associa tion." The Omaha Fruit Growers" Association o(&gt;erates largely in Douglas County. Its fruit sales in IMS were about S72.IMMI. The association furnishes crates, baskets, and boxes to members at practically wholesale cost, and buys seed potatoes by the carload. The incorporators of these associations lielieve that in time they will exert as great an influence upon the production and marketing of fruit as do the western associations. They expect to furnish home grown apples to every Nebraskan at lower prices than fruit shipped from a distance can l&gt;e sold. THE MANAGEMENT AND THE MANAGER The success of a cooperative company dej&gt;ends very largely upon the efficiency of the management. The executive powers of </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Cooperation. a cooperative association are usually vested iu a Ixuird of direc - tors elected by the aWiHilwri. Tlie board of direetora elect or ap- I &gt;&lt; • j n i the manager ami his assistants, ami direct the geueral policies of the company. The director! should make thoro in - spections of the business periodically. Complete records must l»e kept, aud they must l&gt;e audited at stated intervals, not less than twice each year, aud better once a month. The most important task of the directors is the selection of a manager, for upon him devolves to a large extent the success of the company. If they elect a competent man, the rest of their work is easy. They simply hold him responsible for the develop - ment and execution of their policies. •I. \V. Shorthill of Hampton, Nebr., secretary of the Ne - braska Fanners" CooperatiTe drain and Live Stock Association, who has had an exceptional opportunity to learn the causes ci' success and failure of cooperative companies, emphasizes the iui - portauce of securing a competent manager. The following is a characteristic quotation: "The manager of a cooperative organization is the most im - portant single factor in its success. He is the official whom the patrons meet, and their opinion of the company will lie gauged to a considerable extent by their opinion of him. In choosing a manager the Ant qualification to consider is honesty, the second industry, the third natural business ability, and the fourth busi - ness ethical ion. All are important, but they are named in the proper order. Experience i" the line of business to be handled is a very desirable qualification, but it must come after those named above. "The man whose sole recommendation is that he will work cheap cannot measure up to these qualifications or to such posi - tion. The competent man seldom works for a low salary; it is not necessary. The man who has tailed in his own business is not apt to make a success of a cooperative enterprise. The extra salary demanded by a competent man over the incompetent is small compared with the results which he secures. "The importance of the manager as a contributing factor in the success of a cooperative company is strikingly illustrated in the history of the Grange store ai ( (lathe, Kans., one of the largest cooperative stores in the United States. This store prospered for 30 years under the continuous management of one man. After his retirement about eight years ago, the business declined grad - ually under different managers, finally reaching a point where the stock failed to pay a dividend. Under the present manager the business is again increasing. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Cooperation. "The manager must give a bond in keeping with the financial responsibility he must assume. The average grain company should require a bond of $5,000 from the manager, and it is pref erable that he give a fidelity bond rather than a personal one. "The statement is often made that cooperative companies are successful because their stockholders are loyal. This is not true. The reverse is the true statement — the stockholders are loyal be cause the company is successful. Let the company become in volved or fail 'to make good,' and the members will fall away one by one. The success of cooperative companies is not due to senti ment, but to good business methods and steady hustling. The companies must work continually for both new members and new business." SOME BUSINESS PRINCIPLES It seems hardly possible to overemphasize the necessity for the utilization of sound business principles by a cooperative or - ganization. In order to be truly successful a cooperative com - pany must do not only as well as, but better than, the private organizations with which it competes. If it can do only as well, then why assume the danger and responsibility of running an independent business? The statement has often been made that JM) per cent of the individual ventures in mercantile lines and 15 per cent in manufacturing lines end in failure. Cooperaton can not afford to fail. They must compete successfully with the in dividual ventures which prove successful. Before launching any cooj&gt;erative organization, the promoters should know very definitely just what advantages their company will possess which will enable it to meet competition successfully. It is not enough to say thai too little is received for the products sold and too much paid for the goods purchased. The cooperative company must be able to run at less expense than its competitors in order to pay more for produce or sell goods cheaper. The general store may be used as an illustration of this point because it is something with which all are familiar. Altho the price at which it sells many necessaries is admittedly high, and altho the difference between the price received by the primary producer and that paid by the ultimate consumer seems to be in creasing, it does not necessarily follow that the retailer is making a large net profit. The fact that the goods pass thru many hands, and that we demand better service of the merchants than did our grandfathers, account in part at least for high priced merchan dise and high cost living. The truth is that few merchants make more than a fair labor income after deducting interest on their </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Cooperation. 29 investment, so that the cooperative store must use better busi - ness methods or curtail service in order to be successful. Before starting in business the cooperators should possess at least the major part of the following vantage points : 1. Sufficient capital. — Staple goods may be bought in quan - tity and all bills discounted. 2. Business done on a cash basis. — A credit business ties up a part of the capital and nearly always results in a loss due to bad accounts. When the merchant acts as a banker by furnishing his patrons with credit he must necessarily get his pay for such service by charging more for his goods. 3. Store should be assured of a large patronage. — Where the volume of business is large, a smaller proportion of the gross profits is consumed by overhead expenses such as manager's sal - ary, rent, heat, light, telephone, and insurance. The capital does more work because it is turned more rapidly. 4. No so-called "free delivery." — According to the United States Kural Organization Service, "the cost of delivering an order of goods from the store to the home of the town consumer will vary from perhaps as low as 3 cents to at least as much as 10 cents per order, depending upon the size of the town and the kind of delivery. Where goods are delivered, the delivery charge alone is said to cost town stores from 5 to 20 per cent of the cost of goods sold, depending on size of town and character of goods." It is manifestly unfair that the farmers should pay any part of this delivery cost, or that town people who receive two &lt;&gt;r three large orders each week should pay as much as those families to whom goods are delivered two or three times each day. Delivery is an individual service which should be paid for by the person receiving it and not distributed among all the pa - trons of the store. 5. Only staple goods should be carried in stock. — The members of the cooperative store company should be willing to wait for less staple goods to be ordered from a wholesale house instead of requiring that they be carried in stock. This saves the tying up of considerable capital and the risk of depreciation due to change in fashion or goods becoming shelf worn. 6. Buy in carload lots. — Apples, potatoes, and similar prod - ucts should be ordered by the carload at the time of year when the price is low. By transferring such goods from the car di - rectly to the purchasers' wagon considerable expense is saved. Grange members in one Nebraska community without the aid of a cooperative store purchased two carloads of peaches and one of </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 V oo iteration. grapes liuri :g the season of 1914. The price was much lower than that at which any cooperative or private store could afford to sell them when distributed in the regular way. 7. Buy of pnducer. — When any considerable quantity of any one kind of goods is I. and led it is much easier to buy of the pro - ducer than when only a small amount is purchased at one time. For example, if a ■tore were ordering only 10 bushels of alfalfa seed, the simplest method would be to order of a seed house. On the other hand, if several hundred bushels were required, the merchant could undoubtedly pmcliase the seed direct from some locality where alfalfa seed is grown. In order that this may be done, persons wishing seed should give In their orders .several weeks before the seed is needed. This is not intended as an exhaustive list of principles. Froli ably most of the readers of iliis bulletin will thiuk of other* which they wish to add. r l liose gives aie, however, fundamental. Other lines of cooperative endeavor would require somewhat different rules. Members of a cooperative creamery, for example, should not expect to be paid in full each time cream is delivered. for the operator does nol then know at what price his prodnei will be sold. The members of an el- valor company must not ex pect that their company will always quote the highest price for grain. Competitors may he paying more than the market war - rants, drain should Ik- sold when purchased and not be held for speculation. The members of any cooperative organization should feel per sonally responsible for its siucos. There is no magic in tin word cooperation. The best remit! must come from favorable conditions, well-laid plans, and careful, conscientious manage mem. Under such conditions, cooperation has proved its valm in many places, and each year has seen its practice more wide spread. COOPERATIVE LITERATIM In this brief bulletin it is impossible to do more than oiitliiu a few of the many cooperative enterprises. The reader who i - particularly interested in Cooperation will tiud the following literature helpful: 1911. Cooperation Among Farmers. Sturgis &amp; Walton Co New York. 1'lunkett, Sib Houace 1910. The Hural Life Problem in the United States. Mai millaii Co., New York. COULTEK. JOBM LEE. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Cooperation. 31 WllI.KF, HEN! i W 1!&gt;12. Cooperation in Agriculture. I'. S. King &amp; Son, London American Gooiierative •Journal, monthly magazine. Chicaeo. 111. Iterative Joaraal, monthly magazine, Chicago, 111. &lt; 'ooiHTation. H'ration. lminthly magazine published hy Cooperative Educa tion Bureau, Metropolitan Life Building, Minneapolis, Minn 4-24-' 15— 20X1 I'hwki.i., Harold. 1913. Cooperation in Agriculture. Mncmillan Oo., New- York. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>