<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State of Nebraska Biennial Reports of the Superintendents of the State Hospitals at Hastings, Lincoln, and Norfolk, Nebraska Including the Fourth Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Reports OF THE Superintendents OF THE State Hospitals AT HASTINGS, LINCOLN, AND NORFOLK, NEBRASKA Including the Fourth Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor: The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finkle, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens, The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the blen - iiium without Incurring any deficiencies ; although the cost of living, fttitl consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly Hot decreased since the appropriations were made fnr the blennlumv Hume iiupt f ivr-tiir-fif c; ,,f &amp; pefttiaMietu &lt; Imun ti r hive been made at the vsri§u§ iustittitiens during the peried severed by this report, A hospital building, bakery and seullery have been erected at the Nebraska InititutteH fur feeble Minded, ttettriee, Nebraska j a e§ttage tor girls at the yirls' Training McIimuI, Geneva, Nebraska » a h§»pital building at the §§tdiers and Mailers' iUmw, Murkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska ; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska ; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to see the necessity for several others tliat were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. This institution was established as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminals. The legislature of 1921 authorized the establishment, therefore, of such an institution, making an initial approproation of $300,000. Of this sum the Roard ex - pended $37,500 for 10 acres and a brick building known as the Hay ward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of contiguous land for the sum of $49,531.25. Thi*r land is used for farming, stock raising, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trades are taught such as tailoring, shoe repairing, carpentry and joinery, brick laying, electricity, automobile repairing, launder - ing, engineering, firing, and barbering. The manual labor about the institution is, of course, performed by the inmates, of which there are at this date 189. Mr. A. W. Miller, the superintendent, is doing much constructive work with the young men committed to his charge, and we believe the institution is amply justifying itself. The difficulty of employing the penitentiary inmates at suitable labor that does not conflict too much with the prerogatives of the free workers of our state, has been pretty well overcome. The state still operates the fibre furniture factory which has been at the prison for some years, and has also established relations with the Oberman Company by which shirts are made and disposed of with a minimum of competition with free labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 INMATE POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control of the Board, and at this time (July 1, 1^23^1 the inmate population is 5917, as compared with an average of 4 ( &gt;80 for the biennium ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following table will be found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest liirniiiiiiii biennium number Institutions ending ending at any one (With "Key" Letters) June .30, June 30, time past 1921 1923 two years A— Institution for Feeble-Minded 607 725 756 B— Girls' Training School 106 173 189 C— Soldiers and Sailors' Hume 40V 353 412 D— Hastings State Hospital 1152 1193 1219 E— State Industrial School 217 214 241 F— Hospital for Tuberculous 78 102 106 G— Lincoln State Hospital 837 971 995 H— Orthopedic Hospital 64 88 102 J — State Penitentiary 363 586 596 f k.T I ..I... r l *._:.. i tl j o&lt;". nn K— Nebraska Industrial Home 73 86 99 L— Soldiers and Sailors' Home 148 162 195 M— School for the Blind (a) 47 53 57 N— Norfolk State Hospital 646 733 768 P— School for the Deaf (a) 171 178 187 R— State Reformatory for Women " 18 28 S— Home for Dependent Children 53 91 107 T— State Reformatory for Men (b) Not open 150 192 Total 4"80 5876 6249 (a) 19 months (1921, 9 months school; 1922, 10 months school.) (b) Open only 21 months; started October 1, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following table reveals the expenditures at the various institutions for the past biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting the first. Capital outlay represents permanent improvements to the realty and equipment. Board of Control, Lincoln — Maintenance $ 5,151.87 Salaries and Wages 42,529.53 $ 47,681.40 Institution for Feeble-Minded, Beatrice — Maintenance 253,843.43 Cash 27,524.49 Capital Outlay : 93,899.95 375,267.87 Girls' Training School, Geneva — Maintenance 111,808.47 Cash 4,964.20 Capital Outlay _ 42,000.00 158,772.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett— Maintenance _„ 176,148.28 Cash _ 67,846.61 Capital Outlay 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash _ 99,853.78 Capital Outlay.... 38,850.25 639,888.49 State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay _ 43,44024 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay 117,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 375,095,50 Cash _ 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash „ _ 25,627.53 25,627.53 Capital Outlay 4,490,17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 229,205.92 Cash 161,633.02 161,633.02 1 Outlay 390,838.94 Capital Outlay.. Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance 61,306.38 Cash _ 2.578.26 ■- - 2,57826 1 Outlay 63,884,64 Capital Outlay. Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,406.99 Cash — _ _ 29.700.29 29,700.29 Capital Outlay .'..ZZ 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City — Maintenance „ 57,82522 Cash _ 3.989.06 3,989.06 Capital Outlay ZZZ 3,952.01 65.76629 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk— Maintenance 321,060.71 Cash _ _ 50.535.76 50,535.76 Capital Outlay...- _ 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance ..._ 137,695.55 Cash 16.819.16 16,819.16 Capital Outlay ____ 4,'5Oo!oO 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance 28,489.38 Cash — 2.733.39 2,733.39 Capital Outlay 46,'996.'l5 78,218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Grand Total 4,538,783.65 At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance _ Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.53 itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance _ Cash Capital Outlay _ 72,188.46 6,959.45 300,000.00 379,147.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1922 SALARIES and WAGES * 1^2,276.94 OPERATION and MAINTENANCE 2,272,465.46 FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT 196,093.94 NEW BUILDINGS 6O3.6H9.60 LAND 48.748.08 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID 6,848.53 PERMANENT IMP. TO BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 1 2 1,02570 TOTAL 4,491,10225 4,4 91, 10225 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">« 10 INCOME FOR 1921-1922 3,8HI,3H8.I3 598,304.90 66,960.00 •48,100.56 4,554,713.59 STATE FUNOS CASH FUNOS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS TOTAL *UH€XPENOEO BALANCE OF CASH .FEDERAL ONDTWJCT FUND (clothing funo,\nstitote for feebleminded) rehppropriateo </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. SUMMARY OP EXPEND [TUBES, STATE July 1, 1«K 11 to June 30, 1923 Salaries and Wages Operation and Maintenance Furniture and Equipment Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds New Buildings Land Fixed and State Aid Charges Total for Biennium Per Cent Institution for Feeble-Minded.... Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital - State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital School for the Deaf. State Reformatory for Women.... Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (a).... I 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410.19 226,534.52 60,739.65 45,281.20 178,107.10 56,46438 93,393.20 19,294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137341.88 77,242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 ? 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,198.27 351,30624 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,86020 42,879.03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,918.21 $ 25232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,568.22 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28.624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,348.27 45,077.86 .... ....■•...............*...■ $ 87127 3.40 10JJ0 171.19 ijmM 500.00 24.75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 $ i 375,267,87 158.77Z67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63\884.64 140,041.38 65,76629 431.S9S.48 139,014.71 78,218.92 72,611.53 379,147.91 8.3 3.5 8.0 i n 5.7 12.0 3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 84726 22I66228" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 39/KSZS2 9078915" 48,74J\08 ■" Total .. $1242276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6343.53 $4,491,102.25 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 POPULATION AND PER CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1923, Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inmates to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Biennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School _ Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital — — Orthopedic Hospital _ State Penitentiary. Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind (a).... Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf (a) State Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (b) _. 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 S3 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 61 19 62 158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 11 8 5 2 8 4 3 7 6 $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 484.27 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 35.28 54.23 19.19 69.25 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 65.27 31.83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total _.... 5,917 5,876 883 851 • 7 $ 598.15 $ 24.92 I $51,890.46 !_ (a) Average during school year. (b) Openi ■d October I, 1921 -21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 [OSE ADMITTED FOB F. TOST TIME 'eriod Ending June 30, 1923 Under 5 years 5 to i 9 yrs. inc. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs, inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs, inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs, inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs, inc. Over 90 yt-ar.s Unascer- tained Total ustitution for Feeble-Minded ■iris' Training School ioldiers' Home, Burkett „ la stings State Hospital itate Industrial School iospital for Tuberculous -incoln State Hospital )rthopedic Hospital Itate Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home ioldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind. Norfolk State Hospital Jcbraska School for the Deaf itate Reformatory for Women fame for Dependent Children itate Reformatory for Men _ 15 6 67 67 17 9 ioG ...„ _.. 70 28 65 14 89 2 38 134 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 « 112 63 185 17 223 6 _ 80 28 135 10 61 6 1 36 16 50 i 18 9 59 "i'2 70 14 i 16 58 8 43 3 79 61 " 31 lo 15 I .... 2 l~ 3 i 1 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 .„ ' 3 6 15 7 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 4 27 1 39 66 a 4 - 80 74 36 41 38 2 26 34 i 121 '67 44 6 5 3 i ... 180 46 —I I Total 211 293 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 18! 271 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 1VI )F 1 HOSE ADI ITTED rOl FIRST TIME Bifii iniutn Kndini [ June 30, 13 !. (or FMbte Mind«d alnlnic School Soldiers and Sailors' Home Kurkett Hospital State, Indiutriil SdDol HoBpiUl for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers and Sailors' Home Milford Nebraska School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nebratiku School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory lor Men Total 7 AMrii _ " « - ■ « )■■■..................... rn __ 1 ••»..................•■ 3 6 -— i .......... .......... I i'4 .................... I 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 28 3 6 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 30 1 8 1 2 1 2 44 6 1 1564 124 30 .. 2 2 i „ iUXV. I" r _. "" T "~' I 12 &lt;-v:__ "" " .... 3 l" UiiM CaMho-Slorskia Dcoaric Enclaad GfMOt ............ Hollaad _ Hungary ireSKr zz luly Mexico . _ Moravia „... Mebmiai .._ z_._ Vetfcerlandi PofauST _ RttMia „ Saaoay s*ri* zzz::z:zz Sicilia .„.. Sfwfa I Sweden _.. _„ "1 Switzerland Turkey IS. other than Nebraska. fiAnown ' Mlk-r Countrie*..... ""T^aL ZZZ" I 7 6 _ 17 8 6 2 — i . _ T j 4 1 4 5 1 2 27 r 1 "i 3 2 i i . 1 19 1 • ~ 1 "i 3 2 1 i 2 ■■■" 2 "" rd 2" 2 32 1 I 1 2 1 ~" H j n i 3 ___ * s"~ f i -' 1 i ..._.„„___ - i "~ 4 2 ■• 1 "" 1 1 119 1 3 i 11 2 i i 209 "" 98 "2 ""T57 188" "ioi" 339 74 66 1 12 ioi""' 26 30 232 72 ~ 1 2 3 8 1 ~ 2 1 —' ""3 10 2 1 2 1 .2 s 1 ■ """■ 4 i " 2 ... 1 i I -— — _ _ 1 2 1 I I ... - r ' 2 2 13 2 4 1 1 256 5 i "" 1 13 1 "\ 32 ' sis r . 4 _.._. 20S" 26 iW 76 209 42 4 42 "20 116 8 129' 9 29" 5 1 ii'(i 45 246 472 333 220 586 384 369 92 " iF~ 21 26 344 35 "&lt;g 238 _ - 241 - 4074 162 135 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 f ISIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. County Institution for Feeble Minded Oirls' Training School Soldier*' and Sailors' Home Burkett Hasting? State Hospital State Industrial School Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital I I Orthopedic State Hospital Penitentiary I Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Uilford Nebraska School for the Bliii'l Norfolk State Hospital i Nebraska i _ . School j Heformatory for the ., , fOT Deaf Women Home for Dependent Children I Reformatory for Men I Total A si»alf,a &gt; Arthur Banner Boooc Bo» Botte Boyo n Brown Bnffalo Bnit Btstler Cats Cedar Cherry^ gSSmx Dakota ZZ Daves Dawson Dead Dixon Dodge gag* Pillmore Praaklia Frontier Fwnaa Gate Garden Garfield Goeaer , Grant __ _ Hamilton .. Harlan .'. Hayes __. _.. Hooker ..„. Howard Jefferson Kearney —_, ,, ,. Ken* ' „ Keya Paha Kimball Km " I.aa_aster lineoln _ ljum __. Maefisnn .. _. I McPherson i". Merrick ..... __„ Nehraika Industrial Home Iforrill „ Nanre . 3«_kotts . Z 7 Otae „_«_ Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte Pole Red Witiow Richardson Rock Saline I. Sarsw TOitfnoers Seotti Bluff Seward ■—»««»«.«..._«_._&gt;._.... Sheridan SET" zrzzzz — Stanton Thayer „ _„...___„_„ 8 1 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 1 2 32 " 3 2 12 3 1 2 2 L_ i 3 2"" 1 2 6 1 y 2 4 2 1 2 44 2 1 . 3&gt; 1 _. i 1 1 10 1 6 1 r 4~ .. _ 7 6 I 4 "2 " 1 _ 32 5 1 1 3 2 « 1 1 l " ~y 25 io 4 ri 19 - id 4 5 4 17 13 5 9 3 1 4 5 25 12 10 2 5 8 11 5 1 "" 4 1 12 1 4 4 4 3 4 ~ 3 3 7 109 1 2 1 2 7 1 2 6 3 3 3 1 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 8 3 1 ' 1 1 9 3 2 1 1 "2 2 2 4 i 4 4 68 1 1 2 2 5 1 5 2 2 1 3 2 2 2 I » 1 " „ . 19 i' 2 6 1 18 211 1 1 1 56 I „ 2 4 1 9 1 3 1 5 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 I 2 2 I 2 6 1 3 5 2 1 8 3 3 1 3 1 4 1 3 2 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 1 6 9 2 1 2 6 2 6 2 13 125 3 " 1 4 3 11 5 1 1 3 5 1 3 6 2 i i 1 1 1 1 i" 4 2 6 I 4 1 2 8 i i 1 1 1 i 1 2 ... 2 1 2 i 1 i 3 _ _ 2 i 27 3 1 2 8 8 3 i i _ "2 i 2 :-••- 1 5 .... 1 26 1 I I 12 3 9 16 6 7 14 12 3 5 1 76 ~"~ 18 i » i 1 1 I 1 1 I i 1 1 1 1 7 2 1 ! 1 I 2 1 1 _ _. I 2 2 1 i' i 1 i 2 I i 9 1 2 3 _ i 1 g 5 2 2 5 10 6 3 5 i 4 1 1 2 i" ~'~ 6 " i" fj 2 » 3 4 7 2 2 3 1 2 1 6 1 8 10 6 68 2 4 2 8 2 4 1 2 2 2 t 97 35 t 2 2 26 20 27 19 85 31 38 46 38 14 19 51 ; 32 l'J a 74 23 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 27 110 7 9 5 1 12 112 39 22 4 18 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 46 3 37 7 19 1 2') 21 4.i 33 49 20 16 22 20 40 12 39 68 8 38, 11 39 44 53 28 27 7 17 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 1 1 55 &gt;•• r "12 4 "7 1 _ . 1 1 4 24 5 a 1 2 2 1 1 r""-~ ■ 1 49 ™ 1 2 1 3 4 1 2 3 25 3 145 1 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 38 i 16 2 !■* _ "2 1 1 I is "' 102 14 4 1 3 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 2 "4 3 1 2 21 « ~4 8 1 3 1 1 " i 1 2 T" -TTi 1 " ____ ! 1 20 1 1 2 1 3 1 5 1 4 3 1 1 15 18 9 4 3 2 7 1 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 T 1 1 1 6~ 1 l i 8 6 i' 1 2 ' " 2 i "" 8 2 3 i 5 ~ 1 1" i " 3 ' "4 8 2 1 2 1 1 1 2 2 l 2 2 I i 5 "1 1 "'id 10 i 3 12 5 1 5 3 6 r~ 9 14 1 "7" 1 3 7 i is 4 3 2 5 2 i I 2 ~'l 4 5 15 1 1 1 ""3 ... 17 6 19 4 2 i 3 1 7 3 2 4 i i 2" I i 1 3 3 1 4 1 7 1 4 6 5 i 2 1 2 Q 3 5 11 2 1 2 i 1 8 5 1 9 6 6 11 7 "2 "76" 2 "2 8" I ... I 2 2 5 6 2 " 1 1 1 4 1 2"" 1 "17" 1 2 2 i 1 3 2 1 2 1 1 _ 2 • 6 i ... _ "i 4 T- "T a ' 2 ■ ! [ 16 1 1 umnown ...» — .~. w — .- — Valley Washington Wim Webster Wheeler Other States. York 7 I, ,„ 2 2 F~ 4 5 1 2 13 ""2 1 1 1 2 "7 7 1 1 1 11 ~ i ~"7 ____ ~"i ' 5 10 1 I 2 1 _ _____ 2"~" 1 -•- - i m ; I i _ h-r- _ ; i 18 g ! "1 "4 I - Total 162 135 472 333 384 369 125 35 241 4074 </seg>  
            <seg id="p016">17 HASTINGS STATE HOSPITAL Ingleside, Nebraska OFFICERS WILLIAM SHERMAN FAST GEORGE MORENNS WHITE CLARA MAY HAYDEN Superintendent Assistant Superintendent Staff Physician Staff Physician Staff Physician HARRY JAY PITTOCK WARD WILLARD HEDLUND MICHAEL O'MEARA Steward LIBBIE GARRISON THORDSEN Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1887 Number of employees 160 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 1200 Highest number of inmates 1219 Per capita cost per month $20.18 Number of acres owned 623 Number of acres under cultivation 523 Value of lands and buildings ,, $1,192,049.00 Principal industries : Farming and stock raising. Visiting days, every day 1 :00 to 4 :00 p. m. Admission to the hospital for the treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. </seg>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. In compliance with your order 1 herewith submit report of the activities of Hastings State Hospital for the period ending June 30, 1923. Work in the several departments of the hospital has been carried on in an efficient manner during the past period. Depart - ment heads have worked in harmony and all have apparently been in co-operation with the executive office, and in harmony with the Board of Control and State authorities. This report deals only with the essentials relative to the activi - ties of the hospital. There will be no recommendations at this time for appropriations as the biennial report will be in your hands six months before the next legislature meets, and we hope at that time to go into detail in our recommendations for additions and improvements at the hospital. For several years past we have recommended for the State of Nebraska a building or an institution for the care of the criminal insane. The legislatures in the past have had recommendations accordingly, but as yet no funds have ever been made available to carry out this needed improvement to state hospital service, and in this connection I will say again that the matter of caring for the criminal insane is a serious problem and should be thought over very carefully, both by the Governor, the Board of Control, and the local hospital authorities. The physical plant of Hastings State Hospital has been well cared for. A force of workmen with many patients helping have been continually kept at work caring for and improving buildings and the equipment of the hospital. . The State owns at Hastings State Hospital one of the best holstein herds in the state. The number of cattle and producing qualities of the herd is set forth in detail later in this report. The State Library Commission has furnished a large number of well selected books for the hospital. No other department of the institution contributes more largely to the contentment and happi - ness of our patients than does the library. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">20 Water supply of the hospital is excellent, quality good and quantity is sufficient. Plumbing and sewerage in excellent shape. General health of the population good. There has been no fatal - ities among the officers and employees during the past year, and there has been no epidemic of contagious disease at any time present among the patient population. Appended to this report will be found condensed statement relative to movement of population which will give in one table most of the essentials. Numerous tables relative to nativity, citizenship, phychoses, environment, economic condition of patients, etc., are attached. Also inventory of live stock and farm products, also garden, orchard, dairy, and poultry products. In closing this report, it is my desire to sincerely thank the members of our medicial staff and all the local officers for their loyalty and cooperation. To the employees, I wish to express my appreciation of the worthy service they have rendered the State, in helping to care for those who are unable to care for themselves. We believe that all of our co-workers have kept in mind the fact that Hastings State Hospital is being maintained solely for the purpose of providing comfort, treatment and protection to the unfortunate citizens of Nebraska who have become mentally ill. To you, the Governor, and to each Member of the Board of Control, we owe a debt of gratitude for your wise wise counsel and advice, for your personal friendship and for your kindly indulgence in overlooking our many shortcomings. Respectfully submitted, W. S. FAST, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">21 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Present at beginning of period. Admitted : For first time. Readmitted ... Transferred from other institutions. Returned from parole Returned from escape. Total under treatment. Discharged ... Recovered . Improved ... Unimproved Died Without psychosis. Transferred to other institutions. Paroled and not returned Escaped and not returned. Total Remaining at end of period. TABLE II— NATIVITY OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T United States. Austria 208 157 365 2 0 2 1 1 2 4 1 5 5 0 5 5 2 7 6 1 7 1 0 1 Belgium Bohemia Canada . Denmark England France .. Germany Greece . 12 7 19 1 0 1 Ireland 2 2 4 Jugo-Slavia Mexico 0 1 1 1 0 1 Moravia Norway Poland Russia .. 3 0 3 2 1 3 2 1 3 4 4 8 Saxony Sweden 1 0 1 8 4 12 Switzerland 2 0 2 Unascertained 11 9 20 Total 281 191 472 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. 748 412 1,160 SI 3.3 2 57 s 191 14 0 36 0 472 47 2 93 5 1,126 653 1,779 33 37 4 180 1 1 105 9 9 21 0 7u o o HZ 0 42 58 4 259 1 187 9 370 191 561 756 462 1,218 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">22 TABLE III— AGE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Fifteen to nineteen years Twenty to twenty-four years Twenty-five to twenty-nine years Thirty to thirty-four years Thirty-five to thirty-nine years Forty to forty-four years Forty-five to forty-nine years „ Fifty to fifty-four years Fjfty-five to fifty-nine years Sjxty to sixty-four years Sixty-five to sixty-nine years Seventy years and over Unascertained 10 V) 26 34 23 22 21 13 13 18 26 55 1 281 10 9 22 28 23 12 15 15 18 7 7 23 2 191 20 28 48 r 62 46 34 36 28 31 25 33 7&amp; A 472 Total TABLE IV— RACE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. - — ■ ■ . _ Bohemian Canadian Dane English _ French German Grecian Irish Ji Mexican Mixed Negra (Southern) __.___.„. Russian _. Saxon Scandinavian Scotch Slavonic _ . Swedish Unknown _ 0 2 6 188 1 26 1 4 1 13 3 5 1 8 0 8 3 11 ~3 3 0 2 2 8 111 29? 0 1 22 48 0 1 3 ::7: 1 : 2 IS 28/ 2 : 5 2 .: x o l \ %: 7 15 6 9 7 18 Total 281 191 472 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">23 TABLE V— CITIZENSHIP OF FIRST ADMISSIONS TABLE VI— DEGREE OF EDUCATION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS TABLE VIII— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Aliens Citizens by birth Citizens by naturalization Citizenship unascertained 21 208 18 34 3 156 15 17 24 364 33 51 Total 281 191 472 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Illiterate Common High School College Unascertaned 36 200 16 16 13 21 138 23 2 7 57 338 39 18 20 Total TABLE VII— USE OF ALCOHOL BY FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Abstinent fetnperate ntemperate Jnascertained 186 14 71 10 187 1 1 2 373 IS 72 12 Total 281 191 472 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. Inited States, both parents oreign, both parents _ fixed _ Fnascertained 117 85 26 S3 65 69 29 28 182 154 55 81 Total 281 191 472 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">24 PRODUCTS OF LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY, FARM AND GARDEN LIVE STOCK AND POULTRY On hand June 30, 1923. Quantity Value Bull Cattle Male hog Sows Pigs Horses Old hens... Young chickens Roosters Ducks ~ Geese _ 1 64 1 35 130 18 305 4,100 24 17 4 $ 100.00 9,510.00 50.00 875.00 1,040.00 2,700.00 305.00 2,050.00 18.00 17.00 16.00 Total $16,681.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">25 2 c ir. «— r. "3 l^J 1^1 OQ QQ f^^ f^*] 8 &lt;7^ 5 •r. C U ««■ v. u OONfOO OO'OOONCmOQ o o o ■**• "^ o &gt;c oo *t- po rs. u^ x f*-j cv ~* iH o o SS8S?S8 O O O O 00* O O Cs) t^ r^i ro 1 I PL, ««■ CO i—l u "3 oinqqN ssss ooo© 2oo&gt;nc Vt -o od Vr cS o s CM "5 £3 in i/i in in in n n in m — -O T3 -O -O "O 13 •O'O : : : ; ui : : : : wi : iii;viiiM! i : &gt;&gt; i-a • i cs : g : j &lt;uuuuwooo«w^ ~2 a </seg>
            <seg id="p025">26 4) 3 S8 T3 H ! S28£88S?S88?KE8S883382gSRRS8 8|§2SfeKJ^^K«22S^S^?2;?gS8SS2ffi52^g i-h ionh i-T rt'«' «sf vd" -h" I 3 en I (/I o 0*^00 io O^OOOOOOOO io O O *^ O OOoOOOOO r^ oo c&gt; r^ to io i o po »^ *"^f\j 10 **$ c5 00 IO VO t&gt;* u^\O fO tO O 00 fO 'O vO &lt;^J rv Tf *O 3 I S2SSS8S§S8g?{qS8S88?5828SSS^8 &lt;222S952inN v£ ' &lt;v^ v S 0 0' Hl " |^oopo'0"*oo'^ :&gt; o&lt;*5^Ho;«c&gt; 9gS. &lt; 5f&gt;s tV| . 10 !2t; K "'~' vc&gt; '~"'' 0 0'f' H '^"'' u^oooo — «&lt;ff^"i ioi-ti-4 t-T rsf oT •-T 10 -a s ■§ m | O i') O 'O *O i S io w O &lt;O C&gt; ■— oo &lt;S *^ I s * 1 * "s io to to ir&gt; **$ cS o^ o &lt;&gt;a 3; go" t&gt;r&lt;-Tsd'«Ni' r^\o\na^g\ uiofin oCqo c*iio*PM"o*oo"r-T ■a 5 I JSS8 IS ! I I I | |&amp;j§ I I JSS | i J8 \S I I • IOOO* :o : ; ! : : :&lt;■■*© : : io© i i io -o ! i : * 00 t*i : o ; ; : ; ; : eg &lt;3 : j ♦ 3F5 : : 2K ; K i ; ;|j; ;•-« I ; ioo' ; I ; ; I ; oo'on'p^ ; oo ; | ; ; i j g"&gt;W : i i fvf ui i I : of ' tC I I ' 8 5&gt; 5 § 01 BSCCCBSCSBBCCCCCCCCSCCSCCCCC 3333333333333333333333333333 0000000000000000000000000000 ac.q.o.c.q.e.c.c.c.c.ao.c.c.c.c.&amp;cc.c.c.accc.c.c. : bi ::::••::'••• i : i : : : i • • i «i *^ iiJiiJlliJifiiiWJil! "5 o H </seg>
            <seg id="p026">27 LINCOLN STATE HOSPITAL Lincoln, Nebraska OFFICERS D. G. GRIFFITHS R. H. SPRADLING H. GUY BROWN MARIE L. GROTE J. R. HELMS Superintendent Assistant Superintendent and Physician Staff Physician Staff Physician Steward MARGARET E. HAY Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1870 Number of employees 132 Number of inmates June 30. 1923 981 rlighest number of inmates 995 995 Per capita cost per month $19.19 Number of acres owned 640 640 Number of acres rented 178 Number of acres under cultivation 788 Value of land and buildings $1,053,900.00 Principal industries : Farming, gardening and stock raising. Visiting Days : Every day except Saturday, Sunday and holidays, 1 :00 p. m. to 4 :00 p. m. Admission to the hospital for the treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">1 &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">29 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I hereby have the honor of submitting the report of the Lincoln State Hospital for the period ending June 30, 1923. During this period Dr. A. N. Anderson resigned, June 30, 1921 ; Dr. Marie L. Grote joined the staff, June 15, 1921 ; Dr. H. Guy Brown joined the staff February 27, 1922; Dr. W. H. Hunnicutt resigned, June 30, 1922; and Dr. O. L. Asher joined the staff, September 3, 1922, and resigned, December 14, 1922. In addition to this we have had Dr. G. 11. Laugharn, who acted as interne, during the summer of 1921, and we have with us now Dr. J. Blaine Babcock, who is acting as interne during this summer of 1923. The dairy barn, which was erected during the past biennium, was put into use during this period, and the old barns, cow sheds, etc., have all been moved from the old location to the new, which makes a decided improvement in this department. The Farmers' Lodge, for which we had money appropriated in the 1921 session of the Legislature, has been completed and is occupied at this time. It consists of a house for 24 patients, and the necessary attendants; a fine horse barn, cattle shed, and other splendid improvements; and is a great addition to the hospital, facilitating the farm work, as well as serving the patients better and hastening the recovery of many of them. We have had four new wells put down on the hill south of the hospital, which furnish an abundance of good water. We have three new boilers installed and we feel that our heating and water system are in first-class condition at this time. We have been having considerable trouble with the pumps on the hill as it seems they are too light to stand the work and possibly will have to be changed. Amusements have been carried on as usual during this period. We have had a picture show and dance each week ; also, regular Sunday morning services in the chapel. We have a ball game twice each week during the summer and this form of recreation is </seg>
            <seg id="p029">30 greatly enjoyed by the patients. During the winter, many outside organizations and individuals gave entertainments for the patients, and we wish to take this opportunity to thank them all for their kindness. This, and all other forms of recreation, we find, are very conductive to the welfare and improvements of those mentally afflicted. The Legislature of the 1923 session appropriated $125,000 for a receiving hospital for this institution. This has not yet been erected, but we hope to get it under way in the very near future. In this hospital building it is intended to have all the facilities and conveniences for treating and caring for the insane, such as : an X-ray room, dental office, physicians' offices, and all the different examination rooms that will enable us to better study and treat those mentally afflicted. This will undoubtedly increase the efficiency of our institution. There are other things which are needed very badly by the hospital, one of them being a new kitchen and refrigerating plant ; and another, a nurses' home. We could then house 100 more patients in the rooms that are now occupied by the employees. I wish to thank the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions for their kindly advice, also for the trust which they have placed in me in the administration of the affairs of this hospital, also the officers and employees associated with me, who have been loyal and faithful during the past biennium. Very respectfully submitted, D. G. GRIFFITHS, M. D., Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">31 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF INSANE PATIENT POPULATION For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Insane patients on books of institution at beginning of period 475 494 969 Admissions : First admissions. Readmissions 345 241 586 43 46 89 Transfers from other institutions for mental diseases 5 1 6 393 288 681 868 782 1,650 Total received. Total Discharged : As improved As unimproved 83 114 197 53 29 82 1 0 1 As without psychosis. Transferred to other institutions for mental diseases Died 4 2 6 157 105 262 Total discharged, transferred and died. 298 250 548 Insane patients remaining at end of period. 570 532 1,102 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T 223 187 410 United States. Australia United States 223 187 410 4 3 7 7 5 12 9 8 17 6 2 8 5 1 6 2 0 2 4 3 7 Australia 7 5 12 Canada Canada Czecho-Slovakia Denmark Czecho-Slovakia 9 8 17 6 2 8 Denmark England Finland . Germany Greece ... England 5 1 6 2 0 2 Finland Germany 23 9 32 23 9 32 1 0 1 1 0 1 Greece Hungary Ireland . Japan ... Hungary 1 2 3 1 2 3 5 2 7 5 2 7 Ireland 2 2 4 2 2 4 Japan Mexico 3 0 3 3 0 3 Mexico Poland Russia Scotland Spain .... Poland 1 2 3 1 2 3 Russia 7 3 10 7 3 10 Scotland 3 1 4 3 1 4 Spain 1 1 2 1 1 2 6 3 9 6 3 9 Sweden Sweden Other countries. Unascertained ... Other countries. 4 0 4 4 0 4 32 10 42 32 10 42 Unascertained ... Total . Total 345 241 586 345 241 586 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">32 TABLE III— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF INSANE PATIENTS ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Total Adams Cass Cheyenne Clay Custer .~ Daw son Dodge Douglas Fillmore Franklin Frontier Gage Garden Jefferson _ Johnson _ _ Kearney Lancaster _ Lincoln Merrick ■. Nemaha Otoe Pawnee _ Phelps Richardson Saline Sarpy Saunders Seward ■■) 1 19 1 2 6 1 18 211 1 1 1 56 1 2 4 1 145 1 2 15 18 9 1 18 17 6 19 9 Total 586 TABLE IV— CITIZENSHIP OF FIRST AI MISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Citizens by birth Citizens ny naturalization Aliens Citizenship unascertained 225 17 74 29 187 7 30 17 412 24 104 46 Total 345 241 586 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">33 TABLE V— PSYCHOSES OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. 3 0 3 Traumatic psychoses. Senile psychoses 42 31 73 4 1 5 Psychoses with cerebral arteriosclerosis. General paralysis 72 11 83 3 0 3 1 0 1 1 0 1 74 82 156 2 5 7 Psychoses with cerebral syphilis... Psychoses with brain tumor Alcoholic psychoses, total Manic-depressive psychoses, total. I nvolution melancholia Dementia praecox (schizophrenia). Paranoia and paranoid conditions. Epileptic psychoses % 85 181 9 5 14 22 12 34 1 2 3 IS 7 22 Psychoses with psychopathic personality. Imbeciles Total 345 241 586 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 African (black) Bulgarian Cuban Dutch and Flemish English Finnish French German Greek Hebrew Irish Italian _ Mexican Portuguese Roumanian Scandinavian Scotch „ Slavonic Spanish _ Spanish-American Welsh Mixed M. 16 0 1 2 5 4 2 29 3 8 11 5 7 1 0 19 5 10 2 0 2 213 F. 14 1 (I 1 5 1 () 15 0 5 4 4 ] 0 1 15 2 12 0 1 0 159 T. 30 1 1 3 10 s 2 44 3 13 IS ') 8 1 1 34 7 22 2 1 2 372 Total 345 241 586 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">34 ADMISSIONS TABLE VII— AGE OF FIRST For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Fifteen to nineteen years Twenty to twenty-four years Twenty-five to twenty-nine years Thirty to thirty-four years Thirty-five to thirty-nine years Forty to forty-four years Forty-five to forty-nine years Fifty to fifty-four years Fifty-five to fifty-nine years Sixty to sixty-four years Sixty-five to sixty-nine years Seventy years and over 32 47 53 43 37 33 28 ..18 13 IS 17 11 40 46 32 23 17 15 9 9 6 14 54 87 99 75 60 50 4.3 27 22 21 31 Total 345 241 586 TABLE VIII— DEGREE OF EDUCATION OF FI ST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 ~M. F. T7 Illiterate Reads and writes Common school High school College Unascertained 18 42 225 44 14 4 10 30 140 41 12 2 28 72 369 85 26 6 Total 345 241 586_ TABLE IX— ENVIRONMENT OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Urban Rural \ZZZ"ZZ". Unascertained 179 151 15 114 125 2 293 276 17 Total 345 241 586 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">35 TABLE X— ECONOMIC CONDITIONS OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Abstinent Temperate Intemperate .. Unascertained Total 345 241 586 TABLE XII— MARITAL CONDITION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS 119 Ui8 287 94 2() 114 60 0 60 72 5.? 125 M. F. T. Dependent 172 120 2&gt;)2 Marginal 125 83 208 Comfortable 34 2\ 55 Unascertained 14 17 31 Total :.| 345 241 586 TABLE XI— USE OF ALCOHOL BY FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1023 \. F. T. i ingle Carried Vidowed Separated divorced Jnascertained 138 92 43 36 28 8 102 71 31 19 9 9 240 1(&gt;3 74 55 37 17 Total 345 241 586 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">36 H ioh fi vo i-h go e2 fc OiflOONHH*«lM«O I m S 1 1 H ii 'A 3 O o bo I f*5 i— i O4 Is 1 £ i— i b OJQOONjn — 2 r^ lCVJ '- &lt; I'o •a o S H^KlHOm^-lNOO |S &lt; ft ■&gt; o O H 8 •a I o u c 5 lii OO VC VO « ° |8 5 S3 i .8 3S &lt; d 3 J M a o 3 * « 2 »&lt; S ||t|] ;::::: Ml! ililiiliilll { ! I Mill Jill 3 P 3 is Ml III IE f ! 1.2 s :.S J ° : w i I ! Us •] Jlu i ! K|sl|Wj ! : !S£tfi Bo&lt; sa8 i I i«S5^.2-3.2.HS£ lljiillllll T— I 2 VC u-. 3 o </seg>
            <seg id="p036">37 TABLE XIV— CAUSES OF DEATH OF PATIENTS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. General Diseases: Erysipelas 0 1 1 0 2 2 7 14 21 2 2 4 2 4 6 1 3 4 Septicaemia Tuberculosis of lungs Other forms of tuberculosis Cancer Diabetes Nervous System: Cerebro-spinal meningitis 0 1 I 15 14 29 51 13 64 0 1 1 9 8 17 Apoplexy (cerebral hemorrhage) General paralysis of insane Cerebro-spinal syphilis Epilepsy •'i — ~-r"j Circujatory System : Pericarditis 7 6 13 17 12 29 0 1 1 Endocarditis and myocarditis Angina pectoris Arteriosclerosis 5 2 7 0 1 1 Other diseases of circulatory system Respiratory System : Bronchitis 1 0 1 3 1 4 S 7 15 Broncbopneumonia l.obar Pneumonia Digestive System: L'lcer of stomach 1 I) 1 2 1 3 2 13 2 1 3 1 0 1 Other diseases of the stomach (cancer excepted Diarrhea and enteritis Hernia and intestinal obstruction Other diseases of intestines Genito-Urinary System : Acute nephritis Acute nephritis" 1') 3. 22 Chronic nephritis \ 1 6 7 Chronic nephritis Violence : Suicide 1 0 1 Total Total 157 105 262 .\ lungs </seg>
            <seg id="p037">38 DIPSOMANIA —TABLE NO. I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Period Ending Movement June 30. 1923 M. F. T. Present at beginning of period. Admitted : 8 1 9 For first time.. Readmitted 147 22 169 49 8 57 Total under treatment. 204 31 235 Recovered . Improved ... Unimproved Insane 125 14 139 23 9 32 0 0 0 0 0 0 4 0 4 Died Escaped, not yet returned or discharged. 15 0 15 Total on hand at end of period.. 37 8 45 DIPSOMANIA— TABLE NO. II— AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Age M. F. T. Under 15 years 15 and under 20 0 0 0 0 0 0 20 years and under 30. 30 and under 50 29 4 33 83 16 99 27 2 29 Over 50 years.... Age not known. 8 0 8 ota DIPSOMANIA— TABLE NO. Ill— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. ingle „ „ _ _l tarried _ Vidowed _ )ivorced _ ieparated Jnknown . „ 55 59 7 5 14 7 0 12 3 2 5 0 55 71 10 7 19 7 Total _ _ 147 22 169 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">39 DIPSOMANIA— TABLE No. IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Primary 5 1 6 86 14 100 Common schosl. High school 29 5 34 College or university. None 10 1 11 6 1 7 Unknown 11 0 11 147 22 169 Total DIPSOMANIA— TABLE No. V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Nativity June 30, 192J M. F, M. F. T. Nebraska j j j jg United States other than Nebraska ?5 _j 115 25 18 4 133 29 Total native born j^j -7? Foreign born 7 "q 140 7 22 0 162 7 Total .". 147 22 147 22 169 DIPSOMANIA— TABLE NO. VI— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Period Ending June 30, 1923 Occupation M. F. T. Auctioneer - Baker Bookkeeper Butcher Carpenter Car repairer Clerical worker Cook — Dentist - Driver Druggist Editor - Electrician Embalmer Farmer _ Fireman _ - 2 3 1 1 4 1 .3 7 2 2 1 1 2 1 1 0 0 (I (I 0 0 0 0 I) 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 2 3 1 1 4 1 .3 7 2 2 1 1 2 X 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">40 DIPSOMANIA— TABLE NO. VI— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF on :in For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Guard Hotel proprietor Housekeeper Laborer Lumberman - Mail carrier Musician None Nurse Painter Plumber Physician Porter Real estate dealer Salesman : Stenographer Stock Buyer Stoie proprietor Telegraph operator Unknown Waiter ... 1 0 4 0 0 13 29 0 1 0 1 0 3 1 16 5 0 1 8 0 1 0 4 0 2 0 3 0 12 0 0 1 1 0 3 0 1 0 11 0 6 1 1 4 13 2') 1 1 4 21 1 8 1 4 2 3 12 1 1 3 1 11 7 147 22 169 DIPSOMANIA— TABLE NO. VII— COUNTY C OF THOSE ADMITTED IF RESIDENCE Ending June 30, 1923 For Period County M. F. T. Adams Antelope Arthur Boone Buffalo Burt Butler _, Cass - Clay Colfax - Custer _ Dakota Dawes - Daw son .... Dodge Douglas ~ _ 4 3 1 1 2 1 .? 2 1 3 1 1 1 1 1 73 1 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 16 5 3 1 1 2 1 3 2 1 3 1 1 1 1 1 89 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">IPSOMANIA— TABLE VII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED (Continued) For Period Ending June 30, 1923 County M. F. T. Frontier Furnas Gage Hall Jefferson Johnson Km ix „... Lancaster Lincoln Madison Mcrrick : Nance Nuckolls Otoe Pierce Platte Polk Richardson Saline Thayer Thurston _ Washington 2 1 4 .3 1 2 1 12 1 3 2 2 3 2 1 2 1 0 0 3 0 0 0 o i 0 0 1 0 I) 0 0 p 0 0 0 0 0 0 2 1 7 .? 1 2 1 13 1 3 3 1 1 2 1 1 1 .? 2 1 2 1 Total 147 22 169 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">42 o o 55 « « K K HI 1=1 8 w &gt; I-H 1-1 fa o to H O « 04 9 B S &gt;— &gt; 3 88 I IS8S8 8 i d _3 &gt; S3 !S8S8S 8 5 ! d ; -3 3 2 I U$;8 ! j i i te» i R ! I* ! i 111 si HJHJ 3 d ~3 I J »- * ! i ! i"N ; ; • 6 1 1 SS |S88§8 O 1 • O *^ lO On 00 &lt;M : g PQ PQOQ : 8 6 invo • Tf a* rq cvi rs. ■"" 1 5 s I ooo -oooo q3\^ :pfcjpp |&gt;k ©\ '• ~^ W5 \© On ■ 'O fO *"^ 3 3 o H d M J I 1 j | i O "S * ■3 2 o H GC tNk 8 1 3 u I c 8 2 o o S *5 l : I ; : ! d j o H </seg>
            <seg id="p042">43 o ft a Q I SgSSg8^g^S8S2 IN, o O O^O^f^^^OOfMCMO^ 00^^ iN^tN^^ 00 f*5 lO 0*1 ID PO 00 1 V. o 2 a" s 'l*S* s " s "i" %*3S"s I 1 CL, u g ggggggogggo gg'ogcjpiuSrQoo-jcvi 3. v&gt;- o H s |8SS"i SSSSf^* sssss to cm 1 8882 CNCX in 5&gt; o w- "rt u 3 2 3 m m t— I i I I i i ! i I I I I | I i i ; II I ! I | j I ; ci : ! I ■ : • i i : • ■ : jO ■ ; ; i • I ;:;•:: ■o i I i i i i ! i i I ! i JB ! I ! : i ': i i : : i |J \Ji4% M I J is I 0 c J I O 00 OO_fj »— ir. i t3 O i. •S) 3 u 3 ■-n u OOOOm 3; "o &gt;-iu5 CJ a 3 u ir&gt; o p "1 S 00^(\l IT) I. O H U u : : • tn : i i : .a i : ■ • *C : ui &lt;" i cn.SJ -J5 oi ■atSSSSt S^ 3 8S &lt;uuoo s I </seg>
            <seg id="p043">44 "S I S^8.8888S8?8{QS8JQ8^888«8888S88 SfcSS5:38$3£fc«23Xlg££33S:2d l c2Ki3328' •^ «{vf.-r tx »-&lt;" m 1 ■3 w- 2 'o H B Qg in *-h no^On &lt;*^ O no O CO eg »— • **^ O Ov oo to io O V^ t- 1^ ■g a. o 3 I S8888888S8?8&lt;q88£8888838888888 S"fc2Ki3SS£33fc~23Ki8&amp;££3822!2£33J&lt;g „ ««« oo pn ~ 5 i M&gt; a S s § s lllss2 S S?^5RS88g§IQ8SK:5Q2 M S2R2-2~ "^2 2-§gJ^ j£»rfg« 3 &gt;f--.- 5 - g $ 2 - I § I i 88 8 8 8 8 8 •» ' 8 * I i £ 1; </seg>
            <seg id="p044">45 NORFOLK STATE HOSPITAL NORFOLK, NEBRASKA OFFICERS G. E. CHARLTON E. L. EM RICH WILLIS WILSON C. E. REMY Superintendent First Assistant Physician Staff Physician Staff Physician A. J. GUTZMER Steward BERTHA LUDWIG Matron Miscellaneous Statement Established 1885 Number of employees 90 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 767 Highest number of inmates 768 Per capita cost per month $20.87 Number of acres 455 Number of acres under cultivation 400 Value of lands and buildings $829,877.40 Principal industries : stock raising, farming and gardening Visiting days : every day, except Sundays and holidays between 9 A. M. and 4 P.M. Admission for treatment of mental diseases is had only through commitment by the insanity board in each county, consisting of the clerk of the court, a physician and a lawyer. </seg>
            <seg id="p045"/>
            <seg id="p046">47 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I herewith respectfully submit the following report of the Norfolk State Hospital for the period ending June 30, 1923. During the past biennium the health of the entire hospital was very good, being spared the presence of infectious or contagious malady. In the past, up until five years ago, we have had each year a few cases of typhoid fever. We attribute the lack of the ty - phoid infections to the extensive use of the typhoid vaccine. Occupation is generally recognized as a potent factor in the treatment of mental diseases, and we have been quite successful in finding suitable occupation for a large percentage of both our men and women. Light work is preferable to enforced idleness on the part of those who are convalescing, and all patients are encour - aged to do some work. During the past few months this insti - tution has been regularly visited by inspectors of the United States Veterans Bureau and we have been complimented on the number of patients that we have occupied, and upon the form of occupation. The farm, garden, dairy and poultry yards, and constructions, furnishes employment to patients who prefer to work out-of-doors ; while a large number find employment in the kitchen dining room and laundry. The female patients are encouraged to work in the domestic department, and a large number are regularly employed in the sewing room, laundry, dining room and kitchen, while many occupy themselves with fancy work and assist with general domestic work on the ward. In the art room we have a special instructor where a number of ladies are encouraged and taught to do fancy needle work. Since our last report, considerable more dental work has been done than in former years. We are still handicapped however, by not having a resident dentist. It is needless to say, that proper v </seg>
            <seg id="p047">48 dental work is as necessary to the health of this class of patients, as any other class of medical service. In the last few years, it has been proven beyond all doubt, that the elimination of focal infec - tions in the insane is of great importance. I sincerely hope that during the coming biennium arrangements may be made for a resident dentist. The laboratory work has been directed along therapeutic, as well as diagnostic lines. It is felt that the laboratory is a valuable adjunct to the rest of the hospital work, and that it should be ex - tended. Within the past year much has been written both in medi - cal journals and magazines along the line of the roll that focal infection plays in the causation of mental disease. If this institu - tion is to keep abreast, along these lines of investigation as it should a laboratory expert should be added to our staff, as no institution is capable of doing research work unless men especially qualified for such work are employed. The farm and garden report may be found among the statistical statements which shows considerable activity in these departments. We are especially fortunate this period in having fairly good crops, which materially reduced our maintenance cost. The new power house completed during this period is now in operation, and is in no way disappointing. The transfer from the old building to the new was made without any interruption of service. Considerable credit is due the management of this depart - ment for the service that was rendered during the construction and opening of the new plant. A great deal of extra work was made necessary by the moving of this plant, such as piping, wiring, etc. The new kitchen is now completed and has been occupied since July 5th of this year. The equipment and arrangement of this building is excellent and meets our expectations in every wav. It would not be amiss to say here, that the arrangement of this ventilation in this building has brought forth favorable comment from those particularly versed in this work. A new root cellar 50 ft. by 60 ft. has been completed. The root cellar was located in the pit that was formerly used in the old engine room and we are able to save considerable expense by making use of the old walls. The ventilating system in our root cellar is something rather new and we expect that it is going to prove very satisfactory. Many minor improvements and repairs have been made in </seg>
            <seg id="p048">49 keeping up the physical condition of the buildings. There are many improvements yet to he made that have been put off for the lack of funds. In closing this report, I wish to express to you as a Board, and to each member individually, my appreciation of the full sup - port and encouragement which you have at all times given. Also to thank my assistants in all the departments of the institution for that continued active co-operation which has always characterized the work of the officers of the hospital. Respectfully submitted, G. E. CHARLTON, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p049">50 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF INSANE PATIENT POPULATION Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. nsane patients at beginning of the period - Admissions during period : First Admissions Readmissions 426 346 772 203 SO 141 36 344 86 Total admissions 2S3 177 430 Total at end of period 679 52.? 1202 ischarged : As recovered As improved As unimproved Transferred to other institutions for mental diseases Died 54 57 7 41 48 1 95 105 8 1 76 1 73 2 149 Total discharged, transferred and died 195 164 359 Insane patients remaining at end of period 484 359 843 TABLE II— NATIVITY OF FIRST AD ISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. United States Austria Canada - — Denmark — - Enffland m m . ( , ,. Fahad _ - &gt; — France , „„.,, H Germany - .- Hungary _ Ireland — Norway - Poland _ - Russia „ — Scotland Sweden Switzerland _ Wales Other countries „ Unascertained 135 3 3 2 3 0 2 21 1 3 0 1 3 2 7 1 1 1 14 97 11 0 2 2 1 0 6 0 0 1 1 2 I) 6 0 0 0 12 232 14 3 4 5 1 2 27 1 3 1 2 5 2 13 l 1 1 20 Total _ 203 141 344 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">51 TABLE III— ADMISSIONS BY COUNTIES For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Antelope IS 5 20 Boone 3 5 8 Box Butte Boyd Z.JL..Z: 0 1 1 3 4 7 Brown 4 8 12 0 3 3 4 5 9 8 8 16 0 1 1 S 1 6 5 2 7 8 6 14 5 7 12 2 1 3 5 0 5 &amp; 1 1 46 30 76 Holt 13 5 18 Kearney 0 1 1 Keya Paha IL_!Z___I Knox 1 1 2 11 S 16 Lancaster ~~~™™"I!~~ZHZ! Madison 0 2 2 11 10 21 Morrill 5 3 8 Nance 5 1 6 Nuckolls 0 1 1 Pierce 8 2 10 Platte 5 5 10 Rock 2 13 2 13 Sheridan Sioux 6 2 8 5 0 5 Stanton .S'"'~~'~~~"~"~'"~~" Thurston 1 5 6 7 4 11 Wayne 6 4 10 Washington 4 1 S Total 203 141 344 TABLE IV— CITIZENSHIP OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. Citizens by birth 141 105 246 39 21 60 10 5 15 13 10 23 Citizens by naturalization Aliens Citizenship unascertained Total 203 141 344 Buffalo Burt Cedar .-LZZ—ZZIZUZZ Chase Cherry cdfax zir/rzrz.i..r.r..:ir.r.z~!! L'utning Dakota Dawes Dixon Dodge ""_.._..!;Z Douglas "_'"2 on ed ZZZZZZZZZZZZZ </seg>
            <seg id="p051">52 TABLE V— PSYCHOSES OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. " T. Senile psychoses 35 14 49 0 5 5 32 1 5 Psychoses with cerebral arteriosclerosis General paralysis 5 27 Psychoses with cerebral syphilis 4 Psychoses with other brain or nervous diseases Acute chorea 1 1 0 1 0 2 0 Alcohoj psychoses Delirium tremens 1 Other types, acute or chronic 2 Psychoses with other somatic diseases Post-infectious psychosis Cardio-renal diseases Other diseases or conditions _. Manic-depressive psychoses Manic type Depressive type _ Other types 1 0 1 0 5 0 2 5 2 9 15 24 22 26 11 13 4 2 Involution melancholia 2 3 5 42 91 Dementia praecox (schizophrenia).. Paranoia and paranoid conditions .. Epileptic psychoses Psychoneuroses and neuroses 49 7 0 7 7 11 18 Hysterical type Psychasthenic type, (anxiety and obsessive forms).. Neurasthenic type 1 2 1 6 0 6 2 1 3 Psychoses with mental deficiency. Undiagnosed psychoses Without psychosis. • fi 1 7 2 0 2 Epilepsy without psychosis Alcoholism without psychosis -. Psychopathic personality without psychosis. Mental deficiency without psychosis Others 0 11 0 2 0 1 2 1 14 8 22 4 11 141 344 / Total 203 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">53 TABLE VI— AGE OF FIRST ADMISSIONS For Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Under fifteen 1 0 1 Fifteen to nineteen years 4 8 12 Under fifteen Twenty to twenty-four years 14 13 27 Twenty-five to twenty-nine years 20 20 40 Thirty" to tliirtv-four vears 20 20 40 2() 20 40 Thirty-five to thirty-nine years Thirty-five to thirty-nine years 24 11 35 Forty to forty-four years IS 21 3" 18 21 3" Forty-five to forty-nine years I 1° 17 Mi Fifty to fifty-four years 17 4 21 * I . *J H. ...*_. ...«. JW .. U A, • — . Fifty-five to fifty-nine years 12 8 20 Sixty to sixty-four years 15 10 25 10 25 Sixty-five to sixty-nine years 12 1 13 Seventy years and over 26 8 34 Unascertained 1 0 1 1 0 1 Total 203 141 344 TABLE VII— DEGREE OF EDUCATION OF FIRST ADMISSIONS \ Total for Period Ending June 30. 1923 M. F. T. Illiterate 8 9 17 Reads and writes 19 V) 38 Common school , 141 88 229 High school 13 20 33 College 10 4 14 Unascertained 12 1 13 x Total 203 141 344 TABLE VIII— ENVIRONMENT OF FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. Urban 83 59 142 Rural 119 80 199 Unascertained 12 3 Total 203 141 344 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">54 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. &gt;ependent iarginal "omfortable 89 63 51 38 39 64 127 102 115 Total 203 141 344 TABLE X— USE OF ALCOHOL BY FIRST ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Abstinent Temperate Intemperate Unascertained 92 10 31 70 85 4 1 51 177 14 32 121 Total '. 203 141 344 TABLE XI— MARTIAL CONDITION OF FIRS ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. Single Married _ Widowed Separated Divorced Unascertained 100 63 26 5 5 4 50 66 17 3 5 0 150 129 43 8 10 4 Total 203 141 344 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">55 TABLE XII— PSYCHOSES OF RE- ADMISSIONS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Senile psychoses General paralysis Alcoholic psychoses 1 1 2 1 2 3 3 0 3 7 H. 2.3 Manic-depressive psychoses. Dementia praecox 16 14 30 Paranoia and paranoid conditions Epileptic psychoses 4 0 4 4 1 5 Psychoneuroses and neuroses Psychoses with mental deficiency Undiagnosed psychoses 3 0 3 4 1 5 2 0 2 Without psychosis 5 1 (, Total 50 36 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">56 .1 o a H fc I vo is. «-h « o\ cvj *-h ««t (*5 o\ t*i rg &lt;&lt;*■ I op I O^J(*5OOO'if0iH00»-iwMio^« I O *O « Cg ' I »-&gt; fCf « O «^ &lt;*5 Pg fN. 00 *-* fO I 00 H M c^l 1O NH h s I fl fe tN r^ o OO Is W o « a S 5 o ?j o oc *-H tN-« Is H iHinwiii &lt;-xvi t rm 00 t (S Tf ON Ov -H I 10 I f-H o H Q o •a i s I fa O«5.-i©O© »-H CM-H 1-^ •-&lt; IO f* t-N IO si «tv)C\|««PM o w 8 X o w a, o 1 o H fcu nN O-h O4 *-tr*5 »-» 00 OhoON "&gt;"{!}«•&gt; Ig 1-1000 m x ! 1 1 § i ! i M i i : i i iS ! ! i-2 IS ! j ! S l # -3 IS J i i J j I I IJ jj I i ii] iffliB lit rtl S C C L • </seg>
            <seg id="p056">57 TABLE XIV— CAUSES OF DEATH OF PATIENTS Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. 0 1 1 Dysentery Krysipelas 0 2 2 1 1 2 Septicaemia 4 2 6 Tuberculosis of lungs Other forms of tuberculosis 1 1 2 2 1 3 Cancer Tumor (non-cancerous) 1 0 1 12 10 22 Apoplexy (cerebral hemorrhage) Ifeneral paralysis of insane 18 4 22 2 0 2 Cerebro-spinal syphilis 2.? 17 40 Exhaustion from other mental diseases 1 0 1 Brain tumor 1 0 1 Other diseases of brain. 2 2 4 Eniiepsy Circulatory system pericarditis Endocarditis and myocarditis 0 2 2 2 2 4 0 1 1 Angina pcctoris Other diseases of the heart 2 3 5 2 1 3 Circulatory system (continued) arteriosclerosis Other diseases of circulatory system. 1 0 1 Respiratory System : Lobar pneumonia Asthma 7 0 7 1 0 1 Digestive System : Diarrhea and enteritis Appendicitis and typhlitis Other diseases of intestines 0 2 2 1 0 1 0 1 1 (jenito-urinary system : Acute nephritis Chronic nephritis .. 2 0 2 5 1 6 1 0 I Other diseases of kidneys and annexa Violence : Suicide .. Homicide 2 0 2 1 0 1 Total 95 54 149 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">s § s « fa N" a H •-&gt; &amp; O a. Q •&lt; &gt; S .-3 bod S5 o I— I H O £&gt; § a H &gt;-) &amp; O a. Q Q CO II I 1 as I OS i— t 3 S8'&lt;5!88 *O to VO I'V O 9 i. r^ »-h cvj 0 o 3 8^ in o »2" s] c u §1 c c 6~ feS2 SDOOO 0Oc*5«— &lt; 00 f3 d -a 1 88888 s o im~~ _3 5 88888 s § 3 o 6 &gt;5 ©tmooooo CO 00 I i | j j ail! j * 1 S S O H ■o 5 3 S c fcj ■ ■ D O re &gt; 3 f5 § 8 5 o K re u © i — i </seg>
            <seg id="p058">59 I ffj •=» f&gt; s&gt; »r; wv © pj p) «f !■£ 5 ?i 9 I t I H wf ■* t* * 3 u 0, rt o H E u 2! ■o""" w H U &amp; o o «■ 04 Q W o o m tfi fl m in m « *O "O "O 'O "13 "O *U c a c c c c c 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 O O O O O o O C — C O. C. c. &amp; o H '£ r E S5«..« «.SW "&gt;•£ &lt;UUOOwd, -7. I 82£888g 3 ■— « ~* ro wi o »-* *t- r^ fN C^J r*5 r^ P3 (\j fvj t&gt;. i— i (\| O O to : ifl 0) : &lt;l&gt; ■g 3 4 I w- u 3 M K tf - "8 £ r. •5 *o c4 o 0 s »-o IO CVJ 00 Wi O 5&gt; E 3 &lt;/! o a oo o o o o o l^s. O O O "^ O 'f O^ O^ *^ oo = -a o u I S888S8 tt o &gt;d ■* &lt;si to 5&gt; &lt;«• o Cti NOOON-tO "O -T O O C^ t&gt;&gt; t&gt;. S3 -h frj •a "3 888838 3 I a o «/9" 73 o H a 3 It © ©*o •**■ o © OOOO — CM?Fc\ •-« &lt;*5 CVJ « i ! I i' : g ! ! 3 •■:•■:■. Q i i i ■ O, : • : I I ! i | i : I ■V i : ! i C i i ■ j ? I «.a \ ' Iff j l 1- W &gt;»+j +j O C « rt ctj « UWffiWOO </seg>
            <seg id="p059">60 I 3 i "3 &gt; E ■ t- » t !SS£§^S l 352§S?$S8§8S.§8.:2S2JSK8S8 % t'-C"»i«i«3J^^iioooo»nio\ct&lt;i : c^odo6"^ :^i"»fO»-"^"&lt;ri&gt;oo; p4 OS s i&lt;-r S i I i I H j A. B M i s s S 8 S 1 s 8 S 2 ■5 ■ ~1 &gt; ir. &lt;/^ I 8 1. tfi &lt;s&gt; &lt;fi &lt;ti w U; iri t, T !■ r. i. I &gt;i, i. r. r. r; T. r. I. -r. r, i. f, r. r. r. r. 999339939333333333933993933993 ■ ooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo o H !■» « h» »»5 X "". «5J&gt; OC «". X — 1^ fj X " &gt;O r»&gt; &gt;/5 © — Cts")vC^ — WO i &gt;.' x — &gt; —^ &lt;vf o* *c "£ &lt;^s o* o* od «oo « 10 rvf rC »-«" o* csf H" oo «m 00 — * « r^ *-^ — ~-« IO t-^ O4 "~t" © © © O © xn CO I i I | Lujj ig I I I || I III I I I I I . In ■•Ib.J llBfrl I i I I* « M I ! ' !» I lllllilfflillllllllllllll|l|l </seg>
            <seg id="p060">61 r * MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF EXAMINERS OF DEFECTIVES W. S. FAST, M. D., Chairman, Superintendent, Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside. D. G. GRIFFITHS, M. D., Secretary, Superintendent Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln. Superintendent Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk. J. H. MATHAI, M. D. Superintendent Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln. S. J. STEWART, M. D., Superintendent Feeble-Minded Institution, Beatrice G. E. CHARLTON, M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p061"/>
            <seg id="p062">63 To the Governor and Board of Control, of State Institutions Lincoln, Nebraska : We submit herewith the Fourth Biennial Report of the Board of Examiners of Defectives, covering the period ending June 30, 1923. This Board was created and appointed by the Board of Control complying with Chapter 237, Laws of Nebraska, 1915, entitled "An act to authorize the sterilization of feeble-minded and insane inmates of state institutions, in certain cases, and provide for the appointment of a commission, and to define their powers and duties in connection therewith." There have been tetvflheetings of the Board of Examiners of Defectives held during tntLpast two years. Meetings are called by the chairman on request of the superintendents of the different state hospitals. Appended to this report will be found five tables : Table I, referring to the Hastings State Hospital ; Table II, the Lincoln State Hospital ; Table III. Norfolk State Hospital ; Table IV, Feeble-Minded Institution ; Table V, combined report of the action of the Board as it pertains to all of the institutions. This combined report shows in detail the number of patients examined, the number ordered sterilized, those whose discharge was author - ized without sterilization, and those in which action was deferred. Section 1 of the law governing this board reads as follows : "Sterilization of feeble-minded or insane inmates of state insti - tutions. Hereafter no feeble-minded or insane inmate, physically capable of bearing or begetting offspring, shall be paroled or discharged from the institution for the feeble-minded, or the hospital for the insane, nor paroled from the penitentiary, reforma - tory, industrial home, industrial schools or other such state insti - tutions, except as hereinafter provided, or by order of a court of competent jurisdiction." All patients examined were from the three hospitals for the insane and the institution for feeble-minded. The Board has adopted and followed a conservative policy in dealng with applicants for sterilization. No controversies have </seg>
            <seg id="p063">64 been invited nor entered into, prejudices in most cases have been overcome and religious scruples have always been respected. No patients have been sterilized without full consent of the relatives and the consent of the patient himself. Authority to sterilize has not been given in any case until after careful consideration of the personal and family history of the patient and the Board con - vinced that the patient was capable of bearing or begetting offsprings and that the offsprings "would inherit a tendency to feeble-mindedness, insanity, or degeneracy, and that such children would probably become a social menace an that procreation by such inmate would be harmful to society." In every case operated upon, recovery was prompt and complete. Respectfully submitted. G. E. CHARLTON J. II. MATHAI, S. J. STEWART, June 30. 1923 \V. S. FAST, Chairman, I). G. GRIFFITHS, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p064">65 HASTINGS STATE HOSPITAL, INGLESIDE NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending June 30, 1923 TABLE I M. F. T. M. F. T. Number examined 42 30 72 Authority given for steril - ization before parole or dis - charge Authority given to parole or discharge without steril - ization Action deferred Total Sterilized according to law 7 5 12 LINCOLN STATE HOSPITAL, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners _'n 15 35 35 17 5 12 8 42 30 72 42 M 72 :ec :ives or ie Biennium TABLE II ing ine •i 1 M. F: T. . M. F. T. Number examined Authority given for steril- ization before parole or dis- charge Authority given to parole or discharge without steril- ization Action deferred 28 28 56 14 4 18 28 28 10 1&lt;&gt; 26 4 8 12 Total 28 56 28 28 56 Sterilized according to law ... 8 3 11 NORFOLK STATE Hi OSPITAL, NORFOLK I, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Unde of Defectives for t r the Observation of th&lt; be Biennium Ending J TABLE HI i Board of Examiners une 30, 1923 M. F. T. M. F. T. Number examined Authority given for steril- ization before parole or dis- charge Authority given to parole or discharge without steril- ization Action deferred 21 14 35 11 7 18 14 35 ') I 6 1 15 2 Total 21 21 14 35 Sterilized according to law .... ... </seg>
            <seg id="p065">66 FEEBLE-MINDED INSTITUTION, BEATRICE, NEBRASKA Table of Patients Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Examiners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. M. F. T. Number examined Authority given for steril- ization before parole or dis- charge Authority given to parole or discharge without steril- ization Action deferred 24 26 SO 22 24 46 24 26 50 1 1 1 1 2 2 Total 24 26 50 .... Sterilized according to law 15 COMBINED TABLES OF PATIENTS FROM HA; PITAL, LINCOLN STATE HOSPITAL, N( HOSPITAL, AND THE FEEBLE-MINDED I JTINGS STATE HOS- &gt;RFOLK STATE NSTITUTION, Coming Under the Observation of the Board of Exai niners of Defectives for the Biennium Ending June 30, 1 m TABLE V M. F. T. M. F. T. Number examined Authority given for steril- ization before parole or dis- charge Authority given to parole or discharge without steril- ization Action deferred US &lt;AS 213 67 50 117 115 98 213 37 11 35 13 72 24 Total 115 115 98 213 Sterilized according to law .... — 26 18 </seg> 
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>