<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Nebraska State Hospital for Crippled, Ruptured and Deformed Children LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30th, 1906 TO HON. J. H. MICKEY GOVERNOR AND THE HONORABLE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">EThe Nebraska State pital for Crippled, Ruptured and Deformed Children LINCOLN, NEBRASKA FOR PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30th, 1906 TO HON. J. H. MICKEY GOVERSOR AND THE HONORABLE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. Hon. A. Galusha Secretary of State rris Brown Attorney General Peter Mortensen Treasurer SURGICAL STAFF. John Prentiss Lord, M. D Orthopedic Surgeon and Superint'd II. Winnett Orr, M. D. ■ Anna E. Hardwick Luella Stahl Edith Mullen Miss Bessie Bixb; Miss Elizabeth Rogers Hon. H. M. Eaton Land Commissioner, Chairman </seg>
            <seg id="p003">PLED, RUPTURED AN D DEFORMED. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, NOV. 30, 1906. To the Honorable John H. Mickey, governor, and to the Honor - able Board of Public Lands and Buildings: I Gentlemen — In compliance with the statutes, I herewith sub - it to you the first biennial report. Very respectfully, J. P. LORD, Superintendent and Orth- opedic Surgeon. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I'll' da Hospital for the Crippled. Ruptured and De torm a part of one of the buildings at the Home for the Friendless; a building formerly known as the Hoy's Dor initory, $10,000 having been appropriated by the last legislature an orthopedic hospital there. This was rendered habitable, and suitable for a hospital by alterations and repairs. A frame addition. thr&gt; &gt;f which ore glass, was added on the south to furnish needed air, and for debilitated patierr ve additions, alterations and repairs were made to both the steam heating and plumbing. An operating room was established in the northeast corner of the basement with tile floor and floor drain. Only the n sary equipment was provided in this room as well as other* copied by us. An X-ray apparatus was installed because distortions and dis - eases of the bones and joints cannot be treated with full infor - mation without its i. The accommodations afforded by this building were exhai. lie time from fifteen to twenty patients had been admittet and inasmuch as we had for most of the time the past year thirt.% &gt;atieuts or more the building has proven sadly inadequate t&lt; he evidently constant demand for this work. Many times during the present year the hospital wards wert make it necessary to put two patients into one bed nil there were too many beds in the wards This over crowd ng I ily objectionable in cold weather, when the tniosphere becomes very bad. We have had to use an insidt without windows for fifteen to twenty patients his rendered the ward unwholesome and unsanitary. That we hail to occupy basement rooms for these children is alsc reproach to our state. Better housing of both patients and employes is much needed. !mpi nitary conveniences, better light, air and heat should be provided. The lack of an elevator has also rendered it nec - essary for our nurses (all women) to carry our path </seg>
            <seg id="p005">417 whom are heavy, from one floor to another. We are greatly in need of a gymnasium supplied with special devices and apparatus bo that all our children, irrespective of their condition, may have systematic exercise. t Sufficient funds should be provided to employ teachers for the ckward and bedridden children. This latter work has been ne so far by charitably disposed women of Lincoln. A manual training or industrial department should also be stablished, where knowledge of the use of tools, typesetting, ay modeling, wood carving, designing, drawing, basket weav - ng, sewing, etc., may be taught. We have many bright chil - ren capable of acquirii ■ ■! general education, who could nijrht occupations suitable to their physical defects. The tate has a responsibility beyond attention to the physical de - ects of these children. Unless provision is made by the State for making these children self sustaining, our institution will be jliged to recommit some of them to the poorhouses from whence ley came, or to homes, which are, perhaps, worse. Our institu - on has now six or eight children, who are incurable, and all ut one capable of receiving a good education, but these will [ways be dependent unless provided with suitable occupations. 'he State has only begun its responsibility, therefore, when it &gt;as finished the surgical and mechanical treatment of deformity nd disability. It is necessary that more ground be acquired. The present play round is very inadequate. There should be at least an acre r two for garden purposes both for reasons of economy, and for le good of the children who need the work, recreation and edu - ation incident to its care. Space should be had also for _ zed barn and barn-yard. Cows should be kept, that fresh whole - ome milk and cream may be provided infants and children, iany of whom are diseased, puny and debilitated ; and the care t their tuberculosis or rickets may depend upon proper feed - iji. There should be plenty of fruit trees, grapes, berries, etc., nd the place made spacious, attractive and home-like, instead : simply a "Corral for cripples." All children, rich or poor, should be taught to work. The State should provide useful developmental employment for the chil - dren over whom it has assumed control. For apparent reasons, therefore, health, hygiene, morals, etc.. adequate housing, am- 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">418 includi a workshop and school shook be provided in order that the function of the State may be full and adequately performed. This must be done, not only b dk. bat enabling then ad alone in lid morally and 1h • pportunity r happiness. TAGIOl'S DISEASES. Tli hniiiry one of which was fatal: o of diphtheria. The scarlet fever epid loyment of additional trained nurses, at an which depl&lt; iry. I In tagious disease becomes n jmmii and opportunities fur ration rendei I difficult, or well nigh impossible. I The muni greater than expected r, and &amp; &lt;\y with thai of other population. With a us and facilities and remo the lik • ppropriation for ik would be doubled and perhaps trebled living another bienninm. To maintain this most worthy and creditable nary in - stitution, to 'he entire remaindei of the block md surrounding our institution should b( room for additional buildings, garden, or - char' ard and barnyard. I building, modern and fire pi-. pted t&lt; il use should !&gt;• 1 on th mds. It shoulc ator, li&lt;rht sunny wards, and verandas, which ma\ 'ed and made available for out door treat From twenty to thirty per cent of our eases are tubercular or rachitic and absolutely require this form of treatment. ■h a building would cost at least 060,000.00 furnished, am would accommodate about seventy-fire patients. Modern hos pitals for aduli- boot $1,000.00 per patient The addi tional ground n led will cost approximately $10,000.00. For the ;&gt;ital in conjunction </seg>
            <seg id="p007">419 with t lit- Home for the Friendlea thirty thout dollars for t lie bieanimn maintenane mated, or ■ total ap - propriation of $90,000.00 for ground, buildings and upkeep and incidentals. Detention wards fur new arrivals are an absolute □ eially in a children's hospital if proper precaation aken against contagious d The institution should provided with ■ pr&lt; disinfection appar lothing and bedding, [nereased furnishii &lt;&gt; meet the demands incideni to the growth of tin- institotion Vmple bedding is also needed of a quality and maintained in sanitary condition. A hospitiil should have heat and hot water, available at any and all times during the year. This &gt;f a chil - dren's hospital in which operation- rmed upon I of tender aye with poor vitality. Inasmuch as at least one-third of the children received reatmeni are suffering from tuberculosis or rickets or i y in which nutrition is ai fault, proper provision should be uide whereby, such My. can tie fed upon fresh milk both of which as well as vegetal ild be prodi pon the premises. The care of cows, chickens, and well garden would furnish proper mpation ami I habits of industry. These thing! for the roper physical education and moral developmentof the chil - ren deprived of home influences, many of whom require a resi - eiice iii the hospital of from one to fiv&lt; rBPORT OF THE NEBRASKA STATE HOSPITAL FOR THE CRIP - PLED. RUPTURED AND DEFORMED. Part II. REPORT OF THE ASSISTANT SUPERINTENDENT. The conduct of the internal affairs of the Nebraska Hospital lor the Crippled. Ruptured and Deformed for the 14 months ending November .'{(I. 1906 can .&lt;&gt;d by i to the tables which are made a part of this report. t Table No. 1 shows in the way s 1 by the chairman of e Board of Public Lands and Buildings a summary of both e clinical and financial reports. Even from these few figures will be seen that a much larger number of patients than was </seg>
            <seg id="p008">420 expected came to the hospital during the period for exam- ination and treatment. On the financial side the figures show what a large amount of our appropriation we were obliged to spend to alter and equip the building at the Home for the Friend- lew for hospital purposes. Almost exactly one-half of our $10,000 wu devoted to this purpose and on the remainder an average of twenty-three patients and five employes were cared for in the institution for the entire period. In addition, of course, the salaries of the superintendent and assistant have been paid. TABLE NO. 1. STATISTICAL FORM FOR STATE INSTITUTIONS r PARED IN ACCORDANCE WITH A RESOLUTION OF THE NATIONAL CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND COR - RECTION. ADOPTED MAY 15, 1906. rOF INSTITUTION— NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE CRIPPLED, RUPTURED AND DEFORMED. OCTOBER 1, 1905, TO NOVEMBER 30, 1906. Male. Female. Total. Number of inmates present at beginning of period _ none none none Number received during the period 53 53 106 Number discharged or died during per. 74 Number at end of period 15 17 32 Daily average attendance during period... 23 Average number of officers and employes 5 5 EXPENDITURES. Current Expenses — 1. Salaries and wa^'s | 84.91 lothing none 3. Subsistence 307.50 4. Ordinary repairs none 5. Office, domestic, outdoor, drugs 894.99 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p009">421 Extraordinary Expenses — 1. New buildings, land, etc. none 2. Permanent equipment and impts. to bldgs _ $4,957.55 Total Grand total $10,844.96 EXECUTIVE HEAD. 5)r. .1. P. Lord . )r. H. W. Orr Superintendent Assistant Soon after the beginning of the work at the hospital and be ore a sufficient number of patients were received to use our available space the Board of Lands and Buildings authorize&lt; he officers of the institution to receive patients for treatmen who were able to pay at the rate of $7 per week. This was pro - ided for in the law creating the hospital when by so doing the riterests of those who were strictly wards of the State woul&lt; lot be jeopardized. Under this provision whenever vacancies xisted pay patients were received. By other means, such as tie x-ray and sterilizing apparatus, money was occasionally earnec vhich together with that from the pay patients was paid month y into the office of the state treasurer. Table No. 2 shows the mounts received and paid to the state treasurer in this way At this institution no cash fund has been kept, every dollar, ex ept the personal funds of our patients and a few gifts by pri ate charity such as gifts for the piano and our school teacher lave been turned into the state treasurer and only paid ou pon vouchers approved by the state board as provided by law TABLE NO. 2. Money received from pay patients, for operating and x-ray rooms fees, etc., and paid to state treasurer. 1905. July 1 35.00 December 31 $104.50 August 1 81.00 September 1 41.00 1906. October 1 65.00 February 1 55.00 March 1 126.00 November 22 55.00 April 1 57.00 $863.00 May 1 _ 149.00 June 1 95.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">422 TABLE NO. 3. Table No. 3 shows in detail how the entire amount of money .ended, both of the original $10,000 and the mpple- d during the periH. Bassett. June 47.15 Bassett. Juim- ... 47.15 ■alary nurse ■alary n printing 27.00 inn Bros 27.00 printing Bixby, Beam 145.00 14 salary nurse salary none salary maid salary Blunt. Maud Blunt. Maud 7.-..IU salary maid Brown, Sara 37.50 37.50 salary Electrical Equip. Co. 7.25 Electrical Equip. Co. 7.25 wiring door bell, lights, etc. wiring door bell, lights, etc. Wold A: Co. 7.98 rug rug Hardwick. Ami;; Hardwick. Anna '•)■'&lt; . salary head nurse hospital tupp undertaker salary head nurse Harley Drag Oo. 406.97 Harley I)n; 406.97 hospital supplies Heaton 14.00 '..11 14.00 undertaker Hum.- for the Friend Hum.- for the Friendless 301 subsistence-pay patients subsistence-pay patients salary maid salary superintendent traveling expenses window shades, etc. salary nurse K.-nyon. Mrs. Helen 3.87 von. Mrs. Helen 3.87 salary maid Lord. Dr. J. 1'. 1500.00 I. Dr. ,1 1'. 1500.00 salary superintendent Lord. Dr. J. P. 14.50 I. Dr. J 1*. . 14.50 traveling expenses Miller &amp; Paine 37.51 Miller &amp; Pa m.- 37.51 window shades, etc. Mullen, Edith 165.00 Mullen, Edith 165.00 ki Sec Co. 75.00 ,ska Tel O N».4."&gt; salary nurse 75.00 wiring remodeled bldg. r wiring remodeled bldg. telephone salary asst. supt. ska Tel. Co. telephone Orr, Dr. H. W. 1066.06 Orr, Dr. H. W. 1066.06 Dr. 11 \V 40.00 'I'l i: &lt;"o. 1148.96 salary asst. supt. Orr. Dr. II. W 40.00 stamps stamps Penfokl &amp; Co. 1148.96 operating room furniture peratinfr room furniture and instruments and instruments Perkins &amp; Perkins 4.25 IVrkins &amp; Perkin- 4.25 printing printing . L. W. Poa U W. !M(0.88 plumbing plumbing Princen. Dreakie 103.06 Princen. Dreakie 103.06 or's Pharniii. ■&gt; 311.27 salary maid salary maid t's Pharmac 511.27 hospital supplies hospital supp fumigating salary nurse hair ratting salary n Rhode, Il-alth Officer 4.55 fumigating Nellie 30.00 30.00 salary nurse Richards 2.00 Richards 2.00 hair ratting 114.00 114.00 salary nurse E&amp; Guenzel Co. 450.22 Anna "&gt;2.50 ihl. Mrs. Luella 262.50 Iff* &amp; Guenzel Co. 450.22 hospital furniture hospital furniture salary maid salary nurse salary nurse Anna 52.50 salary maid !d. Mrs. Luella 262.50 salary nurse Sward. E 40.00 lid, Ki]-:. 40.00 Ada 98.00 salary nurse Swartz. Ada 98.00 salary nurse </seg>
            <seg id="p011">423 Thompson, Ethel 11.10 salary maid Tyler &amp; Soa 100.00 architect remodeling building Vanderveer, O. W. 2139.75 $10844.95 Total expended for the period ending November 30, 1906. Many interesting facts arc developed by a careful study o able No. 4 in which an effort is made to supply complete in ormation regarding every patient received at the hospital dur ng the period. The patients are classified according to diagnosis nd each patient is entered in the table by his case numb. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">424 i I 3 5 s — ■- — I I - 1 I m I a I a I c — a &amp; X I I 5 Appendicitis 14 73 ' ♦ • X X x X X X . Arthritis deformans Bow legs Bullet wound Burn Cleft palate ■ • X X X x X .. .. X X X X 21 105 4 10 12 15 ..I I I X X ■ X . , X X I X X X X z •• X .. X X X X ... X| X X X I X X X X X X X X X X X X Epilepsy Foreign body in hand . . . •■ X X + X I t X X X X x X X X 1 X •s •• 86 x| X x X X I x X .. X .... Fracture compound Fracture, radius &amp; ulna. Fracture, un united Hernia femoral Hernia, unguinal ■ • X X X X .. .... X X • • X X X X X X t t I X ... ... ... X X X X X X X X .... 1 101 X X .... .- X X X t * X X Hernia, umbilical Hare lip X X X * .. .... .... .. ♦i . .... ■ » Hip, congenital disloca- tion of I X] X X X X X X I X ■ • X tip. congenital disloca- tion, suspected ip, fracture suspected.. M M X X X t * X X X .... X ■• ... .... X * .. x' ...I .... Icbth vosis Knock knee X • * . X X X • ■ 4 1 X X X X X X X X X 1 Leukaemia, mvelogenous Lymphadenitis . X X X X X * •• ■• .... X X X X X X X X X X X 1 .. tarasmus iscellaneous X X •• V X x X ••I X .. ••« •• X 31 X X - x X X X X X X . . . * </seg>
            <seg id="p013">lued. ,E Ni i. 4 i s 1 •I ■ I S L. V D 1 I c I ! 1 i | 2 I _ a 1* I | ! 5 3 s D s 5 Miscellaneous 51 tilt X X X X X X x X X ... ... .... I ... x .... My x oedema Paralysis, infantile X X X •• ... X •• '» x : ... X .... 1 9 17 37 X X X X X X 8 9 13 X x x x ■an X X .. t -■ X x X X ... x X X X X X X X X X X X X t X X + ... - X X * ti7 76 77 *K 91 19 til 87 102 6 20 82 97 23 7 23 35 36 21 5 22 49 74 urn ll 13 29 X X X X ... ■• ... X X X X X X X ... X ... X X X X • X X 4 4 X X X X " ... .. .. ... 'aralysis, spastic X X X X X X X X X X X ... - X X X .... • • 309 31 1 196 107 13 4 X .. •• ... .... X X X X .... X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X ■ ■ X 'aralysis, spina bifida.. 'aralysis. tuberculous. . X 1 1 1 X X X X X X X X •• X X X X X x! X X . IS X X X * .... . . * 'eriostitis 'hiraosis tickets x * .. v X .. • • • • X X • .... ■ ■. .. .... » • * .... * • » icarlet fever pine,. lateral curvature. .... # • * ■♦ ♦ X X X X X X X X io X X X •■ . X X X 'uberculosis, ankle 'uberculosis, hip • X X x X X 2 1 X x X X X "h i X X x x X X </seg>
            <seg id="p014">•Counted elsewd- treatment. It will by this table thai &lt;&gt;f the 106 patienti received iiui t&gt;4 under 14. of the 75 re - in patients at the hospital ."&gt;1 win- under the age of 14 ■nd of i latientfl operated upon '!i' were under 14 yean of aye. I'pon these .VI patients I total of 7*i operations has beet with only one fatality during the period apparently the i of the operative procedure. A total of .'{II patienti have been discharged from the insti - tution as cured during 1 lie period, of whom 15 were children un - der the age of 14 Thirty-two remain under treatment at the present time. tAs was expected a large number of our earlier patients were Jin Laneai uty. People have some hesitation about en jsting their children to a hospital but when the hospital is w with no results to show it is a natural thing to suppose that •. 4.- ■ I X t_ rr I | - I 1 - M ;. Tuberculosis, hip X X t x . 4 1 I 4 x ... * * » Tuberculosis, humerus. 1 1 !■■: Knee 41 20 an (Pulmonary Tibia.. I X X x 1i # .. X I .. X X X i ' 1 1 Totals X • •• - 7-&gt; :il </seg>
            <seg id="p015">427 ■atients from the outside will be slow in coming in. In Lancas er county as soon as the work of the hospital began to be mown there were many applicants for examination and treat dent. Table No. 5 illustrates this very forcibly; of the fifty pa ients numbered between 25 and 75, thirty were from Lancaster •ounty. The Urge number of other counties represented, how •ver. leads us to believe that as our cured patients become ributed through the state there will be the same increase in onfidence in our work that has been manifested in Lane; • lunty where our results could be seen and where naturally the lospital lias been better advert i- ('OINTIES FROM WHICH PATIENTS WERE ADMITTED. Physicians who have visited us from other cities in the state been uniformly commendatory in speaking of the work [ the institution and the visits of physicians to the hospita frequently been followed within a week or two by an ap - &gt;lication for the admission of a patient from the district to which our visiting physician belonged. The members of the ature of 190") have also taken an interest in the welfare Adams, patient No. 25. Buffalo. 90. 19 61 74 77 82. (lay, 3. Coif; Carter, 12 15 102 II Dawsoii. 1!&gt;. 1 )o&lt;l&lt;re. !I4. las, 2 13 18 76 78 80 84 FrankLiu. SO. 4."). ir.-.'lt'.v, 67. lall. 39 42. Holt. KM. Jefferson. 46 101. Keitli Lane;, s 7 14 16 27 28 31 32 33 34 35 36 38 40 44 K4 - 70 72 73 75 96 97 98 108. Lincoln, lnti. tfenfck, 104. Xance. 71. .Wmahn. 10. Otoe, 1 51. Pawnee, 41 I Richardson, - Saline, 79. Saunders, 17 Sherman. 21 22. urd, 43- Shoridan. \, 24. Thay.'p. 62. Wiishiriirton. Wheeler, 29. York. 6 89 91. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">428 of our institution and several of them have recommended patients who have received treatment at the hospital. It may be unnecessary to supplement the report of the super intendent in this regard but the assistant superintendent canno refrain from urging upon the legislative body and its officers the necessity for a more liberal policy in dealing with this work The care of the crippled children calls for a proportionatel larger amount than some other departments of our state wor but we hope it will be seen from this report that the result justify the extra demands made. The patients received and th work done compare very favorably with what has been accom plished in any other similar institution and is certainly bette than what could be done in a general hospital or without th peculiar resources and equipment essential for definite orthopedi and surgical work. Our nurses by reason of peculiar trainin bave also a peculiar interest in the care of these children an&lt; the results accomplished would have been absolutely impossibl without the intelligent and faithful co-operation of our hea( nurse and her associates. Part III. REPORT OF THE HEAD NURSE From the standpoint of the head nurse, the first period o ur work in a new institution with more patients than were xpected and inadequate accommodations has been accompanie&lt; »y many difficulties. Everything considered, however, what ha &gt;een accomplished by the other nurses and myself has been its wn reward for our labors. Our patients themselves have in gen ral co-operated in every way to contribute to the welfare o le institution and all our nurses, both those who were with s" temporarily and those who have connected themselves per manently with the institution, have been untiringly faithful in the discharge of their duties. Not the least of the factors which have contributed to our pro gress thus far and to the success of our work up to the presen time has been the interest taken in us by many residents o Lincoln and others who have contributed in one way or another to our children and to the hospital. The list which follows is submitted because any report of our work would be incomplete without some acknowledgment having been made of the gifts </seg>
            <seg id="p017">429 that have been made in various ways by the friends whose names are mentioned. 1905. Dec. 17, Dr. Lord ... Hooks, irames. Dec. 2A. .Mrs. I. If. Raymond Potted plant. Dec. 24, Mrs. F. M. Hall Toys, candy, oranges. Dec. 24, Dr. Lord for children, hdkfs. for nurses. Dec. 24. Mrs. S. M Molio-k Toys, dolls, work basket, books. Dec. 24, Dr. Orr ..Games, books, toys. Dec. 24, Mrs. Eninia .Johnston Toys (donated to home for Christmas.) Dec. 25, Rev. Benj. Fitz Christmas tree and decorations. DONATIONS 1906. Jan. 20, Mrs. E. Johnston Four roses. Jan. 27, Mrs. Kimball Doll for Carrie Bacon. Jan. 29, Mrs. I. M. Raymond, Lincoln hotel .Fruit for children. Feb. 2, Dr. Orr Hired band to play one-half hour Feb. 14, Mrs. E. Johnston Flowers. Feb. 21, Mr. and Mrs. Elmer Sides .Flowers, 4 night shirts. Feb. 23, Miss Pauline Becker, 3424 R St Cake and Jelly. reb. 23, Mrs. K. Shankland, 1130 Huff St Cake and Jelly, eb. 23. Mrs. A. Rynier, 2750 1 Si Scrap book and pictures. Feb. 23, Mrs. L. Marsh Flowers. Mch. 4, Mrs. Capron Clothes. Mch. 6, Mrs. Lienberger Clothes. Mch. 9, Mrs. Johnston Flowers. Mch. 13, Schieffelin &amp; Co. 4bt Uriform, 1 Salusol New York Mch. 17, Anna W. Horton, S- S. class Flowers, books, mags Mch. 2:5 Mrs. P. X. Francis Magazines. Mch. 23, Mrs I. M. Raymond Books and pictures. Mch. 23, Miss Tremain books and pict Apr. 2, Mrs. Kauffman Bird and cage. Apr. 4, Mrs. Rolofsmi, Xo. 14th St. 3 doz. eggs. Apr. 11. Mrs. &lt;;. A Wilson. 1742 South St., Slippers and books. Apr. 11 Miss Daisy Mastcrman, 1340 Pine St Books. .Spr. 14, Mrs. Raymond Easter lilies. Apr. 14, C. H. Prey l; Apr. 14, Friend from Lincoln hotel Dolls, candy, eggs. Feb. 14, Mrs. H. \V. Orr Fancy E Apr. 14, Mrs. R. Egen, Omaha Easter eggs. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">430 Apr. 14. Mrs W Bananas Apr. 14. Mil K.iM. r cards. Apr. 15, Mil Barter .Npr. 15, Miss ( Candy and I Easter lily. Apr. 15, W( Easter lily Apr. lti. Mi Easter" lily Apr I'.- ll K 4 chairs llili li-hiiir. magazines Rowers 1 Iti Glyco-ThymoliDf! 4. Mrs. shanklaml Canned fruit, popcorn. Flowers 24. Mrs. Baird K nd fruit .May (I. Mrs B aha ( &gt;r,. In ( andy and li PI ml Fruit Clothes Dr. Mary A Quincy, Ashland Flowers. 11, Mrs -144 Washington Dolls and candj 11, Mrs Dolls and candy 12. Henry Mayer Lawn swing, hobby 1 11. Mi-- Bai Mrs M. Pn Candy and papers Candy and papers Selleck Bible scroll and scrap book Dr. Mary A. Quiney, Ashland VI May in. Mrs Pomerine and niasrazines May 19, Repaired children's wa| June 2. Mi adelman. Plattsmouth Br June 9. Mr :i Flowers .lun. Church Aid - Clothes June 20. Miss Stein! Papers June 20, Mrs Bixby Clothes. June 21. Mrs Kimball Braces J t me 23, Two hoys. Valparaiso Basket cherries June 23. Mrs. Weil Orantres t'une 28. Mr. Bixbj Box cherries June 28. Mr and Mrs. Perry Fh </seg>
            <seg id="p019">431 June 30, Mrs. Weil (Jewish ham ap July 4. Dr. Orr's S. S. claaa Tally ho to country dull for fireworks. July •"). Mi- Spencer, Falls City Flowers July ... Miss II. Capron Plo .inly 5, Mrs. DePrance Cap and dn July 16, Miss Baird Candy. July 30, Mrs. Funkhouser, Lindell hotel Clol Aug. Mrs. Thorp, l'.i'l 1) St. 4 -&gt;lly Aug. 1* : . Mrs B. K. iha 4 :elly Aug. I*'. Mrs. Shankland Flowers and popcorn Aug. lti. Mrs I). GouM, Fork 1 bbl. ap It;. Mrs. Neil, Waterloo I Aug. lti. Dr. Orr 1 Aug. lti. Mr. Bixby &lt; Aug. 19, Mrs. Witt 19, Mrs. Putney Aug. 19, Mrs. Dunkle Flo \'K Mrs. Brown I Mrs. Young Fruit Mrs Kjcll.lin Fruit and bird 8, M at Anna Smith lti. Mrs. Powell . F1-' Sept '2-1 Mrs. Otterstein - prs crui :&gt;&lt;-t. 28, .Miss Anna Robertson Floi Mrs. Northrup Oct. I'M. Mr. Mullen bbl. ap Oct. 29, Mrs. (lark 2 lbs 29, Klliot school I 'oil )i Nov. 1. Mrs. Selleck Doll, trunk, carr Nov. 2, Mrs. Powell Flowers. Nov. ."&gt;. Mrs. Lord Clothing. Nov. .-&gt;. Dr. Lord Ap] Nov. 6, Mt Gift to piano fund. Nov. ti. Mrs. Harwood Oifl to piano fund. Nov. 9, Mi 14:i:* O St piano fond, a|)ples. popcorn. Xo\. 9, Mrs. Weisman two comforts. \'ov. lti. Mrs. Wesse] and Mrs Weil Clothe* and jelly. Nov. lti. A friend 1 Jb car.dy. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">432 I^ANO COMMISSIONER S IkKtv)!*! Nov. 16, Mrs. Ensign Eggs for Stephen. Nov. 19, Mrs. Weeks, 801 N. 16th Clothes, Youth's Companion. Nov. 19, Geo. Bonnell, 1245 Q St. Pictures. Nov. 19 Mrs. Trow, 231 No. 13th Jelly. Nov. 19, Mrs. French Crib and mattress. Nov. 19, Mr. J. Blunt, Burehard ... 3 bbl. apples. 1!*. A friend 1 comfort. Nov. 19, Myrtle Vinton Theater Co. Box of clothes, breakfast foods. Nov. 19, Mrs. O'Mahnev 3 glasses jelly. Nov. 20, Mr. Rogers Blackboard paint. rov. 20, Miss Rogers Material to make baskets and weekly instruction. Nov. 20, City school board Loaned school books. Nov. 21, Mrs. Norris Brown 21, Mrs. W. B. Wilson 21, Mrs. Plummer Under clothes. Dolls for Christmas. Dolls for Christmas. 21, Mrs. Milton Scott 21. Mrs. I. C. Jones 21, Mrs. G. R. Barber Dolls for Christmas. Dolls for Christmas. Dolls for Christmas. Nov. 21, Dr. Green, East Lincoln Flowers. Nov. 22, Miss Polleys Candy and bananas. N'ov. 22. Miss Huntsinger Books. Nov. 22, Miss Polley* $2.50 school fund, $2.50 piano. Nov. 24, Mrs. Cook Apples. N'ov. 24, Mrs. Stanley Bananas. 25. Junior League M. E. C Surprise package. Nov. 25, Mr. Adams, Fairbury . 2 chickens. 29, Home Mission E. M. C. Potatoes, pies, 1 doz. cans fruit, 2 cakes. 3-4 bu. apples. Nov. 29. Mrs. Hart, Mrs. Geo. Kline Games. Nov. 29. Mrs. Egart Popcorn in bags. Nov. 29, Mrs. Tipton Popcorn in bags. Xov. 29. Mrs. Beans Popcorn in bags. Nov. 29, Cong, church 5 cans fruit, 5 jelly. Nov. 29, Star 2 cases emulsion, 1 crate eggs, 1 crate oranges, 1 crate bananas, books, and funny papers Nov. 29, Mrs. S. H. Burnham ... 3 loaf cakes. Nov. 29, State Supt. McBrien 30 school books. Nov. 29, Mrs. Trover can fruit. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">433 Not. 29, Mrs. Swan Basket apples. rl, Mrs. Ben Appel _2 baskets grapes, oranges, bananas, apples. Nov. 29, Cook If. E. church 5 dolls, handkerchiefs, games, cloth, can fruit. Nov. L'!», .Miss Tipton 2 loaves bread, 2 jelly. Nov. 29, Mrs. Norris Brown 1 quart cranber Nov. 29, .Miss Daisy Dial apples. Nov. 29, GriswoM 8« Roll ol reed for basket work. Nov. L'!t, Mrs. S. E. Campbell 3 jars, mincemeat, 1 jelly. Nov. 2'.K Mrs. Everetta Fin Nov. l'!». (Unknown) Box l&gt;y expresi Can fruit peaches, eandy, cornstarch, :5 cans plus butter, eoo GIFTS FOR PIANO FIND. Dr. Orr Mrs. Stahl Hardwick 1.00 Mullen Mrs. Stahl 1.00 Bixby Mullen 1.00 Hardwick 1.00 Bixby 1.00 Friend Miss Roger* 1.00 Paul Bloedel 2.00 Edith Gealy 1.00 Children - .98 Hardwick .. .50 Eliethe Soucey .ti") Leinberger Prineen Jfrs. Stahl Blunt Friends 1.75 Gould . 1.00 Mrs. Wilson . 1.00 Henry Egen Mullen Miss Carlson Appel . 1.00 Mr. Pntnej Friend 1.00 n 1.00 Alice (Jould .70 Mrs. Stahl . .50 '"apron 1.00 ■ O'Brien . .75 Hardwick Especial acknowledgment for entertainm en for the benefit of the children and for special instruction of one or more of the children is due to Miss Irene I'olleys. Mrs. H. B. Miles. Mrs. M. Weil. Mrs. Westell, Mrs. 1. M. Raymond, Mrs. F. M. H I tolflOO .Mr. 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">434 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT ■ Miss Anna Rogers, Miss Lucile Brown, Miss June Brown, Beth Bonnell, Miss Tessie Tipton Mr. C. E. Prevey. Respectfully submitted, ANNA E. HARD WICK. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>