<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seed Preparation and Planting Methods for Spring Small Grains</title>
               <date value="1932-07">1932-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 273 July, 1932 Seed Preparation and Planting Methods for Spring Small Grains T. A. KIESSELBACH AND W. E. LYNESS THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Buna, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Summary J 3 Comparative Yields of Spring and Fall-sown Crops'. 5 Farming-mill Tests 6 Seed Treatment for Smut 1 Oat smut - 1 Barley smut. 12 Manner of Planting 14 Eate of Planting.-.. 15 Time of Planting 16 Time of Harvesting 20 SUMMARY The results reported m this bulletin were obtained on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln. In a 24-year test of various farming-mill grades of Kherson oats, the heaviest one-fourth of the seed, as separated by a gravity wind-blast fanning mill, yielded only 0.2 bushel, or 0.4 per cent more than un - graded seed, while the lightest one-fourth produced 1.9 per cent less. During a 12-year period the largest seed, as separated from the Kherson variety by means of a screen fanning mill, yielded 2.5 per cent less than the ungraded seed, and the smallest seed yielded 3.C per cent less. Results obtained from grading a pure-line selection were similar to those with the original Kherson variety. The chief benefits from the fanning mill under Nebraska conditions are the removal of trash, weed seeds, and smut balls m wheat or barley infected with covered smut. Both formalin and Ceresan disinfection of smutted seed oate gave effective control of smut. In three years' crops from untreated seed, 7 4 per cent of the heads were smutty, while four different formalin treatments averaged 0.2 per cent and Ceresan averaged 0.6 per cent. With corresponding seed treated with Corona Blue Dust, 2.1 per Icent of the heads were smutty, while with seed treated with copper carbon - ate (20 per cent) the percentage of smutted heads was 2.9. It appears that formalin may be used successfully for smut con - trol m oats m various degrees of dilution. The most important | con - sideration m its use is that a pint of f ull-strength formalin (40 per centlolution of formaldehyde m water) be applied to approximately 50 bushels of seed. There was no evidence of stimulative effect .from any of the treat - • merits, although all of them increased the grain yield through reduc - tion of the amount of smut. Neither formalin nor Ceresan had a significant effect on loose I smut of barley whereaV standard applications of both of these gave almost perfert contebf oT covered smut. The hot-water treatment for loose smut is recommended only for removing the disease from a small seed supply which may be increased for future use. Broadcast oats yielded 2.3 per cent less than drilled oats during a 12-year period. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 a large seeded variety Swedis* Tcj^L^ ® - CO o?l spondln S elda for 43.6, 43.2, and 43^ b^hS pe r afre ' * 369 * 4 °' 9 ' 42 ' 2 ' 42 " 9 ' of 33.9, 36.6 37.1, 3* I tnd 36 A^JS* *%*■ the "active yields results that th£e may be r^W Jm?!?' ? "evident from these very materiaU^^ffertinl resStf OnthX MF** I ate witto « t expected to decrease weltoSiri tr?„ P =£?," Planting rates may be the amount of rf&amp;HKu * St * te ' becaUSe of reduction in opf&amp;SeVptnW stadie d.with respect to the ,„ Por . th . e respective planting dates of March 19 March 11 a«^i qq' Md £ pnl 21 ' the relative of spring wheat were 107 uS 93, and 65 per cent; oats 104 100 91 «ri »k ™» - * *_. , ' 90, 100, 103, and 94 per cent.' ' ' Per Cent; and barley Kherson oats harvested when mature and 2 4 and r A_n_ \._t mature gave the respective yields of 100 97 92 mH «« ?L rfo ? JSSrfW?? 0^.^h«?before f they'a?e 7 'rip 2 e' SrovL^he S </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods for Spring Small Grains T. A. KIESSELBACH AND W. E. LTTNESS Experiments have been conducted for a number of years on the Experiment Station farm at Lincoln to determine the effect of certain cultural practices upon the production bf oats, barley, and spring wheat. These studies have been con - cerned with grading and treatment of seed, time and mannjer of planting, and time of harvesting. While some of the cul - tural practices were not studied with all three crops, the re - sults are believed to apply generally to all, except where other - wise indicated. It is recognized that results identical with those obtained at Lincoln might not be secured m all parts |of the state because of differences m cropping conditions, but local experience will ordinarily aid m an effective application of these results. COMPARATIVE YIELDS OF SPRING AND FALL-SOWN CROPS Small grain production m Nebraska is practically limited to wheat, oats, barley, and rye. Both spring and fall-sown varieties of wheat and rye may be grown m this state. Oats and barley, on the other hand, are planted only m the spring because of insufficient hardiness of the winter types. In gen - eral, the fall-sown grains are superior m yield, as indicated by the tests reported m Table 1. For purposes of labor dis - tribution, diversification, and rotation, however, the spring grains are extensively grown. Their proportion is larger m the northern and western sections where they are better adapted. For information concerning varieties the reader is referred to Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 253, which summar - izes the varietal tests up to and including the 1930 crop. Table 1. — Comparative grain yields of various crops at the Experiment Station — twelve years, 1920-1981 1 Gratn yIM "•* acre Ctod and variety per . . htwhel As threshed Without holl» _ _ — - — — £-£ Spring grains: Oate, Nebraska 21 32 53 1709 1196 100 Barley, Comfort 48 33 1573 1337 112 Spring wheat, Java 60 17 1001 1001 84 Spring rye 56 18 1019 1019 85 Winter grains: Winter wheat, Nebraska 60 60 36 2189 2189 183 Winter rye, Rosen . 56 35 1948 1948 163 'OaU and barley are regarded as being 80 and 16 per cent hall respectively. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 fanning-mill tests As a result of 24 years' experiments in the use of the fan - ning mill, it may be concluded that its chief value lies in the removal of trash, inert matter, and weed seed. With seed wheat or barley, smut balls may be advantageously removed by fanning in conjunction with seed treatment for this disease. Aside from these considerations, grading the seed does not appear to have significantly increased the yield of grain. Two tests of seed grades based on weight and size of seed have been made with oats during 24- and 12-year periods respectively. In the first of these, the lightest one-fourth and the heaviest one-fourth of the seed, as separated by a wind-blast gravity grader, were planted in comparison with the original ungraded Kherson oats. During the years 1908 to 1930 each grade was taken annually from the crop that was grown the previous year from the corresponding grade, ex - cept that the various seed grades were renewed in 1917 from ordinary seed. This has given opportunity for the occurrence of cumulative effects. In the second test, which began in 1917, the effects of grad - ing within a commercial variety and a pure-line selection have been compared. Ordinary Kherson and Nebraska No. 21, which is a selection from the Kherson, were used. Four grades of each were planted in comparison with the ungraded seed. The grades consisted of the heaviest and the lightest fourths as separated by a wind-blast gravity grader and the largest and the smallest fourths as separated by a screen fanning mill. «-S? y* elds be en determined annually in duplicate one - thirtieth-acre field plats. The planting has been done with a press drill set to sow at the rate of 2y_ bushels per acre. Table 2. — Effect of fanning-mill grading upon the yield per acre and the test weight of Kherson oats — average for 2A years, 1905-1930 1 „ Test weight Yield of grain Grade 2 of grain [ per acre Lbs. P.ct. Bu. P.ct. Original ungraded 29.3 100.0 53.3 100.0 Heaviest one-fourth 29.6 101.0 53.5 100.4 Lightest one-fourth 28.7 98.0 52.3 98.1 'Crop destroyed in 1918 and 1826 and not harvested. "Beginning with ordinary seed in 1908 and 1917. continuous selection by grading was practiced throughout the two periods, 1908-1916 and 1917-1980. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods LIGHT AND HEAVY VS. UNGRADED SEED OATS The yields obtained during 24 years from light and heavy seed, as compared with the original ungraded seed of common Kherson oats, are summarized in Table 2. As an average for the entire period, the heavy seed yielded 0.2 bushel per acre or 0.4 per cent more than ungraded seed. This would be at the rate of only one bushel more for every 250 bushels harvested. The light seed, on the other hand, showed a slight reduction, amounting to 1.9 per cent. The . data indicate that the test weight of the grain harvested was raised one per cent in case of the heavy seed, and reduced two per cent by planting the light seed. COMPARATIVE EFFECTS OF GRADING A PURE SELECTION AND A COMMERCIAL VARIETY The pure-line selection from Kherson oats, known as Nebraska No. 21, and the ordinary " commercial Kherson! variety responded rather similarly to fanning-mill grading. The results for the 12-year period are summarized in Table 3. As an average for the heavy and large seed grades, the yield for common Kherson was 2.4 per cent less than for the ungraded seed and for the pure-line selection 0.6 per cent less than for the ungraded seed. In average results for the light and small seed grades, the yield was lowered 4.2 per cent in the case of the commercial variety, and 2.8 per cent in the case of the pure selection. In only one case did graded seed surpass; the heavy seed of Nebraska No. 21 oats out - yielded the ungraded 1.5 per cent. The general conclusion that clean, sound seed is not likely to be benefited by grading would seem justified. SEED TREATMENT FOR SMUT Unless the j smut diseases of small grain are properly con - trolled through seed treatment, material losses in grain yield may occur. The tests here discussed for oats and barley will serve to give information regarding the control of oat and barley smuts. For information concerning the control of the wheat smuts, the reader is referred to Nebraska Agricultural Extension Circular No. 132. OAT SMUT The smuts of oats may be effectively and economically controlled by seed treatment. Several standard treatments for such control were compared during a three-year period, 1929-1931. These consisted of both sprinkling and spray applications of formalin, and dust applications of Cere3an, Corona Blue Dust, and copper carbonate. The effects on 1 de - gree of infection and yield per acre were studied. The tests were made annually in duplicate one-thirtieth-acre plats. Smut </seg>
            <seg id="p008">TABLE Z.-Relative effects of fanning-mill grading upon Kherson and a pure line of Kherson % oats'— twelve-year average. 1917, 1919-1925, and 1927-1930 "Mrson g Character of seed planted ~ £■ " ' ■ Grain harvested 00 Weight Date — ZTT. £? Grade* .£. Date Height Weight YiM '" — "* 1000 Per h6ad rlpe _&amp;. H . seeds buahel tnuhel Actual Relative X COMMON KHERSON g HeSS t , S ed _::::::z=zz:"" SS g-J K! V,l III 30 - 8 52 - 7 ™* % Lightest fourth ■' 1648 IU ln\ Vn WW l°* 51 " 5 »" 3 Largest fourth ZZ 23 30 _\\ Imt VI !2'2 29 - 6 49 - 8 94.5 M Smallest fourth = SS SJ &amp;! $ ffi SS otJ gj H NEBRASKA NO. 21 KHERSON i Ki n e ?tfS e ?.zzr~z--~" SS ll* I IS • &amp; 6 2K 310 53 - 3 mm 5 Lightest fourth -..ZZ.TIZ 17 39 »14 fim VA 52'2 3L3 "- 1 1015 e Largest fourth ...ZZZZ:Z7Zr 2445 322 fim Vh ft. !H 51 - 5 96&lt;5 § Smallest fourth _l _ Iff S£ 3 W 30.1 31.4 51.8 97.2 g — 10.U1 di ;,6 6/13 7/ g 29g 312 g2l g77 g by ."cLMnMu*. "" BeParated Wlth a W,ndblast """"»« "■• *"". the large and the small grade, were separated £ CO 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods percentages were determined for each treatment by averag - ing ten counts of 100 heads made in various parts of the duplicate plats. Because of severe and uneven lodging of the grain in this test, the yields were not determined in 1929, Formaldehyde vs. dust treatments. — In the crop grown from naturally infected seed oats the percentage of smutted heads averaged 7.4 during the three years, 1929-1931, andj its average yield was 42.9 bushels during two of these years (Table 4). Corresponding averages for four different stand - ard treatments of formalin were 0.2 per cent of smutted heads and 45.5 bushels of grain per acre. The increase in grain yield was 2.6 bushels. I Four different dilutions of the formalin (40 per cent solu - tion of formaldehyde in water) were compared, all of which were applied at the rate of one pint of formalin to 50 bushels of oats. Three of these consisted of one pint formalin diluted respectively with 40, 10, and 3 gallons of water. .These solu - tions were applied with an ordinary garden sprinkling can. The seed was shoveled about so as to assure uniform wetting. By the fourth method, one pint of formalin was added to t one pint of water and the solution sprayed on the seed by means of a small chicken-house sprayer. Each shovelful of .seed was sprayed lightly while being placed in a pile on the floor. In all four cases the seed piles were reshoveled immediately after the solution had been applied. Other studies have indi - cated that such reshoveling with the more concentrated solu - tions tends to prevent injury to the germination from uneven distribution of' the formalin during application. After the shoveling, the seed was covered with a canvas for six hours, in order to retain the formaldehyde fumes, and then the) seed which had been treated by the sprinkling methods was spread out to dry. „ _. J . The various formalin treatments were all very effective in reducing the amount of smut. Compared with 7.4 per, cent smut for the untreated seed, as a thre*year average, the seed treated with the various dilutions containing 40 gallons, 10 gallons, 3 gallons, or one pint of water to one pint of formalin, resulted respectively in 0.1, 0.0, 0.2, and 0 4 per cent smutted heads. Corresponding average gram yields for two years were 42.9 bushels for the untreated and 45.3, 46.5; 45.0, and 45.0 bushels per acre for the respective treatments. While a solution of one pint of formalin and 10 gallons of water sprinkled on 50 bushels of seed gave the best control and highest yield, the other dilutions were nearly as effective. It has been learned from various tests that the procedure as outlined may be varied somewhat, but that certain import- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 7 ! T^ o, g, o„ g. „ I Crop grown hH Seed treatment Smutted heads | yield per~^ Q ■ . 1929 I 1980 I 1931 I Av. ~~_Wp Hsl AvT~ § *■*■ P-ct. P.ct. P.et. ~^Z. B„. Bu. £ Untreated oc § Formalin sprinkling treatments: ~ 46 14 -° 7A «.l 41.7 42.9 1 pint formalin to 40 gal. water, on 50 bu hpp&lt;i nn ns 1 Pint formalin to 10 |S. water oS 50 buieSr 0 J 0 0 on Si VA 43 " 5 45 " 6 S 1 Pint formalin to 3 gal. water, on 50 bu. seed ZZ n'l 02 no n - ?' *H 44S&gt; 465 $ Formalin spray treatment: °- 2 °- 2 °- 2 4 »-0 40.9 45.0 H 1 pint formalin to 1 pint water, on 50 bu. seed... 01 nn ne a a ,«» .- 2 Dry dust treatments: . ° 6 °- 6 °- 4 49-6 40.4 45.0 Z Ceresan, 3 oz. per bu no . n _•■'__ m Corona Blue Dust, 3 oz. per bu ZI if 2? H g? «.5 44.0 44.8 g Copper carbonate (20%), 3 oz. per bu ZZZZ H g jj g fi{ ffij JR | fields not detennined in 1929 because of severe lodging. — - ■ § to 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods ant principles must be adhered to: (1) It is important that fresh, full-strength formalin containing approximately 40 per cent formaldehyde be used. (2) No matter how the formalin is applied, the rate should be one pint to approximately 50 bushels of seed. Much stronger treatments are likely to seriously reduce or destroy the germination. (3) The for - malin should be distributed uniformly throughout the Eieed pile. (4) The seed should be covered with canvas or blankets for a brief period in order to hold the formaldehyde fumes until they have, had time to act on the smut spores, which cling to the exterior of the grain or beneath the hull. The duration of such covering may vary from three to ten hours, according to the convenience of the operator. The seed should then be uncovered and, in order to avoid serious seed injury in case of the sprinkling treatments, it should be spread out to dry rapidly unless it is planted at once. The spray method and the two more concentrated sprinkling treatments are pre - ferable because the smaller quantities of solution facilitate drying or immediate seeding. Because of the widespread and successful use of the copper carbonate dust treatment of wheat for stinking smut, much interest has been aroused in the feasibility of a dust treatment for oats. Three dust treatments of oats have been tested during the last three years in conjunction with the formalin treatments previously described. These were Ceresan, Corona Blue Dust, and copper carbonate. All were applied to j the seed at the rate of three ounces per bushel by means of a home-made barrel seed treater. Ceresan, whose active (dis - infecting principle is ethyl mercury chloride, proved to bei the most effective dry treatment and nearly as effective as [for - malin. In no way did it serve as a crop stimulant, however, and it did not increase yields more than did other treatments. Corona Blue Dust, with copper as the active chemical prin - ciple, and copper carbonate were materially less effective in smut control than Ceresan in these tests. It would seem from these comparisons that the choice be - tween formalin and Ceresan may be based largely upon ques - tions of cost and ease of application, if properly used. With formalin, too strong a dose or too slow drying is injurious to germination. Too little formaldehyde fails to give good ! con - trol. With the Ceresan there is no danger to germination. Lack of thoroughness in dusting the seed or an insufficient amount of the dust will reduce its effectiveness. Livestock should not be permitted to eat grain treated with Ceresan or other poisonous disinfectants. During two years the effectiveness of various quantities of Ceresan applied per bushel of oats was studied. Whereas </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 t n d 8eed P^uced 4.6 per cent of smutted heads in 1930 and 14.0 per cent m 1931, Ceresan applications of 1 2 and fa Mffi B JEiB be ! reSU i te /o in o 2 - 5 ' 2 - 3 ' and 10 Per cent 'smut m 1930, respectively, and 4.9, 2.0, and 0.7 per cent in 1931. 1923 a^r? i£__7Z3S2£&amp;* ST^f^"*- A test wa * made in SW 9^ 4 H determine the effects of treating naturally infected seed oats of a susceptible variety with various amounts of formaldehyde. Solutions of different s JenShs were prepared (Table 5) by adding formalin to watef at the rates of one pint to 40, 35, 30, 25, 20, 15, and 10 gallons «,? °? e P^t Se ° f this stud y these solutions/ rVardless of rateof WalrTfto^^^ £ 6 method at the ?£?«£,,£ 8«"«ns to 50 bushels of seed. In a second part of JfrK^&amp;s&amp;SS* solutlons L consisting of one pint of formalin to 5 and 10 gallons respectively of water, were applied fa re - bSdsofSS* S ° t0 equal ° ne pin &lt; of for^ n S to T^^5fS^' ,ar S 0MS /' a&lt;es of formaldehyde application on smut-mfected seed oats— average for 1923 andl92i Strength of solntion I SolnUon applied' Formalin Esti- Crop grown Formalin Water B £°* SObo- 60to. ™ddf Smutted Grain . wed ofseed ofseed stand heads peracre «• GaJ. Gal. CI. Pfc ~^ ££— Untreated 1M ? 2? 08 40 1-60 90 00 415 1 15 ol 12 20 ° 80 0-0 86.5 1 10 o S In _'_l 60 00 32.7 1 in S'S 40 4 - 00 25 0.0 18 8 •1* W 0-2 10 1.00 100 0.0 494 __^ g o- 1 s i-oo 100 ol soil 'Formaldehyde solution applied by the sprinkling method. iJSSP^ th 29 ' 4 P er &lt;* nt of smutted heads and 39.9 bushels of grain per acre for the untreated seed, the most 4B 2 fflT^ in °- 3 pe r; cent of smutted heads and £ik£S?? of + « rain P^ acre. The increased yield was un - doubtedly due to smut control. While all strengths of solu - ff^^T U l c&lt;mtro1 ' the use ° f more thanone SwfeH? t0 50 - Ushels of seed resuIted in reduced germination and acre yield. barley smut smEE&amp;EiS £?° S*iii 6f 8mut in barle y. and they require fflSSSSiS^"^ conspicuous black heads, which soon lose all their parts except the central stem, are diseased with </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Seed Preparation and Placing Methods loose smut. This disease is carried over from year to year inside the infected grain as well as on the surface, and the only recognized cure is the hot-water treatment. This treat - ment is based on the fact that the smut organism succumbs at a temperature somewhat below the fatal temperature for the grain. The other form of smut is known as covered smut. Here the diseased heads tend to retain their normal form but they contain the well-known blackish masses or smut |balls in the place of normal seeds. At the time of threshing or other handling these smut balls break and the smut spores adhere to the exterior of sound seeds. When this seed is planted, the spores germinate with the seed and enter the growing plant. The preventive treatment consists of disin - fection of the exterior of the seed. The following tests) have been made in connection with these studies for smut control. Loose smut of barley. — Although hot water is an effec - tive treatment for loose smut, it is recommended primarily for eliminating the disease from only a small amount of seed which is to serve as a foundation stock for seed increase. The reason is that hot water is likely to impair the germination and lower ithe yield. A common procedure for the hot-water treatment of barley is outlined by Meier 1 as follows: Treat the seed in (sacks only half filled and tied at the top. Soak 4 hours in cold water, dip in water at about 120° F. for a moment, and then soak 13 minutes at 126° F. The seed should then be drained and dipped at lonce into cold water or spread out in a thin ! layer to cool and dry. It should be planted as soon as the seed will run freely through the drill, or should be thoroughly dry be - fore being stored. The hot- water treatment for the loose smut of wheat as described by Meier is the same as for parley except that the immersion should be for 10 minutes at 129° F. Covered smut of barley. — The failure of formalin and Ceresan in case of seed infected with loose smut is demon - strated by the tests reported in Table 6. However, the same treatments gave excellent control in the case of light infection with covered smut. i ■ ■F. C. Helcr, Miscellaneous Publication No. 94, Bureau of Plant Industry, United States DeDt. of Agr. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 Table 6.- Effect of seed disinfectants upon the control of loose and covered smut of barley— 1929 Crop harvested Seed treatment Method of — . application Grain Smutted heads ■ to seed per ""= acre Loose Covered ■ _ smut smut Bu. p.ct. pZetZ~ No treatment . Solution 1 pint formalin, 40 gal water* fiiTmw'" %}_ H 4 . 1 - 1 tSSSSl ?}£**■ formalln . ! Pint water*. Spraying 509 I02 o? Ceresan (3 ounces per bushel) DusUn/ |g.6 111 Jo --X^*__ll_i_?Zf_l t * at * f0rm,Un to "° ba » heI " 5 — the method. Fanning the seed to remove smut balls should prove advan co? SS smut' 6 SeT^f "T ° f - hea^ *KKlS? covered smut. Either soaking or sprinkling the seed with a dilute solution of formalin or dusting with Ceresan J? b«« been described for oats is recommended S haS - MANNER OF PLANTING fc JL P J ta *«S rain T S _ are sown in this state by either drilling or broadcasting. It is customary to broadcast a half-bushe mo seed per acre than is drilled in order to allow for fmoerfect m»?%«SR d - Ies _ "™f°™ germination. In a 12-S test O919-1930) in duplicate field plats at Lincoln, broadcSt Kherson oats yielded 1.1 bushels per acre or 2.3 per crat i^S^-^ 11^/ 8 *!: With the additional halflbushel per acre used fa broadcasting, this makes a net gain of 1 6 bushels Platte^Sn X^_%2^ U _^ rt^ ?^« person oate yielded 6.5* bXlsToVe^ha ? broadcast^ Six SSS °C oats „ We J e 8eeded P e r acre in both casts A driU places the seed at a more definite and uniform depth in the TABLE 7.— Broadcasting compared with drilling oats— twelve years, 1919-1930 - Manner of Hat e Date _ Tert Yield of grain pianting P~ $£ Pig* wei«ht pera^ : — . __ grain Actual Relative In. Lbs. Bu. Pjst. saLr±_ s g g a g g «m </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods j soil. This is especially desirable in relatively dry or other - wise unfavorable seed beds. For this reason drilling is more important ih western than in eastern Nebraska. rate of seeding Much speculation always centers about the question as to the best rate of seed per acre. To obtain some definite infor - mation, rate-of -planting tests have been made with both) oats and barley. The seeding has been done in the early part of the normal planting season. It is apparent from the results! that the amount may vary widely without materially affecting the grain yield. Sowing more than is necessary would be a waste of seed. On the other hand, seeding too thin lowers the 'yield and permits more weed development. In general, the amount per acre should be reduced westward in the state in order to offset the conditions resulting from lower rainfall. RATE OF SEEDING OATS Kherson and Swedish Select oats were drilled annually at seven different rates during a 13-year period. The Kherson has relatively small seed, while Swedish Select is large. When planted at the respective rates of 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, and 16 pecks per acre (Table 8) Kherson oats yielded 43.9,147.2, Table 8. — Rate-of-planting test with two varieties of oats differing in size of seed — average for thirteen years, 1917, 1919-1930 J m t Yield of grain Seed planted Date Date Plant weSht per acre per acre in head ripe height of ~«_ n Actual | | Net , Ph*. ' Tn. Lbs. Ba. | Bui KHERSON 4 6/15 7/7 29.2 30.5 43.9 42.9 6 6/15 7/7 28.4 31.1 47.2 45.7 8 6/14 7/7 28.1 31.7 47.6 45.6 10 6/14 7/6 27.8 31.8 47.8 j 45.3 12 6/13 7/6 27.4 32.0 48.0 1 45.0 14 6/13 7/6 27.3 32.1 47.0 43.5 16 6/13 7/5 26.9 31.9 46.5 42.5 SWEDISH SELECT 4 6/20 7/13 32.7 29.8 36.9 35.9 6 6/19 7/13 32.8 30.0 40.9 39.4 8 6/19 7/13 32.3, 30.2 42.2 40.2 10 6/18 7/12 31.5V 30.3 42.9 40.4 12 6/18 7/12 31.3^ 30.2 43.6 40.6 14 6/18 7/11 30.9 30.5 43.2 39.7 16 6/18 7/11 30.4 30.7 43.0 39.0 *By net yield ia meant the yield per acre less the amount of seed planted, j </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 4 ?'i 6 J _¥&amp;'_&amp;£_ 47 '° and 46 - 5 bushels, while Swedish Select yielded 36.9, 40.9, 42.2, 42.9, 43.6, 43.2, and 4S™ bushels gr rr,_t?«f n &amp; y? r *« e l or the 13 years, both varieties gave the SS^SE SS 8 When T*!* at the rate of thr ee bushels per ?£_ Vr* n the amount Panted is subtracted from the yield, the difference may be thought of as net yield. With the 1 ?^ th ? ma3dmum yield was obtained from LSS? °L 6 Pecks per acre, while 12 pecks of Swedish SfSiST he eatest » et return. The extreme differences in yield for seeding rates ranging from 6 to 12 pecks per acre were only 0.8 bushels for Kherson and 2.7 bushels for Swedish Select. All things considered, 2 to 2% bushels of seed per acre may be regarded as desirable for varieties with small seeds and a half-bushel more for large-seed varieties under average Eastern Nebraska conditions varieties RATE of seeding barley ioS? m I &lt; S? barl^J UM be en grown during five years, 1926 - 1930, at the respective seeding rates of 4, 6, 8, 10, and 12 pecks lf« a&lt;^i Corresponding acre yields (Table 9) have been 33.9, fS&amp;Sh 7- ' and 3 ?- 4 babels, while the net yields, after subtracting the amount of seed planted, were 32.9, 35.1, 35.0, Jk&amp;sSrT* 3 ' 4 bu -?r el8 -,n Thu8 , *** neatest actual yield was obtained from drilling 10 pecks per acre while 6 pecks gave the highest net yield. The extreme difference in yield for planting rates ranging between 6 and 12 pecks was one bushel per acre. Since almost identical net yields were obtained for 6, 8, and 10 peck seedings, a rate of 8 to 10 pecks per acre, as a general rule, is most desirable for this region. TIME OF PLANTING The time of planting spring grains has proved important ui the production of maximum and most profitable yields, sowing early in the planting season is especially advantageous Table d.—Rate-of-planting test with Comfort barley— average for five years, 1926-1930 Seed planted Date Date Plant Te »* YId i. of ***** Peracre Inhead rije hdgft weight per ■" 0f8raln Actual Net* ***" f*. Lbs. Bu. ~B_\ t !£? V.l 282 459 8 3.9 32.9 i 1%} VI 285 46 -° 36.6 35.1 ,2 %** W 28.6 45.8 37.1 35.1 l2 _£2 " VI 289 459 37.4 34.9 12 6/10 7/7 28.2 45.9 36.4 33.4 *By net yield is meant the yield per acre less the amount of seed planted. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Seed Preparation and Planting Methods with oats and spring wheat. Barley withstands delayed plant - ing better than wheat and oats. It would seem that where more than one of these crops is grown, the planting order should be wheat, oats, and barley. - j Experiment station results bearing on this question are available during 14 years for wheat and oats and seven years for barley. One-thirtieth-acre field plats have been planted in duplicate or triplicate annually. From three to four plant - ing dates with approximately 10-day intervals have been compared each year. In farm practice, field conditions in this region seldom permit planting - before March 19, and this date is regarded as "extra early". March 30 is early and may be regarded as the beginning of the normal plant - ing season. Most of the spring grains are planted by about April 10, while some planting is done thereafter. TABLE 10. — -Time of planting Java spring wheat — fourteen I years, 1917-1930 Time of planting Year and character Extra I early 1 Early | Medium | Late Bu. Bu, Bu. Bu. ANNUAL ACRE YIELDS, SHOWING SEASONAL VARIATIONS 1917 31.3 25.8 23.2 1918 3.4 1.4 |0.4 1919 ! 3.1 2.4 1 1.5 1920 ! 19.8 15.8 13.5 1921 18.9 16.8 11.2 6.7 1922 i 15.9 15.6 10.0 8.2 1923 20.5 18.2 9.2 1924 16.9 14.2 8.2 1925 12.3 10.7 12.6 10.1 1926 1 5.0 3.8 4.4 3.6 1927 12.1 13.9 9.4 4.2 1928 15.5 16.1 15.0 12.8 1929 i 25.9 24.0 23.4 14.9 1930 ! 26.6 22.2 19.1 13.7 SUMMARY FOR 8-YEAR PERIOD I I Time of planting 3/19 3/30 4/10 4/20 Date In head 6/8 6/10 6/13 6/17 Date ripe I j=- 7/5 7/7 7/9 7/11 Length of growing period (days).. 108 99 90 82 Length of fruiting period (__!/«)_ 27 27 26 24 Plant height; (in.) 31 30 . 29 27 Test weight of grain (16*.) 58.2 58.5 57.4 55.9 Av. acre yield, 8 yrs. (bu.) 16.5 15.4 13.1 9.3 Av. acre yield, 8 yrs. (p.ct.) , 107 100 85 i 60 Av. acre yield, 14 yrs. (6u.) 15.6 13.1 9.3 Av. acre yield, 14 yrs. (p.ct.) 100 84 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 time of planting spring wheat During 14 years (Table 10) plantings of Java spring wheat made on March 30, April 10, and April 20 yielded 15.6, 13.1,- and 9.3 bushels per acre. In eight of these years a still earlier planting on March 19 was included. The aver - age yields from these four successive dates were 16 5 15 4 13.1, and 9.3 bushels. These are relative yields of 107, l6o! 85, and 60 per cent. Corresponding ripening dates were July t_l' ¥r, a ? d 11 ' and the test weights for the grain were 58.2, 58.5, 57.4, and 55.9 pounds per bushel. Delayed planting also reduced the plant height and shortened the length of the fruiting period between date in head and date ripe. TIME OF PLANTING OATS As an average for the 14-year period (Table 11) the fol - lowing acre yields were obtained for Kherson oats planted on Table 11.— Time of planting Kherson oats— fourteen years, 1917-1930 Time of planting Year and character Extra " ' 1 early Early Medium late Bu, B~u. Bu. Bui ANNUAL ACRE YIELDS, SHOWING SEASONAL VARIATIONS 1917 95-9 94 5 73 g 1Q1Q 149 60 4 -° ilH 56.7 34.2 35.8 iof? •— 693 65 ° 58.2 io,, 68 - 2 61.1 59.2 31.3 1922 30.6 34.6 19.3 17.2 1923 __ 752 67 - 4g6 1924 _ 57 5 4g 6 34 ? i_2_ 30 -5 27.2 29.1 27.2 1Q97 64 80 7.4 5.2 ?ooi 582 56.0 49.7 41.1 Too! 464 48 - 3 49 -6 53.7 1929 80 .i 76 4 63 „ 55 3 1930 63,0 58.5 52.2 50.7 SUMMARY FOR 8-YEAR PERIOD Time of planting 3/l 9 3/30 4/10 4/20 Date in head 6/8 6/9 6/13 6/18 ?l^? Pe . Us 7 /l 7 / 2 7 /5 7/9 Length of growing period (days).. 104 94 '86 80 Length of fruiting period (days).. 23 23 22 21 Plant height (in.) 28 27 26 26 Test weight of grain (lbs.) 31.3 31.9 30.9 29 7 Av. acre yield, 8 yrs. (bu.) 47.9 46.3 41.2 35.2 Av. acre yield, 8 yrs. (p. ct.) 103 100 89 76 Av. acre yield. 14 yrs. (bu.) ___ 52.8 46.2 38.4 Av. acre yield, 14 yrs. (p. ct.) 100 88 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I . ■ . •: i ' ■ ' Seed Preparation and Planting Methods successive dates: March 30, 52.8 bushels; April 10, 4^.2 bushels ; and April 20, 38.4 bushels. During eight years j an 11-day earlier planting was included. The average yields for these four successive dates were 47.9, 46.3, 41.2, and 35.2 bushels per acre. These are relative yields of 104, 100, !89, and 76 per cent. The corresponding ripening dates were July 1, July 2, July 5, and July 9, and the test weights of the grain were 31.3, 31.9, 30.9, and 29.7 pounds per bushel. Plant height and length of the fruiting period were also reduced by the delayed planting. TIME OF PLANTING BARLEY Comfort barley (Table 12) gave the respective average yields of 24.0, 26.6, 27.4, and 25.0 bushels per acre when planted March 19, March 31, April 10, and April 21. These Table 12. — Time of planting Comfort barley — seven years, 1924-1930 Annual yields of grain per acre • Time of Planting — — — 1924 ! 1925 192S 1927 1928 1929 1930 Bit. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. Extra early 10.9 4.7 31.0 31.3 32.8 33.2 Early 18.7 9.7 3.6 43.6 27.5 37.4 37.5 Medium 17.6 13.4 2.4 30.7 27.1 50.0 40.7 Late 19.1 10.5 4.6 26.6 28.4 47.2 02.6 SUMMARY ~~ Grain yield. Date Date Grow- Fruit- Test fi-yeaijav. plant- in Date ing ing Plant wt. of 1 Time cd head ripe period period height grain iRela- Actual | tive Dans Daits In. Lbs. Bu. . P.ct. Extra early.. 3/19 6/3 6/30 103 27 25 46.3 24.0 I 90 Early 3/31 6/6 7/2 93 26 25 46.0 26.6 , 100 Medium ...... 4/10 6/10 7/4 85 24 24 45.5 27.4 , 103 Late .._ 4/21 6/14 7/8 78 24 24 43.8 25.0 94 are relative yields of 90, 100, 103 and 94 per cent. The test weight, length of fruiting period, and plant height were all reduced by delayed planting. The date of ripening was re - tarded nine days by 33 days' delay in planting. WHEAT, OATS, AND BARLEY COMPARED During the six years, 1925-1930, these thrbe crops were compared directly with respect to their reaction to time of planting. The results (Table 13) were very similar to jthose given in the three preceding tables. For the planting dates of March 19, March 31, April 10, and April 21, the respective relative yields of spring wheat were 107, 100, 93, and 65 per cent; oats 104, 100, 91 and 85 per cent; and barley 90j 100, </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 273 103, and 94 per cent. The oats and wheat have reacted very similarly, receding in yield with each delay in planting. The barley, on the other hand, averaged relatively low for the earliest date, and medium-early planting was better for this crop. It would seem from these results that barley is better adapted to the climatic conditions associated with delayed planting than is either wheat or oats. Table 13. — Comparative effects of the time of planting upon the grain yields of oats, barley, and spring wheat — average for six years, 1925-1930 Yield of grain per acre . . _, P ate . Actual Relative Time of planting planted ■ Spring Spring Oats Barley wheat Oats Barley wheat ___. . _ Bu. Bu. Bu. P. et. P. et. P.et. Extra early 3/19 47.4 24.0 16.2 104 90 107 Early 3/31 45.7 26.6 15.1 100 100 100 Medium 4/10 41.8 27.4 14.0 91 103 93 Late 4/21 38.9 25.0 9.9 | 85 94 65 TIME OF HARVESTING Because of the recognized superior feeding value of oat straw when harvested somewhat immature, tests have been made during the 10-year period, 1921-1930, to determine the effect of such practice upon the yield of grain. The aim has been to cut comparable duplicate plats of Kherson oats when ripe and at intervals of 2, 4, and 6 days before ripe. The yields (Table 14) when harvested at these four stages of maturity were respectively 47.1, 45.9, 43.1, and 40.7 bushels per acre. These are relative yields of 100, 97, 92, and 86 per cent. The principle would seem fairly well established that the grain continues to gain in weight until it is ripe. Since this increase was only 3 per cent during the last two days, it appears permissible to harvest the oat crop when it is slightly green. However, if harvesting is done four or five days before the oats are ripe, a reduction of approximately ten per cent in grain yield may be expected. Table 14. — Oats harvested in various stages of maturity — averages for ten years, 1921-1930 Time Moisture In ~" Yield of srain per acre harvested srain when Test weight before ripe harvested of grain Actual Relative Days P.et. Lbs. Bu. P.eU 6 42 29.5 40.7 86 4 37 30.8 43.1 92 2 28 31.6 45.9 97 Ripe 16 3^0 47;! 100 IBM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>