<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  CULTIVATION OF SMALL GRAINS.  THE USE OF THE FANNING MILL FOR SELECTING SEED WHEAT AND SEED OATS.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XX, Article V. F CULTIVATION OF SMALL GRAINS. USE OF THE FANNING MILL FOR SELECTING SEED WHEAT AND SEED OATS. Distributed May 29, 1906. CULTIVATING WHEAT WITH A HARROW LINCOLN. NEBRASKA 0. S. A. By E. G. MONTGOMERY. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">&lt;r AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD 'H| RiaiNTI Or tmi UNiVCHtlTVj CHAS. S. ALLEN, Piesukni, Lioco \VM. G. WHITMORE, Valley FREDERICK H. ABBOTT, Aaron • &gt;K G. LYFORD, FaUs City CHAS B. ANDERSON. Crete GE COUPLAND, Elgin THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BIRNETT, B.Sc, Director E DALES, M.Ph.. Financial Secretary W. MARSHALL, I lerk THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry A. T. Peters. D.V.M., Anim.il Par- Frederick D. Heai.d, Ph.D., Botmmy F. J. Alway, Ph.D., Chemistry A. L. Haecker, B Sc.A.. Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bkiner, B.Sc Entonun E. G. Montgomery, B.Sc, Field Crops Frank. J. Phillips. M.F., Forestry Erwin H. Barbour, Ph.D., Geology BR. CHATBURN, A.M., Highway Engineering A. Emerson, B.Sc, Horticulture O. V. P. Stout, C.E., Irrigation G. A. Lovelakd, B.Sc, Meteorology Alvin Keyser, A.M., Soils W. P. Snvdkk. M.S.. Suf&gt;ei intendint F xprnuuntal Substatu»i . \ J. H. Gain. M.D.C., Associate in Animal Pathology A. F. Magdanz, Jr., A.B., Assistant in Animal Husbandry L. B. Stlrdevant, A.M., .Issistavt in Animal Pathology Stella A. Hartzell, A.M.. Assistant m Chemistry K. M. Little. B.S&lt; ., Atsistmmt in Pain Husba* KNki.sov. M.S., .hsistant in Field enny, A.B., Assistant in Horticulture ERIN, Farm Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p003">i in CULTIVATION OF SMALL GRAINS MY i:. G. MONT0OMK1Y. 1 • of cultivation fo* hood rropa has so kwg bem hat in&gt; niic knows when 1 1 1 • - advnntagr was first iikI it is altogether n-asonaMe to snppo-u- that lia&gt;l hi uf small grain a rorTenpondiiig advantage tli« - iilil have been made early. However, the fact that ii of small grain ' s certain to yield less striking In- cultivation of IumhI cropn does not prevent it ■itiniis in the farmer. Nebraska fainiiiiu hat t land is as vnlunhlc as the time of horses and r wortls, it i, iay br as profitable to acid three &lt;n - tM the average yichl per acre by car-ful cnlti- Iniv more land for the «»rowing of extra kiiiu i-nltnre can ilo for small grain on Nebraska Stilt ion ilurinu the last eiirlit years has been at lien results were obtained (1 SOS), oats wen inches, twelve inches ami six inches between One of the t'\o plats devoteil to ('rills six s left uncultivated. For the cultivation of tin ■ I until lie- erain liecame too hiuli larrow w ni umall i;i;iin am! ihf u imliT tin- iliroction of T. I., l.vnn Jon of this work terrain phi* iii distances (»f twentj-foai </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 I llt'll Jl Sliuil l-slliivi'lril &lt; P It I V.I h &gt;r was Sll l»s| II lltftl. I iiivcs Hi!- data and results : Tabu j, lit Distance Sc-i-.l No. of Yii-lil .." apart of jkt cultiva- per Method irivii ' . apart of per milt N "' drills. :„• • nil i\;ii ion may !«• coiisidcn &gt;l u;iis. The Htaudard |&gt;lan v ls-iiirli. and s per rein lai ■&lt;.&gt; fvt'i-. ilic iulvanta&lt;rc rtf fin«-«' IH-i i iH-ln-s apari is !7 per et»nt. Tb incut is that in a \t-,iv of normal rainfall, om* cnltivatioo givon ; wav is ailviiiilii.iii-uiis ; but ll:at i *i vat ion docfl nut warrant i 'n- i nan si\ inches for t h&lt;- nil r i tost ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I mlaril r than r than Im- 1 I 1 rrsi \ l i In I!mmi. dril lit ivat ion were lats :',S and 4 1 I 1 1 i r till* j i ? i I \ llillL! I lie II / ■I \ Method giving larger yield method &lt;&gt;f growing yielded, in 1899, 26.6 per i the 24-inch I rultivations plan, and &lt;&gt;.:&gt; per the 18-im-h 4-niltivations plan. In iliai year, inch triple rultivntion method gave L'.'J.l |&gt;'-i- Its thai the stnndiinl, :ind one cultivation in- I of a standard drilling plat 13.6 per cent. in the results obtained on the two yearn with ipart may he accounted for in the difference the yearn. The growing sestson of 189H was us drawn from Table II arc that one cnlti - scaxin is a decided idvMilaue lo :■ Rtandard and that a farther advantage is s. cnreil by limber of drills by one-half and cultivating i n IX «nd l'foadi astinj; oats with and without: ■ compared. All plats were sowed on April 4. I were harrowed &lt;&gt;n May IS, that cultivation lie ihev recei\ed The results were as folloWK llv moist : Hint &lt;&gt;f 189!) &gt;v;is mon ilitiu nor- . ( Ordinary mcthiHl without cultivation ■Jt» 7 X 8 jK-r iint large yield. ■j* 0 Ordinary ractbcxl without cultivation. ■_ M .i. 7 6.3 (K-r rtnt larger jrteM. :u; .". 12-inch trilling with eattrratiaa, W.I ii.ii j&lt;r cent larger yield. Ordinary method uith one cultiva- 2B.7 tion, 13 per cent larger yield. .03 Inch below normal; January-July. II jw niirmal; June, 3.92 inches above normal. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">fi M Drilled No cultivation Drilled .. Due cultivatioi •Jl I Broadcast. Nocultivati Hroudcasl. One cultival ■ Drilled. Nocu Broadcast. Nocu f Drilled... On Broadcast ( in With the exception of A] ■u\v of 1JM&gt;O and the mouths I \\ Cl'l c-astcd and drilled urain, rultiration was a iiiarl,c&lt; Take IV. /. M.. Junr 1 * / ■;" Drilled, not cultivated . 1 1 4'J III. IM ■ ! s Drilled, culti vated 11 l.i in 4-j -** ' Broadcasted, not cultivate.] 12 38 loss cultivated . 11.11 I i -j: Tabus III. Effect ol Plat Mfthcxl of ... vi No. planting I'-tnunt Advantage of brnadc-i Precipitatioo : Kail, lln.adiasti'd grain \ iclilci ckt-i&lt;l&lt;il1 ti connection \\ itli tin- 1900 llioisl me rnnlcill of i lie 1&gt;I; in;; the season. The ivs jj o Experiment 41 HroaHi-iisteil. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I riking is.lm-io tlic fan thai the in uctl plat* made increased demands t " K " t - i J'u-r.- Increase in vicl.l. Bushels. ,,, y ».3 | -M Bj cultivation. Ill .* ncli a •ore the normal: Jaanary-Maj normal; June July. 1902, J1.S1 Inches below tl normal. V shows the effed of rnltiratioa on the yield of Kker - in 1982. Cultivation for drilled o;it* in a dry spring seemiru nioistii-c .« m , ( . s j n t i, ( . &lt;&gt;ai . lv Sllm , „,.,._ is irofitable. AVisi No.ofcnl- Yield Method uivinj; Imfn tivations. per acre. yield N M I he s.jis.m of 1903 wjis one ,,r .-xc-ssivc rainfall. Under li -bisons niltivation ban nsnally proven injurious, owing lilt' filet I ll;| I I ||( *|*( • is Mo Him 1 1 if ■••■*• tin- advantage of ciilti\;i "«■. Thai ilic Hgurra in farur &lt;«f i.msJu/s. /'a,, nl 0 83.9 1) HIliiiK .-. it/lout culti- 1 81 .0 | vatimi gave 7.r ( per " '-"'J cnit larger yk-l.l. II liil.'.l 58.2 Krua(lcastiii K without ' 58.9 oultivation gavt- 7 1 11 86.9 per cent larger yield nehea abore the normal; January -July above the normal; heavy precipitation </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 thr cultivation tools. over three i imes with ; No. of Drillt-.l Cl Drilled Bn t. ■1 8 Broadcast. Not Drilled. e Broadcast. (. c I&gt;r I - I nary noni Ahho the rainfall w, vn-v heavy, the s.- ; is,,ii creaae thru enltivatioo it often happens thai ■ sillls. which cill|(ll;lsizr: sciics of \( iii-s art' r&lt;-li ! ;i VI Tai Mrthn,l No plantin ■ DrilK.I.. Cull Drilled. Not ■ Drilled... Cultiv; Broadcast. Cnltivi ■ Drilled. . . Not cultivate. Broadcast. Not cultivate! I) nary-June. I tion in Han nti.nlit product 1 grain ;m- In 1905 ili&lt;- phus i-uhivai IF;il!i»ck wifder. T\m.&gt;: VII. / Method of .,. . planting. lrt ' ;itI " Precipitation: \ H Broadcast Cultivated Broadcast. Not cultivate Precipitation: Aagust-neceml </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 v i i \ ■ It i \ I May, yel &lt;n 1 1 i\ :ii ion gave no iacr » to the abundsince of moisture earlier of cornstalks on the effective. hi-avv srrowth u was not vcrv InlltJ oats foi 190G 190t! Ax I In. /.'«. I'.u. 1902 l!« ~j(i 4:i.."&gt; ivi.i kcm r*.2 :.i.) •', r.7.1 M.fl as mil ( omltictcd in 1901. In 1901 tin - i owing to wet weather and high winds w n so badly that thej could noi Im- liar imrease of l.s luisliels was given by ciilii ition generally consisted of two or thiw i\s ai»art. \\iih a common amooihing liar- after sowing. The trash, like cornstalkK, and is not ,i^ MIS Hint* and l»roa&lt;lmstin«i with and without // 180K \v Method /: viel.l l 'iilli: n/ioii, "i ■'! 1&gt;ii .V.i Si 57.9 larger, or HI Without cultivation p* l.'.tlm Imrsrr.orSJl 1 Hi-J.1 IX ."it ii •24 7 07 I Icastinff, .9 bu an i »i ii or i :&gt;, I tlll-cr to live \V("«'k^ after SOWing. Ill' 1 r thfln sip' harrow, principally bwamtp ii imii.u-iiI. Tin- results nn- given in the 1 Drilling, 8.3 l&gt;u. lar t L'ir, or 11*. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Hi 'I Where broadcasting ;in&lt;l tlrill iu cultivation, die broadcast ing '4;m W Inn cultivation w;is \n-,u iis&lt;-.t. creased in vicld ."&gt;.;; i.uslnlv IM -i- :i&lt; IV, W ll tls were diTicuscd 1.0 Inishi i&gt; sow n brotulcaKt, (he barr mis, while wiih i Ik- drillc ■oytnl. I n our experiments scol |»c|- ;icjv in Imp! Ii CMS4-S, ri . In tls smvii !i|-(i;lilc.|s| mi 'T, c.\|M'|-ic||cr IchIs II I n-s i • iisc&lt;l tlic irrnin rn/i II ii tin- autumn of liMHl t for cnltiviil ion cxih-i s Mav s. The- various TA! Ptmt M. tli ■_"•' l!riml( SI Drillcil .... N.i cultivatioi Krilk-il Drilled .... ( »i PrecipltatJon: Kail. 190 aniiary-lnii' hi the sc;is.,n of l!nil-l!iiil fall nnd R|»ring cultivation :im&lt;1 rollin- «hv Wod. In tl,- .iiitivM.ion tin- common apikt- tTP |il;!lili-«l w illi Till Klril plafM for &lt;lrill 1 1 I lllr SMIIU- illlti •'»' KH1U-.1 .... N&lt; I The (-(inclusions ilrrtwn from Tahl«&gt; XI an- thiti when '"inir is cxrcrdimih dry, drilling lias a dvcMctl :idvnn (•!• In-oadciisiinii, ;iim! tli.il cnliixaiinii ilun navt". </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 • disk Were lisril ;il dil eeder was used lor the Irr ami ih I'll A ■&gt; etirl.v iii .Ma\ . Two tilted with Uiu; Frame wheal. All [ilals wel. - and drought, the Big lit 1 olle | furkish I Hut while tin- &lt; &lt; &gt;imIi - li. the plats in each set (•nsisicd o( a liuht bar I in all cases. The spring cult i\ at ion wan i, except that the broad - diskini:. at the time of ■red alreadv quite mel ■e diske&lt;l and harrowed ult ivation was similar, was given on April 1 1. el- with llreed'a wee&lt;ler |.lais i-ultiviitcd lian-ow &lt; j d at'lri hey were consul Ml cull ivatcil idals we 1. Tin- second ( aliove. and well shmted hack and iiai'ihi. Following are the resulls rtisM h'nl u/i,at ih Yield I Metho&lt;l Riving UrjcCT viil.l. /',;,/. /.';&lt; ■ no i ;1 . . Non-culture . i. Hi i Noii-i-iilturi- . Rolling ami pring cnlti- | 8s N \ugu8t-Dpoeml inches above the normal; normal; heavy in Jun« liv i-hinrli bilgx Fi-riii}; I lie nun*. iVllolt' Wrl'c 1|||C«( [tanihle. ion w;is &lt;«ven, ii Wrlv ;l' r ; Ml 'Ji'lic iv In- harrow n^cil wh Cultivation, SHIT, i fall ami sj .t I7.K5 i „ ... Rolling valion </seg>
            <seg id="p012">VI Spring cultivation of wii drilled, when the rainfall late, Table XII indicates to evei-, the disk harrow was i this year. Before am! nin«-e harrow and weeder hare l« veiv (iii the plants, \\ hich n loss due to riilt i\ at ion. 1 '&lt;»! 1 i lie a |Hisii ivo ilisjidvantaii used I w ire on 1 lie rlllt iva! II liseil. Til Mi I ill. 1 \ In I Tabli x Ptat No. T Brctai in fall Broiulci 8 Mrillitl. nil sjirin 11 Krill .i In ]&gt;rilli-.l.i-ul i-2 DHII.mI, rol It Drilled, no cultiv 13 Drilled, rolkd 'J7 Broadcasted, cultiv and s])rint Broadcasted, m&gt; culti •_".• Drilled, cultivated f '!- Drilled, rolled in spring .11 I&gt;rille&lt;l. no cultivation . 33 Drilled, re ilk-. I and &gt; vated in spring inter wlivtit, cither lir&lt;i:ul normal am! imi ul 1!M!L\ onlv 1 In- cunihiuii sii Inlllil ilCCOUIli loss doe in cult i\ al ion. Holliti lion. |&gt;;ivs: rolling alone [mys Ill roniHM-tion wiih i!n in 1 ll:l I luii^ w i-i-c in. i cultivation upon i Ik ntiiiltH are civ&lt;*n ;i&gt; vatic] fall ami s])i » spring Drilled, cultivated in s]&gt;riiu </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Hi iiiai fall and spring cultivation of n conserving the soil moisture. u. s that spring rolling of drilled grata aiiuir. possess to a less degree the saim i(lvanta«;c the table ■hows for the enlti- w iin is ton slight to he taken into serious August-December, IMS, t;.oi Inches above normal- Jin Ja-ion'^Mnv 1 - in ' ll " S a """' n ° rma ' ; heaVy of plentiful rainfall, l.roadcastinj: apjH'ars to Jm drilling, no culture to he preferable to enltira ing followi-d l»v cultivation to he idvmt- &gt;r 'i i itiu: tit ittji (in II Rig /■mm, wheat hi igoj. frcatment. I Method (rirnx tmtmu peracre. jrield. ted in spring . . Itivated ........ 1. fall ami spring. Huskels n-rct. I:,, -4.1 Non-culture i! 1 I ■jr..:, 34.0 Non-i-ulturi- lt.5 1 .", tirated 1, fall and spring. •Jii t i Non-culture 7 •_' tivated tivated . . I Uma.ica.t I .", 1 1 m spring tivated and harrowed in l; 3R6 Rolling... 4 4 11 aw Rolling and 27.3 | harrowini;. 7.0 |J </seg>
            <seg id="p014">u Ettble XV shows the ciVcci of &lt;!iHcri'iit nielli cultiviitintr Turkish R&lt;*&lt;1 wliciit. Tabu ' IS Drilk-il Ifi Drilled .... N M Drilled . ... C K Broadcast N&lt; Broadcast. Cn llrilk-.l . . \ot TJ Broadcast Not 17 Itrilli-d i IS Drilled Not cultiv 1* Dnlk-d . . K.,11,-,1 ai t Method ' planting </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 »n of l!to;5 was one of altnornial rainfall. In such a ti vat ion apparmih works a positive injury both mil with drillod grain. Ilollin« in tin vivci-. gave excellent rrsnlts. lmt harrowing afti-i \ as evidently injurious ii/li:ii/ion on Turkish Red wkeml in /y&lt; reatawat. .I^m-L. ****** ***** 1: ' r «" &gt;i'l'' Km l\&gt; ,1 Km in sprinj; :»; i I Culture H '1 ti Not cultivated .!! n.i Non iiilturt tivatecl :Bt. I i . , e&lt;l in spring Hi.t, Cnltwe. X.0 s i BroadcastiaK . . US :, I I Rolliim 131 I 5 I : •prinj; :it"&gt; 'J Rollini; ami c-ul i vat in lecember, 1904. 1 ", l teckea below normal; Jan- ii&gt;'.liinc. I ■ :i(h below noniKil slightly above </seg>
            <seg id="p016">i ! ]&lt;; I' l*K, cultivation, whi. one exception, save i, **■ Boiling again gave ; , large intnswe, Iml ha «• the roller was ihX ax «ood ss rolling alone Enst whv harrowing after rolling should result "i «wy apparent. i,,.i ihis ,,...„], h;ls ,„,,„ t)l) Table XVII M.-th. So planting '.' Drilk-,1 L BUrille.l N,,t, Drilled.. Cult sprn H Broadcast. Not ,ul Broadcast Cultivai ■ I'rilled.. Not cul Broadcast. Not cul ■ Drilled.. Rolled in aprii Drilled. Not cultivated Drilled... Rolled ami cu] Hi sprii August-December, IJK)5 .-4 i nc uary-June. M06, .52 Inch below tacion in March, but dry in Mav </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 rimtM/s, fho7ciui; th&lt; msI tniil drilled. Bu. liu. Aw. Hm. Hi 81.0 :!7 :; Noo-cultui i.2 bushel more 1 ii - :"• :i N.niciiltui - •_".•" :RM .",7.4 .is 2 bushels ■ 7.1 ii 36.9 81.037.3 DrilliiiL'.wluinul- 4II.-J X1.8 35. 3 tivatrcl,:M.ii&gt;hcN l.(i more W. V.I '.I ;!7 . s I iiffcreiice less (i .iti.'.i til .0 37.3 than one bushel M a i.: 4.3 •"&gt;'.' - - 3.3 4:;.:S Rolling. 5.1 l.u-h !4.:t ."MM! .is .-.' els more S 28.1 »».« r.-J.l in ii Rolling anl ml (O.:S 2H.M •:4.:i .V.1.1; 38.2 tivatiog, 1 tiU;.ht 1- iii truni the above data tlwit during the pairt ri \ • • 1 \ icld cuuld be Rei'iirud from cultivation of Cultivation of broadcasted wheat lvsulhil in f almost three bushels per aere, while culti i rcsiiltcil in ,i li.*s nf onlv one-half biiMhel Rolling ilif wheat, however, has never faile&lt;l lo sjiv&lt; useil yield, the average increarc being -".I lmshels pel he rolling was y;iven early in ihe spring, soon aftei t was out. and :ii&gt;out the time growth started. Cultivation r the rolling was not as good as rolling alone. The fact thai wlual sown broadcaal has given as re ills as w heal sow n with a press drill may occasion some rat prise. The principal advantaged of drilling are that the is pressed down firmly into the moiri mil, thus neraring ■ J»et- miMbJlMH Ay. "tare^^kT* 10.3 28.8 .I4.3 •'»!&gt; U :)8.'J „ ,-., </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 tor and more uniform germination. Also drilled wheat u to withstand winterkilling somewhat lx*tter. Uowevei tin- shore experiment the l:iinl was plowed early, ;it lea&gt; weeks before Heeding time. time the land is always v. orl - moothing harrow, so that wh thorolv repacked and moist. and there is no lack of moist vere, drilling has little advunl where the plowing is late m i \ el-ill t hues willl II the. W heat is ] Ml t ill, tin Where the seed bed is me and t lie winter* un 1 he w inters are severe, t here i i^ the better method. no uiiest ion i hut drilli It should not lie assiin ii Rn of winter w \wn\ w Cultival ion is (&lt;&lt;i ih I lie \eills for which ill \;lln there W;is no hick of l;li ( (l\ E point liliMlulll Ollt r!i nt w ith oiiis imd ttiieu lire the s;lllle resnMs e; ii-niiil rainfall, \«&gt;&lt;\\ i\ »ats or wheat. When i II leil \car. u \ h&lt; i tnri' a lieiiv\ crop of urain, plants with harrow or pi when precipitation before dry weather follows, eiilth t is cert Iwrisser. (&gt;i leedilll: it ion of \ drilled grain results well. I advantageoiiii even to drill f; in enltivate as thorolv as the r inler \er\ drv cond of tillage in the few experiments conducted at the N Dakota Station and iis failure at the more humid Minm Station are in harmonv with the tesuits al Nebraska. )»ci \\ iM'ii plow inn an ijp'ovcr broadcast sowiui' ir apart, ksi.y twelve wide drilliiiL; n.-nnii </seg>
            <seg id="p019">( I' N rmiriit mall ii tit i hrl-r'ol ivat i 1 vi«-l n ii i i I'.. ving noil moist uu - urn. potatoes ami •h is a Ix-ncHl to a tlieorv. l»iil a well- \;n ion fin- (oiimm iis c|1&lt;mi upon » u'n itirtli mule i. ton 1&lt; l it In- inaiii - ■In n the grain itself srrvoi iM'iii-lit t»» the is in maintaining riinciiis with thi' IS-imh ami 24-inch l''\»M'i i'lirn' Station, as well as similar at the Montana an«l Wyoming Sta rain is not profitably *rown in &lt;li-ills i-iii it i&gt;f ronvfiiiriit inii-rtillairi'. Wid* 1 , im-iiIk to lti' ri'sitiicil to; ami so far tin- us ili'viscd for tin- work an- tin- wii-ili-r ]•!( iinnts, w hili form iii'. r a useful mul&lt; h h'a&gt;- :i!ii jjniin whirli in \\ii ur normal I. Tin' low cf •rrain jilants in theme s«a In n iiki all of i In- grain plants ran Hial the tiiiring oni of plants is a i s'iihiIiI never lie wet then — a light ! il«Mjm' to form a surfaee ninlrli. It ii'ir:h" t 'h • \ ii Id of grain, lmt in years i normal rainfall it decreased tin- yield. i'iith«T is no lunuci- a 1 i ;i !i«h1 ■ iirili mulch, i-Min iii&gt; to t In* time wli i^otiih'. v onhl I'l* of il.inl. Tin- iliffit-nltv &lt; m .1 1 iii'inim; from cultivation, li is I with ili&lt;' ;;« « »&lt; 1 &lt;1&lt;iiic by t ti&lt; ■ cultivation &gt;l' winter lt'm'.i. n'-cssiii^ tin earth ili.ii !i:i\c Ihmii partly liciivcl &gt;r &lt;&gt;\ !n'i*'» 'isv r\|»»&lt;-ii, produci's good rmultx. ml iii:i\ Uc -:iiil to f n i-n i&gt;-i| ;i new rra*on for n. Mii'vcM-r. if ill" uriMnnl i&gt;; not \\H ;il the ii &lt;lii:ll! 'li'lTrr !u FoHll ;l minuet* lUUlrll. II than ronipnH tin- wirfatt*, ami in thi* men xiipuriii i'Mi. in mo (&gt;xporimen&lt; did cnltiva </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE USE OF THE FANNING MILL FOR SELECTING SEED WHEAT AND SEED OATS. li liiis generally been awumcd thai &gt; Ik- separation &lt;&gt;f ti light-weight and small grains from seed wheat would resul in an improvement of the crop prrown, not onlv in quant Inn in quality as well. An experiment was started in I'.mm for the purpose of testing the valm- of the heaviest era wind lilasi, when conm the lightest. Two varieties ta hard winter wheat, and l'.i" Ft w machine used is so constructed tlia w is delivered into an upward wind I carried over 1&gt;\ the wind \\hi!&lt; Wast into a receptacle below. A lot of wheat was separate designated the "Lighter Half and die ■■Heavier II i Lighter Half" was again sepni known as the "Lightest IJirht." The "Hi also separated and the "Heaviest Heav; The same method has been followed from tlic "Lightest Light" was separated into four p cording to weight, and onlv the lightest fourth retained at the rrop from the '•Heaviest I! ■;ivv heaviest fourth retained. To check results another lot wheat has Keen sown continuously with the season of 1904 the wheat was so poor tack of wheat scab, that no separation wa nt separation. due to a Bevel made, hut the from each plat was simply cleaned and sown. Results for eight years are recorded in the following ihh t 20 (teed wlicat ;is sc|»iii-;iti(l li\ </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Fanning Mil &gt;&lt; &lt; &lt;/. 21 per men for light and lit, RK1SH RED WHEAT. .»&gt; 1901 1902 1904 1905 1906 1907 Av. •JiVii IT.: /;«. /.';&lt;. /.«. Bu. Hit :;i 8 u ;s -jo.:) 63.0 51.0 :ii o lit :i •_".•.■; is s 330 ii.e 80.7 t'li.i; 53.5 BIG 1 kAMK WIIHAT Bu Bi 25 s 11 Ru Ha Bu. Bu. flu 12.5 ; ti 50.0 21.2 B 0 25.8 12.3 19.7 B0.5 .Vt.O 1 1 I S Tl'KKISH RED WHEAT. /ill 111! Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. 44(i 62.0 M.O 00.0 12.5 B2.0 61.0 81.0 :,7 36 1 II .."&gt; 61.0 61.0 ■ BIG 1 KAMK WHEAT 1902 Urn; /.'« /.'« B8.6 til. 0 59.0 i 5.".. 3 n. ■» 6 30.0 16.8 S\:l &gt;Y2.:&gt; 51.0 no iso) toe uoa ism mob , wot. ism iii B 17 5 :&gt;:&gt; 0 54.8 BO I usfiel of nop //,," red for five \ears. l!*l_' IMS l'.KM UK).-) 1908 I9OJ A 1!HH 1MB IWa I'.kjT Average. /.•«. II u. Bu. Bu. 39.5 5it.il 80.5 .",!». o 51.7 4u. .-&lt; n ii a.fi r&gt;tt.u </seg>
            <seg id="p022">ll 1. a ii&lt; 1 th M'lril not show litlel u it was 1 w l\ in favor lect ion lo not i n&lt; 1 i It should Tlic tirsi two \ears of tlic experiments, t lie "Lii: produced least, the "ordinary" was next in yiel "heaviest" yielded lust. Since then, results have v year to year, aud the average for the eight years dot a marked advantage for either grade of seed. The weight per bushel has been r&lt; corded in tiv wars, lmt no average difference has been noted. . yean' continnoua nele.'tion by the fanning mill, iile li\ careful cxaminntion in 1M07 to note a tidier the quality or i h i the lijjhl and ln-a\ \ si wmuk at nit i ri' sr \ Band Canada beuriu^ »n this wibjiH-t. A Itnral College, tiiielph, Canada, where I l»eeii compared with metliiim or wit of the principal cereal and root pro uniformly been secured from ih&lt; lai ri'snlts from the small seed. Also i ma 'lit carried on for thirteen years i sr.-ds of .loanelte oats have been n I is»ht -colored seeds, the result has be&lt; i he brrge, Mark seeds The hcciIh foi all selected liy hand, and nut l-y fai not show, however, the yield of tin comparison with the crop not so &gt;■ States a number of experiw years have been reported where large or hea\ pared with small or light seed, with results sli«jh&lt; of the heavier seed. However, where cont innoiis se l&gt;(H&gt;n carried on for more than two years the data &lt; cate an advantage in favor of Vnvv or larsre s i also be noted that in most of the experiments the ( (Juiir a little* \\ i»rk In </seg>
            <seg id="p023">&gt;' I \l the Oh i i 1 N'orth 1» r field The Kau Ml . fix or of imtpaml, I Bulletin 1«! North Dak( Bulletin 59 /■■ her than of the large seed with the original not so selected. meive thai differences might be obtaiued in particularly if wide extremes were selected. rent difference might W&gt; found iii the latter, c selected seed with Straight, unselected stock utical test. i Station,' experiiuentii have ln^'ii carried on for &gt;y pontinuous selection, in which three grades of (1. viz. : "First "fade, the large grains; second ■st grains posting thru the sieve in screening out ile; third, unscreened wheat as it came from the ichine. The average yields for eleven yean show in \ield or quality of grain. Three years' work r difference in the quality of the different grades ilar resulis. In Bumming up, Professor Wil - lie following statements: mis extending over a Berk's of thirteen yean have »' on the average any sain from the use of aecd the small and light grains have been removed hv lining mill, aitho three seasons out of the thirteen le gave largest yie'ds." ota.-' after four years' hand selection and com rg»" and small grains, concluded that the indi i-oni large grains are larger than the individual nail grains, but made no comparison of yields &lt; unlit ions. •as Station, 1 after four years' work with light, mseparated seed, secured slightly increased yields the heavy wheat when the light and heavy were nit no dilli renci when the ordinary unseparated nupnred with the hoavy. 5. Ohio Experiment Station, 1905 ata Report. 1901. Kansas Experiment Station </seg>
            <seg id="p024">liis ver\ ii I) ill I i ■ i.-l tun ir i p. How )&lt;• un ingle plan it will I llie plant point, ten 84 At the Indiana Station, for four vears, lanse m * iverage yield of J.47 bushels more than small seed Iu order to obtain a censes of opinion upon i portant question, a circular letter was addr her 31, 1906, to the various experiment sta! ions in and western states, asking tot an opinion on th • I 'lest ions. 1. Have you any experience or reliable data w prove conclusively iliat the continued use of the f io remove the shrunken and verv lisriit grains from w tend to increase the crop? -'. After the light, shrunken and shriveled gi eitjii natter have been removed from the wh seed, and this practice continued for a t'ect one way or the oilier the yi&lt; Answer* from eight wen 1 i he effect that, except for tl matter and weed s is. both of which in securing a uniform stand, or obn infect the land, there was no good evident ous use of the fanning mill wouh or increase the quantity of the vie] It Btay as well lie plainh stated thai lor \ seed wheat has been reasonably well clean. be expected by the further use of the fanninj tion for seeding. At first thought it would seem that if -like pro the large or heavy seeds should produce the best , r ever, we must recognize the individual plant selection, rather than the individual seed. If a of wheat be taken and the kernels threshed out found that all sizes of kernels are produced by some large and some small. To illustrate this evidence tlmt finiln i- separation of il specific irmvitv of the tn-;mis. thai i machine, no pera*nent improvemen </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 I ■I i n Ucii vvhirli had grown nnd-i" i from each plant, a sample of t went \ -live kef li.lom from each, exeep* with plant No tv-flve were taken in order to twci iiii|&gt;liiiu;. Then catli srrain was weighed ■i^lits tabulated. Hiled in the following table: Ills WIT" whci'i nurserv: ■«l from 200 t&lt;&gt; 100 kernels. All wry i rmls were removed. After thoroly </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 * x i« 3 r. I : i i ■ OB ( I "l i g I 15 3 5 3 5 5 5 5~ s' 3' 3~ q" s' 2' :•' s' 2' c&lt; * * ? ? ? Iliiiiiiiiiiiiliiilliiiii nnnnfnnnnnnnn * ? I ; a g 'i i~ u. g I g «■»- £.5-35 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">/ 2? is stand out clearly in the above table: First rage weight of kernel varies between plants, tin iiiLt from .01' 11 gram to .68011 gram ncs being almost one-half heavier; second, thai i cadi plant vary in size, the larger kernels in inii about twice as beavv as tlie smaller. Not only when whole plant.- an considered, hut in each &gt;f wheat we find a .similar variation. Ten heads of li Red wheat were selected at random from a box of f w li had been harvested from I he jjenrral field. Bach ,\ Iih as i hreslied and the kernels weighed separately. Tin .veil developed and all kernels weighed wen Ael and mature. jrains fi-om c ■ liiains froni each head were also placed in a screen with irhih inch opening*, and, after a vigorous shaking, thoar thru linrl thnnr n mnininn i • i </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Tabi.e XXII.— Tat,/,- skoKimg mveiage si:,- of keruet and %?J* '"' W * °f T "*M *&lt;* ■•/".&lt;/. I/so res* •weight in centigrams. / / I/so , 1Ua ' 1N ° 1 2 .1 \ A 5 I r| 7 c, s ■f kernels. j :&lt; i Average weight t No. passing thru . 12" serein . No. on top . 12" screen 1 Kernel No. 1 Kernel No. 2 Kernel No. 3 Kernel No. 4 '.'.'.'."' Kernel No. B Kernel No. 6 Kernel No. 7 Kernel No. 8 Kernel No. 9 Kernel No. 10 Kernel No. II Kernel No. 12 Kernel No. 13.... '. Kernel No. 14 Kernel No 15. Kernel No. 16. Kernel No. 17. Kernel No. 18. Kernel No. 19. Kernel No. 20 '. Kernel No. -1 Kernel No. 22 K' "W. -- 1 No. 21. 1 No. »».. ...."' Kernel No. 25 '. Kernel No. 26. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">i w het 1 si i ill i t \ i i pa rated l&gt;\ a n. Ki u roi •nels was tat re then mad&lt; ■3 ii separate i\ sack &lt;&gt;t wheat into two lots, lalf, it is evident that not onlv is the im separated into two parts, a portion bill the grain fi'oin mob head is also sep - iiii; into each lot. There is no reason to rgi' grains I'.-iiiii a lisii-r ii-uhir head or plant I lietler than the small, any more than the nil on an e;,r will vidd better than the small, nursery whore the kernels from individual are planted separately, the kernels six inches how I hat the &lt;rraiii8 from a sinjrle plant or head rue to type, tho there is some variation. The if (lie sereeii would tend to preserve in the long ■rneled type of ..heat, is it gives advantage to - hk*h produce the largest average-sized berry. s no evidence m show that there is any rela - ' of berry and yield. A pot experiment ;it the &lt;lio\\( d no difference in the yield of grata from 1 seed from the same plant, all ho the large seed rous plants a! the start. However, under Held usually sow three to tive times as much seed io make a stand If there is an.v difference owth. the weaker tend to lie eliminated 1&gt;V rinieiits have also shown that plants bearing 1 kernels do not produce as large a number of icai a weigh! as those plants bearing kernels ■ medium in Rise. 2 hserve what the result would lie if wheat were riling to weigh! as is done when the wheat is w ind blast, insf.-ad of according to size as with heat plant* from ISM crop were selected at ii &lt; a&lt; h plan! a representative sample of 100 cen. Two salt rotations of different densities ■ up. nsinsf sodium nitrate: i '.hi i </seg>
            <seg id="p030">:;.i was alxini one-third heavier than water. No. - had :i s\ gravity of l.'.V.i. In the lighter solution alioiit 96 per c» the grains sank, while 1 ou tin- (warier only Til pt r .nn lo the bottom. If a lot &lt;&gt;f wheat \\is witarutctl hnlf ami li from each plant would be seuarati'*!, :i |&gt;,iii going int&lt; of the crop from one lot would materially differ from other. Tabu xxiii. ft Nuin floatinu 1 I 1 Rrage mixed nuiple of Tnrkixh B«] wheal is from I.: i. 1 Alioul nine-tenths, however, fall between 1.30 &gt;. Wheal from different plant* will vary some in sp gravity, altho this variation will noi begn*a&lt; when 1 all p have been equally well matured. Also, the differeni ke &lt;peclt 'Hurcau ol Plain Industry. Miillfiin Nil 1 had ;i specific gravity &lt;&gt;f L.31, wliirli u n -;i n-&lt; tha ieoord ing t&lt;&gt; dciisitv. an w.-is th«* inw with N Int. Then- is little reason to U-lieve ilwt 1 1 1&lt; - vivid or nil Solutioi Tlic range of sjMiiiic ii i"; i \ i s \ n( iiic \ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">I !/ II 31 / \u!:!i! therefore have about the same )&gt;• seed. &lt; &gt;f course, since sonic i iiT i him &lt;•! hers, then* sin m Id be a tendency l&gt;i sii\c ,i heavier type of wheat. (i\\c\cr. the fanning mill does nut make clour mi to have a verv marked effect in this direc the heaVKT strain should be more desirable Ilicnltv. however, is that the select ions are not e it is apt to lie a different strain of plants grains each year. For example, one year the ii •hints may Buffer most from drought and are the early plants m-iv suffer most, another year turiug | le next I ants that lodged most, and another time rust determine which plants produce light seeds y. and in all seasons some parts of the Held vheat and other places light. le 1 I I V thiit each year the fanning mill is apt to favor in of wheat. The fact that results have never continuous nw of the machine world con- mdi'ds or thousands of i»laiHs are planted, hoiit si\ iinh&lt;s apart each way. Wh- n the i ire, tliev are al! examined and only a few of i veil. The product of each selected plant is ir several vears. and thnrolv tested until the ■ found. Vlioilt one ounce of seed is se&lt; ured first year, the second year five to ten pounds iml the third year two or three hushels. Kx- V he in-owi * • • iiyi' usimllv being from :i I &gt;&lt; m t l.:{0 imnitinn according to gpecifii trating ilic grain** from * -it &lt; - 1 1 plant i- is tinal plani ili imi.iI nii'tlHMi of inipnivini! ilir ridding power II si! seems to i'c thru Bonw s.\&lt;i&lt;'iu of plnnl sc- •liiiil l»r linjr, :in il is now nllctl. llv this </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 i i I hat I. h shown ;i marked difference in the \ i&lt; !&lt;l ;in&lt;l quality of from different plants. LIGHT Vi:i. Pi 1905 an experiment was started for the par value of light and heavy o;its for swd purpi \ Kherson oats was taken ami means of a wind blast, the lii a receptacle, and (he heavici into a box below. Then (he into two parts, the two being and "Ileaviesi Light." The li two portions obtained being I livided into two eqnal part liter Imlf being blown over part falling njrainst the I lighter half was again div known as the "Lightest Li ■avier half was also divided now ti as ''Lightest !! •I'iinent has been mm "Heaviest Heavy." The .-xp. the same manner since, using The seed was sown at the rat and 1906 and eight perks in 1 avenge results. The plats li with check plats between. !M»T. 'I i\ Table xxi\ fC Kin. Lightest heavj -l lieavv !H Chirk ]&gt;lats 1 The heavy seed has averaged about 1.6 bushels n the very lightest, hut only .7 of a bushel more than the rh plats, which were planted from nnseparated seed. The data indicate that the use of a fanning mill to remove th&lt; AVY &lt;&gt; VTS ■■■&lt; &gt;K S 1 : 1" 1 Lightest lij^lit Mi .&lt;\ iest lij^lit </seg>
            <seg id="p033">r &lt; i&gt;it ;ii rultiv i . 1 1 1 n ltiv iniiiii idea Hollin i ii. in n&gt; immediate effed on the crop, even tho three - ieed be taken out. liur data do not show wli.it &gt;n&lt;j continued selection of Beed mi^hr be, lmt •suits with wheat, very little could be expected. SUMMARY. i i'wn 1. 1 ion of small grain — oats and wheat — paid when ion was lielow the normal. tion proved a punitive disadvantage in seasons of u-tiial precipitation. On the average, cultivating has increased the yield 1 to ."&gt; bushels per acre, it ion of fall wheat has not been profitable. proved a safer method, year in and year out. me. of winter grain always produced a paying in- Id, the average increase being over rive bushels ht-peck seeding of Kherson oati has been the l&gt;le of the measures tried, namely: of the irelve, ami sixteen-peck seediags. other varieties ve same results. erson oat plant tillers freely when thin seeding! t few tillers when twelve or more pecks per acre I Mills farther apart tlw.n sk inches were too wide apart, it under exceedingly dry conditions. Then twelve-inch served licst. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">u PAKT II mill, \\ hen compared with not resulted in iiuprovi of grain. 9. As every w hen |,i the fanning mill ;is inheritance is rmicrn 10. The discussion in Mini in no »vav ilisciiiii- 11. The us,- of h«m S. Tile use of lleav\ results which m.-iv !»■ cxn for removing nhuoxiou* portion trf the seed jjmin is sin it will no dnuht im-n^am- tli need. mill li:is lmi piven incmis*il vi&lt;-Ms </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>