<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00070.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN BIENNIAL REPORT 1929-1930</title>
               <date value="1930">1930</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN BIENNIAL REPORT 1929—1930 h. j. Mclaughlin Secretary of Agriculture </seg>
            <seg id="p002">lkjkl </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Honorable Arthur J. Weaver, Governor. Sir: I herewith submit for your consideration and ap - proval the Biennial Report of the Department of Agriculture for the period from December 1, 1928, to December 1, 1930. Respectfully submitted, h. j. Mclaughlin, Secretary of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">TABLE OF CONTENTS FOR BIENNIAL REPORT 1929-1930 Page No. Letter of Transmittal &#132;;.... 3 Table of Contents 4 General Powers ... T 5-6 Progress of Nebraska Agriculture— l 929-1930.: „... 6-20 Bureau of Animal Industry 21-67 Bureau of Dairies, Food, Drugs and Oil 69-86 Division of Agricultural Seeds 87-96 '■ ■■) Division of Weights and Measures ...... 97-98 Division of Potato and Hay Inspection 99-100 Division of Agricultural Statistics 101-112 Division of Nursery and Apiary 1n5pecti0n.......... .'. 113-138 Financial Statement .......139-142 Publications &#132;..,..........r . ......143-i44 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE General Powers dustrie, liX &lt; "°°' € T^ 0 * o£ cond » c «»K these several m S theTS 't 6 ° f VaIUG t0 thG IS • *? atC; t0 with the Federal Govern - ment m the matter of collecting such statistical informaHon Such department shall include m its publmtions tteTeSs of agricultural, horticultural and like societies, and ofTe stock associations. Such published statistics shaU be the offi cial agricultural statistics of the State ; 4. To encourage the planting of trees and shrubs and th* improvement of farm hom«s generally; distributS t P n r( !t UCe rJ ma^ ufacture bio^cal products to be distributed to live stock producers at the actual cost thereof; 6. To Jnquire into cause of contagious, infectious and communicable diseases among domestic animals and £ means for the prevention and cure of the same; Jo Jk J° *? m . easures necessary for the preservation, SSS^SSS!^ and restoration of fish ' « a ™ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE 8. To see that live . stock and stock yards, and other like places where live stock is confined, housed or fed, are properly cared for; 9. To execute and enforce all laws relating to the in^ spection of foods, drugs, dairy products, oils, commission mer - chants, cider and vinegar, oleomargarine and butterine, sani - tation of premises used for manufacturing and preparation of foods, cold storage ware-houses, paints, seeds, commercial feeding stuffs, live stock remedies, hotels and inns, weights and measures and commercial fertilizers, and from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations and adopt such standards of food products as are necessary and proper to en - force the provisions of this title. The Progress of Nebraska Agriculture, 1929-1930 The biennium, 1929-30, was a period of about average crop production, taking all crops as a whole. The 1929 wheat crop was about the average, while the 1930 crop was the sec - ond highest on record. There were rather extended periods of drouth m both years. The summer drouth m 1930 was most severe m east - ern Nebraska, but the ill effects were partly offset by the heavy reserve supply of subsoil moisture. The 1929 season began with very little reserve subsoil moisture, but the sum - mer rainfall was more evenly distributed. As a result, the pro - duction for the two years was about the same except for One noticeable feature of the two year period was the tendency to lowered production m 1929 as the season advanced and the opposite tendency to increased production as the sea - son advanced m 1930. The final outcome of production m 1930 which generally exceeded expectations must be attributed largely to the splendid reserve supply of subsoil moisture m the spring and early summer and to tillage methods which con - serve the moisture. ' Also, it was a banner year for production m western Nebraska. For the country as a whole, the year 1930 will go down on record among the years of most severe drouth. Part of 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 W ' ■ i Nebraska is the Third Cattle State Nebraska's most important crop section received about as lit - tle rainfall as other drouth regions m the country. Despite this fact, the production. of practically all Nebraska crops is above the five year average. This is concrete evidence as to how well the Nebraska farmer has mastered the problems of a semi-arid climate- through proper cultural methods that conserve the moisture supply. The outstanding feature of the biennium was the very severe reduction m the prices of farm products beginning m the autumn of 1929 and continuing with increasing severity throughout 1930. Before the close of 1930, farm prices had reached the lowest point since the World War. This was a severe blow to Agriculture which had made slow but generally 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE gradual advancement since the deflation which followed the war. By September, 1929, the purchasing power of the farm - ers' dollar had advanced to 92 cents as compared to 75 cents, the previous low point since 1920. In less than a year, the purchasing power of the farm dollar had declined to 73, the lowest since the World War. Before the close of 1930, farm prices had reached the lowest level since 1916. Obviously, such depressed prices have been a severe setback to the indus - try which had been slowly improving since 1920 and had just begun to see a few signs of recovery m the near future. Despite the deplorable farm price situation, the close of 1930 found Nebraska occupying a much more favorable posi - tion from a production standpoint than other agricultural states. While the grain and hay crops had been reduced so heavily m some of the drouth stricken states as to necessitate selling off part of the live stock and importation of hay, Ne - braska had exceeded the average production of crops to such an extent as to be m position, not only to maintain her live stock, but also to increase her breeding and feeding opera - tions and yet have sufficient grain arid feed left to winter live stock shipped m from other states even after shipping out hay to the drouth stricken areas. One favorable result to Nebraska from the widespread drouth was the fine advertising as to the high standing of Ne - braska agriculture. The enviable position of second or third place among the states m the production of staple grain crops, live stock and its products is now recognized throughout the country, and this is bound to react m more rapid progress and development m agriculture as soon as farm prices return to more favorable levels. The latter is anticipated as one result of the business depression, part of which is a direct result of decreased farm buying power. Another result of the business depression which was ag - gravated by the severe drouth and further decreased farm buying power was the recognition of the importance of the farm buying power by other industries. An unfair return to any one of the major industries is bound to react unfavorably 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 / CORN \. / V44.OQOPm.Z \ WINTER WHEAT •/ &gt;P jK /om \ " / \ yALL 771 ME WAY /Z4BQOOOP(m\ / \IS32,OOOfiCRES/ fit* V / Acreage Devoted to Each Crop and Percent of Total Cultivated Area on other industries sooner or later. The effect of the business depression upon industry and the low farm prices which were further aggravated by drouth had revealed the necessity of price "equality" that agriculture has sought for the past dec - ade. Students of economics will admit that the depressed sit - uation of agriculture for the past decade is partly responsible for the present depression of all industries. Agriculture has been living since 1920 on hopes that it would obtain price equality with other industries. It appears that these hopes may yet be realized. Prices of products of other industries have dropped. Labor is accepting employ - ment at reduced wages which means lower production costs 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE The depression has taught the necessity of greater economy and reduced spending for non-essentials so that a greater amount can be reserved for food, clothing and shelter most of which is furnished by agriculture. Agriculture has at last been recognized by the govern - ment to such an extent that at least a start has been made to improve the condition of the farmer, Already there are evidences that something further will be done if the present steps taken for the improvement of agriculture are inadequate. This means that Nebraska, one of the leading agricultural states, and one that is dependent almost entirely upon agricul - ture for its development, will profit most. The live stock, industry has made a somewhat better . showing than the crops. About 70 per cent of the gross farm income m Nebraska is derived from the sale of live stock and its products. Cattle prices reached thse peak of the price cycle and had begun to decline. Despite the gradual price decline, cattle gave a fairly good account of themselves except for the grain-fattened cattle that were sold during the first eight months of 1930. Due to smaller supplies of hogs, prices aver - aged fairly well, but expected advances could not be obtained, due to competition from other meats and the effects of the business depression and unemployment. Sheep prices were maintained quite well until 1930 when the severe price breaks were disastrous to sheep feeders. The dairy industry which had enjoyed one of its most prosperous periods faced a most severe break m price before the close of 1929, and this continued throughout 1930. As a result, milk production was reduced about 10 per cent m 1930. Prices of chickens remained on very high levels until the autumn of 1929 when a marked downward trend took place and extremely low prices prevailed throughout 1930. Eggs remained very high throughout 1929, but the early spring of 1930 saw a decided drop m price until they reached points below pre-war levels. The close of 1930 finds the live stock situation somewhat more favorable with the future prospects considerably brighter. The severe nation-wide drouth had reduced feed- 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 ing operations considerably. Cattle production had been on the increase m Nebraska since 1928. It is probable that the in - crease m cattle m western states may be offset partly by forced marketing m eastern states, due to short crops. This will be of considerable advantage to Nebraska. The cattle feed - ing business looks quite favorable for the present season m view of the reduced feeding operations, cheaper feeder cattle and lower grain and hay prices. The future pork situation appears equally as encouraging or more so.. The spring pig crop is 6 per cent short for the country as a whole. Cold storage holdings of pork are far below the average. Lard stocks are low. Considerable curtail - ment m pork production is expected m many of the states, due to the short corn crop. Nebraska with the present normal pork production and with grain crops above the average is m position to expand pork production and take advantage of the pending shortage which is expected to result m higher prices. Feeder lamb prices have been the lowest for years The year is closing with brighter prospects for lamb feeders than last year. Nebraska is the second largest sheep feeding state and has an abundance of feed. Sheep were not placed m feed lots as early as usual this season, and a much larger propor - tion were purchased through the stockyards instead of coming direct from western ranges to sheep feeders. Gross farm income for the year ending June 30, 1929 reached $496,058,000, the highest since 1920. Farm prices had averaged considerably better for that period, and the farm situation was about the best since the deflation which began m 1920. Unfortunately, the tide turned within about three months, and the business depression which came during the last quarter of 1929 carried down farm prices to much lower levels, resulting m a reduction of the gross farm income for the year;ending June 30, 193.0, to $463,759,000, the preliminary estimate. The record of gross farm income is as follows: 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE GROSS CASH FARM INCOME. 1921-1930 (Year ending June 30) | Value of Sales \% of Total Income Crops and Year Crops Livestock Livestock Crops (Livestock 1921 $160,716,065 $224,611,177 $385,327,242 42~ 58 1922 97,237,464 191,862,381 289,099,845 .34 66 1923 93,997,079 239,635,068 333,632,147 28 72 1924 92,096,617 256,269,845 348,366,462 26 74 1925 120,239,278 308,329,022 428,568,300 28 72 1926 102,723,241 ' 333,382,164 436,105,405 24 76 1927 92,981,112 323,167,781 416,148,893 22 78 1928 156,831,843 314,146,813 470,978,656 33 67 1929 140,681,125 355,376,736 496,057,861 28 72 1930 133,803,560 329,955,997 463,757,557 29 • 71 The setback which agriculture received largely as a result of the business depression was indeed unfortunate. The in - dustry has just begun to reach the dawn of a better day after having survived to some extent, for nearly a decade, one of the most trying times in history. While badly shaken, it is not broken. Recognition at last by Congress, after nearly ten years of agitation, that there is a farm problem and the hopes that agriculture will finally get similar aid that has been given to other industries, is inspiring confidence. This, together with the expected improvement in the general economic situation and the sturdy determination of the Nebraska farmer will win, if farmers bring forth united demands for the needs of their industry. When one considers the great progress that has been made in agriculture in Nebraska in a half century from, almost barren prairie to a state of second or third rank in the pro - duction of grain, live stock and its products, with the many handicaps under which it has labored, he is likely to make an optimistic forecast of the developments within the next fifty years which will take place if agriculture is placed on an equal - ity with other industry. Give agriculture the same protec - tion and aid that has been given to the- great manufacturing industries, and there will come a distribution of wealth that will be to the best future interests of our country. A prosper - ous agriculture is essential to the welfare of any country, and the millions of farm homes which now dot the country should </seg>
            <seg id="p013">GROSS CASH FARM INCOME 1921-1930 GFUn ; GIVEN IN MUUOUS — — — _ : — ___ I &lt;Soo B I j 111 I J I I II II [| II </seg>
            <seg id="p014">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE not be permitted to diminish through denial of equal privileges granted to other industries. As stated previously, farm prices had gone down to pre - war levels before the close of 1930. Even the effects of one of the most severe drouths m history could not check the down - ward trend. Fortunately, the Nebraska farmer had produced crops above the average and is m a position to increase his live stock herds sufficiently to have a larger surplus on hand to meet a possible shortage later that may arise due to a cur - tailment m live stock production on account of the drouth. Taking the situation as a whole, Nebraska agriculture is m better shape than that of the average state, and is probably not excelled by any state m 1930. Live stock contributes 70 per cent of the gross farm income, and for this phase of farm - ing the future looks best. With live stock being maintained and even increased by 1930, the Nebraska farmer will have an advantage of the farmers m other states who will have to build up their herds that the drouth forced to market. The business depression has lowered the level of prices of manufactured products which is favorable to agriculture. Labor may be employed at lower price levels. The combined result of the business depression, unemployment and reduced farm production from the drouth may ultimately result m a price equality between the farmer's products and manufactur - ed products which may finally give agriculture the thing it has attempted to get for nearly a decade. What then of the future of Nebraska agriculture? If one could assume that agriculture would be placed on a price equal - ity with other industry, he could safely predict as great, if not greater progress, during the next half century than the great advancement that has so characterized the past. The Ne - braska farmers are progressive and they farm more econom - ically than any other farmers. Their per capita production is very high. They have mastered the difficulties arising from a semi-arid climate. No better evidence of this can be ob - tained than the production record of 1930 with nearly all crops exceeding their five-year average. Farmers have diversified their crops and live stock. They have developed the live stock 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 industry until it now furnishes over 70 per cent of the gross farm income. Live stock fanning means a permanent and enduring agriculture. No tine can deny that a group of farmers with such a record of performance as outlined m the foregoing paragraph cannot only stand upon their own feet, but they can prosper and furnish a splendid market for the products of the manu - facturer if they can have the same safeguards thrown about their- industry that the manufacturer has enjoyed for years Give agriculture a fair chance, and you will see it grow, pros - per and make strides that have not been attained heretofore It will then furnish increased buying power for manufactured products needed. The advancement made under the handi - caps under which it has labored for nearly a decade is suffi - cient evidence of the future possibilities. While it is possible that the present economic upheaval may result m the betterment of agriculture, the farmer cannot afford to stand by idly and depend on others alone. This is a time for united action. If the action already taken does not bring results, farmers should make a united demand for some - thing else m the same manner that manufacturers did years ago. Experience has taught that self-help is the best help and the farmers must unite m an organized effort with their demands for the things that will place their industry on an equal footing with other industries. Such efforts will win. One Method of Storing Wheat Temporarily " ■ ! ■ '■ ■ 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE GROSS CASH FABH INCOME,* 1029— 1030 (Year ending June 30) *. Gtobb Sales j . Production Quantity I Ay. [ Total 1% of I Marketed ) Price | Value | Total r " . 212.701,000 77,797,500 .77 'times' 42.8 Z &lt;»,9in,000 07,745,450 .02 C 2.138.316 .44 * 2 at ! 78,036,000 8,106,000. .403 3,306,860 "3 ?" ley "."18,000 2,803,600 .50 I.S ft, £ y ' •3,486,000 1,743,000 .764 1,331,632 "o ™ a ' OCS KMWWOO 2,871,000 .544 1_563.«K) l!l „ ha * 3,877,000 191,318 11.00 2,104,860 IS *"?" bccU 1.&lt;K1.000 1,021,013 0.98 7128,672 51 Other crops __ 1,608,000 1.1 All Crop.. 1020 ...._ ...... $140,681,125 .... Iluttcrfut lv cream ............... 80,644,820 .423 34,152,428 06 E &amp;S&lt;» 65,994,895 .238 15,716,832 4^4 Chlckcns ••• 10,244,479 2.9 Beet cattle 1,20T,047 100.70 142,514,580 401 Calves - 59,454 36.83 2,103,258 .6 Ho » 8 5,567,404 23.70 131,074,945 37.1 Bheep and Lambs . 1,528,827 12.15 18,580.214 5.2 All Livestock, 1020 ......... — ;.. $355,376,736 :... Crops &amp; Livestock, 1029 . .. $496,057,861 Corn 235,605,000 67,650,000 $0,680 $46,353,045 34.7 A " whei| t 73,275,000 63,423,000 .086 62,516,111 467 OatB 8«,017,000 11,&amp;SO,000 .376 4,462,640 S3 Barle y 22,330,000 3,007,320 .487 1,932,085 1.4 B J" e 4,995,000 2,142,520 .755 1,617,602 12 rotatoe » 9,400,000 4,345,200 1.175 5.106,360 3.8 AU nn y 15,099,000 189,908 9.869 . 1,874,217 1.4 Sugnr beets 1,001,000 1,062,000 7.000 7,434,000 5 6 Other crops : _.;.._ ..._ 2,477,500 1.9 All Crops, 1030 „„ $133,803,560 Buttcrfat In cream ...; 78,841,820 .338 20,658,640 8.1 EBBS • „„..„ 13,937,687 4.3 sickens 0,617,517 2.0 Beef cattle 1,369,962 101.13 138.544,257 42.1 CaITCS 62,753 34.48 2,163,723 .5 H °BB 5,713,074 22.78 130,144.089 39.4 Bheep and lambs „ 1,381,675 5.62 8,889,184 2.7 All Livestock, 1930 „ :.„_ . $320,055,997 __ Crops A Livestock, 1930 '. ' ... $463,751)!557 • Preliminary. 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA CROPS, 1929— 1130* | Area | Production Value I ' Per Per I Cr °P g I Acres Acre Total \ Unit \ Total Corn 1029 9,U4,000 26.0 237,744,000 Bu. |0.69 $164,043000 __ 103 ° 0,171.000 25.7 235,695.000 Bu. .52 122,561400 Whiter Wheat 192» 3,354,000 16.0 53.664.000 Bu. 09 53127000 1930 3,622.000 10.4 70,267,000 Bu. .51 35,836.170 Spring Wheat 1929 194,000 .14.0 2,801,000 Bu. 00 2 775 000 1930 ISB.OOO 16.0 3,003,000 Bu. .51 IWoSO All Wheat 1029 3.548,000 15.9 66.555.000 Bu. .99 55.902000 M3O 3,810.000 10.2 73.275.000 Bu. .51 37,370550 Oats 1620 2.480.000 34.8 80,304.000 Bu. .38 3*l*ooo ■ 1030 2.485.000 32.2 50.017.000 Bu. .27 21,604.590 Barley 1929 047,000 20.2 18.892.000 Bu. 50 9446000 1930 725,000 30.8 22,330.000 Bu. .33 Kye 1929 262,000 14.1 3,094.000 . Bu. .76 2807000 1030 333,000 15.0 4,995,000 Bu. .34 1,698,300 S " elt 1920 «,000 265 1.057.000 Bu. .50 543000 ■ lt&gt;3 ° «.«» 23.4 1,004000 Bu. .33 331 950 Buckwheat 1929 1.000 11.2 n.OOO Bu. .85 90CO MHO 1,000 8.0 8,000 Bu. . .75 6.000 Flaxseed 1929 17.000 7.0 129.000 Bu. 2.80 361,000 1030 . 24.000 6.0 144,000 Bu. 1.24 178,560 Grain Sorghum 1929 22.000 17.1. 376,000 Bu. 1.00 376,000 1030 17,000 20.0- 340,000 Bu. 90 300000 Potato, Irish 1929 92.000 97.0 . 8,024,000 Bu. 1.10 9,810X00 1930 94,000 100.0 9,400.000 Bu. .85 7,990,000 Hay, Tame 1929 1.532,000 2.33 3.572.000 Tons 10.50 XT,GO6,m 1930 1,611,000 2.37 3,818,000 Tons 9.33 35,659.600 Alfalfa 1929 1,095,000 .2.52 2,759,000 Tons 11.33 31259 000 1030 1.135.000 2.62 2,974,000 Tons 10.60 31,524400 Sudan 1929 59,000 2.30 139.000 Tons 650 004 000 1030 59100 ° SAS Us '°°° TonB 00 ° 87o!oOO Millet 1929 60.000 1.72 103,000 Tons 6.00 018000 1030. 59,000 1.82 107.000 Tons 5.50 588,500 Clover, Bed 1029 70.000 1.90 133,000 Tons 10.00 1330,000 1930 93,000 1.77 165,000 Tons 9.90 1,633,500 Clover, Sweet 1929 105.000 1.99 209.000 Tons 700 14630C0 ™ m. „ 109.000 1.80 196.000 Tons 6.00. 1.17&amp;000 ao..Tlm.Mx. 1929 64.000 1.64 105,000 Tons 9.50 WoOO . 1930 80,000 1.59 127,000 Tons 0.70 1,231,900 Grninforhay 1929 34,000 1.00 54,000 Tons 6.00 375 000 n^.n, 103 ° 3 ° loo ° IJSa 48 ' 000 Tons 5-50 253.000 Other Tamo 1020 23,000 150 34,000 Tons 5.50 238000 „',,.•• 193 ° 28.000 1.11 31,000 Tons 8.00 2451000 Timothy 1029. 19,000 1.49 2aooo Tons 0.50 2C9000 , 1030 15.000 1.48 22.000 Tons 9.50 2091000 An! Legume 1929 3,000 2.50 8,000 Tons 6.90 62000 1930 3.000 1.66 5.000 Tons 0.50 32 500 Hay Wild .1029 3,048.000 .87 2,652.000 Tona 740 10 625000 1930 3.078,000 .85 2,616.000 Tons 7.00 l&amp;W.'ooo All Hay 1929 4,580,000 1.36 0,224,000 Tons 9.18 57131000 1930 4,659,000 1.37 6,434,000 Tonß 8.27 53,209,180 Sugar Beets 1929 92,000 11.5 1,054.000 Tons 7.00 7377000 1930 81,000 13.97 . 1,132,000 Tons 7.00 7WOOO Sorgh. Forage 1929 152,000 2.5 380,000 Ton* 6.50 - 470000 1930 137.000 2.9- 397,000 Tons 5.00 1,985,000 Sorghum Syrup 1929 2,000 90. 180.000 Gals. 1 00 180000 1930 2.000 80. 160,000 Qalg. 1.00 i^OOu </seg>
            <seg id="p018">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE NEBRASKA CROPS, 1020—1030* | Area | Production ■\~ Value I . Per I ■ T Per ■ ~ Crops ) Acres Acre | Total | Unit Total Clover Seed Hod lteo 22,000 1.0 35,000 bu. $11.00 $355,000 1930 24,000 1.8 43,000 Bu. 11.30 483,000 Clover Seed Sweet 1020 21,000 4.3 00,000 Bu. 3.10 270.000 1030 25,000 4.4 110,000 Bu. ; 3.00 330,000 Alfalfa Seed 1029 30,000 2.8 84,000 Bu. ' 11.75 057.000 1030 32,000 2.8 00,000 Bu. 10.00 954,000 Millet Seed 1029 3,500 12.8 . ; 45,000 Bu. 1.25 50,250 1030 . 4,000 15.7 03,000 Bu. 1.00 03,000 Sweet Clover Other thnn Hay 1029 . 1030 017,000 . Beans, Dry Edible 1020 0,000 0.4 55,000 Bn. 3.75 310,000 1930 10,000 11.8 118,000 Bu. 3.20 377,000 Popcorn 1!H'» 13.000 075.0 10,725,000 Lbs. .025 205.000 1030 11,000 1248.0 13.725.000 Lbs. .02 274,560 Aiiples, Com'l IU2O . 00,000 Bbls. 4.20 378,000 miO 50,000 Bbls. 5.00 250,000 Apples, Total 1920 SOS.OOO Bu 1.40 1,215,000 1930 402,000 Bu. . I.GO 730,200 Peaches 1020 , 08,000 Bu. 1.65 112.000 1030 31,000 Bu. 1.75 54,250 Pears 1029 40,000 Bu. 1.50 00,000 1930 . 27,000 Bu. 1.50 40,500 Grapes ]02!t 2,125 Tons 57.00 121,000 . 1030 1,825 Tons . 50.00 91,250 Total 1929 . 347,059,250 1030 200,104,420 •Preliminary, 1030. VIVE-YEAU CBOF AVERAGES, 10SS— 1020 j ; Value Crop | Acres Yieia Production Frlce | Dec. 1 Acre | : Total Corn S.oofi,ooo 24.85 223,550,000 Bu. $0.00 $10.40 $140,970,000 Winter Wheat 3,135,000 16.02 52,110,000 Bu. I.OS. 17.95 56,239,000 Spring Wheat 185,000 15.05 2,890,000 Bu. 1.05 16.43 3,048,000 All Wheat 3,321,000 10.53 54,907,000 Bu. 1.08 17.85 59,256,000 Oats 2,510,000 28.50 • 72,300,000 Bu. .38 10.94 27,474,000 Barley 3,500,000 . 28.50 10,164,000 Bu. .52 14.82 5,309,000 Uye 249,000 13.19 3,254,000 Bu. .76 10.02 2,450,000 Grnln Sorghum 24,000 17.50 420,000 Bu. .84 14.70 353,000 Potatoes 88,000 89.85 7,907,000 Bu. 1.03 94.34 8,280,000 Susar Beets 80,000 12.41 993,000 Tons 0.01 111.81 7,147,000 Alfalfa 1,215,000 2.35 2,S0o;0O0 Tons 11.00 .27.26 33,183,000 Tame Hay 1,048,000 21.85 3,597,000 Tons 10:00 23.79 39,236,000 Wild Hay 2,903,000 .83 '. 2,422,000 Tons 7.02 65.74 10,184,000 All Hay 4,551,000 1.32 6,019,000 Tons 9.70 12.80 58,384,000 Apples 608,000 Bu. 1.49 9,982,000 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 LIVESTOCK, JAN. 1, ESTIMATES, 1928— 1930 | MILK COWS | OTHER-CATTLE Year Average I Total Average I — Tola! Number Value | Value Number Value ] Value 1921 (i(HJ,000 $57.00 $34,542,000 2,018,000 $3060 $S01»4 000 1024 C12.000 06.00 34.2T2.000 2,774.000 20.50 ffl 734 000 1023 025,000 54.00 33,750.000 2.GS0.00O 28.80 77^000 102&lt; &lt;J13,000 uo.00 33,715,000 2,200,000 32.04 70,073 000 1028 ■ 013.000 71.00 43.523,000 2.153.000 43.21 03 020000 1029 610,000 84.00 51,090.000 2.312.000 52.34 l'l'oS&amp;OOO 1030 O3S.O0O 70.00 50,402,000 2,410,000 48.41 116,871,000 LIVESTOCK, JAN. 1, ESTIMATES, 1923—1930 J SHEEP SWINE " Y * nr I I Average | Total | "" Average ToTal I Number | Value | Value | Number Value Value 1023 840.000 .$S.0O ?O.72O,O0O 5.038,000 $12.00 $67,650000 1924 800,000 7.!)0 6,320,000 5.9S3.0OO 10.00 59,S3O,O00 1920 780,000 10.30 8,103,000 4,81S,00O 13.20 03,598.000 1928 810.000. ' 10.30 8,353,000 4,700,000 17.00 82 820000 1027 GS4.000 8.70 5,929,000 4,597,000 10.50 SWOlioQO 1025 a03,000 9.10 8.212,000 5.492.000 13.50 85,230.000 1029 1,000,000 9.50 0,055,000 5,327.000 15.00 79.715.000 1930 1.20S.000 8.20 9,S6O,0O0 3,274,000 15.70 S2,853,00O I.HK.STOCK, JAX. 1, ESTIMATES, 1823— 19S0 1 HORSES- | MULES = Year Average Total Average Total . Number Value Value Number Value Value 1923 882,000 $59.00 $52,472,000 120.000 $75.00 $8,908.000' 1024 832.000 57.00 48,754,000 121,000 73.00 8,882.000 - 1023 802,000 58.00 40,773,000 120,000 74.00 S.932,000 1926 840.000 . 61.00 50,931,000 120,000 7S.00 0 398 000 1027 .815,000 50.00 .43,458,000 HS.OOO G9.00 8,133,000 1925 789.000 60.00 46,868,000 110,000 75.00 8,210000 1029 772,000 61.00 48,778,000 101,000 70.00 7 704 000 1030 ■ 757,000 61.00 45,819,000 08,000 70 00 7453 000 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE MARKET RECEIPTS OF LIVESTOCK FJiOJI NEBRASKA 1921—1039 | CATTLE j HOUS j" SHEEL' |Oi]ialin| Other I | Omulia I Otlior I Omaha Other |Kec'pt»|MnrketB) Total | Itec'pts | Mnrhetß ) Totnl Rec"pts Markets Total 1021 83.1,930 340,080 1,200,025 2,017,187 1,505,300 3,5 M,180 818,442 217,019 1,035,461 1922 l,0«!,300 387,525 1,390,825 2.218.G59 1,940,221 4.1C0.418 886,854 217,293. 1,303447 1023 1,018,478 428,501 1,446,979 2,820,541 2,375,514 5,790,055 1,013,262 347,401 1,360,663 1924 1,156,338 537,890 1,694,828 3,106,413 3,304,000 0,470,073 1,030,495 257,781 \ 1,281,270 1923 1,099,870 522,919 1,022,789 2,535,808 3,110,130 5,601,99S 796,212:319,768 1,115,980 1920 1,232,022 fi31,503 1,803,825 1.970.053 2,900,837 4,570,920 017,002 327,403 1,245,395 1927 909,422 445,344 1,304,706 1,866,236 2,577,970 4,444,200 900,922 283,179 1,200,101 1028 071.806 457,235 1,429,101 2,300,468 3,382,000 5,085,02S 1,038,085 324,382 1,362,467 W29 971,435 431,839 1,403,274 2,430,966 3.350,0G3 5,823,029 1,129,130 374,757 1,503,85T M Ci^+r-r-:rr2^M BBS ViM^. Y^ttzXlSn Hi II B * ~ : "' c^dk B'vB RUM HI II : iV^rafll ■' Conditions are Ideal for Poultry m Nebraska 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">BUREAU OF ANIMAL INDUSTRY C. H. Hays, Chief GENERAL STATEMENT The Nebraska Department of Agriculture has been ac - tively engaged, m a number of ways during the biennial period covered by this report, for the protection of the health of livestock against the infections of communicable diseases to which domestic animals may be susceptible. This work as provided for by statute has been directed and carried on through the activities of the Bureau of Animal Industry. Al - though the work of the Department m this particular has been somewhat general m its scope, the greater share of the time and expenditures have been given to the eradication of certain specific diseases, especially to tuberculosis and scab - bies or mange. The eradication of these two infections have been the object of definite projects carried forward m keeping with " the basic principles and methods adopted m the previous bi - ennium, but which have been greatly intensified and extended during the present biennium. A limited but specific project has been applied against swine diseases, more particularly with reference to hog cholera, though not to a similar degree as m the other two projects. Services other than specific pro - ject activities have been largely a matter of special investi - gations and visits to outbreaks of disease to assist m diag - nosis, and to recommend or direct control measures. Abor - tion disease and anthrax have been given special considera - tion. Attention has also been given through the applica - tion of quarantine regulations to protect against disease that may occur through the importation of livestock into the state or from transportation of animals within the state. In the project work for the control and eradication of tuberculosis, of scabies and of hog cholera, and m numerous special investigations to meet existent emergencies, the De - partment has had the cooperative assistance of the United </seg>
            <seg id="p022">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE States Bureau of Animal Industry, such relations being with the state bureau. The success which has obtained under these several different projects must be credited m a considerable measure to the cooperation had from that federal department. This cooperation was made possible by departmental arrange - ments under certain memoranda of understandings had with the United States Bureau of Animal Industry. Valuable aid has also been received from the Department of Animal Path - ology and Hygiene of the State Agricultural College. Confi - dences established and maintained with the livestock industry through various farm organizations and individual owners, and related livestock interests have had much to do m ad - vancing the work of the Department for successful services rendered. No changes have been effected m the statutes or by reg - ulations pertaining to animal disease, since the last biennial report was submitted by the Department, that affect depart - mental duties relating to the protection of the health of live - stock. One change m the livestock laws, however, was ef - fected by the Legislature of 1929 giving an increase m the amount of reimbursement which may be paid from state funds to owners of cattle determined by the Department to be affected with tuberculosis and caused to be destroyed on that account. This increase was m the maximum indemnity payable, from $15.00 to $25.00 on a grade animal and from $30.00 to $50.00 on a purebred animal. This legislative ac - tion removed cause of some apparent dissatisfactions from that account and gave encouragement to greater progress m the eradication of animal tuberculosis. . TUBERCULOSIS The eradication of animal tuberculosis m Nebraska has been almost wholly confined to the disease among cattle. However, the effects are not restricted within that species of livestock, because of the susceptibility of other animals, and of man, to the bovine type of tuberculous infection, which is especially true m regard to swine. Departmental atten - tions directed against tuberculosis as a disease among poul - try has been somewhat limited yet the effects have been rather potent and a marked decrease of the disease has been re- 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 Nebraska Milk Production Increased 74% During the Past Decade ported which may be credited m a measure to such efforts as were expended through suggestions advanced by the De - partment. Any reference to methods and plans which have gov - erned the organized campaign against tuberculosis must nec - essarily be a repetition to reaffirm what has appeared m prev - ious reports and reviews of the work. The same fundament - als of livestock sanitation and hygiene have governed: to wit (1) the determination of tuberculous cattle by means of the tuberculin test; (2) the destruction by slaughter of cattle thus found to be affected with the disease; and (3) the clean - ing and disinfection of premises contaminated with the in - fection of tuberculosis. These have been applied as a part of the specific work expended under either the accredited herd or the county area plan, or through private service by authorized practicing veterinarians upon request of owners desirous of establishing their herds tuberculosis-free or to meet requirements m the sale of breeding stock or dairy products. The efforts to establish tuberculosis-free herds of areas have without exception been the result of organized eradication work. Work under county area plan has account - ed for the great volume of testing of cattle completed, which otherwise translated means eradication. 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE A summary of the tuberculin testing of cattle completed during the biennium, December 1, 1928, to November 30, 1930, inclusive, has been compiled and is presented as Table I. This has been arranged to show the testing under the different plans as well as by years, and also the number of herds and cattle tested, the number of cattle classified to be reactors (tuberculous) and the number of herds which contained tu - berculous cattle (infected herds). The greatest number of cattle tested in any one month was during October, 1930 when a total of 62,506 cattle comprising 8,181 herds were tested. i . , • •"'..-'; TABLE I — TESTS OF CATTLE FOR TUBERCULOSIS Part 1— December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inclusive Tested Reactors Infected Plan of Testing Herds Cattle Cattle Herds County Area 28,521 404,435 2,496 1,437 Accredited Herd 105 4,938 19 7 Private Service 4,793 38,359 279 177 Total Testing. 33,419 447,730 2,794 1,621 Part 2 — December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inclusive County Area 29,250 454,050 2,632 1,406 Accredited Herd 84 4,326 1 1 Private Service 3,759 26,653 224 89 Total Testing 33,093 485,029 2.H67 1,496 Part 3 — December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1930, Inclusive County Area 57,771 858,485 5,128 2,843 Accredited Herd 189 9,264 20 8 Private Service 8,552 65,012 503 266 Grand Total 66,512 932,761 5,651 3,117 County Area Testing On December 1, 1929 there were forty-five (45) counties in Nebraska which had been established testing areas as pro - vided for under statutes for the eradication of bovine tuber - culosis. This number had been increased to fifty-three by November 30, 1930. A map of Nebraska has been included as a part of this report, shaded and otherwise marked to show the extent and relative position of these testing areas. The </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 county testing areas represent fifty-eight per cent of the total number of counties (93) m the state, and they pos - sessed 52.8 per cent of the total cattle population m Nebraska measured by the livestock assessments for 1930. There were m 1930 a total of 1,310,821 cattle m the area of these coun - ties of the total cattle population m the state numbering 2,478,206 head. The continuity with only limited intercep - tions m the area of testing presents very decided advantages for success m maintaining as well as establishing tuberculo - sis-free herds and areas. This also makes for greater econ - omy m operations necessary to obtain such status. The fifty - three county testing areas which had been established by de - partmental order to date of November 30, 1930 are as fol - lows: Hamilton, (A) Hitchcock, Harlan, (A) Jefferson.^A) Johnson (A) Kearney, Knox, (A) Lancaster, Madison, Nance (A) Eaha A Polk' /A) ) £dwnJ n l A) /iW 1 ?' i A) P , h * e ! ps ' ? ierce - platte A) i s T'o ( ' ,a , w ' 110w &gt; &lt; A &gt; Richardson, (A) Saline, (A) Saunders (A) Sarpy, (A) Seward, Stanton, (A) Thayer, (A) Thurston (A) Wayne (A) Washington, Webster; (A) Yorkl-Total 53 countieV hpp^i^-fij 6 . 0 u ng * f?"? 1 / 2 I *,? 6 indicat es that such county has -Total 43 cJuSies 6 ' 8 ° dlfied Tuberc »losis-free Accredited Area! Accredited Tuberculosis-Free Areas New work completed or commenced during the period of .this report included the initial and first general test of all herds m. ten different counties of the group listed, namely, m Adams, Buffalo, Cuming, Franklin, Frontier, Knox, Madi - son, Nance, Platte and Webster. Retests were also completed during the same period by which five of these counties have been officially certified to be modified tuberculosis-free ac - credited areas. Testing has not been commenced m four of the counties of the group recently established testing areas, namely, Antelope, Harlan, Pierce, Stanton, but can be ar - ranged for m a part or all of these early m 1931. In addition to the initial testing cited, m seven other counties retests completed made possible the accreditation of the same. The counties not certified to be Modified Tuber- 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">MAP NO. 1 Extent of Testing of Cattle for Tuberculosis m Nebraska Under the County Area Plan to Date of November 30, 1930 ayj^Sy&amp;affffS^^ . MADISON STMTOH CUMJMS fk ■ H J ' " i 1 • J ' I ' A A I A A A cask jon/tsoH l#r*owk . fompLJM™ *"' CMCOC * Ktomuort \h*has bV»ila// franklin wcisrca \Duc*oiisirnAyi/t icmmoH A | *V White Area — County Testing Areas Established under Statutes - - WBM . Total 53 "A" Counties: — Certified Tuberculosis-free Areas - - - - - - - T0ta1............."..:...".!43 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">MAP NO. 2 Showing Extent of Testing of Cattle for Tuberculosis m several of the Central States Under the County Area Plan to date of November 1 1930. ' White Area— Counties Established Testing Areas by Official Order. "A" Counties— Certified to be Modified Tuberculosis-free Accredited Areas by state and federal official order. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE culosis-free Accredited Areas prior to December 1, 1928, but so certified during the. biennial period of this report, num - bering twelve (12), were as follows: Adams, Boone, Buffalo, Cuming, Dawson, Dixon, Douglas, Franklin, Frontier, Kear - ney, Sarpy, Washington. The total of county testing areas m Nebraska which have been accredited numbered forty - three (43) on November 30, 1930, the names of which m the group previously listed are indicated by (A) preceding the name. This was an increase from thirty-eight on November 30, 1929 and from thirty-one on November 30, 1928. In addition to testing for initial accreditation, the use of which word should be accepted as snyonymous with eradi - cation, retests were applied m a total of twenty-four (24) county testing areas for the purpose of maintaining such territory m the official status of accredited tuberculosis-free. In this reaccreditation of county areas either a part or all of the herds and cattle m such areas were tested," but m no instance less than fifty per cent and m the greater number all herds were retested. A practice was established to test all herds m the precincts where the incidence of infection had been one per cent or greater on the last previous test of the cattle of such area. In these areas any herd which had on previous test contained reactor cattle was retested if said herd remained m the county. All herds producing milk for sale for human consumption as such, m so far as the same could be determined, were likewise tested. These were usu - ally herds located immediate to the towns and villages. The following is a list of county testing areas reaccred - ited during the biennial period: Burt, Butler, *Cass, Colfax, Dakota, Dodge, *Fillmore, *Gage, Gosper, Hall, Hamilton, ♦Johnson, *Lancaster, *Otoe, *Pawnee, Perkins, *Phelps, Polk, Red Willow, *Saline, *Seward, Thayer, Thiurston, York. Tests of only a part of the herds were applied m those coun - ties of which the name is preceded by this sign *, total ten. There will be a total of thirty-two counties m Nebraska for reaccreditation during the biennial period 1931-32 under the terms of the present uniform methods and rules governing this work. 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">• BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 Hi m B Nebraska Ranks Fourth m Production of Creamery Butter Personnel Engaged m County Area Testing The number of veterinarians employed by the Depart - ment and by the United States Bureau of Animal Industry m the testing m county areas m Nebraska is shown by Table 11. It will be noted that three subdivisions have been made classifying the veterinarians so engaged as Federal, State and Private. Those indicated as federal and state were full time employees while the private vetrinarians^were author - lzed veterinarians m private practice who could be engaged 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE only part time m the area work and. who were employed on a per diem basis. Practicing veterinarians were usually en - gaged on a four day a week basis but were rarely available for a full month of service even under such arrangement. TABLE II — SHOWING NUMBER OF VETERINARIANS ENGAGED ON COUNTY AREA TESTING Part I—December1 — December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inclusive nriims — ■ : — : : : Dec. Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. I * Federal 12 11 11 11 10 11 10 11 0 10 11 10 Stiite ,_. 10 10 18 ' 18 IS .18 17 17 17 18 10 15 •Private 8 S 14 11 12 10 11 ' "3 3 3 0 10 Total 30 35 43 43 40 39 38 33 29 31 33 33 Part 2 — December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inclusive. Vcterln- JD2O l!) 30 ' iirlans : : : (- Dec. Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May June July Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Federal 11 10 10 9 8 9 10 ft 10 9 S 9 State 10 10 15 16 15 15 15 15 15 16 10 . 10' ♦Private 10 S 10 10 « 5 2 SOS 9 ". 11 Total 37 34 35 35 .29 29 27 27 31 33 33 36 •"Private" were practicing veterinarians engaged on per alem basis, the flg- - uri-H representing the number of different practicing veterinariiins employed though only for limited number of days of the month specified. Field Operating Expense County Area Testing As referred to m previous reports submitted by the Bu - reau of Animal Industry, it is deemed well to include a state - ment of field operating expenditures under county area test - ing because of the economics as relate to the public service involved. The items of expenditures listed under Table 111 do not include the cost of supplies such as equipment, tags for identifying cattle tested, report forms and other such in - cidentals, but does include the cost of all services direct and indirect required to organize, the testing work, test the cat - tle, and supervise the disposal of reactors and disinfection of premises contaminated by reason of having contained tuber - culous cattle. 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">. BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 table : m iKra5B8^e88^iffi* plan ™ tt Part 1— December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inclusive From State Funds From Federal Funds Month Salaries Subsistence Transportation Salaries Subsistence December ........$3009.79 $1085.21 $1671.76 $2690.80 $62010 J a " uaf y 3520.63 1046.85 2886.32 2886 36 691 59 * ebruar y • 3662.50 875.05 2370.32 2520.80 651 65 March ;... 4370.37 1022.73 2655.40 2491 91 64899 AP"1 4045.50 923.45 2154.80 2604^ 585 8? May 4169.71 1000.09 2229.02 2424 69 72272 June 3810.00 873.38 1814.10 2B20JO 730 ?? . ™y ■■■:- • 3153.61 706.90 1314.06 2726.89 53412 Au S ust u 3493.55 1120.88 1891.02 2658 28 456 19 September 3428.33 978.51 1938.06 2491.89 474 80 O ctobe r 3138.90 1031.00 1817.82 2370 25 714 61 ' November 3473.70 938.10 1808.88 2728.28 612.59 12 months $43276.59 $11602.15 $2455156 $30815.08 $7443.90 Part 2— December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inclusive From State Funds From Federal Funds Month Salaries Subsistence. Transportation Salaries Subsistence December ......$ 3482.54 $ 840.51 -. $1688.88 $2508.01 $64418 January 3380.00 842.18 1721.64 2516.06 648 30 February 3168.32 827.05 1902.60 2524.40 57225 Ma «h 3411.37 902.02 1790.82 2465.52 684 25 fpnl 3303.00 924.99 1792.92 2302.74 620 10 May 3206.00 941.94 1824.82 2511.63 762.57 June 2867.00 864.55 . 1737.06 2762.74 731.52 July • - 3007.35 781.75 1249.80 2642.74 345.71 August :... 3413.00 871.80 1764.78 2763.85 540.31 September 3649.65 1004.00 1794.96 2380.25 448 75 October 3758.81 1137.99 1866.54 2217.20 503.23 November ..■■■■ 4085.00 960.75 1864.70 2480.51 605.52 12 months......$40732.04 $ 9889.53 $20999.52 $30075.65 $7106.69 A summary to ascertain average costs of services was also cqmpiled of area testing but covering calendar year periods. Such compilations show that the costs for similar . items to those of Table III during the twelve months of 1929 totaled $103,019.19, during which period a total of 409,272 cattle, comprising 28,752 herds, were tested under the county area plan, making the average cost a fraction over twenty - five cents per animal. A similar report for the calendar year 1927 shows the per animal test was made at a cost of 30.1 cents, and for 1928 at 29.5 cents. The average per animal </seg>
            <seg id="p032">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE cost chargeable for refund by the counties m which testing was applied, as provided for under statutes, shows that there has been a proportionate reduction m that particular. Of these costs, the part refunded by counties for 1929 averaged approximately six cents per animal test, while m 1927 and 1928 this part averaged approximately eight cents per animal tested. These costs are variable and dependent upon many factors some of which may be classed as controllable, others not controllable. The maximum that may be required of any county is fixed by statute at 15c per head on the animals tested m the given county. This should not be reduced though the figures presented might indicate such possibility. Indemnity and Salvage on Reactor Cattle Cattle classified to be reactors to tuberculin test were destroyed by slaughter, the same under supervision of the meat inspection service of the United States Bureau of Animal Industry at different market centers where such inspection is maintained but more at Omaha and Sioux City than elsewhere. This has been m accord with statutory and departmental re - strictions governing the handling and disposal of such diseased livestock, and has applied m every instance where any bovine animal was determined to be tuberculous irrespective of how that determination was made. A compilation has been made, from month to month as reactor cattle were destroyed on account of tuberculosis, to show the disposition of the carcasses of the same as to whether passed for food purposes or not. The record on 5,256 reactor cattle slaughtered during the period December 1, 1928 to Oc - tober 31, 1930 shows that the entire carcasses of 389 cattle were condemned as unfit for food on account of extensive or generalized tuberculosis ; that the disease had extended to a degree m 143 of the other cattle among the reactors to cause the sterilization of the carcasses under supervision after all diseased part had. been removed and condemned before such carcasses were released for food purposes; that the carcasses of the other part were passed for food purposes after the diseased parts were removed, and destroyed against use for food. 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Reimbursement provided for by statutes as indemnity on cattle caused to be slaughtered on account of tuberculosis paid during the period covered, December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1930, amounted to a total of $202,485.90. The federal gov - ernment under its cooperation with the state through the United States Bureau of Animal Industry shared in this re - imbursement to the extent of $90,631.36, the remainder being paid from state funds. The state expenditure on indemnity may be divided into two parts, $97,979.72 for reimbursement • on cattle determined to be tuberculous under cooperative work and $13,874.82 on cattle so determined as a private service by practicing veterinarians. The owners of the cattle slaughtered on account of tuberculosis derived a net total of $257,280 85 as salvage from the sale of carcasses, or parts thereof Of this amount $233,944.17 was oh reactors to cooperative tests and $23,336.68 was on reactors to private tests. Table IV— Indemnity Reimbursement to Owners of Cattle Reactors to Tuberculin Tests. Period Nebraska United States Total December 1, 1928 to ' DeSbTvT, 3 &amp;9 9 t 2 o " ■" ? 47 '° 77 -" ? 35 ' 672 - 09 * . November 30, 1930 ...,. 64,776.55 54,959.27 119,735.82 Totals - $111,854.54 $90,631.36 $202.485.90 Tuberculosis Incidence and Herd Morbidity Among Cattle in Nebraska The incidence of tuberculosis, which is to say the per - centage of cattle of a given group determined as result of tuberculin test or otherwise to be tuberculous, and the herd morbidity rate as expressed in percentage of herds which con - tain tuberculous cattle, more especially the herd morbidity are important in any estimate to be made of the progress had m eradication work. In the reports covering the biennial periods 1925-26 and 1927-28, a table was incorporated showing the results of the initial or first general test in the several different counties of Nebraska established testing areas, com - pleted to date covered by the respective reports. To carry forward this record and thus present a more complete repre - sentation of tuberculosis incidence and herd morbidity rates </seg>
            <seg id="p034">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BSSBsiMMdUM^ ii ■! iii ~ **"~ Ii»- -&gt; • I ■•" S! r7^- ' i FirSirfH IWrTSiS^i ' gfiyf" ?~STTiMir iry^MßMSSfiTiMffi 1 Nebraska is One of the Leading Cattle Producing and Feeding States m Nebraska there have been included under Table V similar results m eight additional counties making a total of forty-six (46) reported on to date of November 30, 1930. Table V — Results of the Initial and First General Test of Cattle for Tuberculosis m Counties Established Testing Areas Completed. - Part I—From1 — From December, 1928 to November, 1929, Inclusive. Tested Reactor Cattle Herds Infected County Herds Cattle Number Per Cent Number Per Cent Adams 1473 .13,804 236 1.70 169 11.47 Buffalo 2343 35,188 297 .84 ■ 170 7.25 Cuming 1910 36,838 463 1.25 207 10.83 Franklin 1374 23j064 259 1.12 131 9.53 Frontier 1307 29,670 159 .53 101 7.72 Knox 2525 49,676 559 1.12 290 11.48 Madison 1908 30,066 297 .98 159 8.33 Platte 2197 38,000 290 .76 123 5.59 Eight Counties -- 15037 256,306 2560 .99 1350 8.9 Part 2— Completed to Date of November 30, 1930. Counties 81,867 1,120.488 13,572 1.2 7,303 8.9 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Progress m Eradication of Bovine Tuberculosis It seems, pertinent to incorporate m this report certain matters which evidence, and become a partial measure of the progress made m the eradication of bovine tuberculosis m the state by reasbn of the organized work which it has been the privilege of the Nebraska Department of Agriculture to di - rect. The fact of tuberculin tests on cattle, followed with the destruction of tuberculous infected animals thus determined extended as has been the work to include a large area of the state must be correctly accepted as evidence of an accomplish - merit for the specific purpose intended, the eradication of bovine tuberculosis. However there are somewhat more pre - cise measures by which the gauge of the progress may be established. A review; of the testing completed during the successive calendar years since organized work was inaugurated m 1918 (see Table VI) shows a gradual but constant reduction m the percentage incidence of tuberculosis among cattle. These per - centages do not apply to the state as a whole for there is yet a considerable area of unknown incidence. Whatever is said regarding this unknown area must be an estimate, speculative m the greater degree. . The higher incidence shown by records of the earlier work may partly be accounted for because efforts were then limited to more or less known seats of infection. However, there were m certain counties a comparatively high average general in - cidence and herd morbidity rate as shown by results of a partial, and m a few a practically complete test of the herds m. such county areas, applied under a modified area plan dur - ing 1921-22. Tests under such plan m Douglas County for instance showed a 5.8 per cent, infection, m Sarpy County a fraction over four per cent., m Washington County 4 5 per cent., and m Clay County 3.5 per cent. By. later testing m a number of counties an incidence as high as 2.5 per cent with all herds included m test has been disclosed. The removal and proper destruction of 38,571 reactor cattle to prevent the spread of tuberculosis as has applied, each a potential spread - er of the infection of the disease, must be acknowledged as a 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE very potent factor for a reduction m the hazards and dangers that would otherwise obtain from the disease. Table Vl— Summary of Cattle Tested m Nebraska Period— l9lB to November, 1930, Inclusive Year . No. Cattle Tested Reactors Per Cent 1918 984 62 6.3 1919 18,315 1204 5.5 1920 : 49,792 2002 4. 1921 . 124,292 ' 3067 2.5 1922 203,532 5704 2.5 1923 50,507 854 1.6 1924 211,835 '. 3276 1.&amp; 1925 .... 361,706 4470 1.3 1926 476,841 5140 1.1 1927 .• 413,721 3876 .9 1928 368,445 3601 1. 1929 461,855 2832 .6 1930 (eleven months) . 447,232 ' 2483 .5 3,189,057 38571 In order to preserve for counties their standing as ac - credited areas, it is required under the uniform methods and rules adopted to govern the work that retests be made each three-year period after the initial accreditation to prove with - in a reasonable degree of safety the incidence of tuberculosis among the cattle therein. Dependent to a degree upon the incidence m the area at the time the initial test was applied, testing for reaccreditation may be required of only a part of the herds m the given county but has as an object to determine and provide that the incidence does not exceed one-half of one per cent. As has been previously stated, reaccreditation tests have been completed on twenty-four counties, the results of which are summarized under Table VII. All of the counties listed were reaccredited, but m certain counties retests follow - ing the reaccrediting tests recorded m Table VII became necessary. The last general test completed would obviously indicate more accurately the present condition, but the mea - sure of the situation at the end of the certain three-year period is our object, therefore, the record of the last general test has not been used m the tabulation presented. The counties m which an increase m the incidence occured were those first to be tested as areas, at a time when their 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 territory was completely surrounded by untested area. In Nebraska, as m the several states similarly engaged m main - taining- modified tuberculosis-free accredited areas, quaran - tine rules and regulations have been promulgated by the De - partment to govern the admission and movement of cattle into the testing areas established. However, no policing activities have been maintained to prevent violations, compli - ance being urged and solicited by seeking to have the matter ' controlled as much if not more through a proper appreciation of the advantages to livestock owners and others engaged m such traffic than through authoritative force. That violations of prescribed regulations have occurred through the move - ment of untested cattle into the tested areas has been as - certained through inquiries at the time the tests were applied and where specific proof of violation of quarantine regulations was obtainable, indemnity payment was necessarily denied Such violations, it is correct to say, have been the exception • and not the rule. Withal, a comparative study of incidence and morbidity rates as revealed through data contained under Tables V and VH shows progress. At the time the initial tests were com - pleted m the several different counties listed under Table V the average incidence was 1.2 per cent, and the herd morbidity rate approximately nine per cent. These percentages have varied m the different areas from as much as three per cent to as low as two-tenths of one per cent. In the testing prior to 1925, particularly during 1921-22 the percentage incidence m certain county areas, as previously stated, was as great as four to as high as six per cent. After the lapse of a three-year period^since a general test was applied, the results recorded under Table VII reveal that the average incidence m twenty - four counties m less than one-half of one per cent, and the herd morbidity less than four per cent. Measured by averages this denotes a sixty per cent, reduction of incidence and a fifty-eight per cent reduction m the herd morbidity rate. Such reductions have been greater m the counties which have been established testing areas since the work has been adopted to a sufficient extent of territory to afford at least a reasonable protection against importation of untested cattle into the re - spective tested areas from adjacent non-testing areas, and 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE particularly since a fuller appreciation has obtained among livestock owners of the values of the service. Table VII — Results of Tests for Tuberculosis of Cattle for Reaccreditation of Modified Accredited Areas Completed Prior to November 30, 1930. Tested Reactor Cattle Herds Infected County Herds Cattle Number Per Cent Number Per Cent i — — . , Burt 1550 16566 88 .53 65 4.19 Butler 1982 24783 100 .42 68 3.43 ♦Cass 1141 11974 68 .43 44 3.85 Colfax 1369 21465 21 .1 11 .8 Dakota 686 7189 24 .33 13 1.89 Dodge 1762 26234 124 .47 65 3.71 ♦Fillmore 1259 12499 .40 .32 29 2.30 ♦Gage 1273 12807 55 .43 31 2.43 Gosper 759 13877 19 .13 17 2.24 Hall 1530 17943 67 .37 48 5.1 Hamilton 1798 15757 79 .5 68 3.78 ♦Johnson 609 6800 16 .22 15 2.46 ♦Lancaster 1629 20410 80 .39 43 5.0 ♦Otoe 948 10602 45 .42 28 2.95 ♦Pawnee 724 9970 39 .39 33 4.5 Perkins 778 11825 28 .23 22 2.8 ♦Phelps .-. 595 7899 19 .24 16 2.68 Polk 1492 16514 187 1.13 129 8.64 Red Willow 1109 22313 107 .48 46 4.15 ♦Saline 1353 14945 13 .9 10 .73 ♦Seward 1288 13432 51 .38 . 41 3.18 Thayer 1887 22519 311 1.38 129 8.64 Thurston 1001 12052 36 .29 25 2.49 York 1976 20308 144 .7 111 5.6 24 Counties 30488 370683 1751 .47 1189 3.8 NOTE — Counties with ♦ preceding name, the test included only part of herds but m no instance less than 50% of herds m county. Another measure of progress obtained m the eradication of bovine tuberculosis, and quite concrete evidence that the infection of tuberculosis among cattle has become greatly suppressed, can be had from a review of records available of the United States Bureau of Animal Industry. These pertain to the preparation of meat and meat-food products intended for interstate or foreign commerce, by which an inspection by competent and skilled persons of the federal bureau becomes required on animals and carcasses of the same at the time of slaughter. The presence of any disease or disease process thus determined is recorded; therefore, such records present ac- 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 i-V; B^i -ffe " : ■'■•.'* 7 m^ "^ ; . v?" if W The Average Value of Poultry ProductionfExceeds $30,000,000 Per Year curate evidence insofar as the service applies. These data cover approximately sixty-five per cent of the animals slaugh - tered m United States for use as human food. Tables VIII and IX contain summaries from such federal records of positive evidence of tuberculosis m the tissues or parts of carcasses of cattle and swine at the time of slaughter under federal inspection. The carcass of any animal m which a lesion of tuberculosis is determined is retained for further and more detailed inspection. Only those carcasses are passed for- food m which the lesions are slight and localized, and then only after the affected part is removed and condemned The carcass of any animal m which the disease has become ex - tensive and generalized is condemned as unfit for food pur - poses, while the carcass of any animal m which the disease may be well marked but not extensive is passed for steriliza - turn under supervision after all diseased parts were removed and condemned. Table VIII contains summary from records covering the entire United States from 1908 to 1929 for both cattle and swine, while Table IX is from records of animals slaughtered 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE under federal inspection at Omaha only. The figures in Table IX cover only the period since 1&amp;16, which coincides with the inauguration of organized work in the tuberculosis campaign in the United States. The commencement date in Nebraska, however, was 1918. Obviously Table IX is more representative of Nebraska conditions. Table VIII — Showing Losses Due To Retentions For Tuberculosis Fiscal Years 1908 to 1930, Inclusive (From Federal Meat Inspection -Records) Part 1— Losses of Cattle, Excepting Reactors . Fiscal Year End'g Slaughtered Retained .Condemned and Sterilized June 30 Number Number Per Cent Number Per Cent 1908 7,116,247 68,395 : .9 25,884 .36 1909 7,325,337 ' 100,650 1.3 26,506 .35 1910 7,962,189 123,501 ' 1.5 30,269 .37 1911 7,781,030 133,551 1.7 30,069 .38 1912 7,532,005 160,122 2.1 38,234 .50 1913 7,155,839 152,560 2.1 36,961 .51 1914 6,724,117 143,699 2.1 33,354 " .49 1915 6,964,502 158,239 2.2 ■ 38,840 .56 1916 7,387,051 173,754 2.35 39,218 0.53 1917 9,276,049 195,488 " 2.11 49,214 0.53 . 1918 10,912,417 196,917 1.8 . 46,235 0.42 1919 11,212,543 176,250 1.57 42,729 0.38 1920 9,666,188 157,016 1.62 39,305 0.41 1921 8,137,982 132,068 1.62 33,312 0.41 1922 7,795,323 137,472 1,76 34,712 0.45 1923 8,934,975 156,738 1.75 41,113 0.46 1924 9,049,342 141,595 1.56 • . 39,333 0.43 1925 9,595,969 145,012 1.51 40,374 0.42 1926 9,817,599 138,506 1.41 41,125 0.42 1927 9,810,797 112,924 1.15 31,755 0.32 1928 8,837,882 91,856 1.04 25,664 0.29 1929 8,120,992 81,276 1.0 21,265 0.26 1930 8,119,760 61,192 0.75 15,487 0.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Part 2— Losses of Swine "n i i I Yr.Ed'g Slaughtered Itetnined Sterilize.! I o ■Tun eTO | Number | x ,,;,;;; or . r . J i 1 ™ 1911. 29,916,367 iffiffl -\% tl'oll '£ 28 ' 880 -W 1912 34,966,378 lfil'lOO 4 7 X?'! ' »WW .16 pii ill If II s=^s nil II II At the Omaha Market for the Years 1916 to 1929. ' Cattle— Does not include reactors. aissd assla] a, ! s l I .£„ I^.,|?^ | ss ;,'.£;.;; ■- : | is s -s s. sis s ■•■„; -r" "■- "-■• </seg>
            <seg id="p042">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Hogs. Cal- No. No! endar Number Number % Stcr- % Con- % % Ster. Year Slaughtered Retained Ret. IHzed Ster. demned Cond. &amp; Cond. 1910 2,170,215 170,312 S.I 8,000 . .30 4,733 .22 .5S 1017 2,236,715 189,441 -8.4 S.079 .30 4.014 .21 .57. 1918 2,132,0CS 171,408 S.I 8,121 .38 3.070 .17 !55 1910 2,841,140 230,027 8.3 8,400 .33 . 5,359 .IS .51 1920 2,143,345 23S.4O3 11.1 0.777 .31 0,373 .20 .00 11)21 1,050,752 2S0.029 14.3 3,405 .28 5,202 .27 .55 1922 1.810,313 302.099 10.G 4,892 .27 5,004 .27 .54 1923 2,030,487 415,088 15.7 5.954 .22 0,115 .23 .43 1(124 3.0M.G39 419,553 13.0 6.4S9 .21 0.8S3 .22 .43 1925 2,S40,S50 379,120 13.3 D.022 .19 7,185 .25 .44 1920 1,874,013 203,241 14.0 3,000 .10 3.971 .21 .37 ■ 1927 l,SS2,0(M 240,024 12.8 2.53S .13 3,200 .17 .30 I92S 2,214,444 203,714 11.9 3,306 .15 2,070 .12 .27 1929 2.087.18S 223,009 10.S 2,58S. .12 2,037 .10 .22 1 Certain scientific facts must be taken into consideration in making a proper appraisal of the evidence presented by Tables VIII and IX. It has been quite conclusively proven by recognized scientific procedure that though tuberculosis among swine may be the result of either bovine or avian infection, generalized and extensive cases of the disease in swine are invariably of bovine origin, while lesions the result of avian infection in the same species remain localized and limited to single lymph nodes, usually in the cervical or neck region. In consequence, under the classification of tables VIII and IX the condemned and sterilized swine carcasses may properly be attributed to bovine infection, together with an additional un - determined part of all retentions on account of tuberculosis as shown. Though the primary purpose of the program of tubercu - losis eradication work has been to suppress tuberculosis of bovine origin, considerable attention has been given to tubercu - losis among poultry, the avian type. In previous reports by the Department records have been presented of work com - pleted in this particular as will also be mentioned later in this report. At this point attention is directed to the effect of such activities, in Nebraska and also in the other states, which be - come reflected in the slaughter records presented herewith. Table X has been added to show, by comparison in the records of several different markets, 1922 against 1930, the reductions </seg>
            <seg id="p043">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 which have prevailed in the amount of tuberculosis among the swine slaughtered. The variations in results indicate more the extent of the efforts expended in the territory contribut - ing to the different markets, than a failure to obtain results. The monetary: savings are very striking when the waste in - curred is reduced to a dollar-and-cents basis. Table X— Showing Number Swine Slaughtered, Number and Percentage Retained, Sterilized and Condemned for Tuberculosis Under Federal Inspection at Ten Leading Markets for Fiscal Years 1922 and 1930. ■ • ■' Slaughtered Hetainert SterJliz'd Condem'd %sTeF~ Market Year Number Number | % [Number] Number &amp; Cone). Chicago 1922 6,073,928 1,233.101 20.3 32,121 20 "1° S5 1930 0.904,441 895,500 12.8 13,018 11037 *33 Wisconsin 1022 1,527,S1G 412,214 27. 3,472 3"&gt;o 3 i3 1930 1,808,(150 337.4SO 17. 2.70S -139 '05. St. Paul 1(122 l,904,&lt;M 334.891 18.1 4.185 3045 "41 1D30 2,080,227 432,128 lfl.l 2.872 1 S09 10 Sioux City 1022 0Su,003 191,273 19.4 3.842 2 001 '&lt;» 1930 1,448,000 101.020 11.1 2,242 1739 "&lt;&gt;0 Omalin 1022 1,810.313 302,099 10.0 4.S92 5004 54 : 1930 2,351,830 201,193 8.5 ooog I860 17 St. Joseph 1922 1,«2,9S3 100,323 0.8 1.0C1 1807 03 1930 1,142,072 99,177 8.0 435 700 10 Kansas City. 1922 2.084,205 210.747 7.85 5,345 3»6* '3" 1930 2,000,009 133.594 5.10 1,401 1 183 10 . Kntlonal StJr. 1022 1,177,050 123,330 10.4 "173 l'oco '*&gt; ' Yarils, 111. 1930 1,328.140 144,512 10.8 1.791 1444 '00 In these comments relating to progress made in the eradi - cation of tuberculosis among livestock reference has been given wholly to the matter of commercial economics. This is in accord with the statutory duties of the Department under which the service has been applied. While the protection of animal health has been the primary purpose, those engaged have not been unmindful of the effect the results obtained might have upon human health. Though these advantages, both economic and health, are to a degree general to the state as a whole, obviously the much greater effect lies within the operative areas and to those resident therein having a part in the program. Future consideration should be given to ways and means by which a systematic and orderly extension of this service may more expeditiously reach all parts of the state. With the more rapid progress of similar efforts in a number of states to </seg>
            <seg id="p044">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE . which Nebraska markets cattle and dairy products, and the inevitable restrictions that may be expected against animal and dairy commodities to protect against tuberculosis, it be - hooves serious and immediate attention to this matter. An outline map of several central states included with this report shows the extent of the work in the area to which Nebraska more extensively ships cattle. Among these several states Iowa, Illinois and Indiana have statewide testing laws; the entire state of Michigan is a modified accredited area; all of Wisconsin is under test and Ohio will be completely tested within the coming year. Para-Tuberculosis Among Cattle Para-tuberculosis (Johne's Disease), correctly recognized as a form of tuberculosis, was first diagnosed among cattle in Nebraska in 1927. Any reported case, or disease condition among cattle leading to suspicion of the presence of the in - fection of para-tuberculosis, has been promptly investigated. Specific tests for determining the presence of the infection have been applied in each instance where clinical evidence warranted, except one yet to be tested. A total of seven herds of cattle have come under such investigations during the period December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1930, of which three were found to be affected. One of these was located in Fillmore County, one in Dodge County and the other in Clay. None of these cases were related one with another as a source for the infection. These cases were brought to the attention of the Department through the professional work of practicing veterinarians or veterinarians regularly employed by the state. Para-tuberculin or Johnin tests, the specific test for de - termining the presence of the disease in an animal, was ap - plied on cattle in six different herds, seventy-five cattle being so tested of which four were classified to be reactors. Two other cattle, in a herd last to be investigated and not yet tested, were determined to be so infected through clinical evi - dence and postmortem examination. These were confirmed by laboratory findings. A request has been filed with the Depart - ment for a test in the latter instance. A retest of another suspected herd will be made in December. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Table XI — Tests of Cattle for Para-tuberculosis From December 1 1928 to November 30, 1930. Tested Reactors Indemnity Paid Herds Cattle Cattle- State Federal 6 75 4 $100.00 $70.00 NOTE— Indemnity on two cattle recently destroyed not included. While para-tuberculosis does not appear at present to be a serious disease factor among; cattle' in Nebraska, it is highly probable that losses attributed to other causes may be the result of such infection. It is not possible under the conditions prevailing to even estimate with any degree of accuracy the prevalence of the disease.- A constant vigilence should be maintained by the State that each suspected case be thorough - ly investigated, not alone as a service to the individual owner whose herd may be affected but to obtain a more exact knowl - edge as to the prevalence of the disease in the state and the possibilities for its control and suppression. Tuberculosis Among Poultry Although the Department was not engaged in a specific project for combating tuberculosis among poultry, certain at - tentions have been given to the problem of suppressing the disease that may be credited with securing a reduction of the disease among poultry. The practice of having inquiries and surveys made, on premises where cattle were being tested, to determine in so far as possible through clinical manifestations the probable extent and prevalence of tuberculosis among poultry has been continued. These contacts have aided ma - terially in spreading information and the recommendations of the Department as to the most practical methods for suppress - ing tuberculosis occurring among poultry. The recommenda - tions of the Department in this premise were published in a circular edited by the Department under the title "Give the Old Hens a Ride." These recommendations incorporate not alone the Department's though and conclusion but the opinions reached by joint conference with several who have studied the problem by research, experimentation and in the field, and who heartily cooperated with the Department in the com - position of said recommendations. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE This circular first published in 1928 was revised in 1929, and a total of ninety thousand copies have been distributed to date to poultry producers, hatcherymen and others related to or engaged in the industry. The cooperation of the ex - tension service of the State Agricultural College, the organized poultry dealers, hatchery operators, veterinarians and others have aided in this distribution. Encouraging reports have been returned to the Department from several different sources indicating effectiveness of this effort which leads to the conclusion that it was well worthwhile. Much remains to be done for securing the greatest possible adoption of these recommendations made. To such an end a specific program should be inaugurated within the state. As a matter of permanent record, the recommendations as made in the circular "Give the Old Hens a Ride" have been entered in this report, and are to wit: First, POULTRY PRODUCTION "Most farm poultry flocks will return greater profits where early hatched pullets are used for lay - ers. Trapnest records of hens of various ages kept at the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station show that on the average pullets lay 30 per cent more eggs the first year than the same birds will lay during the second year. 0 "The market quality of yearling hens is also higher than for older birds so that both quality and quantity of poultry products will be improved and in - creased by disposing of hens after they are a year old. "Shippers, feeders, and others engaged in the trade complain of inferior stock, diseased fowls, and poor shipping and finishing qualities. The principal cause for such complaints is due to unsanitary living conditions, though inadequate and improper feeding accounts for a part. "The maintenance of large flocks on small areas of land is wrong, unless methods be designed and followed to remove the disease, hazards peculiar to dense population. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p047">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 "The diseases now most prevalent are tubercu - losis, fowl typhoid, intestinal worms, fowl cholera, • bacillary white diarrhea, blackhead, coccidiosis, roup, pox and canker. All of these diseases are more or less subject to control by sanitary flock management, and most of them to such means only. "Prevention of bacillary white diarrhea involves, aside from sanitation and flock management, the eli - mination of infected birds as breeding stock by means of a specific blood test. Roup, pox and canker can be. favorably influenced if over-crowding is avoided. "Most transmissible diseases are transported from place to place in the body of mature birds." Second, AVIAN TUBERCULOSIS "Tuberculosis is the most prevalent of poultry diseases in the middle west, and it causes great losses in the infected flocks. Poultry tuberculosis is the source ■ of most of the tuberculosis affecting swine which comes to light in the packing establishments of the region mentioned. "Avian tuberculosis is transmitted through the infected droppings by which food and drinking water are polluted. It is therefore subject to sanitary con - trol measures. Fowls in the later stages of tubercu - losis scatter enormous numbers of germs on the pre - mises which they occupy. "The principal, if not the only spreaders of poul - try tuberculosis are the older fowls. Tuberculosis is • but rarely seen in fowls less than six months old. Affected fowls less than one year old are not apt to have developed the disease to such an extent as to have become spreaders of infection. "The most effective measure for protection against, poultry tuberculosis is the elimination of the older fowls. Hens should be gotten rid of prior to becoming two years old, and it would be the safer practice, and more profitable, in infected flocks to place the age limit for keeping hens at not more than eighteen months. "The elimination of fowls at the end of the first year of egg production carried on for .a number of years, will eventually eradicate tuberculosis from the flock." 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Third, POULTRY SANITATION "The principal hazard responsible for disease is contamination by body wastes. No animal can live in intimate and enduring contact with dropping of . its own, or of other species, without incurring an ex - traordinary risk of disease. "The most effective means of defense against disease among poultry is sanitation. Such requires the application of measures and efforts necessary to make premises safe for poultry, namely : Rotation of Poultry Yards, Clean Water, and Unpolluted Food. "Rotation of yards is advisable because small areas of soil occupied by a large number of fowls are apt to receive a greater supply of body wastes than the earth can dispose of. . "Water is a most common vehicle for the spread of the microbes of disease and the eggs of the larger parasites. The water supply of the poultry yard is never superior in quality to the worst water the fowls may have access to. The elimination of a bad water supply, such as surface pools, is fully as essential as the sanitary supervision of clean water, as provided in drinking utensils. All that is possible should be done to prevent the water from becoming contami - nated. "Food must be provided in such a manner that it cannot be polluted with drpppings of the birds or the soil of the yards. Food must contain all the nuti'itive substances required by the body. Even the persistent lack of one of these may cause a type of starvation resulting in under-developed and unprofit - able birds. "It is wise when new stock is to be introduced in the flock to acquire such poultry in the shape of hatching eggs or day-old chicks. Chicks brought onto premises to replace old birds should be reared on new grounds and in clean quarters." SCABIES Work by the Department for the control and eradication of scabies has had to do almost entirely with the infestation among cattle and sheep, more extensively however with cat- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 ft n Any ™ V0 *. or J inf formation brought to the attention 01 the Department indicating the possible presence of the dT sease among animals of either of these species has been tt subject for prompt investigation. Within the area of the com mon prevalence of the disease among cattle, the range coZ - try to be specific constant attention has been directed against seats of repeated infections, and by inspections or otheS new seats of infection have been disclosed. All known mo - tion or exposure among either cattle or sheep were placed under quarantine .restrictions as were deemed necessary to protect against the spread of the disease to animals of other ots or herds. The methods and plans governing the eradica - tion of scabies have not been varied in any fundamental way over those which have applied during the preceding biennium. a™ Co 1 °P e '; ati y e from the United States Bureau of Ammal Industry was continued under the memorandum of understanding which has brought federal aid to the stated a number of years to maintain this service extended to the livestock industry for combating scabies or mange. Supe*! r 0 ,,^* ° f affGcted herds or flocks have been cbsely followed as well as followup inspections on such in" frl ti 1 - 1° C v t0 de A temine results and assure tater freedom from the infection. A personnel of three state and three fed - era veterinarians was engaged constantly under this project in the range country. This force was supplemented during the spring dipping period by additional assistance, in order T^r^Vr 6 7ff en( : ies &lt;* tha * Period of intensive work. wL f iZ / Gderal em P lo y ees ™ assigned during the spring of 1929 for approximately a three-months period each and again two were assigned in the spring of 1930 for two months. The field travel expense on these employees was paid from state funds. From time to time aggregating quite a considerable service veterinarians from the state or fed - eral office has been assigned to special investigations relating to. scabies eradication. These have had to do largely with feed-lot infections or with farm herd exposures in the east - ern part of the state which could be handled more economi - cally from the Lincoln office. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Cattle Scabies Eradication The greater part of scabies among cattle has concerned breeding herds of the range country, but the disease has also been found in breeding cattle of herds not in the recognized range country. Psoroptic or common mange has been the more prevalent, but twenty different herds were reported as infested with Sarcoptic mange. As these latter cases were not each confirmed by microscopic laboratory determinations, the classification may be challenged, but as a measure of safety, each such case was handled as recommended for the eradication of sarcoptic mange in administering treatments. Each case of scabies determined among feed-lot cattle was handled through the personal attention of a department rep - resentative, and under quarantine restrictions to safeguard against dangers of the spread of the infection from such sources to native herds or cattle in the territory where lo - cated or to contacts made through market traffic. Scabies among herds of breeding cattle was determined to be present in one hundred and thirty-three (133) different herds during 1929 against eighty-four (84) herds during 1930. These infected herds were located one or more in each of the following named counties, which have been grouped in two parts for the different annual periods and with the number of cases in each county indicated in parenthesis fol - lowing the county name: . Part I — From December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inc. Arthur (2), Boone (3), Cherry (50), Custer (8), Garden (8), Garfield (1), Grant (18), Holt (1), Keith (3), Lincoln (12), Logan (6), McPherson (2), Morrill (3), Perkins (1), Scottsbluff (5), Sheridan (10), Sioux (1)— Total 133. Part 2— From December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inc. Arthur (3), Cherry (26), Custer (1), Dodge (2), Garden (15), Grant (10), Lincoln (14), Keith (5), Red Willow' (1), Sheridan (7)— Total 84. A tabulation made from records relating to shipments of cattle from feed-lots found to be infected upon inspection at market centers shows that thirty-one (31) different feed - lots were thus involved during 1929 and thirty (30) during 1930. These infective sources, as previously stated, were the object in each instance of special attentions. The counties of location and the number of different cases in each county are </seg>
            <seg id="p051">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 . - indicated ir the following grouping, one group covering the cases on 1929 and the other for 1930, with the number in parenthesis following the names of the different counties in - dicating the number of cases in each of the respective counties - -Totals (2&gt;&gt; SaUndetS (1) ' ScoLW (%, ( sUon (1) Part 2-Fron t December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inc. goone (1) Burt (4), Butler (1), Cuming (3), Damon (2) rick* I) (1 R ) e &lt; d G^l o (1) V?f H q ( 1} ' H ? K r K (1) ' LinoolnTa)? lS The inspections and supervision of dippings of cattle on account of scabies by federal or state representatives of the Department during the biennium have been summarized as shown under Table XII. It will be noted that during 1929, a total of 1617 inspections were made and 631 dippings super - vised, while in 1930 there .were 1579 inspections and 531 dip - pings. The groupings in this table are divisions of six-month periods which is so arranged because the work becomes thus divided by ranch practices in herd management. A repetition of services on the same herd ofttimes becoming necessary during each of the different six-months periods; however, there is little interlapping by reason of incomplete services from one such period to the following, therefore it becomes proper to classify the repetition of services on the same herd or range as a new service. Grazing Land in Western Nebraska V </seg>
            <seg id="p052">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Table XII — Inspections and Dippings, of Cattle on Account of Scabies. Part 1— From December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inc. . Inspections Dippings Month Lots Cattle Lots Cattle December 25902 31 13886 February 86 23414 16 7736 March 263 106231 71 35199 April 256 75933 105 34739 May 200 72894 124 45953 June 121 55855 51 32297 7 Mo. Total 1008 377390 412 177766 July ; 96 36464 13 4152 August : 121 47786 . 7 1086 September 121 48548 11 3403 October 127 49838 65 21650 November 144 . 59695 123 53932 5 Mo. Total 609 242331 219 84205 Total to November 30, 1929 1617 619721 631 261971 Part 2— From December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inc. Inspections Dippings Month Lots . Cattle Lots Cattle Involved December 128 51161 42 16449 January 56 24863 : 13 3832 February 131 ' 51471 59 22100 March 183 . 84496 54 22825 April 186 84986 64 27419 May 109 50144 44 21527 6 Mo. Total 793 347121 276 114152 June 112 32665 14 7197 July 109 29945 2 830 August 122 42212 2 45 September 140 52778 24 8168 October 166 78427 106 54778 November 137 57044 107 47829 6 Mo. Total 786 293071 " 255 118847 Total to November 30, 1930 1579 640192 531 232999 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Sheep Scabies Eradication .. Scabies among sheep continues to be cause for consider - able attention on the part of the Department but principally as a feed-lot involvement. However, with the increased in - terest in farm flocks the prevention and eradication of scabies to which sheep are highly susceptible becomes of even greater importance and economic significance to livestock production m the state. The disease has not become established, in so far as the Department has determined, in any breeding flock, except where there was a recent importation of sheep. The disease continues to occur as a primary infection through imported sheep by purchase from public markets or elsewhere outside of Nebraska. Scabies was diagnosed among sheep from thirty-three (33) different premises, located one or more in each of nineteen (19) different counties, during 1929, and from eighteen (18) different premises in twelve (12) different counties during 1930. The counties involved and the number of cases in each are shown in the following grouping: n^ rt /Vt^? 1 " *• 1928 t0 November 30, 1929, Inc. Butler (1), Chase (4) Cuming (1), Custer (8), Dixon (1), Dodge ( &lt;l\' &amp;*!? ( ,V,' ?°JJ ( M' Lan( *ster (2), Madison (2), Merrick 1?^}??% (1) ' ??£' ( &amp; Richar &lt;Ison (1), Saunders (1), Scotts - bluff (1), Seward (1), Thurston (1), Washington (1)— Total 33. Part 2— From December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inc. Buffalo (1) Cedar (1) Cherry (1), Dixon (1), Dodge (2), Ham - ■S to l &lt; J? ) '« L ??f oln (1) &gt; Polk (1 &gt;- Red Willow (1). Sarpy (2), ' Scottsbluff (4), Thurston (1)— Total 18. In handling scabies among sheep, each lot so affected was either treated under official supervision by dipping or mar - keted for slaughter at Omaha under specific quarantine re - strictions. Where breeding flocks were involved, treatments have been followed in each instance by later inspection to determine the results. Table XIII has been compiled to show the inspections of sheep made and treatments supervised through services by the state or federal employees under di - rection of the Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Table XIII — Inspections and Dippings of Sheep on Account of Scabies. Part 1— From December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929, Inc. Inspections Dippings Month : Lots Sheep Lots Sheep Inyolved December 14~~ 4611 10 2601 January 14 3505 4 2026 February 11 4488 V 7 1428 March 8 1197 5 869 April '8 2441 1 38 May ; 6 1849. 6 1849 June 4 6337 ■ 1 237 7 Mo. Total 65 . 24428 - 34 9048 July 5 2660 1 . 400 August : 3 966 1 400 September 3 966 0 0 October 12 5515 7 1862 November 8 2506 2 526 5 Mo. Total 31 12613 11 3188 Total to November 30, 1929 96 37041 45 12236 Part 2 — From December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930, Inc. Inspections Dippings Month Lots Sheep Lots Sheep Involved ■ •.;;•; December ! 13 10288 7 4137 January 12 1246 0 0 February 12 10801 9 10641 March :.: 3 175 . 2 25 April 8 6701 6 6652 May ; 4 1480 0 0 6 Mo. Total 52 30699 24 21455 June 10 2282 5 772 July 3 2550 2 1050 August 2 250 2 250 September 4 1250 0 0 October 0 0 . 0 0 November 1 180 0 0 6 Mo. Total 20 6512 9 2072 Total to November 30, 1930 72 37211 , 33 23527 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">L J BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Scabies Among Swine The infestation of swine with scabies (Sarcoptic) is from evidence at hand on the increase in Nebraska. Specific at - tention, as yet, has not been directed against the disease a - mong awine- by the Department, in any measure comparable with the work on cattle and sheep, and as previously applied against the infestation among horsestock. A program for studying the disease among swine, and practical methods for its suppression and eradication has been considered but to date it has not been found possible to inaugurate such a spe - cific project. The study would necessarily involve all skin affections in the-given animals under observation though with a special object to determine the part played by scabies in - festation. Practical methods for treatment of the infection among swine could readily be included as a part of such studies and would become a part of the primary object. Scabies Among Horses There has not been a serious reinfestation of horsestock with scabies in the area that was previously so extensively in - volved, namely the Indian Reservation of Thurston County. While no specific investigation or survey was considered nec - essary, the contacts of Department representatives have been such as would bring it in touch with any serious occurrence of the disease. Such inquiries as have been made have failed to reveal the infestation of any horse-stock with scabies. "WALKING DISEASE" AMONG HORSES The investigations commenced during the summer of 1925, and continued through the summers of 1926, 1927 and 1928, looking to a determination of the cause of losses among horses in northern Sioux County from a condition which came to be known as "Walking Disease" has been recorded in pre - vious biennial reports (1925-26 and 1927-28) . As a follow-up measure to such work, it was deemed expedient to disseminate information obtained from the work through further specific attentions to the area involved, to create if possible more common knowledge as to the nature and cause of the disease, and particularly as to its possible prevention. A veterinarian </seg>
            <seg id="p056">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE who had handled the previous field work was assigned by the Bureau of Animal Industry to the activities and, in cooperation continued with the Department of Animal Pathology and Hy - giene of the State Agricultural College, was accompanied by a botanist assigned through said department. These men were in the field during the summer of 1929, the botanist from April and the veterinarian from in July to late in August. Inasmuch as results of the feeding experiments of 1927 and 1928 definitely established the fact that this disease may be reproduced in its entirety in experimental horses by the feeding of definite quantities of Senecio Riddellii, a plant found throughout northwestern Nebraska, and commonly known as "Groundsel" or "Squaw Weed", it was decided to familiarize the ranchers and farmers, in so far as possible, with the appearance of this plant. This was to be applied in the districts wherein "Walking Disease" had been found, and in the adjacent contact area, so that possible measures might be tried for eradication of the causative plant mentioned. Fol - lowing this plan twenty-five living plants of Senecio Riddellii were transplanted into containers and fifty preserved speci - mens were prepared by placing the pressed and dried, plants on cards. Placards, 14x22 inches, were printed with the fol - lowing information: . "This plant, Senecio Riddellii, common name 'Groundsel', 'Squaw weed', when fed to horses pro - duces a disease of the liver identical to that found in field cases of 'Walking Disease'. The plant is probably responsible for 'Walking Diseas' among horses and cattle in this locality. For further infor - mation address: Nebraska Bureau of Animal Industry or Nebraska Experiment Station, Department of Animal Pathology, Lincoln, Nebraska." These placards together with either a fresh, potted, flower - ing plant or a pressed, dried specimen of the same, or both, were placed in public places, usually postoffices, in the towns or communities as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p057">,.■: - BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Canton &amp; raW f Or 2 Andrews i^anton Marsland Olpn SS2 Hem ingford «™ MS" C anCe Vantassel, Wyo. intS Uff SLide l&amp;rT nS ° n In addition to these places, similar exhibits were placed at five ranches in Sioux and Banner Counties. A bulletin prepared. by. the Department of Animal Path - ology and Hygiene, "On the Nature, Cause and Possible Pre - vention of the Walking Disease' Among Horses and Cattle" was published by the Department. This publication was written to bring to ranch owners, farmers and other laymen the information and knowledge obtained through the investi - gation^ work completed. Five hundred of these bulletins were placed with ranchers and farmers in the territory involved A scientific publication was issued by the Nebraska Experi - ment Station on the work, with the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene and the Nebraska Bureau of Animal Industry as co-authors. • In addition to this a further limited survey was thought advisable to ascertain if possible what was being done to con - trol or prevent losses in the area following the suggestions presented in 1929. A visit was therefore arranged by a de - partment representative to a number, of premises where horse losses had previously occurred as result of feeding on the Senecio plant. A total of six different premises located in va - rious parts of northern Sioux County were officially visited ,- during October 1930. Besides these specific ranch visits sev - eral other inquiries were possible through contacts had at the time of the visits. There had been apparently only a few losses among horses in the area since the departmental con - tact of 1929 and during 1930. However, as a means to avoid such losses the use of mules which apparently escape the poisoning effects of senecio feeding has become more general . This with an increased use of tractors for farm work has re - duced the horse population on many farm operations previous - ly affected by losses from what is now recognized to have been </seg>
            <seg id="p058">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE the result of Senecio plants. The use. of sheep to overcome the Senecio plant was found to have been adopted on at least one ranch. According to the opinion of the owner this has been very successful and without loss of any sheep from such feeding, and with a noticeable elimination of the plants from pastures so handled. GLANDERS Glanders among horse-stock (horses and mules) was di - agnosed on three different farm premises during the period covered by this report, all of which occurred during 1929. Two of the three positive cases were on adjacent farms in Burt County near Decatur and the other in Lancaster County north from Lincoln. The exposure to glanders was evidently brought to these premises as disclosed by evidence obtained through the traffic of a single animal, a Shetland pony. The origin of this animal beyond the first of the three premises involved could not be determined. These cases were followed and tests applied to horses on a number of different premises to ascer - tain the possible spread of the disease on several more or less exposed lots of horse-stock, but all proved negative other than the three cited. Tests for glanders were applied on 154 lots of horse-stock, comprising 1,385 animals, during 1929 and on 106 lots, com - prising 1,556 animals during 1930. These were for the greater part tests of horses intended for shipment interstate and, therefore, testing was a matter of private service. A total of ten horses and mules were destroyed by official order and under the immediate supervision of a department .' representative after said animals had been determined by test or clinical evidence to be affected with the disease. The owners were reimbursed from state funds as provided for under statutes. Such indemnity for the period totaled $783.33. Table XIV— Showing Tests of Horse-stock for Glanders. Period Tested Infected Indemnity Lots Animals Lots Animals Reimbursement December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929 154 1385 3 10 $783.33 December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930 106 1556 0 0 0 .— — , Total ■■■ 260 2941 3 10 $783.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929il930 ANTHRAX Anthrax has never become a widespread menace to the livestock industry in Nebraska, although at times the disease has been cause of very serious losses to individual owners. The disease has been restricted in its occurrence largely to a some - what defined area bordering the Missouri River in the north - eastern part of the state, an area comprising in part or whole Boyd, Knox and Cedar counties. However, sporadic outbreaks have occurred from time to time at other points in the state.. These have been usually the result of the importation or move - ment into the state of infective material more or less direct from outbreaks of the disease occurring in recognized anthrax area where the disease occurs somewhat enzootically. Recur - rent cases have been observed, on contaminated premises after a period of freedom from the disease for considerable time, in instances after a lapse of several years. I In many cases the source of the infection was undetermined, and it was there - fore presumed that contaminated premises were the source of the disease occurrence. ■ The disease among livestock in Nebraska has been more o'ften recognized and has invariably occurred as a primary infection among cattle. From such source the infection in a number of instances has been spread to swine exposed by feeding on the carcasses of cattle dead from anthrax. With - in the past year (1930) lesions of. anthrax have been reported as being found affecting swine of Nebraska origin, said lesions being determined at the time of slaughter of the swine under ■ federal meat inspection and as the result of the official post - mortem examinations made. There were twenty-one such cases reported to the Department as occurring among swine slaughtered at abattoirs handling swine largely of Nebraska origin. In sixteen of these cases the exact origin of the ship - ment to market could not be ascertained, but the others origi - nated from premises located in five different counties, namely: Madison, Perkins, Merrick, Polk, Sherman. Special investi - gations were directed to the premises of such origin but in not a single instance was any evidence obtainable to indicate an occurrence of anthrax on these premises involved, either immediate to the shipment affected or at any prior time. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Visits were made by Department representatives to a number of premises which had received swine for feeding purposes during the early part of 1930 from what might properly be considered an anthrax area of a neighboring state. These in - quiries failed to reveal any evidence of losses that might properly be cause for any suspicion of anthrax. Two cases of positive anthrax may be recorded herein to advantage. The first occurred among a certain lot of swine from a premise in Saunders County determined initially through ante-mortem symptoms manifest clinically among animals marketed at a public stockyards. A visit to the premise of this origin revealed the disease to have undoubted - ly been present among the swine of the herd immediately at the time the shipment was made. This case appeared to be of spontaneous origin, there having been no anthrax carcass feeding, nor apparently any recent case of anthrax among any domestic animals on the premise. There had been fed to this lot of swine, though a number of days prior to ship - ment, the carcass of an old horse slaughtered for the pur - pose. The premise was located in the bluffs south from the Platte river. The second case occurred late in August 1930 which proved to be positive anthrax of an evident spontaneous origin among a herd of approximately 250 swine located in Cuming County south from Wisner. This case was called to the attention of the Department by a local practicing veterin - arian. Through the cooperation had the case was closely fol - lowed but the observations are incomplete at the time of clos - ing this report. This question should receive further atten - tion through prompt investigation of any case presenting clin - ical evidence that might indicate suspicion of anthrax. Ap - parently the disease from such source among swine will not be cause for great alarm yet may be of serious economic im - portance in the preparation of pork for human consumption. Anthrax among cattle occurred with less frequency dur - ing 1929 than during 1930 as indicated by the records of the Department. The disease was positively diagnosed among cattle on five different premises in 1929 and on fifteen during 1930. These were located in the following counties, the num - ber after the county name indicating the number of cases in </seg>
            <seg id="p061">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 each: Antelope (1), Boyd (11), Holt (2), Knox (6). Quar - antine restrictions were applied in all instances to guard against the spread of the infection to other premises than that on which the disease had made its appearance. All cases of the disease known to the Department have had the attention of veterinarians experienced in handling anthrax, as to its prevention and treatment. The Department has had especial interest m seeking to prevent the infection from becoming spread and established on different premises thereby becom - ing an everlasting hazard on such premises to the health of livestock. The prompt disposal of all anthrax carcasses by burning or deep burial has been urged. Burial has been avoided wherever possible preference being given to burning .There should be no letup on this work and where practicable an even closer attention should be directed against any out - breaks. ■ ABORTION DISEASE Abortion or Bang's disease, more especially the disease occuring among cattle, has been a subject for a greater num - ber of inquiries to the Department pertaining to animal di - sease control, prevention and eradication than have been made on any other single disease, not including, however, those questions relating to specific project activities. Without special funds that could be applied for combating Bang's di - sease, the attentions by the Department have been necessar - ily limited, and have been more or less as a part of the gen - eral services expended. Withal, very satisfactory progress has been made possible, basic for services which may now be con - sumated to good advantage and which" it would be advisable to establish even though funds available are limited. It has been possible to spread advice and make recom - mendations regarding abortion disease to livestock owners through correspondence supplemented by bulletins and other printed matter available from state and federal sources Special cases have from time to time been dealt with in a more precise manner through visits that were possible to the premises on which the disease had become established and was causing serious losses. These visits were more often pos - sible incident to other official duties than as a direct and </seg>
            <seg id="p062">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE specific service to deal with abortion disease. These special visits lead to the testing of a number of different herds, and in addition to the value of such service to the owner aided the Department in making a study and survey as to the best practical ways and means for control and prevention of losses from such cause. A great deal of cooperation with livestock owners could have been established had a specific project been inaugurated, and further had the same been expedient. This is a matter of much concern and demands official recog - nition from the state as a disease problem of first magnitude. There have been a total of thirty-four (34) different herds tested under this limited work by the Department. These comprised a total of 1,248 animals tested, many of which were retested making a total of 1,808 individual ani - mal tests completed. The application of such tests were, made possible largely because of cooperative assistance had from the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene of the State Agricultural College. Detailed report of the results of these tests has been omitted because the value is specific and limited to the particular herd in question. Suffice to state that only five herds were found to be abortion infection-free at the time the initial tests were applied. Among these herds were included twelve state institu - tional herds coming under supervision of the Nebraska Board of Control. A verbal agreement was made with said Board by the Department having for an object, the. prevention of abortions in the cattle herds thus represented and to establish each herd abortion infection-free. This was cause for a great part of the testing reported. The results thus far obtained have been very encouraging and withal satisfactory. A cen - tralization of abortion reacting cattle from these state owned herds to two or three different premises, now in process of being consumated, will provide abortion infection-free prem - ises more promptly for the herds from which reactor cattle are removed. Some of the less valuable reactor cattle from this testing have been marketed to slaughter, under quarantine which assures slaughter and does not permit of further traffic of such cattle to spread infection. Additional attention un - der this limited agreement will be necessary from the De- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 partment to protect the work completed and obtain the ulti - mate goal sought. It is possible through practical sanitation measures if adopted to reduce waste through losses from the infection of Bang's disease among cattle. Practical measures for control and prevention of abortions are within reach of every cattle producer, but much educational and field demonstrational work will undoubtedly be required to secure the general ap - plication of the proper measures. The establishment of abor - tion infection-free herds is possible and will become a great - er necessity for marketing of breeding animals because of a demand created through the establishment and maintenance of abortion infectionrfree herds. Departmental relations must necessarily be included in any such program, for in the ex - changes of livestock official state certification will be a re - quisite, therefore, a commercial advantage. The Department should be instrumental in advancing a constructive program of cooperation to combat the present and increasing waste oc - curring from abortions/both among cattle and swine. RABIES Rabies should be cause for much concern in Nebraska, more particularly as a protection to human health but also as a menace to domestic animal life. The Department has continued to give immediate attention to each reported oc - currence of the disease concerning livestock with a view to protecting against the spread of the infection among domestic animals. Each case of rabies reported has under such limi - tation not been the subject of special investigation. The in - fection was positively diagnosed in a total of thirty-three cases during the year 1929 and to date of November 24, in twenty-five cases during the year 1930. As a matter of record a list of the different counties in which these cases were located has been prepared and the same is herewith presented. ■ Part 1— Calendar Year 1929 Butler (2), Cass (1), Dawson (2), Douglas (4), Fillmore (1), Frank - lin (1), Gage (2), Hamilton (1), Jefferson (3), Johnson (3), Lin - coln (2), MerneMl), Nemaha (1), Otoe (1), Saline (1), Saunders (1), Sarpy (1), Thayer (2), Thomas (1), Wayne (2)— Total 33. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE . Part 2 — Calendar Year 1930 to November 24, Inclusive Butler (1), Cass (1), Dixon (1), Douglas (6), Fillmore (1), Gage (4), Gosper (l),.Harlan (1), Johnson (3), Knox (1), Lancaster (1), Morrill (1), Otoe (1), Phelps (1), Saunders (1)— Total 25. The distribution of the infection to different parts of the state is indicated from these records of positive diagnosis furnished by the laboratory of the Public Health Department of the State and by the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene of the College of Agriculture. These cases it will be noted involved twenty-seven different counties. The diagnosis with few exceptions was the result of examination of the brain of affected dogs, the canine being the primary and most active source for occurrence and spread of rabies virus. These may rightly be assumed to represent on a par - tial record of cases which may have occurred in the state. It has been previously recommended by the Department, and can be reaffirmed, that a statutory provision should be effected to place restrictions on the ownership of dogs that will oper - ate to overcome the stray and ownerless dog populations, and further to provide a centralization of responsibility to deal with this subject as a public safety measure for the preven - tion and suppression of rabies. As at present prevails there is an interlapping in this problem between human and do - mestic animal health protection concerning which there is opportunity for confusion, or cause for unassumed responsi - bility. RENDERING ESTABLISHMENTS In the matter of rendering establishments where car - casses of domestic animals, which are not intended for human consumption, may be lawfully so disposed of, there had prior to November 30, 1930, been established and in operation, either part or full time during the biennium, eighteen such plants in Nebraska, the same under permit from the Depart - ment. These were located (by using the nearest city or town to designate location) at the following named towns, the num - ber in parenthesis following each name being the number of such plants near said town or city: Omaha (3), La Platte (1), Fremont (1), Norfolk (1), Lincoln (2), Grand Island (1), Scottsbluff (1), Beemer (1), Schuyler (1), Tecumseh (1), Humboldt (1), Milford (1), Wayne (1), Tekamah (2)— Total </seg>
            <seg id="p065">• BIENNIAL REPORT-1929-1930 18. On November 30, 1930 to the best knowledge of the De - partment four of these were not then operating, but all ex - cept two retained permits to operate. Although the number of plants has not been greatly in - creased the field of their usefulness has been extended so that a larger service has been made possible. Many visits have been made to these plants by a representative of the Depart - ment to inspect equipment and keep a check on the plant operations in order to safeguard against practices that might endanger the health of livestock or create a public nuisance by reason of such establishments. Many improvements have ' been made in the handling of these establishments but a con - tinued regular inspection service should be applied. Special attention should be given to an improvement of the collection and transportation of the carcasses of dead animals to these plants. In order that his service may be self-supporting a greater permit fee, equalized by spreading over the size of field collections, should be considered. This can be readily measured by the number of collecting vehicles being operated. SPECIAL INVESTIGATIONS A summary has been compiled to show the number of special investigations ordered by the Department and com - pleted. These totals include only those cases on which specific reports were filed, nor are these inclusive of repeated visits incident to follow-up work. There was considerable atten - tion required of the Department on inquiries which necessi - tated special visits which could not properly be classified .as special investigations, for. example in communities where out - breaks of disease occurred to secure a more complete knowl - edge of the local conditions in such areas. The special in - vestigations were most often concerned with the diagnosis of diseases, particularly where serious losses occurred, and were in the greater number of instances attended through co - operation with practicing veterinarians, though many were direct to the livestock owners. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE A grouping from the records in the bureau office shows that classified by species of livestock involved these were as follows: 1929 1930 In Cattle ..............;. 94 113 In Horses :..... 20 13 In Swine 81 81 In Sheep 60 35 General i....... 75 48 Total i ., 330 290 REGARDING INTERSTATE TRANSPORTATION OF LIVESTOCK In the traffic of domestic animals interstate from other states into Nebraska, and also from Nebraska into other states, certain livestock sanitary regulations and restrictions apply. These are by order both of federal and the several state de - partments, which may be involved, including Nebraska. These except in a limited way do not involve domestic animals in - tended for slaughter when shipped to public markets. How - ever, domestic animals for other purposes, more particularly for breeding or dairying purposes, are governed in movement by rules and regulations whereby the animals thus transport - ed must be covered by certificates of health endorsed by the recognized livestock sanitary officials of the state of origin. From the records of such certifications Tables XV and XVI have been prepared to show the volume of such move - ment of livestock which has come to the attention of the Department. These figures do not represent all livestock moved into Nebraska or from the state, not intended for slaughter. Feeding animals for fattening for market are not. included, except as apply to certain classification. Even of the groups restricted there is a certain part illegally trafficked. The use of motor transportation as trucks has created a very difficult situation, one that lends to rather easy evasion of restrictions unless guarded by expensive policing activities. This latter cannot be maintained without large appropria - tions for the purpose and would not be warranted except in specific instances. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Table XV— Imports of Livestock into Nebraska To Date of November 30, 1930, Inc. ™* ss 1929 ~193Q Cattle for Feeding and Grazing ' ! — (largely female cattle) A. Prom Omaha Stockyards 42 882 EiRiq ,:_ B. Prom Other Points jnp'soo 147flqn Cattle for Breeding and Dairying ' ' ° 147&gt;63 ° A. Beef Breeds RR7 n ... swine B - Dairy Breeds ==:::::: u°£ Sffi . A. From Public Stockyards 24 233 20 697 Sheep for R^gS,**" " *S , 85 A. From Public Stockyards... '6 065 7 07K Table XVI— Export of Livestock from Nebraska To Date of November 30, 1930, Inc. ClaSS • — T929 T936 Cattle ~" ■ £ &amp; • •••; • ■ -•■ 1,346 911 swine-AH purpose s :::::::::::::;;::;;:;;;;; ?•§" 5,013 Sheep-All purposes Horses-All purposes.. ....ZZZZZZZZ JS UH Iowa [ . I Neirask |Hi'it 1 Iiiiii (II IQBBMi Illinois I Minnesota I Missouri I iTidiam ~1 Kansas f Ohio ■ — — 1 Wisconsin ' ' \ NorihMotfi ZJ Michigan □ Rank of Leading States in Market Receipt of Hogs </seg>
            <seg id="p068">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE / &gt;v CROP VALUES / CORN A Bfl5ED ON DECEMBER 1 PRICE I Al^r ■ \ mi IKM.000 I 4 .'- 0^ \r\ mi. 253,532.000 feS^K/ \ S 55?02fl00 m uiWMO Y^o&lt;%y \ I \nr m,wm VVV^7 mL \ / «?8 327,277.000 "26 102,725,000 X^^^w / / I / VALUE OF LIVESTOCK flND / S S15 /\ LIVESTOCK PRODUCTS MRRKETED / 14^,314,0)00 x&lt; A FISCAL fERR ENDING JUNt 30 / 40.27- "X \ Pit *22f,LU,m. W^ftn-^bl^n H0GS m 25^,27^,000 • \W^3M "'31,974,945 / "25 303.908.000 ¥S#7^ 37/7 / ■«* 329.645,000 V^v^y/ / '^ ■'■■'■ 555,577,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">BUREAU OF DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS AND OIL 0. V. McCracken, Chief INTRODUCTION The Bureau of Dairies, Food, Drugs and Oil is a distinct regulatory department. This work is carried on by research with subsequent examination and analysis incidental to regu - latory operations. It is difficult to show the extent of the .work earned on by the Department. However, we wilTpre! sent some records of activity m terms of figures as an index rttnf TTI *2* accora P lished - Some of the work rep! resented by these figures has taken more time than is rf quired to read the Statistics-they have taken hours, days" and even weeks of work. In many instances the work has called for repeated investigations which cannot be shown herein. From a review of the work done it is easy to sain some impression of the health, comfort and convenience that is afforded the public. Since all of the work of the Depart ment cannot be explained m detail and the figures presented cannot express exactly the scope of the work, it is sincerely desired that this report will show the trend of our activities. The Bureau of Dairies, Food, Drugs and Oil has assigned to it for enforcement a large number of laws of varyingT Zlf S? C f ariUes - ™s takes intensive training the part of the employes and close application to their work. Because the food and drugs law is unquestionably the most important to the welfare of the people of Nebraska that subject will be the first considered. An interlting and p le a s ing feature of this work is the ever-increasing intfrest on th i^llat:^y maUrine a Wh ° leSome ' Pure and honest Drugs .The quality of drugs sold m the regular channels of trade are found to be- exceptionally good. One inspector, who is a Pharmacist and well skilled m his profession, devote? a ] Tot </seg>
            <seg id="p070">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE his time to the inspection of drugs and drug stores. Very few irregularities are disclosed, and it has never been necessary to have a prosecution to correct such infractions of the law. Most of the sanitary orders issued on drug stores have been neces - sary on account of the soda fountain and luncheonette oper - ated therein. There should be further legislation providing for thorough sterilization of all glasses and utensils used in preparing and serving food and drinks in all such places. Foods The demand on the part of the public for enforcement of the food law has been increased on account of the dishonest and unscrupulous party who is prompted by greed and avarice to prey upon the reputation that has been established by the enforcement of the food and drugs law, and the hope that they may ply their trade without detection. This law has been made possible not only through the activities of the workers in the Department, but the people, having learned of the ad - vantages of the enforcement of these laws and being desirous of the protection offered by compliance with the law, are prompt in notifying the Department of any infraction of the law and insisting upon immediate action. It must be borne in mind that the laws assigned to this Department for enforcement were enacted by the legislature, and there is seldom a law enacted that has not had a suffi - cient demand made for such enactment. Very of ten the fel - low who calls from the house-tops to enforce the law is the first fellow to protest if the enforcement encroaches upon his personal business. He is the fellow that attempts to tell others that he has been persecuted and spares no effort or opportu - nity to defame and discredit the enforcing officer and the De - partment. It is not within the scope of the authority of this Depart - ment to separate the good food from the poor food. Whenever, and wherever, there are official standards, it is our duty to compel foods placed on the market in accordance with such standards to be as represented. When there are no grade or quality standards, the labels must declare such information as will guide the purchaser to make an intelligent selection. To </seg>
            <seg id="p071">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 examine every article of food placed on the market would not - only be too expensive but unnecessary. By far the great ma - jority of food manufacturers are honest, and are anxious to meet the requirements of the law. A failure to meet such re - quirements is in most cases a mistake, or an accident, rather than an intention, and a notice to the person in charge invar - iably corrects the offense. In carrying on the work of this De - partment it should not be the desire to display a record of prosecutions, but rather show that by the work of the De - partment there is no cause for. any anxiety on account of the quality of food being offered to the public. Bread During the past biennium no little attention has been given to the marketing of bread. The standard weight bread loaf law was contested and carried through our courts and de - clared unconstitutional by the Nebraska Supreme Court. Our Department took no part in the litigation except to carry on extensive experiments in order to supply the Attorney Gen - eral's office with the necessary information. Our Department has, however, spent much time and effort in enforcing that part of the law which has reference to the proper labeling of bread. On account of the standard weight bread loaf law be - ing declared unconstitutional, many bakers were of the opin - ion that there were no restrictions placed on the method of marketing bread. This erroneous idea has been practically eliminated and, with possibly a few exceptions, bread is mar - keted in full accord with the law. There is a new regulation with reference to bread that needs attention. Reference is had to the numerous brands such as: Milk Bread, Raisin Bread, Whole Wheat Bread, and various others. Heretofore there were many complaints received in the office concerning these breads, but without standards nothing could be done. The committee on Standards have defined each of the above and the work of correcting the irregularities in their labeling should be undertaken at once. Much deception can be found upon investigation, and the purchaser is entitled to that pro - tection. There is, also of late, a great variety of bakery goods being placed on the market that brings a dispute as to whether or not they should be labeled so as to show the name and quan- </seg>
            <seg id="p072">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE tity of the contents. This question is of such recent origin that a determination by the courts could npt be had during this biennium. Butter An investigational campaign on butter has been com - menced by collecting samples in every part of the state, and making a laboratory examination and analysis to determine whether or not the butter offered for sale in our state met the requirements of the definition of butter. We were very much disappointed in the results because we found too many samples that were low in butterfat and high in moisture. However, we were pleased to learn from further investigation that this was caused largely on account of improper methods and equip - ment for making the determinations in the factory. Upon re - ceiving a notice of the discrepancy, each manufacturer ex - pressed a willingness and desire to have his butter meet the requirements, and the results of later investigations show only, an occasional sample that is not up to standard. v Cheese The Cheese Industry is one that has been growing rapidly in the last two years, and has been given considerable atten - tion by this Department. We find that the law is very indefi - nite and, before much good can be accomplished in the way of regulatory work, it must be amended defining the different kinds of cheese. . Ice Cream .During the summer months, especially, ice cream demands a great deal of attention. On account of the difference in the butterfat standards of neighboring states, and the fact that Nebraska has a high standard, the policing of the markets for illegal ice cream must be carried on continuously. The ice cream manufacturers of Nebraska are anxious that their product meet the legal requirements, and it is only fair that ice cream imported into our state should meet the same re - quirements. During the last year, especially, we have had a great deal of trouble over imitation products which apparently are sold to take the place of ice cream. They look and taste like ice cream, and in fact, at the beginning were advertised </seg>
            <seg id="p073">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 as ice cream. On account of the nature of these preparations the Department ruled that they were in fact ice cream, with a low butterfat content, and, therefore, could not be sold unless they were made to contain the legal amount of butterfat pre - scribed for ice cream. When the legislature enacted into a law our present definition of ice cream, they had in mind provid - ing for the people the best possible food and also affording an outlet for the large amount of butterfat produced in this state. We have been very successful in our efforts to enforce the ice cream law, but we believe the law should be amended so. as to be more definite and certain with respect to this class of food products. ' Slack Filled and Deceptive Packages The Slack-Filled and Deceptive Package Law is one that places Nebraska in an enviable position, on account of the extra protection this law affords the public. The slack-filled package received the first attention, and work was centered principally on spices and alimentary pastes. After a great deal of work and agitation on the spice packages, the spice packers presented the matter to the Federal Trade Commission and, after many conferences, definite size cans for containing cer - tain amounts of spice Were adopted. While this action had nothing to do with the enforcement of the Nebraska Law, this Department, considering that this movement was a step in the right direction, and it appearing that the sizes adopted by the Federal Trade Commission were nearly correct for all prac - tical purposes, accepted their ruling and for the present any packages of spices, meeting the requirements of the Federal Trade Commission's ruling have been considered in compliance with the provisions of our law. Serious objection was raised by the Department to the manner in which alimentary pastes were packed. Many pack - ages were found to be large enough to contain two or three times the amount of food product they actually contained. Upon taking this matter up with the several manufacturers, we found them ready and willing to co-operate with this Depart - ment and build a package which would be less deceptive and convey to the purchaser a better idea of the amount of food he was about to buy. We do not kjiow of a single instance </seg>
            <seg id="p074">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE where the package for such products has not been reduced in size and the amount of the food product has remained the same. With reference to the deceptive package law, the most work has probably been done with the flavoring extract manu - facturers. It has been found that, in the correction of decep - tive packages and slack-filled packages, a great many prob - lems are involved. Should we ask manufacturers to build a special package for our state? Should we ask them to discard all packages now on hand and provide new ones? Should we ask them to discard a package that custom has almost made official? Should we ask them to discard special machinery that has been built to make such packages as they are now using? These and other questions present themselves in the enforcement of these laws. Naturally the Department has pro - ceeded cautiously and has endeavored to interrupt business as little as possible. We have worked on the flavoring extract packages for the last two years, and the work is not yet com - pleted. We have found the manufacturers very willing to co - operate with us, and most of them have made arrangements to change their package to conform with our law. This same law is now before Congress, has passed the House of Repre - sentatives, and for the good of everyone concerned, it should •become a law. When it is a National Law, it will materially decrease the work within the state. Vinegar Vinegar is another article of food that has been neglected and which demanded a great deal of investigational work. Probably no food law was violated oftener than the vinegar law. Not that anyone was trying to be malicious, but compe - tition and lack of attention to the law by the proper author - ities tended to increase the irregularities. Numerous samples of colored distilled vinegar, which were being sold as cider vin - egar, were collected from every part of the state. Violations were so numerous that the Department promulgated a set of rules and regulations governing the sale of vinegar and dis - tributed these rules and regulations in connection with our in - vestigational work and issued warning notices. This has prac- </seg>
            <seg id="p075">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 tically cleared our market of illegal vinegar without a single prosecution. ' Meat and Meat Products Meat and Meat Products have received their share of at - tention, and probably one of the greatest benefits to the pro - tection of the public has come from the supervision of the meat sold by. concessions during the hot weather at various fairs and picnics. The food sold at such places was examined daily and, as a result, we were called upon to destroy many pounds of putrid and decomposed hamburger, which were un - fit for human consumption. Fruits It has been necessary of late to give more attention to the supervision of the marketing of fruits. Most of this work has been done in co-operation with the Federal Government. Sev - eral carloads of apples have been embargoed and released only after the apples were properly washed, and analysis showed them to be free from arsenical residue. Grapefruit and or - anges have been condemned and destroyed, and numerous other fruits unfit for human consumption have been withheld from the market. We inspected and examined the apples in the many orchards in southeastern Nebraska, and in only two cases did we find that the arsenical residue was above the tol - erance and, upon receiving this information, the growers promptly washed the crops and later examination showed them to be well within the tolerance. The aforementioned are only a few of the food products that have received the attention of this Department. As much or. more can be said about many other food products, but time and space will not permit. Soft Drinks The manufacture of Soft Drinks is an industry that is growing and one that demands more attention each year. A new Soft Drink Law was introduced, by the people interested, at the last session of the legislature, but it failed to pass. Each year finds more factories, and the consumption of soft drinks </seg>
            <seg id="p076">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE seems to be on the up-grade. When people are assured that any food product is a good, wholesome food, the consumption increases. Therefore, the manufacturers of soft drinks are anxious that the high standard be maintained, that there should be an adequate law, and that it should be properly en - forced. It is only when a good food gains a good reputation and a large demand, that we are bothered wih imitations and substitutes. The roadside Soft Drink stand is one that should have some attention. Not that they are undesirable now, but as the number increases, the liability of undesirables also in - creases. The law should be amended so as to provide for cer - tain definite sterilization of dishes and utensils used for serv - ing all classes of soft drinks in whatever place they may be served. For the protection of the people, this Department has insisted upon the sterilization of all drinking glasses at all roadside soft drink stands. Commercial Feeds The Commercial Feed division is one that has been de - veloped during the last three years. At first it seemed to be of little consequence, but as the industry grew and there was more demand created for commercial feeds,, there was more work to be done by this Department. The first issue of a com - mercial feed bulletin was printed showing the information as disclosed by the registration. No results of analysis could be shown as this information was not available. The laboratory was properly equipped to make such analysis, and at this writ - ing a large number of samples have been analyzed. A system - atic record has been kept of the results of these analyses, and the material is all available for issuing a bulletin, which would give to the purchaser of commercial feeds the information he should have in order to intelligently select the feed he wants for his stock. This is the first time that such work has been done in this state, and we are able to cite you a number of cases where the farmer has been refunded as high as $50.00 on account of having been charged for a feed of higher protein content than he actually received. The work is just in its in - fancy, and more effort and time should be given to this class of work rather than less. ' </seg>
            <seg id="p077">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Live Stock Remedies The Live Stock Remedy division is another that has been developed by this administration. It is not within the province of this Department to decide which is a good and which is a poor remedy, but the law does require that certain definite in - formation be declared on the label, which should enable the purchaser to judge whether or not the preparation is one that is needed by his stock. The registrations of Live Stock Reme - dies as well as those of the Commercial Feeds were all exam - ined, and a great many registrations were found that did not comply with the law. After a great deal of correspondence these have all been made to comply with the law. The files are in order, and not only should a new commercial feed bulletin be issued, but a bulletin on Live Stock Remedies should be is - sued and distributed to those interested. Eggs The Egg Candling Law is one oMhe most perplexing, and yet one of the most important, laws assigned to this Depart - ment for enforcement. It is perplexing because so many deal - . ers are ready to take a chance on the quality of the eggs they buy, and then for fear they will have a financial loss, they use most any means to sell the eggs. . This problem is difficult because we cannot see the quality of the egg before it is broken. It is. a most important law because it creates an op - portunity to afford a vast amount of farm relief. The im - portant purpose of the Egg Candling Law is to make sure that none but the best eggs are offered for sale, thereby improving our reputation for the quality of eggs, which will bring with it a material increase in the price, besides giving the consumer a better value for his money. ;• There are many evils that present themselves in connec - tion with the marketing of eggs. "Incubator Rejects" are placed on the market as fresh eggs, and this occurs princi- - pally in the months of February, March and April, when it is not even necessary to candle eggs. "Incubator Rejects" are also broken, placed on the market as frozen eggs, and sold principally to bakers. The quality of such eggs is often very questionable. The law should be amended so as to forbid the </seg>
            <seg id="p078">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE • sale of "Incubator Rejects" as food for human consumption. This practice has become so common that immediate and prompt action should be taken. Another practice that should be curbed is that of withdrawing cold storage eggs and selling them for fresh eggs. In order to cope with the above situa - tions, it would seem to be almost imperative that eggs placed in an incubator and eggs placed in cold storage be identified by some brand or marking, and a strict penalty exacted for failure to do so. Our producers are receiving pay for their eggs in proportion to the average quality of the egg that reaches the big market. They are being penalized on account of poor quality, an amount of money that reaches into the mil - lions each year. During this administration a great deal of special attention has been given to the Egg Candling situation, and the greatest number of prosecutions by the Department have been instituted under the egg candling law. A new egg candling law should be enacted providing for the licensing of egg candlers, the grading of eggs, and the appropriation of the fees to the enforcement department in order that the provis - ions of the act may be put into effect. Until some such meas - ure has. been enacted the producers will continue to lose a vast amount of money that they have justly earned. The Dairy and Its Products The Dairy Division is another most important division of the Department. Dairying is one of the most important in - dustries in the state, and is making rapid progress. It has made so much advancement that our present law is already in - adequate and practically unenforceable. Dairy products, like the eggs, from Nebraska do not occupy the formidable posi - tion in the large markets that they should. While the quality of our Dairy Products is good, it is not considered the best, and why should Nebraska make anything but the best grade and •quality. From our observations, there is certain to be a change in the method of marketing cream. The cost of getting this cream from the producer to the churn, under the pjresent sys - tem, is by far too great. This should be diminished and the difference returned to the producer. This cannot be done by </seg>
            <seg id="p079">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 this Department, noi* can it be done by the butter factory. It must be done 'by the united efforts of the purchasers of cream and the producers. In many instances the producers are un - reasonable. .They demand, by using unfair methods and ar - guments such as threatening to take their cream to the other buyers and claiming that another buyer will pay more, that the cream buyer pay them for more butterfat than can actually be found in their cream. The producer should selljiis cream to the' cream buyer in whom he has implicit confidence, and it is the duty of this department to see that that confidence is not betrayed and that the cream buyer does his work accurately. Cream buyers who do not do their work accurately and in full conformity with the law, either through ignorance or mali - ciousness, should have their licenses revoked and be expelled from the business. Ignorant and malicious work on the part of cream buyers is costing the producers of Nebraska too large a sum of money to go unnoticed. There are too many cream buyers in the business today who either do not know how to properly buy cream or are malicious in their work. The qual - ifications of a cream buyer should be raised and the charac - •'. ter of the applicant should be investigated and only those who can furnish evidence of such qualifications should be permit - ted to buy cream. A cream station should be in a room built exclusively for the handling of cream, and furnished with such equipment as will enable the operator to properly care for the cream after it is purchased. No other kind of business should be permitted in a cream station. It too often seems to be the case that when a person is incapable of doing anything else they make a cream buyer out of him, and when a building cannot be used for another purpose they want to make it into a cream station. This all tends to impair the quality of the cream, and there is no disputing the fact that good butter can - not be made out of poor cream. There have been but a few cases where permits have been revoked, and but a compara - tively few cases of prosecution. The number of prosecutions should be reduced and the number of revocations of permits should be greatly increased. The cream buying business is of deep public concern and should be considered most seriously. This Department has given much attention to the quality of milk that has been offered to the public. In all parts of the </seg>
            <seg id="p080">I DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE state we have made an investigation to see whether or not the cows producing the milk supply have been tested for tubercu - losis. We have investigated the sanitary manner and condi - tions under which the milk is handled, and the care and at - tention' that has been given to sterilizing utensils and equip - ment. In some instances we have been instrumental in fur - nishing information that has induced citizens of a community to enact a milk ordinance. This should be done in 'every com - munity whenever possible. Good milk is one of our best foods, and no food is worse than poor milk. We have investigated the quality of milk sold, with reference to the butterfat content. We have visited the farm dairies and the city bottling plants. Our laboratory has been equipped with the necessary appara - tus to make a thorough examination of the milk as to butter - fat, sediment and bacteria content. Many samples' have been analyzed from every part of the state, and the people are de - manding that more of this work be done. It has b'een the in - tentions and purposes of this Department to so improve con - ditions under which milk is produced, the methods u'sed in han - dling the product and the methods under which it is marketed, by our regulatory work, that we will be able to remove all doubt in the minds of the consumers as to the quality of the product they are offered. By this method we will be enabled to deliver to the churn a better quality of cream and the grade and quality of our butter should be so improved as ; to demand a higher price on the market. To do this it will be necessary to eliminate cream buying stations not properly equipped for handling the product. In many cases there should only be one cream station in a town where there are now from tliree to ten. Some stations are buying such a small amount of cream that it receives no attention and is held too long before being shipped to the factory. All such business methods are reflected on the financial returns to the producer. While we think thlre is room for much improvement, we are satisfied that conditions are far better than they were two years ago. Paint The Paint Law has had some special attention of late on account of numerous complaints coming to the office about the poor quality of paint that has been sold in a few instances </seg>
            <seg id="p081">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 in this state. So far our investigation has shown that there is little cause to complain of the quality of paint that is sold through the regular channels of trade. We have found a few violations with respect to the manner of labeling, but these are easily corrected by giving the manager or dealer notice and informing him of the requirements of the law. The poor quality paint is largely that which is sold inter-state, direct to the consumer, and therefore this Department has no jurisdic - tion. Cold Storage .The Cold Storage Law has had more supervision durine this administration than formerly. In checking the records we found that some of the places had not taken out the proper hcense and few of them were making reports as required by law. After insisting that each company make such reports the Department started a regular inspection of the different plants. In some cases we found food that had been held in U&gt;W Storage far in excess of the statutory limits, and some of it was in such a. decomposed condition that it was unfit for human consumption, and was condemned and destroyed. Petroleum Products The Gasoline and Kerosene Inspection Law has received a great share of our attention. Much improvement has been made m the methods of our inspection and a greatly increased "ST* iTv h8S been d0ne * New e^ ui Pment has been added to the laboratory, and one man has been assigned the duty of examining samples of petroleum products. Formerly two one-quart samples constituted a shipment for analysis' During this administration the amount collected was reduced, and now we receive lien samples in one shipment, instead of two. This greatly reduced the cost per sample, and also en - couraged the inspectors to collect more samples in order that they might make a shipment. A comparison of the number of samples examined, as shown by the analytical table, best il - lustrates the increase in \ the amount of work. Through our investigation we have been compelled to reject a number of cars of gasoline that were shipped into this state, because they did not meet requirements. An attempt was made to secure permission, from this Department, to doctor up the various </seg>
            <seg id="p082">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE lots in order to make them meet distillation requirements. This has steadfastly been refused because it would only open the way for importing a poor product that might possibly escape notice. During this administration the fees were reduced on fifty barrels or more from three cents to one and one-half cents per barrel. The entire state is covered every 30 days or oftener in order that the inspection may be as close to the receipt of shipment as possible. While our system is not burglar-proof, Nebraska has the reputation of having as good a quality of gasoline, if not better, than any state in the union. There are probably a few places in the law that should be remedied, but as a rule the present system of inspection has proven very sat - isfactory. The number of gallons imported is constantly in - creasing, the number of stations is increasing, jand conse - quently the amount of work of this Department is increasing. Hotel Law The inspection of Hotels, Rooming Houses i, Boarding Houses, Apartment Houses, Restaurants and Concessions is another duty that devolves upon this Department. If each one of the businesses above mentioned were violators and ma - liciously endeavoring to evade the law, this work would be a big task by itself. Fortunately the opposite appears to be nearer the facts. We have found some few places that needed correction, but none of them have been so flagrant as to war - rant prosecution. Some places have been closed, jfter discus - sing the matter with the proprietor and securing his consent to discontinue the business. In some instances it at first ap-. pears that the Department is asking for a lot of work and ex - pense, but after showing the proprietor the reasonableness of the demands we have always been able to get compliance. We realize the fact that anyone can go out and sometime or other find an establishment that does not appear to be perfect. It is easy to criticize another's business, but' the average general conditions in the above named places, for the most part, are not subject to much criticism. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Another duty that takes considerable time in this Depart - ment is of the various liquor samples submitted by state and county sheriffs. Very often we are called upon to go to different parts of the state as witnesses in these liquor cases. ■ We have numerous demands from citizens throughout the state to analyze various products for their own information This, the Department has been unable 1 to do, as our time is well taken up with the duties imposed by law. Were we to un - dertake t0 analyze all these various and sundry samples, sub - mitted by the people, our laboratory force would have to be possibly more than doubled. Miscellaneous Other laws enforced by this department are: Oleomar - garine &amp; Butterine Law, Commercial Fertilizer, Commission Merchant, Turpentine and Serum &amp; Virus Laws, but theyde - mand less attention and time, and space will not be taken to discuss them separately. Suffice it to say that they do not go unnoticed and we insist that the provisions of every law that our Department is called upon to enforce, be met in every particular. Summary In summing up the whole work of the Bureau we find that during this administration far more work has been accomplished, a greater variety of work has been done much more detail has been worked out, closer cooperation with pro - ducers, manufacturers and consumers has been maintained and more reliable equipment has been provided than appears to have been done under the former administrations. There is not any part of the work carried on by this Bureau that does not have a direct relation and benefit to Agricul - ture. Enforcement of the law induces honesty and fair deal - ing; it inspires confidence and encourages business; it im - proves the quality and increases consumption, and with all these conditions there comes to the farmer greater prosper^ ity. The efforts gL- this Bureau should not be decreased, </seg>
            <seg id="p084">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE but they should be extended to .meet the demands of a grow - ing and enterprising state. We are pleased to submit, herewith, several tables show - ing the figures relative to our work, which we present as. an index to the amount of our accomplishments: ANALYSES COMPLETED IN LABORATORY Dec. 1,1928 Dec. 1,1929 to to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Alimentary Pastes 49 80 129 Beverages 107 125 232 Bread 126 83 209 Butter 97 468 565 Butter Substitutes 7 4 11 Candy 1 45 75 120 Canned Goods 41 14 55 Cereals : 14 17 31 Cheese - 5 21 26 Coffee and Tea 2 6 8 Drugs :. 44 50 94 Eggs 5 y. 7 12 Extracts 70 52 122 Feeds 363 1,295 1,658 Fish and Fish Products 5 1 6 Flour 13 9 22 Fruits 25 20 45 Gasoline 1,771 3,127 4,898 Ice Cream 217 331 548 Jell and Jell Products .3 4 7 Kerosene 58 72. .'; 130 Liquor 674 546 1,220 Live Stock Remedies : 7 24 31 Meat and Meat Products 28 40 68 Milk and Cream 215 406 621 Miscellaneous 31 22 53 Nuts and Nut Products ; 9 12 21 Pastry ' 18 48 66 Oils - :..... 16 54 70 Sacchrine 11 27 ' 38 Spices and Condiments ;... 131 90 221 Vegetables 3 6 9 Vinegar 71 ' 84 155 TOTAL 4,281 7,220 11,501 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 . LICENSES AND CERTIFICATES OP REGISTRATION Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 to to „,•,„■ . Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Babcock Test 4,649 4,619 9568 Da^y - -• . 118 138 256 Creamery 1 36 147 283 Cheese factory 26 35 61 - g? te jl I« Cream 40 55 9$ Wholesale Ice Cream 63 75 130 Retail Imitation Butter 3 389 &lt;?1&lt;?? fi kpi Wholesale Imitation Butter 34 'g 72 Manufacturers Imitation Butter 1 1 2 Cold Storage Inspection ; 21 23 44 Live Stock Remedy 115 05 200 Commercial Fertilizer ; 14 12 26 Bottlers 65 74 139 Rendering Plants „ ....„" 17 17 34 Cold -Storage Warehouse 24 27 51 Commission Merchants 40 43 83 Hog Cholera Serum or Virus 19 20 39 Temporary Babcock 740 624 1,364 Cream Station 2,538 2,562 5 100 Field Superintendent 95 77 172 g ot f ls •■ - 739 745 1,484 Restaurants 3i 2 98 3 436 6 734 Rooming Houses ,. 604 665 1 269 Boarding Houses 79 HO ' 18 9 . Apartments 185 201 386 Concessions .:.... 525 422 947 TOTAL 17) 574 17,383 34,957 FOOD AND SANITARY INSPECTIONS Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 r .. Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Groceries . ....: 3 533 3 881 7 4I4 Meat Markets 621 648 1J269 Bakeries and Confectioneries 580 G82 1262 ¥a S l- t0re f •• 941 929 1370 boda Fountains 931 1047 107a Bottling Works 9 1&gt;w g ll9 g Miscellaneous 129 104 oqS Food Factories and Mills "". 13 40 53 Re-Inspections 633 847 1 480 SlI^SEEEir! U7 i '^ SS Dairy Establishments 103 85 188 Cream Receiving Station 2,064 1,905 3 969 Creameries 15 1, 2R Ice CreariTManufacturers .."...' "1 9 in Restaurants 1 )943 2) 041 3,984 Concessions 295 207 502 Hotels, Rooming Houses, Boarding ~ ' " Houses and Apartments 673 721 1 394 TOTAL . 13,670 14,592 ' 28,262 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Sanitary Orders Issued 378 472 850 Prosecutions 107 71 178 Babcock Test Examinations 1,513 1,630 3,143 Dairy Notices ...:.. 308 413 721 New Cream Receiving Stations ... . 722 802 1,524 GASOLINE AND KEROSENE INSPECTION Dec. 1,1928 Dec. 1,1929 to ' ■ to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Gasoline (cars) 27,303 28,932 56,235 Kerosene (cars) 5,142 5,830 10,972 32,445 :•." 34,762 67,207 Gasoline (gallons) '. 212,133,332 227,341,067 439,474,399 Kerosene (gallons) 37,501,398 42,388,629 79,890,027 249,634,730 269,729,696 519,364,426 |**; • vv^v^;,^ ■ ;-v.. -■■.-:. : ~" ' ™ • •; :.;• ■/■.:'] •; '-; .v . -i.; ■ ', .. ■ " . -.: I ' ■ " ' /• / / 1 /■ / ' ■■' ' ' ■"*' " "' ■ .-'*■■ ■ '■' . "*1 I ' ■ :.■':■ ri \M m '.'■.'■ • '■'■% Nebraska is First in Acreage of Alfalfa </seg>
            <seg id="p087">DIVISION OF AGRICULTURAL SEEDS Elva L. Norris, Seed Analyst Activities of the Seed Division: It has been the aim of the seed division, first to enforce the State Seed Law and secondly, to assist those interested m agriculture m securing high quality seed stocks. The State Seed Law. requires that all agricultural seeds offered for sale must be properly labeled. This involves the making of labo - ratory analyses and reporting the results of analyses on all samples of seed sent by dealers and farmers to the state seed laboratory. Labels bearing the results of these analyses must be attached to the bags or other containers m which the seeds are offered for sale. The labeling requirements are as follows: (a) The Commonly Accepted Name of Such Agricultur - al Seeds: The kind of seed must be indicated and the name given must be the one commonly accepted by the public and the Seed Trade. For example: Canada blue grass and Ken - tucky blue grass must be so named, as these are the common- . ly accepted names, instead of simply "Blue Grass." (b) The Purity of the Seed, Expressed as a Percentage of the Total Weight. (c) The Quantity of Weed Seeds, Expressed as a Per - centage of the Weight. (d) The Quantity of Other Crop Seeds, Expressed as a Percentage of the Weight. (c) Noxious Weeds m Nebraska are as follows: (1) Small flowering morning glory (Convolvulus arvensis), (2) Wild Mustard or Charlock (Brassica arvensis), (3) Quack Grass (Agropyron repens), (4) Wild Oats (Avena fatua), (5) All species of dodder (Cuscuta spp.), (6) Canada Thistle (Cir - sium arvenseK If there is more than one seed of the noxious weeds m one-sixth (1-6) of an ounce of the agricultural seeds, its presence must be indicated on the label. If the seeds con- </seg>
            <seg id="p088">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE tain any of the seed of Canada Thistle, the presence of such seeds must be indicated on the label. (f ) The Germination or Vitality of the Seed. (g) The Date on Which the Germination Test was Made. (h) The Full Name and Address of the Vendor: The label must also give the full name and address of the person who sells, flffers or exposes for sale seeds for seeding purposes within the State. (i) Origin of Seed: The recent amendment to the "Fed - eral Seed Act" requiring the staining of imported alfalfa and red clover seed establishes their origin. A knowledge of the place or production of seed is very important to the farmer, since some seeds are not acclimated to the State of Nebraska. Alfalfa seed produced m the southern part of the United States should not be used for seeding purposes m Nebraska; Suggested tag for labeling unmixed agricultural seeds m Nebraska: Pure Seed % Inert Matter ...... .......,..% Crop Seed „• ..:.. % Weed Seed ......% Noxious Weed Seeds Number per ounce m excess of 1 seed to 5 grams Germination % Date tested Hard Seeds ......% Where grown Total live seeds % INSPECTION The regular inspectors appointed by the Department of Agriculture are instructed to visit all places of business where seeds are to be found offered for sale and to inspect and take samples of all the various kinds of field seeds that they find. Samples are taken m duplicate and sealed with an official seal. The one sample is left with the dealer and the other is sent to the State Seed Laboratory for further inspection and analy - sis. 88 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 VIOLATIONS Three different kinds of violations are to be found through inspection work: •1. Seed containing more noxious weeds than is per - missible. 2. Not placing the required information on the tag or label. 3. Seed that is below the guarantee as claimed on the tag. By far the most common form of violation is in not plac - ing the required information on the tag. Violations of this nature are noticed by the inspector while taking the sample and acted upon at once. Lots of seed below the guarantee as claimed and lots containing noxious weeds are discovered when the samples are analyzed in the laboratory. Unfortunately some of these violations are uncovered too late to prevent the sale of the seed, but the information gained has a great deal of future value to the Department and to the dealer who has sold the seed. STOP SALE NOTICE The inspector takes notice and calls the attention of the dealer to any violations in labeling, and makes such sug - gestions as the case may require. When important items as the PURITY, GERMINATION are omitted from the tag the inspector issues one of the Department STOP SALE NO - TICES, which forbids the sale of the seed until the labels carrying all the required information are procured. The sell - ing of seeds after the STOP SALE NOTICE has been issued constitutes, an offense punishable by fine. RELEASE Whenever the STOP SALE NOTICE has been issued and the dealer has secured the proper tags, he may submit them along with his notice to the State Department of Agriculture at Lincoln for examination. If upon examination the tags are found to comply with the law, his notice receives the approval of the Department and is returned with the tags to the dealer and he is permitted to continue the sale of his seed. 89 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE TABLE NO. I. SHOWING INSPECTIONS WHICH WERE MADE IN NEBRASKA DURING 1929 and 1930. 19 29 19 3 0 No. of No. of No. of No. of samples vio- samples vio- Name of Distributor collected lations collected lations Barteldes Seed Cq. — Denver, Colo 3 3 Berry Seed Co. — Clarinda, Iowa 1 1 1 . "l Bonahoom (N.) Seed Co. — Hastings.... 20 3 12 0 Bowman Seed Co. — Superior. 18 2 32 3 Bowman Seed Co. — Concordia, Kans.;. 5 1 5 3 Campbell's Seed House — Seward.: 8 0 13 0 Coy (C. H;) Seed Co.— Valley 7 0 Dakota Improved Seed Co. — Mitchell, S. D .... .... 4 0 Farmers Co-op. Sd. Co. — Omaha 19 18 Farmers Union State Exchg. — Omaha .... .... 7 1 Field (Henry) Seed Co. — Shenandoah, Iowa .... l ■'•..' o Griswold Seed &amp; Ny. Co. — Lincoln...... 9.1 27 0 Griswold, Robt. S. — Lincoln 3 0 17 2 Griswold, W. B. — Lincoln : 6.0 .15 1 Grand Grocery — Lincoln 2 2 Gunn Seed_Co. — Lincoln .... 6 0 Halley-Neeley Seed Co.— Sioux City, la ... 4 0 Harnden Seed Co. — Kansas City, Mo.. .... 2 0 Kellogg Seed Co.— Milwaukee, Wis..... 1 1 McMahon Seed Co.— Rapid City, S. D .... 2 0 Maiwald, F. A. — Cortland .... 3 . 0 Mangelsdorf Seed Co. — Atchison, Kans :. , .... 10 . 2 May, Earl E. — Shenandoah, Iowa .... .... 3 0 Mitchellhill Seed Co.— St. Joseph, Mo. 2 • 0 2 0 Nebraska Seed Co. — Omaha 37 3 67 2 Northern Field Seed Co.— Winona, Minn 1 1 ... Northwest Nebr. Alfalfa Seed Grow - ers Co-operative Ass'n — Crawford 11 0 9 0 Northwest Seed Growers — Fargo, N. D..J ..„ l o Northwestern Seed House — Oberlin, Kans .... 6 0 Occidental Seed Co.— £alt Lake City.. 2 Ouren Seed Co.— Co. Bluffs, Iowa 15 0 16 6 Panhandle Seed Co. — Amarillo, Tex... 1 1 Patrick (Rudy) Seed Co.— Kans. City, Mo • .„. 6 0 Pease Grain &amp; Seed Co. — Beatrice 2 0 2 1 Peppard (J. G.) Seed Co.— Hastings.. 49 5 73 4 Ranney Seed Co.— Omaha 15 1 20 0 Robinson ( J. C.) — Waterloo 7 0 Rocky Mt. Seed Co.— Denver, Colo .... .... 1 **0 Sioux City Seed Co.— Sioux City, la... 10 1 ' 23 2 Sonderegger Ny. &amp; Sd. House — Beatrice 1 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">BIENNIAL REPORT— 192&amp;-1930 TABLE NO. 1— Continued 1929 1930 No. of No. of No. of j No. of XT . _. ' ■ ' samples vio- samples vio- Name of Distributor collected lations collected lationa Standard Seed Co.-^Clarinda, Iowa 4 n Star Seed Co.— Crawford.: 5 6 5 0 Toben Seed Co.— Kansas City, Mo .... 1 i Wertz Seed Co.— Sioux City, Iowa 1 6 12 0 Western Seed Co. — Denver, Colo 4 0 4 - 1 Yager Seed Co.— Fremont...... 4 0 Yonkerman Seed Co.— Co. Bluffs, la.. 9 0 Miscellaneous (Dealers &amp; Farmers).... 96 64 51 30 Total - 361 108 "4I0 *~64 WEED CONTROL The question of weed control is closely connected with the seed problem and it has become one of the most serious problems of our state. Recent surveys have been made and our farmers are losing millions of dollars each year. Weeds cause an added cost in cultivation, reduced prices on weed infested hay and grains, cost of cutting weeds in pastures and on highways, loss of live stock through poison - ous plants and perhaps the greatest loss is the reduction of land values due to noxious weed infestations. The situation demands some constructive action. That farmers are be - coming concerned about this weed problem is shown by the fact that there has been an increased number of plants, sent in for identification and numerous requests for information on weed eradication. DODDER SEED IN RED CLOVER The State of Nebraska has some areas which produce excellent red clover seed. The Department found that the seed was beginning to become badly contaminated with dodder. An effort was made to clean up the infested areas. Much publicity was given to the situation through the local press and several thousand copies of a dodder poster were distri - buted. These posters illustrated the life history of the dodder plant. County Agents in the dodder infested counties gave much assistance. The seed dealers have given fine co-opera - tion and it is now extremely difficult for farmers to dispose of </seg>
            <seg id="p092">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE dodder infested seed at all, except at greatly reduced prices. The reduced prices for dodder infested red clover seed have convinced the farmers of the seriousness of this weed pest. The willingness of farmers to adopt methods of control gives hope that eventually it will be eradicated. PUBLICITY In June 1929 the Bulletin No. 101, entitled "Nebraska Weeds" was revised and reprinted. This bulletin illustrates, describes and gives methods of eradication for the commonest weeds of Nebraska. Normal schools, high schools, rural schools, county agents, bankers, womens clubs and numerous other organizations have sent in requests for this bulletin. A number of requests for this publication have been received from foreign countries. During the biennium a bulletin "Rules and Regulations Governing the Sale of Agricultural Seeds and Notes on Seed Inspection" has been compiled. This bulletin has been placed in the hands of numerous seed dealers and farmers. Numerous news articles have been written and published by county and state papers. The theme of these articles usually centers around the importance of using a high grade of agricultural seed. It is the policy of this department to co-operate fully with the College of Agriculture, County Agents and the edit - ors of agricultural publications. This Department makes pur - ity analyses and germination tests on all State Certified Agri - cultural seed. Counties with agricultural agents lead in the number of samples sent to the laboratory. The "Nebraska Farmer", a leading agricultural publica - tion of the State, with the assistance of this Department, has conducted two very valuable weed identification contests. At the Nebraska State Fair the seed laboratory endeav - ored to impress upon farmers the importance of good agricul - tural seed. Several varieties of Jiving noxious weeds were ex - hibited. Numerous County Fairs gave awards for the best collections of weeds and weed seeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 The Boys and Girls 4-H clubs of Nebraska continue to be interested in the weed and seed problem. Several "Weed Clubs" have been organized and corn clubs and garden clubs devote considerable time to weed control problems. The importance of good, adaptable agricultural seed is receiving more recognition than ever before. The Crop Grow - ers Association and State Seed Dealers Organization are alert. The United States Department of Agriculture with its stain - ing amendment for imported alfalfa and red clover seed and its provision for verified origin seed is giving valuable assist - ance. "The Farm Seed Council of America" is helping to solve the problems of those interested in seed. The Nebraska State Seed Laboratory holds membership in the "Official Seed Analysts Association of North America." This organization is interested in all phases of the seed in - dustry. Special emphasis is placed on research work. Each laboratory works a number of "Referee" samples each year. The results of the tests from all laboratories are compiled and tabulated. This serves as excellent information for each la - boratory. Legislative problems as well as other problems pertaining to public service are investigated and analyzed with a view toward improving conditions. OFFICE WORK During the two years covered by this report the follow - ing material was sent out : - Seed reports - 11,833 Seed Law 3,000 Rules and Regulations Governing the Sale of Agricultural Seed 1,200 "Nebraska Weeds"— Bulletin No. 101 7,000 Dodder Poster 3,500 Miscellaneous 1.500 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE TABLE NO. II. NUMBER OF SAMPLES OF FIELD SEEDS TESTED IN 1930 THE AVERAGE PURITY AND GERMINATION PERCENTAGES ARE SHOWN. Average Average Hard Ki n H n t &lt;3» a o No&gt; 1 £ | uritv Germination Seeds Kind of Seed Samples Per Cent Per Cent Per Cent Alfalfa ; 1,291 96.07 64 Alsl . ke • 7 96.81 70 25 Barley 141 .... 89 Beans 2' 95 '•*"": Beans — Soy 2 86 Brome Grass 12 8121 71 Buckwheat ....'. 1 gg Broom corn : . 1 7 . £ane 48 1 94.53 64 Cantaloupe 1 62 "" Corn ; .;„ 1,024 "" 82 English Rye Grass 7 97 30 67 Feterita 2 94.00 68 s^s • is 89.04 60 ■::::. £ affi r ■■ • 48 93.58 68 Ky. Blue Grass 37 8 5. 38 73 Millet . 179 8377 83 Milo Ma«e ;.... 1 99.25 24 "" Oats •- 79 .... 94 Onwns 3 ._ 65 l*»* 3 .... 91 E°P corn • 1 66 2 99.72 97 clover 383 93.08 75 « § ed T °P 1 .... 86 Spinach ; 1 03 Squash .!!!!"!!!!."' 1' g» | udan •: ■ ZZ'ZZ". 305 95.64 72 Sweet clover , 602 94.59 62 25 Junothy 30 93.68 79 Turnip 1 j 3 Watermelon 5 ca "" wheat ;;;;;;;;;;; 9 2 ;;;! 1% White Dutch clover ..: 11 97.3s 70 {j Total • •: 4,773 93.23 70 17 NUMBER OF SAMPLES CONTAINING NOXIOUS WEEDS _ ■ • ■ Canada Quack Dodder Charlock Thistle Grass Alfalfa "J Sweet clover 3 13 "c ""a Red clover [ ZZ 48 3 Total • 113 14 "5 : "i </seg>
            <seg id="p095">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 TABLE NO. III. MONTHLY REPORT OF SEED TESTS December 1st, 1928 to November 30th, 1929 Identi- Germina- fication Identi - ■ Inspect-- .tion Purity of fication : : ions tests tests plants of seeds December, 1928 7 56 49 January, 1929 .. 2 270 149 "i" "V August, 1929 ; .. .;;; £ g 2 1 30 September, 1929 139 57 fo October, 1929 38 38 5 November, 1929 103 79 54 Total ••— • 359 2.112 1.588 187 66 ♦Inspections made since April 9th, 1929. TABLE NO. IV. MONTHLY REPORT OF SEED TESTS December 1st, 1929 To November 30th, 1930 Identi- Germina- fication Identi- Inspect- tion. Purity of fication — ; ions tests tests plants of seeds December, 1929 4 • 167 215 1 2 January, 1930 8 324 288 1 February, 1930 71 1,041 881 March, 1930 HO 1,593 909 .... "5 April, 1930 66 706 366 May. 1930 117 2 95 178 "2 "" • June, 1930 , 3 62 37 28 July, 1930 .... 22 24 31 August, 1930 „ ...;. 63 124 55 15 "i ' September, 1930 4 166 117 52 2 October, 1930 7 120 84 II I November, 1930 184 175 61 Total 453 4,804 3,329 218 j's </seg>
            <seg id="p096">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE The following table gives the number of analyses and inspections made during the biennium. TABLE NO. V Dec. 1,1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total to to for : ; Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Biennium Inspections .;... 359 453 gl2 Germination tests 2,112 4,804 6,916 Purity tests ; 1,588 3,329 4,917 Identification of plants 187 218 405 Identification of seeds 66 15 • 81 Total 4,312 8,819 13,131 Neighboring states are legislating for better seed laws and are practicing more rigid enforcement than ever before. Nebraska will be a natural outlet for their unsalable seed, un - less constant attention is paid to the enforcement of the State Seed Law. . ■'■■■" 9 rafi ■ ■ ■ I h II ik' h I m\ ■■■ \ ;. I Nebraska's New State House (Courtesy C. &amp; N. W. Ry.) </seg>
            <seg id="p097">DIVISION OF WEIGHTS AND MEASURES This work during the past biennium has been generally satisfactory to all concerned. However, there has been some little complaint made on account of propaganda being put out by those interested in the sale of scales or in transferring the work from the State to the Federal Department. At a recent meeting of elevator men in Lincoln, a state - ment was made by a gentleman that he saw a demonstration where a scale was loaded to capacity and with the test weights of five hundred pounds no error was found, but with test weights of three thousand pounds a thousand pound error was discovered. This would be a physical impossibility. If there had been an error in the above mentioned scale the five hundred pound weight would have discovered part of the error. If the inspector should start to adjust the scale he would find the cause of that error and would naturally find the rest of the error with the five hundred pound weight. There is a great deal of this propaganda being put out by high-powered salesmen and this is doing injury not only to the scale inspection service but to the industries in the state. The present law should be changed to some extent. There are certain inspections that are made by the Department los - ing money on each inspection. In other words, it costs more to make the inspection than we are allowed to collect. There are other cases where- the inspection fee should be reduced, so that the total income would not amount to more than it does. at the present time. Also the present law allows municipalities, where they so choose, to do their own inspection. The cities of Lincoln and Omaha are the only cities that have availed themselves of this option. However, they are supposed to work under the supervision of the State Department. During the past six years at least there has been very little co-operation. This work should all be done under State Supervision and save a great deal of expense to these cities and the service would be much more satisfactory.. " </seg>
            <seg id="p098">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE INSPECTION OF WEIGHTS AND MEASURES ~~^~ Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929" to to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Scales Sealed - 11,406 13,831 . 25,237 Scales Condemned 23 26 49 Pumps Sealed 3,466 4,673 8,139 Pumps Condemned .15 . 16 31 Measures Sealed .'. 174 62 236 Measures Condemned 10 7 ■ 17 Weights Sealed ..... Weights Condemned . Total Inspections 15,094 .18,615 33,709 Scales Released 5 4 9 Pumps Released _10 6 16 LINCOLN Dec. 1,1928 Dec.l,1929~ .-. .to to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Scales Sealed 615 814 1,429 Scales Condemned 4 9 13 Pumps Sealed 1,331 1,438 2,769 Pumps Condemned ! 112 159 271 Measures Sealed .'. 3,644 3,534 7,178 Measures Condemned :... 95 37 132 Weights Sealed ...... Weights Condemned 5 14 19 Total Inspections 5,806 . 6,005 11,811 Scales Released .....: 113 53 166 Pumps Released 112 162 274 OMAHA ~~Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 to to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Scales Sealed 2,632 2,364 4,996 Scales Condemned :......: 179 113 292 Pumps Sealed 732 758 1,490 Pumps Condemned 20 6 26 Measures Sealed 308 251 559 Measures Condemned 4 .8 12 Weights Sealed 972 751 1,723 Weights Condemned "8 11 19 Total Inspections 4,855 4,262 9,117 Scales Released 179 113. 292 Pumps Released , . 20 6 26 TOTAL NUMBER OF INSPECTION'S ~~Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929" - ' ' ■ Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total Omaha . 4,855 4,262 9,117 Lincoln :..... 5,806 6,005 11,811 State ...„ 15,094 18,615 33,709 Total Inspections .■..-. 25,755 28,882 54,637 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 POTATO INSPECTIONS BY CAR LOTS The present Potato Inspection Law was effective April 15 1929 and provides that whenever, on or before April first in any year petitions signed by potato growers representing fifty-one per cent (51%) or more of the commercial potato acreage of the last preceding crop year in any county, shall be presented to the county board of such county, asking that all car lot shipments of potatoes originating in said county be federal-state inspected at point of origin by the State De - partment of Agriculture in co-operation with the bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture, the county board shall fix a time and place for hearing such petition and shall give notice thereof by pub - lication in a legal newspaper published, or of general circula - tion within the county, which publication shall be made for three consecutive weeks commencing immediately after the petition has been filed. Such hearing shall be held not later than May tenth following. At the time and place mentioned in such notice the county board shall hold hearing thereon, and if it shall determine that' the requirements of this sec - tion have been met, it shall enter an order on its records that compulsory inspection of car lot shipments of potatoes by the State Department of Agriculture in cooperation with the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the United States De - partment of Agriculture is in force and effect in said county for the current potato crop year and for all future years un - less in any year, before April first, a counter petition object - ing to the continuation of the compulsory inspection, and signed by potato growers, representing fifty-one per cent (51%) or more of the commercial potato acreage of the pre - vious crop year be presented to the said county board, in which case the county board shall announce and hold a hear - ing as prescribed in this act in connection with a petition re - questing compulsory inspection. If after such hearing the county board shall find that the counter petition represents fifty-one per cent (51%) or more of the commercial potato acreage of the previous crop year, it shall enter an order on its records declaring' that compulsory potato inspection shall not be in force for. that potato crop year or any later years </seg>
            <seg id="p100">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE until such future year when the provisions of this act shall again be complied with. During the period covered by this report ■, one county, Kimball, has taken advantage of the inspection. The follow - ing table gives the number and classification of the cars shipped from this county: Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 ■ . to to Nov.30,1929 Nov.30,1930 Total U. S. No. 1 ;.. 403 241 644 U. S. No. 2 210 341 551 Unclassified , 19. • 69 88 Total : 632 651 1,283 Hay Inspection During the year December 1, 1929 to November 30, 1930 a limited number of cars of hay were inspected. The class - ification is as follows: U. S. No. 1 Alfalfa : 1 U. S. No. 2 Alfalfa .: 31 U. S. No. 2 Leafy Alfalfa 24 U. S. No. 2 Green Alfalfa 1 Mixed Grade 4 Total .......... : ;.;. 61 I - . ■- ' . ■ "Land o' 'Sunshine" Eggs </seg>
            <seg id="p101">DIVISION OF AGRICULTURAL STATISTICS A. E. Anderson, Agricultural Statistician Through some additional equipment and the efficient use rted onT 6 the PI™ 011 of Agricultural Statistics has car! ried on more work than in the past, without any appreciable Z nT m + r t; f Ven th ° Ugh Nebraska ranks ttW, if not second in of staple grain crops, livestock and Js products the state spends for the collection of agricultural statistics the average amount expended by thirty states that are cooperating with the federal government in this work The amount expended annually for the collection, compilation and publication of detailed statistics on the state's greatest basic industry which has a gross income of nearly a half bil - lion do lars is less than one-sixth of the amount spent by a of n fts e bu a s"ness merChantiIe **"*■ *" LinC ° ln f ° r the stath * ics Much extra work was done during the biennium along educational lines to increase the use of statistics and to clear up some misunderstanding. A sufficient number of 1929 re - ports^ were published to place one copy in every rural school and high school in the state. These reports have been used every year in many of the schools in teaching agriculture and agricultural geography. The teaching of the importance of the great agricultural resources of the state to the younger generation is essential for maximum future development of the state. Increased work in publicity on the agriculture of the state was done. The annual report contains three times the in - formation carried by the average state report, despite the fact that Nebraska does not spend more than the average state does for this work. About 200 items are prepared for the press each year which have given splendid publicity that is essential for the development, of the state. Adherence to the facts, has been the keynote of all publicity. Nebraska is one of the leading agricultural states and advertising the great resources creates interest and centers attention on the </seg>
            <seg id="p102">V HB^^^^H Mum mchH l^lfa^H ' ' ' IS^KfIH 1 'KB ■Sfv ran-sa. ■ ■■ ■■ I KB ' M*-"""^Hj IR _ ■: \ ■ ' ' ' ' ' &lt;-31l ' '•"' mri- I 'B "1 * Ba </seg>
            <seg id="p103">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 state. California, the master advertiser, has greatly facili - tated her development through persistent advertising. Z- Pilsm the schools are taught all of the resources of that great state and they believe it, and talk it wherever tW go As a producer of staple food products such as are needed every day Nebraska is far ahead of California, but many of our owl Si\ T i n ° W E at faCt Simply because i state has failed to advertise sufficiently. ahnJ^ f8Ct th8t tYi * mo cr °P Production of Nebraska was above the average while crops were reduced most seriously i n many states throughout the U. S. gave a good opportuni y for advertising The need for hay and feed in many states was apparent The division put out a report of 1930 produc - tion in detailed form in September in which it advertised the surplus in Nebraska and made a market for the same. This re - port served a very useful purpose besides enabling the state to do the greatest piece of advertising throughout the country that has been done to date. The advantages gained and to be gamed through this alone will pay the small cost of the crop reporting service for many years. Crop and livestock reports are very useful in adjusting production to demand. The manufacturer gets very complete statistics on the production of manufactured products through the Bureau of the Census. This has enabled him to adjust his production to demand. Agricultural Statistics enable the farm - er to adjust his production to a limited extent. The farm out - look reports issued in sufficient time to make adjustments are based upon statistics. Past records have shown an almost in - variable relationship between price and supply and demand. The fluctuation in the price of hogs is due largely to fluc - tuation m the supply. In the season 1923-1924, the supply of federally inspected pork was abnormally high, nearly twelve billion pounds, and the price went below $8 per 100 pounds of hogs. During the 1925-1926 season, the inspected pork dropped to nearly nine billion pounds, and the price averaged above $12 per hundred for hogs. In a similar manner the cause of fluctuation in prices can be explained for all years. The sta - tistics gathered by the Division give sufficient advance in - formation on supplies and future plans of farmers in time to </seg>
            <seg id="p104">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE make the adjustments that will tend to stabilize price. If farmers will plan ahead in the light of statistics, they can solve part of the present farm! problem. The potato crop shows the effect on price of over-produc - tion and under-production. The heavy production of 460,000,* 000 bushels in 1928 sent the price of potatoes down to 60 cents per bushel, and the low production of slightly more than 320, - 000,000 bushels in 1925 sent the price to $1.80 per bushel. Past records reveal that production between these extremes have resulted in prices being almost directly in proportion to the production. , In a similar manner the price relationship be - tween quantity and production is reflected in other farm com - modities. It is pretty conclusive evidence that farmers may derive much benefit from a study and use of agricultural Bta - tistice. The indirect value of statistics is perhaps greater than the direct value. The prevention of the ill effects of misleading crop reports by the publication of government reports needs no comment. Higher price levels are obtained when information on supply is known. Dealers who do not know the supply are more fearful of loss and naturally pay less under such circum - stances. A little experience in buying farm commodities with - out giving any consideration to those factors which affect price will convince the skeptic as to the foregoing statement. For the past few years, alfalfa acreage has been decreas - ing. After statistics revealed this fact, the agricultural college has been making investigations and has at last offered a solution. Alfalfa is on the upward trend again. Agricultural statistics revealed the marked progress made by the sweet clover crop from 30,000 acres in 1920 to 1,126,000 acres in 1930. This crop is of great economic importance in Nebraska as a soil builder and a pasture crop, to say nothing of its value for seed. Here again statistics pointed the development after which college authorities made investigations that proved its value and then recommended its use. Statistics are about the only measure of the agricultural practices advocated by the ag - ricultural college which spends considerable money every year in the interests of agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 f OTO *? the State ? * hat make an annual censu a of agriculture bia a SC\ b °t ° f " " etter devel0ped nS IZtl' or I? 66 " made t0 attain C0I "Pleteness and ac - curacy. Questionable returns are sent back to the precinct assessor for correction before being accepted. Precinct a ses - sors are not entitled to their pay until the report of aS - tural statotics as well as their reports of assessment oTpTp - erty have been approved. An accurate record of the progress of each crop ,n detail, for each county, is published each fear. This record is not only most interesting in itself, but it affords the opportumty for thought and study by those interested in the development of agriculture. Not many years ago, farmers were confronted with car shortages that resulted in serious losses to individuals The organization of the American Railway Association with its regional boards solved this problem by a program of regular meetings in which the statistics of all shipments and pro - spective shipments were studied. The statistics of agriculture are presented, and future car requirements calculated As a result, there has not been a single car shortage of consequence since this organization was perfected. Statistics reveal the phenomenal development in agricul - ture during the past half century. It was the foresight of the pioneers who advocated through the Nebraska State Board of Agriculture the collection of agricultural Statistics in order that the record of Nebraska agriculture might be preserved. Agriculture is Nebraska's largest basic industry. Manufac - turing, the second industry, derives 70 per cent of its revenue from the manufacture of raw farm products. Over half of the value of manufactured products come from the packing of meat at Omaha. Transportation is the third industry, and it depends largely on the great bulk of agricultural products moved. The future development of Nebraska as a state de - pends almost entirely upon agriculture. With so much at stake it would indeed be a short-sighted policy to abandon this highly developed and important work which the wisdom of Nebraska pioneers foresaw over a half century ago. Not since the war has a greater interest been taken in statistics than that shown after the widespread drouth of </seg>
            <seg id="p106">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE /owa | 4*3.55/ SU. \ Illinois |«s,w 3 Nebraska JI12MMM Missouri /raa* II Indiana /6Q599 1 . .CORN Minnesota \*zw » 53.2? Aansas [/goraflu- ~~1 A/ebrasJca, (H^ZZHIHBi OA/ab7na j] OWo 2Z2S5 j. ! WINTER WHEAT Wasfci'ufftan, 1 2ff -^ 6 ' , f North Dakota, l/*./35Bu. Minnesota I Wisconsin I A/ebraska fell— Mich wan U^a » RYE I SouhDa.hu\mB ; • 65.5^ I I ■ '■■■.■ Zbwa (2/6569 flu. I I Minnesota .' \ Illinois MM ' ■ I W/isconsin IQ/-976 ■[ ■ I Nehv&amp;shd E2E— OATS Oh?O 1 7A62.9 1 ' 57./^ I ■ :■] . ■ - «t </seg>
            <seg id="p107">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 California 1 4/zs tons i Nebraska |lMBMBM Idaho 2265 | Kansas z/aa j Colorado a»*&gt; Zl ALFALFAHAY Montana I /^»9 i Nebraska Minnesota. zw —\ South DflUfl. /S2s j NprtKDatotal/2^ ) Kansas ycy ] WILD HAY Montana \szs I 70^^ New York j 6796 TflA/S j Wisconsin Ui/g I Minnesota I £502 . -j California | &amp;^5 ■ . -|^| | Iowa \w&amp; 1 334/. Colorado 1 2520 TONS . 1 A/ebraska 1^ Utah bfl "| Michiiran wo I California soz \ SUGAR BETS Wyoming 1 460 i 9 IZ? </seg>
            <seg id="p108">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE 1930. Anything that affects the food and feed supply of the country is of vital concern, first to the individual and next to all business in general. Farmers in drouth stricken areas were much concerned as to possible sources of feed for their live stock. Manufacturers were concerned over the outlet of their products. Financial agencies interested in placing loans were especially interested in the crop situation. Inquiry from individuals reached the greatest volume to date. The co-operative arrangement with the federal govern - ment in the collection of agricultural statistics has proven to be very satisfactory. It has resulted in better work and great - er economy. It has eliminated duplication and has given the service a much better standing. In fact, neither office could function as efficiently alone. The federal government cannot take an annual census such as is being done by the state through the precinct assessors at the time the assessment of property is made. This is by far the most important part of the work since there is no other source of acreage data as dependable. The State pays for ; the printing, as the federal government cannot arrange for that item which is necessary to preserve the records. Each Department furnishes part of the equipment and part of the personnel. The federal govern - ment furnishes the envelopes and the. franking privilege which is worth about $5,500 per year. The federal government pays the major portion of necessary ifield travel to inspect crops and collect information. There are very few state and federal agencies in which co-operation has worked out so nicely. Another advantage is the continuity of the office work under uniform methods which could not be obtained if the Di - vision head was changed every two or four years. This is especially important in statistical work since the value of the same depends on the comparability from year to year. The ability to judge crops and make forecasts requires training and practice. One must be familiar with the agriculture of the state in its various phases in every detail. He must know soils, rainfall, and the many other factors that affect produc - tion. He must be able to get co-operation from farmers and agencies handling farm commodities and products in order, to get the check material necessary to carry on the work. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 The Division of Agricultural Statistics is distinctively a farmer's institution. Representative samples of production of all farm commodities and. in many cases a complete census is taken periodically to keep the farmer posted on all changes taking place. Similar work is done in every state and as a result the farmer gets nation-wide and even world-wide infor - mation on farm production. Such information diminishes the uncertainty of future market trends and absolutely results in higher price levels than could possibly exist if such informa - tion were lacking. It is a well recognized fact that buying is less brisk and prices sag when the future is uncertain. It has been demon - strated by past records of production that the supply is one of the greatest factors in determining price trends. Given the facts on production, buyers have a greater feeling of security which reacts toward higher price levels. On the other hand, the lack of information on supply creates uncertainty and nat - urally lower prices. This is the indirect value of agricultural statistics mentioned in a previous paragraph. Laws may be made and laws may be repealed, but there is one unwritten law which exists that is not man-made that can never be repealed. It is the economic law of supply and . demand. Many attempts have been made to set aside this economic law, and every one of them has ended in failure and in many cases an unsatisfactory situation was made worse. Past experience in this line has proven that when a commod - ity sells at a higher price in relation to other commodities, that increased production begins immediately and the demand tends to decrease. Soon the unsold accumulated stocks become bur - densome and the structure falls with a mighty crash. It has become increasingly apparent that any plan for the betterment of agriculture that does not take into account the control of the production will never be permanent. Any time the production exceeds the demand there will be a surplus. Due to variation in yield of crops, shortages and surpluses are bound to come. About the only correction that can be made is to adjust acreage when the surplus accumulates in suffi - cient quantity to be burdensome- This action is suggested by the government. A study of both domestic and world-wide pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p110">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE / CULTIVATED flßEft y\ / J5.46J.000 ACRES / \ Ud.2/4,420 r \ PASTURE AND FARMSTEADS / \ 25.51U57 ACRES / \ 53.6^ / • ; - .. "' ; • ' ■ : ■■■• . . ■. ■ ki'- Partial View of Agricultural College at Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p111">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 duction and demand is made; and the results are available for the farmer's guidance in the agricultural outlook reports that are issued at an early date each year. After all, the price that the farmer received cannot ex - ceed that which the demand will pay. A more even flow to market of the farmer's products will help to maintain better prices. Not infrequently a market will receive. several times the quantity of a product that it has a demand for and no deal - er can hardly be blamed for safeguarding his interests in such . cases through lowered price levels. Perhaps one remedy for this is through farm organization or co-operative marketing or some agency that can distribute this flow of farm commodi - ties to market more evenly. Such control by producers them - selves is feasible, and this has been demonstrated in certain commodities such as citrus fruits where the flow to market is so regulated as to avoid gluts. The government is trying to get all producers' organizations to unite into one so that in- ■ stead of competing with one another for the markets there will be one single agency that will be in a better position to get the highest price that the demand will pay. The plan or policy of the government is to assist in the development of co-operative marketing associations and for the handling of their commodities, and to help in bringing about an adjustment of production to market requirements. This will necessitate more information on production than in the past as a guide for actions to be taken. The scope of the work of the State and Federal Division of Agricultural Statistics or its methods have not changed . much from that outlined in detail in the biennial reports for 1925-1926 and for 1927-1928. Every effort has been made to improve and develop it without increasing the expense. All employees of this Division have either taken or are now taking outside study to improve their capacity to do more and bet - ter work. The progress made without increasing the expense is due largely to the study and effort of each employee in this office to develop to the maximum extent of usefulness. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Several changes in the personnel took place during the bi - ennium. Mrs. L. G. Strombeck resigned early in the biennium | and was replaced by Mrs. Lucile Hastings. Mrs. Hastings re - signed after about a year's service, and Miss Hazel Pavey was appointed. Mr. W. H. Forsyth resigned in July, 1929, and Mr. Evan V. Jones was selected to fill the vacancy. The State em- i ployees at the close of the biennium were as follows: Miss ! Florence Schneider and Miss Hazel Pavey, clerks. Mr. Evan V. Jones, assistant statistician, is employed jointly by the State and by the Federal Department. The Federal Depart - ment employees are: Mr. A. E. Anderson, statistician in charge; Miss Edith Heed and Mrs. Laura Brewer, clerks. All employes of the Division have had special training and the practical experience has made them well qualified for the posi - tions they hold. km . Hilllllllilllnr .M n ■* RHB i LnBow«W'^"iJBM&gt;Si[Mjll-.— Lt-H I i - Nebraska Has 130,000 Farm Houses </seg>
            <seg id="p113">DIVISION OF NURSERY AND APIARY INSPECTION L. M. Gates, Inspector INTRODUCTORY There have been several changes in the administration of the work of this division since the last biennial report which should be noted here. The Nursery Inspection Law was amended by the 1929 Session of the Legislature, the old Bee Inspection Law was repealed and a new one passed to take its place, and a Cedar Rust Law was assigned to the Depart - ment of Agriculture for enforcement. Under the amended Nursery Inspection Law there has been an increased number of requests for inspection. It has been possible to take care of this increase without additional help because the law now provides that inspections may start June first instead of July first, this provision allowing an ad - ditional month in which to do the work. The new Bee Inspection Law has made possible more in - spection service for the beekeepers of the state, a service that has been greatly in demand. Practically all of the Apiary in - spections have been made by county or district inspectors working under the Department of Agriculture on a per diem basis. Nursery and Apiary inspections have taken most of the time and attention of this division, but it has been necessary to give some time and thought to the alfalfa weevil quaran - tine, the cedar rust law and mill inspection. The mill inspec - tion service has been taken over by the federal authorities during the past year, and very little has been done with the Corn-Borer Law, or the Pest Eradication Law, because of the absence of European Corn-Borer in Nebraska, in the first case, and because of no funds for enforcement, in the other. These variqus activities will be discussed separately and in greater detail in the rest of this report. Nursery Inspection This activity has included the inspection of nurseries, greenhouses and individual plant shipments, the issuance of certificates and permits, and the collection of fees prescribed </seg>
            <seg id="p114">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE by law. These activities require practically all of the time of the inspector from June first to November first of each year, and a large part of his time during the rest of the year. The number of nursery and greenhouse inspections has con - stantly increased since the beginning of the work in 1927, having been 104 that year and 237 the last year of this bien - nium. Likewise, the number of inspection certificates issued has increased from 94 for the year ending December 1, 1927, to 229 for the year ending December 1, .1930. The number of nursery dealers' certificates issued increased from 23 in the year ending December 1, 1927, to 85 in the year ending De - cember 1, 1930. ; It seems probable that there will continue to be an in - crease in the demands on the plant inspection service because of the greater interest in planting trees, shrubs and other or - namental plants, the increased amount of transportation of such plants and the increasing number of state and federal regulations designed to prevent the spread of injurious insect pests and plant diseases. The following tables summarize the number of plant in - spections and the number of certificates and permits issued during the past biennium: PLANT INSPECTIONS Total for 1928-1929 1929-1930 Biennium Nursery and Greenhouse :.„■ 181 237 418 Individual Shipments _.. 53 79 132 Total! Inspections 234 316 550 CERTIFICATES AND PERMITS ISSUED Total for 1928-1929 1929-1930 Biennium Nursery and Greenhouse Inspections .......... 174 229 403 Cert. Tags for Individual Shipments ] 53 66 119 Dealer's Certificates 69 85 154 Agent's Permits 292 227 519 Non-resident Permits .....: 218 206 424 Duplicate Copies 70 99 169 Total Certificates and Permits 876 912 1,788 The following Nebraska nurserymen, florists and dealers have received certificates from the Department of Agriculture during the biennium : </seg>
            <seg id="p115">GROWERS OP NURSERY STOCK IN NEBRASKA WHO RECEIVED CERTIFICATES DURING 1929 and 1930 '. Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 Ak-Sar-Ben Floral Gardens . M. J. Andrup, Prop.... Omaha, 46th &amp; J Sts. General 104 51 Albion Nursery Co. . . : W. B. Throckmorton &amp; . Axel Nelson, Props Albion General ;.. 56 84 Anderson, A. C, Florist Columbus, 1311 8th St. Hardy perennials, M ornamentals 58 69 £2 Andreson, Sophus. Omaha, Benson Station Perennials and ornamentals.. D 97 W Arpke, W. A ...Beatrice, 657 West Court Strawberries and § Arrowhead- Gardens, The raspberries ...;. 25 34 g Harvey W. Hess, Prop ....Hebron Gladioli, hardy perennials 29 40 &gt; Avalon Nursery, Inc. • . Dr. Carl Kail, Prop ..." _ Lincoln, 4410 South St. General 75 128 » Baibcock, Clyde. Shelby Gladioli '. 142 H Baldwin &amp; Co., C. E Omaha, 2874 California Hardy perennials and 2 ornamentals 108 101 g Bancroft, W. P.. Lincoln, 6503 South St. Shade and fruit trees 147 H Barber's Log Cabin Flower Gardens I Mrs. Winifred Barber, Prop Chadron Perennials 131 g Baumann, E. E Beatrice, 501 Wiebe St. Hardy perennials 54 33 to Bayles &amp; Sweet . r H. N. Bayles &amp; S. R. Sweet, Props Bridgeport Chinese elms 136 g Bennett Gardens Ny. o J. H. Bratt, Prop Bennett General 95 19 Benson-Omaha Ny. P. J. Flynn, Prop Omaha, 7313 Maple General 65 126 Benson Perennial Gardens W. F. Rispler, Prop Omaha, 72nd &amp; Pratt St. Hardy perennials 20 20 Bluff View Nursery W. B. Chase &amp; Son, Prop Omaha, Florence Sta. R-2 General _ 16 16 Boehl, Jno. W. *, Archer Strawberries ' 152 Bonde, Chas. W., Florist Omaha, 511C Military Hardy perennials and Bonivu Gardens ornamentals 78 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">Cert. No. Firm Name AddTess Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 G. A. Gregory, Prop Crete -■■■• Peonies, iris and ornamentals 28 Boon* County Nursery C. J. Anderson, Prop Albion, Rt. 2, Bx. 3 General .. 57 72 Boulevard Gardens Mrs. Lucy J. Bixby, Prop Omaha, 5435 Florence Blvd. Perennials and ornamentals.. 11 Bower, P. L. - ~. Beatrice Strawberries, peonies, Boyd's Nurseries hardy perennials 26 32 Chas. J. Boyd, Prop Ainsworth. General : ,. . 156 138 2 Bronson Nurseries - 2 H. J. Bronson, Prop. Omaha, 85th &amp; Blondo Sts. General 102 54 &gt; Bruce, Win. -• - Omaha, 5311 Florence Blvd. Hardy perennials and . Sd Byrd Nurseries, The small fruits 97 g F. W. Byrd, Prop ..Omaha, 6901 Dodge St. General . ., 118 141 g Cannon's Gardens . ; S B. F. Cannon, Prop Creighton, Route 3 Ornamentals and perennials.. 113 80 2 Campbell's Plant Ny. Hardy perennials Ill 42 _ C. C. Campbell, Prop..... Lincoln, 3600 J St. 2 Chadron Greenhouse Co. Perennials and ornamentals.. • D 57 Wesley W. Williams, Prop. Chadron • Strawberries and asparagus.. 150 Chinberg, Sherman .Omaha, 2502 Craig Ave. 2 City of Lincoln ' • • S PARK DEPARTMENT ■-.-.. £ C. S. Kittinger, Supt. — ~. — ..Lincoln *Ornamentals and S hardy perennials 128 127 H Clifton, L. D. &amp; E. E . — 1... Lincoln, 4822 Holdrege Asparagus and strawberries.. 143 . &lt;3 College View Ny. Co. • W Preston Offil, Prop „ College View, 3843 So. 48th Shade trees j : 121 89 H Cook, Chal.......... ..... . Kearney Strawberries and Cook Perennial Gardens ornamentals ...... • 123 Miss Louise Brehm &amp; Mrs. Pauline Frisch, Props....... Cook Iris, peonies and perennials.. ... 2 Crete Irrigated Gardens , . G. F. Pond, Prop Crete Strawberries and Crookis Nursery . perennials ..... 27 B. F. Crook, Prop . College View Fruit trees and ornamentals.. 139 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">Oert. No. Finn Name Address . Kind of Stock . 1929-30 1930-31 Cropsey, P. K..... „. Lincoln Normal Station Rhubarb, horseradish, Danielson Floral Co. asparagus 132 E. R. Danielson, Prop. . ...Lincoln Nursery and greenhouse ornamentals and perennials 96 126 Davidson, J. B.. — .. ~ — Aurora ' __ Strawberries and raspberries ; 40 ...... Davidson Floral Co. W. E. Davidson, Prop Hastings Nursery and greenhouse 44 77 Del Gra Peony Garden . . g A. L. Dygard, Mgr. Waterloo Peonies and hardy perennials 115 13 W Doran, E. H Omaha, 3377 So. 17th Iris 3 2 Doud, Geo. F. ...Geneva, 1233 D St. Strawberries and g Dutch Gardens ornamentals : 46 44 j&gt; Peter Caauwe &amp; Sons. . Wayne Peonies*, ' strawberries, f Eckley Nursery .' . . gladioli : '61 78 . Walter Eckley, Prop Tekamah • Strawberries and raspberries 60 . 92 W Ederer, Chas., Florist. „ Omaha, 30th &amp; Bristol Hardy perennials, . Jti Elm Grove Nurseries greenhouse stock 116 2 D. A. Sawyer, Prop..... Kearney Raspberries and strawberries 47 hj Engstrom Greenhouse I G. E. Engstrom, Prop Holdrege, 1007 West Ave. General 46 46 g Evergreen Nursery i§ Mrs. E. E. Hahn, Prop Omaha, 3174 Belvidere Blvd.. 131 98 f Everett, Mrs. Harry. Lincoln, 2433 Woodscrest Iris 5 g Fairbury Floral Co. g Norman Cherry &amp; Harold Hodgman, Props Fairbury Perennials 93 Fairbury Nurseries C M. Hurlburfc &amp; Son, Prop Fairbury General _ 28 39 Falls City Nursery A. J. A. Spafford, Prop Falls City General 86 120 Farmers Nursery Co. J. C. Henrich, Prop Fremont Ornamentals 12 24 Fillmore Gardens HH Mrs. Mabel Wernimont, Prop.. Ohiowa, , Iris, peonies and perennials.. ■ 30 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 Fleming's Flower Field W. A. Fleming, Prop Omaha. 2734 No. 65th Ave. Hardy perennials 19 105 Florence Perennial Gardens Paul Sick, Prop Omaha. 9609 No. 34th St. Hardy perennials 15 15 Fontenelle Park Floral Co. C. M. Peterson, Prop : Omaha, 4829 Ames Ave. Hardy perennials 84 106 Frazier, Miss Ella Lincoln, 1546 So. 25th Iris 95 a Fremont Nurseries . ■ . tS Mrs. B. E. Fields, Prop Fremont General _ 23 23 ►« Frey &amp; Frey, Florists &gt; Irwin F. Frey, Mgr Lincoln, 1338 O St. Florist stock ;.... 2 7 2 Freude, Mrs. Emma.... Crete, 146 Main St. Perennials 30 3 Friendship Peony Gardens • § Mrs. W. F. White, Prop .Omaha, 3617 Nebr. Ave. Peonies, hardy perennials 117 116 5; Fulton, F. K Lincoln, 2721 Q St. Ornamentals and perennials.. 140 H Fulton, H. A : : Havelock, 532 So. 12th Strawberries, gladioli, . o Fu'rnas Fruit Farm dahlias and cannas .;...... 145 ' &gt;rj Mrs. Jno. S. Furnas, Prop Brownville Strawberries 140 Garrels, Fred 1 D .Odell Strawberries 162 £ Garvey, Mrs. J. F Lincoln, 48th &amp; South Shade trees and evergreens .. 134 pj Gate City Nursery . 5? Mrs. J. H. Marnette, Prop Omaha, 2403 No. 52rid Ornamentals, hardy £4 Geneva Nurseries - perennials 91 ...... f* Guy A. Brown, Prop ...Geneva General 33 63 Gerle, Rudolph No. Platte. 2400 W. 9th Fruit trees, ornamentals ...... 71 71 S Gladview Farm 2 ■Mrs. Nellie S. Long, Prop . Holdrege, Route 4 Perennials, iris, peonies, Gothenburg Nurseries ■ gladioli 99 9 Mason E. Hyde &amp; Sons, Props. Gothenburg . General ..: .-. 73 73 Gowe, Chas. L ; .Omaha, 4211 So. 19th Ornamentals, hardy Graham's Iris Gardens . • . perennials 103 52 G. H. Graham,, Prop Lincoln, 4410 Judson St. Iris, peonies, phlox, Grand Ave. Peony Gardens hardy perennials 148 48 Herbert Cox, Prop „„ Omaha, 3906 Grand Ave. Peonies, hardy perennials .... 120 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">. ' Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 • Granlund Nurseries G. U. Granlund, Prop.. Norfolk, 1215 Prospect Ave. General 124 85 Graves, Mrs. P. C. Omaha, 19th &amp; Ames Ave. Perennials and ornamentals.. 160 ...... Green's Greenhouses, Inc. C. H. Green, Pres. Fremont Peonies, iris, gladioli, Groundhog. Guich Fruit Farm .;. hardy perennials 53 25 S. D. Parks, Prop Brownville . Raspberries and strawberries ...... 135 Grousewald Flower Field . - ■ Mrs. Fred Grouseman, Prop Omaha, Route 8, Hardy' perennials :..... 107 3 Hamilton Seed Co. . Florence Station g R. J. Hamilton, Prop Omaha, 86th &amp; Lake Sts. General :..... 82 82 § Guthrie &amp; Land • ' ' § ' W. E. Guthrie &amp; Francis Land Bridgeport Chinese elm ...... 129 &gt;• Hansen-Brown Ny. Co. t* A. Hansen, Mgr. Fremont, 135 No. M St. Plum and shade tree W seedlings 17 17 H Harms, Carl. Columbus, 1619 9th St. Hardy perennials, § Harpster Floral Co. . ornamentals 59 w Albert E. Harpster, Prop....: ........Omaha, 5720 No. 16th Ornamentals, hardy i-3 perennials 106 | Harris, A. D.. Lincoln, 34th &amp; Vine Sts. Iris, peonies and perennials.. 159 £ Harrison Nursery Co. to E. E. Mason, Mgr York General 34 31 f Hart Gardens, Joan 5 Mrs. Joan Hart, Prop Omaha, 9905 Florence *Rock garden plants, lilacs, g Hastings Nursery Heights Blvd. peonies, ins, perennials .... 137 114 Wellington Keith, Prop Hastings General 45 109 Hazel-Del Nursery Benj. J. Day, Prop Omaha, Florence Station General 122 133 Hein, Albert T. Central City, Route 1 Cedars and cottonwoods 158 137 Hensler, John Lincoln, Route 2 Hardy perennials, ornamentals 7 47 Hill Crest Peony Garden Lincoln, West O St., RM5 Peonies _ J64 Hillegass, Mrs. Rosena C Rising City ' Gladioli and iris 126 108 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">Oert. No. Firm Name AddTess Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 Hoevet &amp; Sons , C. L. Hoevet, Prop Fairfield General _ 32 49 Holdrege Garden Club Holdrege 'Perennials and ornamentals 119 10 Home Landscaping &amp; Ny. Co. Mrs. E. J. C. Sward, Prop Lincoln, 1726 P St. General 123 124 Home Landscape Service " ' ' O. V. Sherpy, Prop Omaha, 924 No. 24th St. Hardy perennials, M ornamentals 21 53 2 Hooge, A., Florist , Omaha, 3517 So. 20th Hardy perennials 110 fc^ Hooks, Robert A. Blair Raspberries, walnuts 63 100 &gt; Howard Greenhouses . . W Howard, A. T., Prop Scottsbluff General 129 61 3 Howe Floral Co. . . 5 Dr. A. B. Hopper, Prop Hastings Perennials and ornamentals.. 141 § Hutchinson Nurseries . . .1-3 P. H. Hutchinson, Prop...... Kearney General .. : 50 60 o Jelinek Floral Co. . !^ V. J. Jelinek, Prop Crete, 1041 Main Ave. Nursery and florist 130 29 . Johnson, Mrs. Fred .„ „..._ Lincoln, 3231 So. 40th Strawberries '. 154 £ Kasparek, Chas Fairbury Perennials 27 37 S Kearney. Flpral &amp; Ny. Co. £* O. L. Erickson, Prop Kearney . General ..J. 49 59 2 Kernine, Fador. Shelby Gladioli, lilies 105 113 t-« Kloepfel Gardens . H H. J. Kloepfel, Prop....... .*.... Falls City ■'.; Ornamentals, hardy ■ Q Kuhner, The Florist •" ! perennials 87 D S C. Kuhner, Prop :.. College View General 85 ra Lake View Farm N. P. Nelson, Prop........ Omaha ' Hardy perennials 18 18 Lathrop, W. A. St. Paul . ' - Hardy perennials 39 64 Lehr Floral Garden . . . . J. F. Lehr, Prop Mead Peonies, iris :.... 37 115 Lewis. Perennial Gardens . M. B. Lewis, Prop. Omaha, 3824 Grand Ave. Hardy perennials, ornamentals 65 130 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">""" "" . • Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 Lincoln Garden Club. ... Lincoln . General „ '.- 133 134 Lin-wood Park Nursery • . . Anton Kostal, Prop. So. Omaha, 6033 So. 24th General ;........ :.. 81 67 Lohman Flower Shop A. A. Lohman, Prop. „ Hastings, 901 E. South St. Ornamentals', strawberries, perennials 157 112 McOurdy, Mrs.. Clark Steele City • Gladioli 151 Mader, P. W . Grand Island, 514 E. 9th St. Peonies, iris, perennials 42 66 M Maple Road Garden . ... S Jacob Sass, Prop.... — ...Omaha, Route 6, ' 2 Benson Station Ornamentals, hardy s Marshalls Nurseries, Inc. perennials, iris, peonies 1 1 S G«o. Marshall, Pres : Arlington &amp; Omaha General ■. _ 6 6 &gt;■ Maxwell, Sam Waterloo Strawberries ~. 144 • " Mid-west Gardens - td Hans P. Sass, Prop Washington Peonies, iris, ornamentals, W Miller's Green Tree Ny. hardy perennials 3 99 2 H. J. Miller, Prop Creston General .■. 135 « Mitchell's Pansy Gardens ■ H Bay Mitchell, Prop. .Lincoln, 1712 No. 48th Pansies, iperennials | and ornamentals 138 g Moller, Ray. Fremont Strawberries 13 26 g Moore, W. E. ...Omaha, 83rd &amp; Bedford Raspberries 76 76 ' r Morningside Ny. Co. 5 C. Pelmulder, Prop. Lincoln &amp; York General 64 § Nebraska City Nurseries Nebr. City General 36 121 Nebraska National Forest A. L. Nelson, Supv. Halsey *Pinea 200 200 Nebraska Nurseries H. W. Stuhr, Prop Lincoln, 3640 J St. General 9 43 Nickerson Nursery &gt;—«»&lt; L. R. Barratt, Prop Nickerson General D 14 Norfolk Nurseries . . C. E. Ward, Prop. Norfolk General 66 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 North Platte Nys. Inc. Efriil Mercheid, Prop North Platte General 72 107 Pass, C. J., Florist North Platte Hardy perennials, ornamentals 74 74 Patterson, H. E Peru _ Small fruit stock 89 119 Peony &amp; Floral Gardens Wm. B. Didriksen, Prop., Kearney Peonies, shrubs 48 58 a Peony Gardens, The 2 H. F. Warren, Prop Trumbull Peonies, iris, hardy t-o Peony Gardens, The __ " perennials, ornamentals — 8 8 &gt; R. Caplis Estate Omaha, 83rd &amp; Dodge Peonies 12 •* Perennial Nursery . . . V:i .. ,"S L. C. Bacon, Prop Bloomington Ornamentals and perennials.. 112 132 Perrin Gladioli Gardens ■ " ■.,.',- 2 Harold I. Perrin, Prop.; ...„ Sargent - Gladioli and peonies 127 65 h Pfeiffer, Otto. ...:.... : Gordon General 67 68 o Phimfield Nurseries . w L. A. Moffet, Mgr. Fremont, 2105 No. Nye General ' 11 21 v Pound, Mrs. J. A Lincoln, 615 No. 27th St. Perennials 4 &gt; Rainbow Iris Gardens, The w Mrs. L. 0. Jones', Prop Lincoln, 3115 O St. Iris 81 ►=; Robinson, A. W ..' Tekamah General :..„ 68 88 q Sala's Gladioli Gardens . : - ,_, Mrs. P. E. Sala, Prop Lincoln Gladioli and Tiardy H perennials 149 90 G Schleichardt, Ed... Grand Island, Route 4 Shade trees ;„. 52 139 g Schnitter, Max Lincoln, 3259 Holdrege St. Perennials 101 56 Schureman, Lee Lincoln, 2222 So. 48th St. Ornamentals 94 96 Joel M. Roberts, Mgr. York Ornamentals and perennials,. 38 60 Seward Nursery, Seed &amp; Floral Co. H. P. Rigdon, Prop. Seward General - 41 4 Sheetz, Mts. W. P Omaha, 3498 Paxton Blvd. Peonies, iris and perennials.. 55 Shiloh Gardens E. H. Wilson, Prop Omaha, 515 So. 56Uh Hardy perennials .........„..:. 22 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">Cert. No. Firm Name Address . Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 Sioux Nurseries R. B. Teager, Prop... : So. Sioux City, General .... 79 Slagel's Greenhouse 216 W. Farnam St. C. W. Slagel &amp; Son, Props Davenport Hardy perennials 31 41 Sonderegger Nys. &amp; Seed House Carl Sonderegger, Prop... Beatrice &amp; Omaha General .. 24 38 Spangenberg, O...'. ...Grand Island Shade trees 51 Stewart's Sd. &amp; Flower Shop C. J. Gerstmyer, Prop Omaha, 109 No. 16th ■ . Peonies, phlox, iris, 2 hardy perennials 77 ■ M Stinger, Grant Nebraska City ■ Strawberry and pansy plants 90 117 g Sunnyside Greenhouse 2 Simanton &amp;. Pence, Props Falls City Nursery and greenhouse &gt; Superior Floral Co. stock 88' 122 F Victor Ryhd, Prop :.... Superior Nursery and greenhouse $d Superior Garden Club • stock '. i 100 110 ' H Mrs. C. O. Groves,- Pres ....I.Superior *Perennials and ornamentals 98 111 £* Swanson, Harry. .-. /..Albion Ornamentals and perennials.. 114 2 Tanner's Greenhouse &amp; Ny. h C. B. Tanner, Prop Lincoln, 1133 Cotner Blvd. General nursery and | Tekamah Greenhouse florist's stock ... 93 91 g Herbert Chase, Prop Tekamah Hardy perennials 125 to Terhune's Flowers . f O. Terhune, Prop Gering General 70 70 £ Therkildsen, C. B..... Omaha, 4828 Ames Ave. General 80 103 g Thomas, Arthur J Nebraska City Gladioli and raspberries 118 Thomas, W. A Lincoln, Route 2 Ornamentals : 163 Tilley's Lake Nursery Wm. F. Tilley, Prop Grand Island General 69 142 Timmler, Rudolph Omaha, 316 No. 57th St. Ornamentals and perennials.. 83 83 Tindell's Flowers E. H. Tindell, Prop Omaha, 7920 Maple St. Hardy perennials 79 104 Topp, A. C, Florist Hastings Nursery and greenhouse stock 43 .-,... Tyler, Wm Central City Cedars, hackberry, and elms- 163 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">Cert. No. Firm Name Address Kind of Stock 1929-30 1930-31 University of Nebraska C. C. Wiggans, Prof, of Horticulture Lincoln 'General 199 University of Nebraska H. A. McComb, Horticulturist. No. Platte "General _ 198 198 Walthill Nursery Jno. Moffet, Prop Walthill : Apple, spruce, hardy o Wayne Greenhouses &amp; Ny.- perennials 161 tg D. Hall &amp; Son, Props ..Wayne General 62 75 Westrom Ny. Co. 5&gt; J. J. Westrom, Prop Omaha, 2006 Ohio St. General 36 36 g Whitney, Mrs. Myrtle Lincoln, P. O. Box 85 Strawberries 155 2 Williams Nys. &amp; Gardens § L. 0. Williams &amp; Sons, Props Lincoln, 4543 Hunting-ton General 5 87 _ jj; Woods. Bros. Nurseries ' : ... , . HJ ' Ernst Herminghaus, Mgr Lincoln, 35th &amp; Sheridan General _'..„ 10 62' q Yager Ny. &amp; Seed Co. . *j J. A. Yager, Prop Fremont Plum seedlings 14 . York Floral Co. • O Grover C. May, Prop ....York Ornamentals, hardy . {d Yule Floral Co. • perennials 35 35 5? F. G. Yule, Prop ; .... Lincoln, 147 No. 33rd. Hardy perennials, c5 Zingerlie Floral Co.** ornamentals 92 94 p Jno. Zingerlie, Prop i.Omaha, 580S No. 24th Florists, hardy perennials .... 109 102 H * — No stock for sale. . S *• — Formerly Hargadine &amp; Zingerlie. . S D — Dealer's Certificate. ;'_i . . . T ' .' ■ ; : '. ■J t . </seg>
            <seg id="p125">BIENNIAL. REPORT— 1929-1930 DEALERS IN NURSERY STOCK IN NEBRASKA WHO RECEIVED CERTIFICATES DURING 1929 and 1930 Cert. No. Firm Name Address 1929-301930-31 Alliance Floral Co. A. F. Irwin, Prop. -Alliance 60 60 Andresen, Sophiis.. Omaha, Route 1, Benson Barbur Floral Company Station 32 Inap. Jas. B. Barbur, Prop .^..Geneva , 56 „. Barratt, L; R.. ; Nickerson 1 Insp. Beatty, Walter Omaha, 4401 Dodge St 26 Bergstrom; John F Chappel 69 Bestor &amp; Swatek Hdw. Co. F. M. Bestor, Mgr Plattsmouth 43 .... * Bilz Seed &amp; Nursery Co Omaha, 1414-16 Harney.. 16 • 16 Brand, Miss Celia.. ~ Madison 12 ' .... . Brandeis &amp; Son H. B. Zimman, Mgr Omaha 51 Calder, Alexander .JDannebrog 58 Carney Seed &amp; Sales Co. C. H. Carney, Prop ...Lincoln, 127 So. 10th St. 54 Chadron Greenhouse Co. Wesjey W. Williams, Prop.....Chadron _ 11 Inap. Daugherty, Wm ........Omaha, 2319 No. 65th St. Benson Station 50 Dymacek, Emanuel Crete 63 Field Greenhouse, W. H .Madison 18 Gaines, O. E Fremont, 1131 E. Military Gold &amp; Co. Ave 20 Ralph W. Tyler, Sec'y- Lincoln, 11th &amp; O St 52 Griswold Seed &amp; Nursery Co. F. P. Quick, Pres Lincoln, 147 So. lOifh 19 Robt. S. Griswold Sd. &amp; Fl. Co. Robt. S." Griswold, Prop Lincoln, 110 No. 10th 28 28 Gunn .Seed Co. ... B. S. Gunn, Prop Lincoln, 127 So. 10th........ 45 HoldTege Floral Co. J. E. Oharlson, Prop.... Holdrege 23 23 Holiib, Edward Omaha 29 Humphrey. Nurseries. The A. G. Billerbeck, 'Mgr. Humphrey 30 Ihm's Nursery F. J. Ihm, Prop .'...Omaha, 2623 No. 52nd 1 St. 47 34 Kilpatrick &amp; Co., Thos........ Omaha 27 27 King, Ada Stein... York 33 Kloepfel Gardens Henry J. Kloepfel, Prop.........Falls City Insp. 18 Kresge Co., S. S. R. A. Bell, Sec'y-."- Lincoln, 1125 O St 33 9 Kresge Co., S. S. R. A. Bell, Sec'y. Omaha, 4828 So. 24th 38 11 Kresge Co., S. S. R. A. Bell, Sect Omaha, 402 So. 16th ........ 37 12 Kresge Co., S. S. R. A. Bell, Sec'y. ...Frifinont, 103 E. 6th St .. 36 IB </seg>
            <seg id="p126">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE Firm Name ' Address 1929-30 1930-31 Kresge Co., S. S. R. A. Bell, Sec'y. Hastings .... 4 McCook Greenhouse C. H. Brown, Prop McCook 15 McCrory, J. G. &amp; Co. G. E. Muschert, Asst. Sec'y-Omaha, 216 So. 16th St... 4 46 Meneray Ny. &amp; Seed Store E. D. Meneray, Prop Council Bluffs, la..... 55 '■ .... Midwest Landscape Co. Alfred Middleton, Prop Omaha 53 Miller &amp; Paine R. E. Campbell, Mgr Lincoln, 13th &amp; 0 Sts 5 5 Nebraska .Seed Co., The H. G. Windheim, Prop..., -..Omaha, 1208 Jones St 34 • 26 Norfolk Floral Co. Frank T. Darling, Owner Norfolk '. 25 Old Trusty Nurseries H. H. Johnson, Mgr ...Clay Center 57 30 Parke-Brown Company O. M. Parke, Prop Lincoln 61 Prickett, C. 0 Wallace .... 32 Ranney Seed Co. C. A. Ranney, Prop .-. Omaha, 1304 Farnam St. 31 36 Rohan Nursery Co. John M. Rohan, Prop .......Omaha, 3315 Webster St. 29 Rudee &amp; Guenzel Co. E. U. Guenzel, Treas Lincoln, 13th &amp; N Sts 17 17 Ryan, T. P. &amp; Son .Omalha, 2622 Dodge St 24 19 Sandfort, Carl ...Humboldt .... 31 Shada, Nicholas ....Lexington .' 46 Singers, G. M Fremont 2 3 Slepicka, Alois Wilber 62 Teager, Ralph E ...So. Sioux City, Nebr. 216 W. Farnam St 48 Insp. Tracy, A. E 9 20 Turnbull, C. E Norfolk, 702 Woolworth Co., F. W. Koenigstein Ave 3 25 J. G. Prall, Mgr Alliance, 368 Box Butte Woolworth Co., F. W. Ave ; 42 42 S. E. Schultz, Mgr Beatrice 49 Woolworth Co., F. W. G. F. Sears, Mgr Columbus .: ......; 41 41 Wnolwo^h Co., F. W. F. J. Kosak, Mgr Fremont 6 6 Woolworth Co., F. W. A. R. Berkhimer, Mgr Grand Island 22 22 Woolworth Co., F. W. E. M. Alspaugh, Mgr Hastings 40 40 Woolworth Co., F. W. C. C. Simmonds, Mgr Kearney 21 21 Woolworth Co., F. W. Jay B. Pulis, Mgr .Lincoln 10 10 Woolworth Co., F. W. G. C. Rone, M«rr Nebraska City, 807 Woolworth Co., F. W. Central Ave 14 14 A. F. Ravenscroft, Mgr Norfolk 39 39 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 • ■'■'-.■ Cert. No. j- , Firm Name Address. 1929-301930-31 Woolworth Co., F. W. A. J. Davis, Mgr. Omaha, 16th! &amp; Douglas.. 8 8 Woolworth Co., F. W. A. F. Deicken, Mgr............ — Omaha, 16th &amp; Farnam.. 7 7 Woolworth Co., F. W. C. R. Bettes, Mgr. Scottsfbluff 44 45 Woolworth Co., F. W. G. U. Baldwin, Mgr. So. Omaha, 4816 Woolworth Co., F. W. So. 24th 13 18 Elmer J. Tonkinson, Mgr.......York 35 35 Woolworth Co., F. W. JO. C. Murray, Mgr.. McCook .. 1 Woolworth Co., F. W. J. R. Holcomb, Mgr..., North Platte J 2 NUMBER AND SIZE OF NEBRASKA NURSERIES The number of nurseries inspected during the past bien - nium was 339, being an increase of 55 over the preceding bi - ennium when 284 nurseries were inspected. The total area inspected was approximately 1,073 acres in 1929, and 1,090 acres in 1930/ The following table classifies the nurseries according to size: 1929 1930 Nurseries growing more than 100 acres of nursery stock 3 3 Nurseries growing from 75 to 100 acres of nursery stock 1 1 Nurseries growing from 50 to 75 acres of nursery stock Nurseries growing from 25 to 50 acres of nursery stock 2 1 Nurseries growing from 5 to 25 acres of nursery stock 9 11 Nurseries growing from 1 to 5 acres of nursery stock 67 72 Nurseries growing one acre or less of nursery stock 90 79 Total 172 167 NUMBER AND SIZE OF NEBRASKA GREENHOUSES INSPECTED In addition to inspecting the nurseries in Nebraska it was necessary to make the following greenhouse inspections: Year No. of Inspections Square Feet of Glass 1929 „...: 10 535,000 .1930 , 8 486,000 Total 18 1,021,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p128">INSECT PESTS AND PLANT DISEASES FOUND IN NURSERIES AND ON NURSERY STOCK From December 1, 1928, to November 30, 1930 No seriously injurious insect pests or plant diseases that are new to Nebraska since the last biennial report have been found in the course of the past two years' inspections. The pine-leaf scale, which gave the nurserymen considerable con - cern two years ago, seems to be well under control wherever an earnest attempt at control has been carried out. Several dif - ferent commercial oil sprays were used by the nurserymen with good results in most cases. A few instances of "burning" were noted, but the evergreens thus affected recovered within a few months and were then entirely free from scale. Another pest of evergreens, the red spider, has been controlled by the use of these same oil sprays. The spruce tortrix, which has been found in various lo - cations in the state during the past. few years, seems to be thoroughly under control wherever a spray schedule is being followed. The addition of lead arsenate to the oil sprays has been recommended for the control of this pest. More diseased gladiolus corms have been found during the past biennium than at any previous time, indicating the need of regulation in the distribution of propagating stock. Specimen corms from one shipment from a non-resident grow - er were sent to Washington for diagnosis of the diseased con - dition by specialists of the United States Department of Ag - riculture, who found them affected by four different diseases, namely, scab, Fusarium rot, hard rot, and Penicillium rot. The growers of gladiolus corms are being urged to cull out all corms showing lesions of any kind, and to treat in one of the approved disinfecting solutions the ones to be planted. Systemic diseases of raspberries were found more com - monly during the past season than previously, and several growers of these plants for propagation are asking for two inspections each season as required for certification by several other states. </seg>
            <seg id="p129">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 PLANT QUARANTINE No new quarantines have been promulgated under the Insect Pest and Plant Disease Quarantine Law. The alfalfa weevil quarantine is still in force together with the two amend - ments which were issued during the preceding biennium. However, it has been necessary to carry on considerable cor - respondence with some of the other states in order to keep Nebraska from being quarantined on account of a report of the finding of one alfalfa weevil larva in Scotts Bluff county. Be - cause of this report Mississippi authorities quarantined the whole state of Nebraska; and Arizona, California, Illinois, Washington, Wisconsin and Wyoming, quarantined Scotts Bluff county. These quarantines prohibiting the shipment of alfalfa hay from the quarantined areas to the states passing the quarantines. Considerable alfalfa hay is annually shipped from Nebraska to Mississippi, Wisconsin and Illinois, and the enforcement of quarantines against Nebraska hay would mean considerable loss to Nebraska producers. By taking up the alfalfa weevil situation with the various state officials it was possible to secure the removal of the quarantines passed by Illinois, Mississippi and Wisconsin. 'Quarantines against Nebraska hay on account of alfalfa weevil are still maintained by other states as follows: Arizona „ '.- Scotts Bluff California .Scotts Bluff (changed to Sioux county) ♦♦ Washington : Scotts Bluff Wyoming _ ..._ Scotts Bluff *U. S. D. A. Misc. Publ. No. 80. "Revision Alfalfa Weevil Quarantine Order No. 7 effective June 20, 1930. California State Department of Agriculture. It will be noted that all .of these states except California maintain a quarantine against Scotts Bluff county, although the report of the finding of a single weevil larva by a federal entomologist is the only record of alfalfa weevil in Nebraska, and it has now been determined that the field from which, the larva was reported is in Sioux county. During the past three years no alfalfa weevil has been found in Sioux or Scotts Bluff county nor in the adjacent territory in Wyoming by state or federal entomologists, although this area has been thoroughly scouted each summer. The Nebraska Department of Agri- </seg>
            <seg id="p130">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE . culture therefore does not believe that alfalfa weevil occurs in this state, and considers all alfalfa weevil quarantines on Ne - braska territory altogether unjustified. i ■'■■■■-.:. •. EUROPEAN CORN BORER The Legislature of 1927 passed a law known as the Euro - pean Corn Borer Law, the purpose of which was to prevent the introduction and spread of this pest in Nebraska. An appro - priation of $25,000.00 was made at that time to be used when - ever the European corn borer should be found in the state. None of this fund was used during the biennium following and the same amount was re-appropriate i for the present bien - nium. The fund is still untouched since the corn borer has not been found in the state. A possible infestation by the corn borer in Nebraska was prevented when a shipment of musk-rats consigned from corn borer territory in Michigan, to a central Nebraska county, wa3 found by federal inspectors in Chicago to be supplied with ears of corn in violation of the federal quarantines. Upon receiving notice of this shipment the Department of Agriculture wired the county officials in the county to w lich the musk-rats were consigned and succeeded in having a 1 remnants of the corn destroyed, thus eliminating a possible source of corn borer in - festation in Nebraska. . PEST ERADICATION LAW The Pest Eradication Law is styll unused because of a lack of funds for its enforcement. TJTie tentative agreement drawn up several years ago between the United States Bureau of Biological Survey, the extension service of the College of Agriculture, and the State Department of Agriculture, which was mentioned in the last biennial report, has not been put into effect. It had been hoped that considerable service could be given the citizens of the state in the control of prairie dogs, gophers and other rodents, by the use of the pest eradication law, in co-operation with the organizations mentioned above. All inquiries received at the Department of Agriculture on this subject are now referred to Professor M. H. Swenk of the College of Agriculture, who is able to give information as to the most approved methods of eradicating rodent pests. </seg>
            <seg id="p131">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 MILL INSPECTION Several mill inspections were made during the past two years at the request' of the mill owners, but this work is now being done by a specialist of the Bureau of Entomology of the United States Department of Agriculture, located at Man - hattan, Kansas. Mr. Geo. B. Wagner is now the agent in charge of the study of insect control in flour mills. . The following list gives the names and addresses of the mills where inspections were made during the biennium: Firm Name Address Date of Inspection C. A. Cooper Co Humboldt May 20, 1929 Gooch Milling &amp; Elevator Co........:.. Lincoln April 1, 1929 Gooch Milling: &amp; Elevator Co Lincoln July 29, 1929 Lexington Mill &amp; Elevator Co Lexington March 28, 1929 Lexington Mill &amp; Elevator Co Lexington Sept. 12, 1929 Maney Milling Co.... Omaha i April 2, 1929 Maney Milling Co Omaha June 10, 1930 Miller Cereal Mills Omaha April 3, 1929 Miller Cereal Mills Omaha April 21, 1930 Schmihke Mill &amp; Elevator Co ...Nebraska City. April 4, 1929 Seward City Milling Co Seward March 27, 1929 Seward City Milling Co ..... ; .Seward July 1, 1929 Wells-Abbott-Nieman Co Schuyler .March 29, 1929 Zwonechek&amp;Aksamit Milling Co Wilber May 29, 1929 CEDAR RUST LAW The Cedar Rust Law, which was passed by the 1929 legis - lature, provides "that the Department of Agriculture shall make preliminary investigation of a locality upon the request in writing of five or more "reputable freeholders" of any county or district, to ascertain if any red cedar tree or trees, in said locality, constitute the host plant for the disease known as "cedar rust." The Department has not received any such request and therefore no legal action has been taken. However, at the request of individuals in several localities in southeast Nebraska, several orchard and cedar tree owners were visited and the requirements of the law explained. The attitude displayed by all parties concerned makes it seem prob - able that many of the cedar trees will be removed without the necessity of using the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p132">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE APIARY INSPECTION The present Apiary Inspection Law has been on the stat - ute books since April, 1929, at which time the old law was re - pealed. The provision for funds for the enforcement of this law is in the form of a colony tax. This is a special tax levied by the county boards and collected by the county treasurer as other personal taxes are collected. The basis of the assess - ment is the report of the county assessor on the number of hives or colonies of bees reported by the precinct assessors in ► the county. The law was passed before the assessors began their work in 1929, and special instructions were mailed to them by the state tax commissioner. Most of the counties reported to the | Department of Agri - culture as to the number of colonies assessed, but some county boards failed to levy the 10-cent tax. Where the tax was levied the full amount expected was not always realized and the money was slow in coming from the county treasurers. There were some receipts as early as January, 1930, and some have been received as late as November, 1930. Although it was late in the inspection season before there were sufficient funds on hand to warrant the appointment of county inspectors, some work was started last spring and has been continued to date. Since more can be accomplished by the apiary inspectors in the spring than at other times of the year, the Department has not spent all of the money available this year, but is planning a larger and more intensive campaign against American foulbrood in the spring of 1931. During the past year 12 county or district inspectors have been appointed at $5.00 per day, from which amount they are required to pay their hotel and transportation expenses. The men selected for the work have been chosen because of their familiarity with beekeeping conditions in their respective local - ities and because of their experience and interest. All of them are practical beekeepers "who are now managing apiaries of their own. They have been willing to sacrifice some time and labor in order to help eradicate American foulbrood. The amount paid them by the State cannot be considered ade - quate compensation for the services rendered, but it did not seem feasible to pay more from the limited funds" available. </seg>
            <seg id="p133">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 1 The response of the counties to the requirements of the law, and the amount of work accomplished by the county in - spectors, is as follows: APIARY INSPECTION NUMBER OF STANDS OP BEES ASSESSED, BEE-TAX RECEIVED, 1929 Listed by Counties Stands Amount Paid . of Bees Amount Due Amount out for County reported at 10c ! received inspections Adams 339 $ 33.90 ? . . . $ Antelope 238 23.80 23.80 ' Arthur 2 .20 .20 ""'Z Banner '. . 0 ....... Blaine 5 .50 "".50 Boone . 350 36.00 33.80 flfon" Box Butte 45 4.50 3.50 Boyd 359 35.90 35.50 Brown 15 1.50 0 Buffalo i 790 79.00 73.81 5000 B«t - • .-.- 425 42.60 40.60 10^00 Butler _ ...... 496 49.60 44.10 ...!„" Cass — 286 28.60 21.60 Cedar 461 . 46.10 40.00 Chase _!..:„. 49 4.90 ' 0 Cherry 105 10.50 0 ■ " Cheyenne 30 3.00 0 Clay ,»...... 472 47.20 0 Coif ax . 125 12.50 0 Cuming .. 233 23.30 Custer 549 54.90 51.70 ZZ Dakota „ 536 53.60 Dawes .......J....... 210 21.00 13"24 Dawson J 719 71.90 37.50 Deuel J . 86 8.60 0 Dixon 298 29.80 29.35 Dodge „... 164 16.40 16.04 10.00 Douglas 460 45.00 0 Dundy _„ 55 5&gt;50 0 jr Fillmore 380 38.00 37.21 Franklin ...J.... 272 27.20 27.20 !"Z" Frontier J 21 2.10 .60 Furnas 1 539 53.90 17.00 "Z" Gage „ 1,478 147.80 102.51 Garden 103 10.30 0 Garfield J — . ..... 113 11.80 0 is".18 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE' Stands ' Amount Paid . of Bees AmountDue Amount out for bounty reported at 10c I received inspections Gosper 128 12.80 0 Grant 20 2.00 0 Greele V • .62 5.20 0 5"00 Ha"-. 266 ? 26.60 ? 26.00 $ 7.50 g an jilton 307 30.70 . 30.70 12 50 Harlan . 85 8.50 8.50 Hayes 65 6.50 0 Hitchcock golt 318 3L80 28.56 Hooker "■■"■■ Howard " 232 ■: &amp;2ti mjo ■ "££$ Jefferson 520 52.00 " 50.60 Johnson 279 27.90 26.10' Kearney 131 13.10 12.60 Keith 235 23.50 18.40 Keya Paha 85 8.50 0 Kimball 11 1.10 1,00 Knox , 339 33.90 32.70 ""'.'.'.'. Lancaster 672 67.20 52.55 50.00 Lincoln 972 97.20 95.14 Logan 61 6.10 0 Loup H4 H.40 o ib'ibo Madison 162 16.20 16.20 McPherson 5 50 0 Merrick ;. 311 31.10 14.90 22.50 Mornll 1,034 103.40 35.00 35.00 Nance 140 14.00 10.60 Nemaha 321 32.10 18.30 Nuckolls _.... 877 87.70 80.60 Otoe , ■„. 460 46.00 18.90 Pawnee 437 43.70 39.90 Perkins Phelps 52 "5.2b "4T20 Pierce .v 75 . 7.50 0 Platte 350 35.00 32.20 's"6'6 Polk 233 23.30 20.34 Red Willow 47 4.70 4 70 Richardson 579 57.90 36.71 10.00 Rock 73 7.30 0 Saline 384 38.40 37.76 5.00 Sarpy 249 24.90 24.00 Saunders 668 66.80 59.40 Scottsbluff 928 92.80 36.00 25.62 Seward 575 57.50 49.00 Sheridan 339 33.90 25.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 Stands Amount Paid of Bees Amount Due Amount out for County ' reported at 10c received inspections Sherman 396 39.60 34.10 Sioux 437 43.70 0 Stanton 110 11.00 10.00 Thayer 514 $ 51.40 $ 50.00 $ Thomas ; I Thurston ...L 534 53.40 41.00 ........ Valley .......1. 459 , 45.90 0 J....... Washington :. 734 73.40 36.00 45.00 Wayne i. 184 18.40 18.25 Webster 302 30.20 25.80 Wheeler 46 4.60 0 5.00 York 558 55.80 48.36 Total ..' : 28.263 $2.826.30 $1,872.83 $338.75 A low j cost of inspection per colony has been possible be - cause the inspectors have put in long hours and there has been good 1 co-operation on the part of many of the bee - keepers. Considerable time has been donated by inspectors and other beekeepers. Our present records indicate that it has cost approximately 8c per colony for the inspections made to. date. Other states have paid. from 20c to 30c per colony for apiary inspection. Eradication of American foulbrood should be the aim of the apiary inspection service and this can be brought about only when there are sufficient funds available to make possible the inspection of every colony of bees in the state every year. Until that [time it may be advisable to concentrate on certain areas and spread out from these as rapidly as possible. The following statistical statement summarizes the ac - tivities of this division for the biennium ending November 30 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p136">APIARY INSPECTIONS Name of Inspector County Inspectors Appointed, Territory Assigned, and Inspection Record Tor Cent of l'er Cent Counties Days Apiaries Apiaries Colonies of Colonies Colonies Assigned Worked Inspected Diseased Diseased Inspected Diseased Diseased Trentcd Burned Burn, A. D Boone 3 9 2 22.2 161 14 6.5 2 § Madison . &gt;&gt; Nance 2 Platte 1 3 2 66.6 41. 16 34.0 16 g Case, Loren S Cherry . . H Dawes ■ . . . . £. Sheridan . ■ l " 3 Dahl, Wm. R -.Kearney 1 0 .. 2 0 . ; O Phelps -2 0 . 18 0 ; Dolezal, Jos. P. . _Cass 1 0 17 0 &gt; Dodge 2 2 2 100.0 54 12 22.0 12 £ Lancaster 10 44 15 34.0 462 46 9.9 14 32 ■ g Saline 1 3 1 33.3 80 1 1.2 1 O . Saunders 1 0 . 5 0, S Seward 2 0 ...... 3 0 U Fleming, C. W Buffalo 10 19 6 31.5 377 21 5.5 . 21 d Hallock, E. L ...Garfield 2 51 . 11 21.5 277 25 9.0 1 24 g Greeley 1 2 1 50.0 83 1 1.0 1 ra Loup 2 13 4 30.7 164 16 9.7 16 Hastings, L. E Lincoln 11 8 72"7 213 36 16.9 26 10 Kroh, Cecil ; Nemaha Richardson 2 . 11 5 45.4 142 16 11.2 16 136 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">Eandall, J. L. Morrill 7 44 4 9.0 553 5 .9 5 Wagner, J. Howard Hall 1-% .14 5 35.7 180 21 11.1 21 Hamilton 2-% 18 1 5.5 301 3 .9 3 Howard % 15 3 20.0 113 3 2.6 3 Merrick 4-% 29 6 20.7 356 20 5.6 20 — Waidelickt-R-E ..■■■JBurt 4- —7- 53.8 — —159 — — — -77 —48.4—^ — 70— _1_ Sarpy Washington 7 22 16 72.7 992 384 38.7 384 181 Yerger, Joseph ...Scotts Bluff 4 10 0 — . 317 0 Sioux '•."■■•' Totals .. .. .... ..: 66 346 99 28.9 • 5,140 717 13.9 613 367 g — — '■ : ; : : — : ; I . ... o to to to CO o 137 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES OF THE DIVISION OF NURSERY AND APIARY INSPECTION 1. Inspections. Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total to to for Nov.30,1929 Nov .30,1930 Bien - (a) Nursery and Greenhouse In - spections 181 237 418 (b) Inspections of Individual Shipments '. i .53 79 132 (c) Mill Inspections 10 1 11 (d) Apiary Inspections 8 475 483 Total Inspections 252 792 £o34 2. Certificates and Permits Issued. Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total ■ to to for Nov.30,1929 Nov .30,1930 Bien - (a) Nursery and Greenhouse Inspection Certificates 174 229 403 (b) Certificate Tags for Individual Shipments 53 66 119 (c) Certificates of Mill Inspection .... .12 2 * 14 (d) Certificates of Apiary Inspection . 6 ■ ,1 7 (e) Nursery Agent's Permits 292 . 227 519 (f) Non-resident Nurserymen Permits 218 206 424 (g) Dealers Certificates „....,;... 69 85 154 (h) Duplicate copies issued .70 99 . 169 Total Certificates and Permits : 894 915 1,809 IF":. .■■■ ' ~~1[ ' .A.T^TSl : I ■ '^* J^ I , m Mm </seg>
            <seg id="p139">BIENNIAL REPORT— 1929-1930 RECEIPTS OF DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE BUREAUS OF DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS &amp; OIL &amp; MARKETS AND MARKETING Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total to to for ■ Nov. 30, 1929 Nov. 30, 1930 Biennium Gasoline and Oil Inspection Fees $ 150,014.03 $ 99,604.47 $ 249,618.50 Babcock Test Permits 9,646.00 9,550.00 19,196 00 Cream Station Permits 5,120.00 5,100.00 10,220.00 Field Superintendents Permits.. 190.00 150.00 340.00 Dairy and Creamery Permits .... 3,350.00 3,511.00 6,861.00 Cheese Factories 296.00 400.00 696.00 Commission Merchants and Cold Storage Permits 520.00 565.00 1,085.00 Retail Ice Cream Permits 40.00 55.00 95.00 Wholesale Ice Cream Permits.... 315.00 375.00 690.00 Retail Imitation Butter Permits 3,352.00 3,151.00 6,503.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter Permits 800.00 950.00 1,750.00 Manufacturer Imitation Butter.. 100.00 100.00 200,00 Livestock Remedy Registration.. 570.00 420.00 990.00 Commercial Fertilizer 260.00 260.00 520.00 Bottlers License 640.00 740.00 1,380.00 Rendering Establishments 850.00 800.00 1,650.00 Cold Storage Inspection 690.00 715.00 1,405.00 Weights and Measures 23,378.40 28,340.65 51,719.05 Hotel, Restaurant, Rooming House, Apartment and Concession Permits 12,303.00 12,800.00 25,103.00 Commercial Feeding Stuff 14,033.49 12,458.03 26,491.52 Refund on Liquor Cases 366.30 556.85 923.15 Miscellaneous 23.05 52.75 75.80 Seed Inspection : , 78.75 97.50 176.25 Total $ 226,936.02 $ 180,752.25 $ 407,688.27 DIVISION OF GASOLINE TAX* Tax Collected 1,679,550.38 1,679,550.38 BUREAU OF ANIMAL ' INDUSTRY Refunds from Counties: Bovine Tuberculosis 39,548.43 29,764.46 69,312.89 BUREAU OF GAME AND FISH** Sale of Hunting and Fishing Permits, etc , 84,381.38 84,381.38 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Nursery Certificates, Permits, • and Inspections'. 3,384.00 3,116.41 .6,500.41 DIVISION OF POTATO AND HAY INSPECTION*** Certificates of Inspection 808.00 3,759.50 4,567.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p140">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE DIVISION OF GRAIN WARE- . HOUSE AND FARM STOR - AGE**** Permits Issued, etc..... — : 72.50 . 72.50 . DIVISION OF BEE INSPECTION***** Bee Tax remitted by Counties.... 1,872.83 . 1,872.83 GRAND TOTAL $2,034,608.21 $ 219,337.95 $2,253,946.16 ♦Transferred to office of State Treasurer May 1, 1929. **Transf erred to Game, Forestation and Parks Commission June 1, 1929. •♦♦Optional Inspection, law effective April 15, 1929. ♦♦♦♦Law effective March 18, 1930. ♦♦♦♦♦Law effective March 26, 1929. EXPENDITURES OF DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE December 1, 1928 to November 30, 1929. . Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total to to . ' for Nov. 30, 1929 Nov. 30, 1930 Biennium DAIRIES, FOOD, DRUGS AND OIL AND MARKETS AND MARKETING Salaries '. ? 63,950.32 $ 72,936.31 ? 136,886.63 Supplies 5,904.21 5,537.26 11,441.47 Expense 38,620.58 40,752.99 79,373.57 Repairs : 162.79 218.35 381.14 Equipment 5,274.06 2,242.18 7,516.24 Fixed Charges 50.00 75.00 125.00 Total ; $ 113,961.96 $ 121,762.09 $ 235,724.05 ANIMAL INDUSTRY - GENERAL ACTIVITIES Salaries $ . 12,229.07 ? 13,412.41 $ 25,641.48 Supplies .". 1,732.24 1,216.47 2,948.71 Expense 5,055.45 5,168.72 10,224.17 Repairs 228.39 314.82 543.21 Equipment 1,060.23 500.65 1,560.88 Fixed Charges 25.00 25.00 50.00 Total $ 20,330.38 $ 20,638.07 $ 40,968.45 ERADICATION OF BOVINE TUBERCULOSIS ' Salaries $ 45,697.42$ 44,637.74$ 90,335.16 Supplies 3,899.11 6,899.07 10,798.18 Expense 37,977.17 32,858.40 70,835.67 Equipment 52.80 11.37 64.17 Fixed Charges— (Indemnity) .... 44,903.72 "65,831.07 110,734.79 Total $ 132,630.22 $ 150,237.65 $ 282,767.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p141">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 ERADICATION OP SCABIES w&amp;L ' • *■ 6 *H21 5 * 6 ' 780 -°° * 12,900.75 Supplies 13766 80.55 21&amp;21 Expense 2,171.83 1,829.39 4,001.22 Repairs . .„.„...... 31 6 . 78 ' 614 52 « 931^ Equipment .. 1,245.00 757.87 2,002.87 Totfl l - — •'• -.. $ 9,992.02 % 10,062.33 $ 20,054.35 HOG CHOLERA AND SWINE DISEASES Salaries $ 1,429.68 $ 1,435.00 $ 2,864.68 Supplies ...„ 4.56 5.00 9.56 Expense -- 248.54 281.46 530.00 Kepairs . . ....1.................. . 16 92 16 92 Equipment ........ 605.6*3 252*54 85817 • Total $ 2,288.41 % 1,990.92 $ 4,279.33 CONTROL OF PLANT DISEASE AND INSECT PESTS Salaries $ 2,840.04 $ 3,220.00 % 6,060.04 Supplies : 413.12 377.34 790 46 Expense 540.66 425.68 966.34 Repairs &#132; .. 187.77 80.43 268.20 Equipment 730.40 301.65 1,032.05 Total $ 4,711.99 $ 4,405.10 $ 9,117.09 POTATO AND HAY INSPECTION Salaries $ 208.53 $ 1,918.49 * 2,127.02 Supplies „.. 12.50 12.50 Expense 204.38 204.38 Total $ 208.63 $ 2,135.37 $ 2,343.90 Dec. 1, 1928 Dec. 1, 1929 Total to to for Nov. 30, 1929 Nov. 30, 1930 Biennium GRAIN WAREHOUSE AND FARM STORAGE* Salaries $ 2,074.62 $ 2,074.62 Supplies ... 639.93 639.93 Expense ; 424.07 424.07 Equipment ....... 307.33 307.33 Fixed Charges ; 10.00 10.00 Total ..: ...... — $ 3,455.95 $ 3,455.95 BEE INSPECTION" Salaries (County Bee Inspectors) .......... — ....... . $ 388.41 $ 388.44 141 </seg>
            <seg id="p142">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE GAME AND FlSH*** Salaries $ 20,434.72 $ 20,434.72 Supplies 8,890.45 8,890.45 Expense 9,213.05 9,213.05 Repairs 5,606.07 5,606.07 Equipment 9,487.86 9,487.86 Lands and Buildings 16,379.75 16,379.75 Total $ 70,011.90 $ 70,011.90 GASOLINE TAX COLLECTION**** Salaries $ 2,575.00 $ 2,575.00 Supplies 20.90 : 20.90 Expense 318.32 .-. 318.32 Repairs 1.65 1.65 Total $ 2,915.87 '.... $ 2,915.87' GRAND TOTAL .j...... „ $ 672,027.20 GENERAL SUMMARY Salaries ..............?302,288.54 Supplies 35,770.37 Expenses 176,090.69 Repairs .'. 7,748.49 Equipment 22,829.57 Lands and Buildings ..-. 16,379.75 Fixed Charges : 110,919.79 Total., - ........$672,027.20 ♦Law effective March 18, 1930. ♦♦Law effective March 26, 1930. ♦♦♦Transferred Game, Forestation and Parks Commission, June 1, 1929. ♦♦♦♦Transferred to State Treasurer May 1, 1929. 142 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">BIENNIAL REPORT— I 929-1930 PUBLICATIONS . The following is a list of the printed matter issued by the Department of Agriculture: Bulletin No. 1&gt; General Powers of the Department. 2. Gasoline and Kerosene Inspection Law. 3. Dairy Law. 4. Pure Food Law. 5. Sanitary Food Law. 6. Cider and Vinegar Law. 7. Oleomargarine and Butterine Law. 8. Cold Storage Law. 9. ' Paint and Linseed Oil Law. 10. Commercial Feeding Stuffs Law. 11. Live Stock Remedy Law. 12. Commercial Fertilizer Law. 13. Commission Merchant Law. 14. Hotel Law. 15. Weights and Measures Law." 16. Seed Law. 17. Potato Inspection Law. 23. Serum and Virus Law. 24. Soft Drink Law. 25. Pest Eradication Law. 28. Agricultural Statistics Law. 29. Law Relating to Warehousing of Grain. 30. Law Relating to Farm Storage of Grain. 143 </seg>
            <seg id="p144">DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURE 31. Rules and Regulations for the Administration of Public Grain Warehouses. 82. Egg Candling Law. 33. Rules and Regulations Relating to Farm Storage of Grain or Seed. 36. Nursery Inspection Law. ... 37. European Corn Borer Law. 38. Insect Pest and Plant Disease Quarantine Law. 39. Cedar Rust Law. 40. Regulations Governing Admission of Livestock into Ne - braska with State Laws Applying Thereto. 41. Regulations for the Prevention and the Eradication of Infectious and Contagious Diseases of Livestock and for the Protection of the Health of Livestock m Nebraska and the State Laws Relating Thereto. 42. Laws and Regulations Pertaining to Sale, Distribution and Use of Tuberculin on Domestic Animals and List of Authorized Veterinarians. 43. Instructions to Authorized Veterinarians on Methods, Rules and Reports of the Department. 44. Bee Inspection. 101. Nebraska Weeds. Rules and Regulations Governing the Sale of Agri - cultural Seeds and Notes on Seed Inspection. Cream Stations, Regulatory Announcements, Circular No. 2. Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1926. Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1927. Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1928. Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1929. List of Nebraska Nurserymen, Dealers and Florists Holding 1929-1930 Certificates— Published February 20; 1930. 144 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>