<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00025.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00025.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1907-1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE. ADJUTANT GENERAL OF THE. STATE OF NEBRASKA 1907-1908 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ADJl'TANT GKNER\LS RKPORT Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln, December 1, 1908 The Governor and Commander-ln-Cbief, State of Nebraska. Sir: — I have the honor to submit herewith the biennial report of the Adjutant General's office from November 30, 1906 to December 1, General Jacob H. Culver continued in office as Adjutant General of Nebraska until July 1. when bis resignation, accepted by the Gov - ernor, June 29, 1907, went into effect. The prfsent incumbent was appointed June 29, 1907 and assumed the duties of the office July 1, 1907. ItKKKltVK MILITIA. The enrollment of the Reserve Militia as provided in Section of the Military Code, has been Complied with by all counties, ex- it pi ins Adams. Bayd. Chase, Custer, Deuel, Dundy. Greeley, Ha Holt. Lancaster, McPherson, Nemaha. Nuckolls. Polk and Sheridan. MILITIA LIST. Count liHiii N Population Number Exempt Number Adams 1884" 2269» 40 2229 Antelope 11344 496 8 488 Banner 1114 14H 2 138 1 Blaine 6*3 16J I-",:! Boone 1 1 1! 8 9 1894 1894 Box Butte 6672 488 488 Uoyd t::::j 1114* 40 1074 Brown :!47d 316 14 302 Huffalo XOI54 3402 81 a;!21 Burt i:'.H40 189f. 14 1881 Butler 181 214.1 13 2130 21440 ZC78 7'.i Cedar 12467 2193 17 2176 Chase 2569 424* 18 406 Cherry 6541 14!U 20 5 1286 Cheyenne 667fl 660 32 628 Clay 161 209T. 7 2088 Custer 191 !•§•• 87 2571 Dakota 6286 IT* 2 568 Colfax 11211 !"•"&gt;« 14 134:2 Cuming 14581 2003 , 2003 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">ADJt'TANT GENERALS REPORT MII.ITIA LIST — &lt; nntinurd 190 0 Net Population Number Exempt Number Oawes 6215 515 5 510 Deuel UeUeI 2630 358* 21 337 DaWSOn 12214 99i« 12214 tUt 49 2i 96 Dixon 10535 978 ■ 971 dg f ***** 2274 55 2219 Douglas 140590 47 6 9 17 . 4752 Dundy 2434 504* 3 0 1 Fillmore 15087 220 1 us |M] FrankIin 1461 11*7 4 8 Frontier 87 81 ltU 50 m Furnas 12373 1344 15 Gage 3oo.-,i , 47I ,,., .,:;- oaBe 30051 347, ,,., ., Garfleld 2 12 7 .*, .. GarfieId »« 343 !j 3 3 " 5 Gosper B&gt;#] . .,, Grant 763 , 4| Grant 142 112 Greele - V B«fl , 7e . 9 „ " Gree 5691 •»•* 9 961 "all 1710* ,., T7 83 Ha 19 ■&gt;~~ 83 Hamilton 13330 l«»| H Hamilton 13 KM 14 ""Ian ,;; T o ,-„„ gl ' Marian 1500 81 141!. Ha&gt;eS - 7 " X B41* 17 464 Haye *«• 17 464 Hitchcock 4409 44 Hitchcock 4409 ** 738 Holt ISM4 17M- ■&gt;■, 14g6 Hoi 12224 1708* 1481 Hooker- 4JJ 4 Hooker 4;: 2 — •• -i-- 98 4 ,,, Howard 10343 14S4 2 0 we. Howard 10343 14S4 20 1 46 4 Jefferson IMM SIM 13 .,,-- Johnson 11197 ,,„ 33 Kearney 9866 ,,„,. 81 " Kelth "51 , :! , 15 2'0 K ya Paha 3076 ls K ya Paha 6 438 l« Klmball 761 ,„ 24 Kimball 21R 24 192 Knox H, 4 j ,,, :! , 101 Knox , Kn0X »««» -'1.12 101 2031 Lancaster 64833 4«St* 42 461S Lincoln H4 16 ,294 44 1250 Lancaster 64833 4«St* 42 46 i« Lincol ° 11416 , 294 44 lfM Logan Ml „, , Logan »«« | (] Loup i SM 9 Madison 16976 ftt 54 199* McPherson 517 ioo» 3 derrick 9255 ,,„ , „ „„ Nance 82 5U8 598 N(maha K952 1861* 99 176 , Nuckolls 12414 1812* 89 1723 Otoe 22288 2264 2242 Pawnee 1,770 1494 26 usii Perkins 1702 sgo </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 ADJl'TAXT GENERALS REPORT MILITIA LIST — &lt; oiiiinutMl Counties 1900 Net Population Number Exempt Nuni Phelps 10772 1648 32 1616 Pierce 8445 1202 BT 1116 Pl.tte 1T747 2490 28 2462 Polk 10542 1499 21 1478 Red Willow 9604 1660 17 1643 Richardson 19614 1160 64 211 Rock 2809 441 11 430 » Saline 18252 24CI h3 2386 Sarpy »080 1036 1014 Saur.ders Z208S 2 8 8 3 tf 2864 Scott's Bluff 2552 803 25 778 Seward iscto 2061 II 2046 Sheridan 6033 738» ta 720 Sherman 6550 1072 107 Pioux 2035 488 488 Stan ton 6959 24 1189 1165 Thayer 14325 20 I960 1940 Thomas (21 160 7 153 Thurston 8756 1034 20 1014 Valley 7339 1418 1418 Washington ISAM 1473 147J Wayne 9862 1281 11 1270 Webster 18619 1616 37 15 79 Wheeler 1362 316 11 305 York 18205 1143 1143 •Estimated Obtained from last report. The wide variation in the ratios of population to Militia in the several counties indicates a great degree of inexactness in compilin the lists. Their incompleteness destroys their usefulness. The system i obselete and an expensr t one. This ofllce recommends the repeal or the law. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 5 ORGANIZATIONS. The organized militia, legally designated, the Nebraska National Guard, on November 30, 1908, consists of two regiments of Infantry of twelve companies each, one Band, three Independent Companies of Infantry, a Signal Corps consisting of one company, a Medical De - partment consisting of a corps of Medical officers, and a Hospital Corps consisting of one Field Hospital. The Medical Department ia under the control of the Surgeon General as chief of department and the officers and enlisted men of same are assigned to Regimental aDd Battalion organizations as the best interest of the service demands. In compliance with the G. O. No. 222 War Department 1907, a medical department was organized consisting of one Surgeon General ■with rank of Colonel, 2 assistant Surgeons with rank of Lieut. Colonel, four Surgeons with rank of Major, eight Assistant Surgeons with rank of Captain, and eight Assistant Surgeons with rank of 1st Lieutenant. All medical officers of the Guard were relieved from duty with pectiv partment The Ambulance Company was also transferred to the Medical De- of 1 Battalion Adjutant, 1st Lieuten - nd Lieutenant, and 1 Battalion Ser- ant; 1 Battalion Quarterniasu geant Major ing failed to attain the standard ot A. G. O. 1905, were mustered out The following organizations h av efficiency required by G. O. No ]f the service 19&lt; aiscontinued Dec. 1, 1907, in that arm of the service, and was made an Infantry company on the same date. Co. C, Beatrice was reorganized March 27, 1908, Its officers and men discharged and the new organization enlisted. The following officers were placed on the retired list. Brigadier General Jacob H. Culver. Brigadier General Patrick H. Barry. Colonel George E. Jenkins. \ izations and transferred to the Medical D&amp; 2nd Regiment Band. Osceola, July 1 Co. D, 2nd Regiment. Fairbury, Aug. 6. 190 Troop A Cavalry, Milford, Sept. 30, 1907. Battery A Artillery, Wymore, was disconti partment and designated Field Hospital No. 1. In further compliance with the G. O. No War Departmem 1 !» i • T , the battalion organizations were made complete by the appoint ment of battalion staffs consisting of 1 Battalion Adjutant, 1st Lieuten </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S REPORT EQUIPMENT, The uniform and equipment of the Guard, as far as its service demands, conforms to that of the regular service. Tlie dress uniform is the old style blue, and the service, the cotton Khaki. The old blue overcoat which has been carried in the store room, has been dropped from the State's accountability. The Government is now ready to supply the Guard with the new regulation olive drab uniform. It is not necessary to have three uniforms, and it is thprefore recommended that the old blue uniform be replaced with the olive drab. Each man should have two Khaki uniforms or at least two pair of trousers, thus enabling him to wash the Foiled ones During the past year the office has encouraged the washing of Khaki uniforms, haversacks, blue shirts and bed sacks by paying the laundry expenses of same. The result was highly gratifying as the personal appearance of the Guard was greatly benefited and the trifling expense of laundering saved a far greater expense of buying new uni - form?. One of the greatest burdens placed upon a Company Commander Is the accountability for property which due to inadequate armory facilities is easily lost. In order to relieve the officer from this bur - den, as much as possible, all tentage, blankets, cooking outfits, bin. - shirts flre carried in the storeroom neatly put up in uniform sized boxes ready for shipment on a moments notice. Blankets and blue shirts are laundered immediately after use in the field. The matter of transportation is also much simplified being less expensive and quicker to ship from a common center. The C. S. Magazine Rifle, Model 19rt^,. Cal. "0 with accoutreme complete, was issued during the past year in exchange for the Kr Jorgen&amp;en. SinVKY WORK The clothing, arms and equipa secured from the V. S. Government. ;e of the National Guard are all being charged against the State's National allotment. Articles so issued, however, do not become abso - lute property of the State. Title remains with the Government, and the State is required to account annually for every articl-e so issued. When property is lost or destroyed, or becomes worn out or unfit for service, the State is required to proceed in a manner prescribed by the War Department to secure release from accountability for such articles. These articles upon the proper showing having been mad^, are by the authority of the Secretary of War. dropped from further accounting. Failing to make proper and satisfactory showing, the total value of the property becomes a charge against the National allotment. The War Department requires that the State furnish proper facilities for safe keeping and preserving all government prop - erty loaned or Issued in this manner. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ADJITAXT GENERALS REPORT From the time of the Spanish American War -n 1898 until the present time, there seems to have been a failure to clear the lo: MM of property, while th ate Appropriation was insufficient to permit the purchase of lockers for the safe keeping of same. This resulted In very considerable shortage of Government During the biennium. extensive survey work has been carried on, resulting most com] with the United :i ages in th nizatior (i the guard, amounting to almost $20,000, som \v bt ■e raced back M occuring fourteen years ago, were surveyed and dr 1 from the States accountability &gt; Of this amount $1,98( »as 1 against the States National allot- ment. Shorta n nuartermast amounting to about $."»,200 which have ac a i years in the storeroom, w surveyed and dropped ii the ate's accountability, but with er General of the Armv th^t »&gt;■«&gt; recommendations of the Quar Army that the i w ■ame. The endorsement of the survey papers by the Assistant Se retary of War in part is as follows i in these papers., it aimear* rha From n appears that 3 a lax and fa ii of accour ;i not seen how relief can be afforded upon this showing. If w unavoidable cans lief can be afforded. If this ca be w .1 charge the amount to the S allotment as recommend State can secure from Coner n special act of The diflu a an efficient Guard in leac • re very great. Appropriations pr are very great. Appropriations providing for armories and facilities for safe keeping of pronertv are inadenuate mr,r.i „■■ . .. .,.- a »e great portion of their time must b. given to their pu pursuit in life. As to the general efficiency in actual service of our organization of Citizen Soldiery, who represent everv line of human at can be no doubt. The spirit of patriot- Ism is of the highest order. Whil the above loss has resulted no doubt from general laxity, and ineffic nt methods, the penalty of twice charging the State's allotment for the loss is too severe. The above penalty if the State does not seeur relief, will be charged against the present allotment and act and reaching that state of efficiencv when losses will be largely avoided. EXCAMPMEXT. The Annual Enampment of 1907 was held at Lincoln. In ord-r to give each Regimental Commander an opportunity to exercise more absolute command, separate camping grounds were selected some miles apart for each regiment. The Hospital Corps and Signal Corps were the accumulation of a property. ly clearing the accor.nt of the State it and unserviceable property. Short- State's, allottr the losses in que ability and unde :&gt;»■ *hown. how factory eviden Quartermaster G adequate, moral suppo public is lacking duty short, for o ven by Guardsmen to militar; ious handicap toward advancement </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ADJITAXT GENERALS REPORT encamped with the General Headquarters at an intermediate point. Major Howell of the 18th Infantry was detailed by the war depart - ment as inspector and instructor. On August 16 the various organizations of the Guard under com - mand of Colonel Storch were reviewed by Governor Sheldon on the Country Club grounds near Lincoln. Further details are contained in the reports of Commanding Officers. TARGET PRACTICE In place of the Annual Encampment, a new expedient was tried in 1908. Investigation seemed to show that the Annual Encampment has been held out as an inducement to enlistment, that it must be held near a city, and that it meant an outing and good time, that it serves as a vacation from work to the individual and that it carries with it pay and other expenses free. When the importance of this recreation, frequently resulting in carousing, dissipation, etc., over - whelms the purpose of the military, something else should be tried. One of the most important reasons for the existence of a soldier is that he may shoot well. Nearly all men are interested in shooting. With this in view and with the thought that the Guard could be in - terested in something military to such an extent that they would not miss the "Good Time" of previous encampments, a Target En - campment by battalions was ordered. Inasmuch as the idea was somewhat of an experiment, it was deemed best to bring the Guard together in smaller units, in order that closer supervision and more effective instruction could be had. The Range was located about four miles from Ashland, far enough from town to discourage the men from going there. Particular atten - tion was paid to the comfort and entertainment of the men. Each man was provided with a cot making the ditching of tents unnecessary and improving the sanitary condition of the quarters. The Garrison ration «;is issued, and in general the ration was greatly improved over i was instituted, which, though ry satisfactory. All men fared the preceding year. A battalion m lacking in some details, was found equally well, thus eliminating that s vails when one set of men belongin use of company funds have better, t: uree of dissatisfaction which pre - : to a company, that through the San those who have no fund. The u.-e of company fund money, i. e. monoy saved up during the year, to buy ■fxtras" with, was eliminated entirely as thes? extras were fur - nished to the battalion mess. Company I, 16th U. S. Infantry was detailed by War Departmen for duty with the Guard. Captain C. M. Bundel, Commanding this company had charge of instruction work on the range and Lieutenan L. R. James acted as his assistant. Most valuable assistance was rendered by Capt. Bundel with the aid of his Company. The presence of the Regular Company served as an exampre and the bes of feeling existed between its members and the members of the Guard </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 9 The time during the day was busily taken up by shooting on the range and the extra time was completely filled in by other drills and camp routine. The Range, pleasantly located along the Platte River with its islands and woods, afforded splendid amusement for the men during their idle time and added much to their contentment. The camp was furnished with a water system and shower bath, and the water, pure in quality, was pumped by gasoline engine from driven wells. Ev - ery officer and man was required to shoot Course C of Firing Regu - lations with the result that a new awakening has taken hold of the Guard. Although few of the organizations had engaged in some des - ultory Target Practice, the greater number had never had any prac- tice at all and a wry large number of Guardsmen had never fired a service rifle. While the relative standing of our Rltie Team at the National Shoot is very low, as we stood 38 out of 50 teams or an im - provement of 13% over our relative standing of last year, yet our fig - ure of merit of the entire Guard this year was 32.60 compared to 13.34 lii^t year, almost 15&lt;i&lt;; improvement. The enthusiastic interest and spirit of co-operation shown by officers and men was very encouraging and indicates that steady and rapid progress will be made in the shooting of our Guard. There To Co. C. 1st Infantry, Beatrice, Nebraska Thirty ($30.00) Dollars, contributed by Colonel F. S. Nicholson Surgeon General, Lieutenant Colonel J. M. Birkner. Medical Corps; Major E. H. Phelps, Assistant Adjutant General. Fourth Prize and Lieutenant L. R. James, of Company I, 16th U. S. Infantry, in The results of this experiment were most satisfactory, even more than was expected, and yet many of the details were lacking, which in the future could be easily rectified. The fact that almost 1000 men were passed through a 10 days Target shoot without a single To Co. E, 2d Infantry, Tekamah, Nebraska: Twenty ($20.00) Dollars, contributed by Captain C. M. Bundel structors at the State Rifle Rang was considerably rivalry displayed by officers and men to obtain po- sitions on the team. The result of the company competition for cash prizes based on "Figure of Merit," resulted as. follows: First I'ri/.-. To Co. K, 2nd Infantry. Schuyler, Nebraska: One Hundr.d ($1M.#O) Dollars, contributed by Brigadier Gen- eral C. F. Schwarz, Adjutant General. S«i&gt;nd Prize To Co. F, 1st Infantry, Madison. Nebraska: Fifty ($50.00) Dollar?, contributed by Major L. P. Davison, V. S. A. Retired, on duty with the organized militia of Nebraska. Third I'ri/e. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ADJITANT GENERAL'S REJORT case of drunkenness, disorder, depredation or complaint on the part of any citizen of the neighboring towns or adjoining farms, not one ser - ious breach of discipline or complaint by men. and not one case of serious illness and almost no sickness at all, is very significant and almost unprecedented. Further details are contained in the reports of commanding officers. TAIWJKT RANGE The acquisition of a permanent Camping Ground and Target Range, either with the money now appropriated by congress or by an appropriation to be made by Legislature, is almost a necessity to Insure the existence of a stable and effective organization. To prop - erly equip a range extensive improvements should be made. Perma - nent grounds would fix the time and plac j , eliminating a large amount of uncertainty and consequent &gt; xpt The Rifle Range near Ashland. Nebraska, was leased for one yea and with an option enabling the State to least- it for two mor years. This piece of land is admirably suited for a camp ground and Range, and is very centrally located. It is recommended that this ground be further investigated with a view to purchase. AKMOKIKS While many States provide Armories for the use of the Nation Guard organizations, no appropriations for that purpose ha of the State of Nebraska. A perman nt home or club nous mewhat similar to the Y. M. C. A. with its Gymnasium, reading row ith room*, etc., would l&gt;e of the highest value to induce the most deal u to enlist, and it would increase pride in the company. It would practically solve the question o this time, when military lit the erection of Armories at one- 1 , is lacking. The State should begin tarting with the larger cities. The distribution of the pr h company is not at all ■nt appropriation of $250 per annum suitable, as companies in the larger cities are obliged to pay four and five times as much for the same a commoduion as the companies located in the smaller towns, T distribution of the appropriation should be left to an armory comm afoB, INSPECTION'S. The present incumbent shortly after his induction into office spected the entire Guard in company with the Regular Army Ofd on his tour of Inspection. While clothing and equipment of the Guard as a whole was quite complete and generally in good condition, still many of the store rooms and armories were badly suited for the purpose of safekeeping and rving property. Heavy losses of property have occurred in many companies. Seventeen companies were found in a greater or less degree of demoralization. Some of them had had no drills since the last en - campment, while others had been meeting with merely an attempt at how to keep up a Compan </seg>
            <seg id="p011">ADJl'TAXT GENERALS REPORT 11 drill and instruction. There seemed to be a general lack of intrest in military work in these companies and the community surrounding them shows the same lack of enthusiasm. Their records were badly kept and equipment and clothing was scattered around the adjacent country, f xcept that which was in the hands and worn by those present. In all of these companies drill was poor, in some instances showing no instructions in Drill Regulations a all. Officers aH.o showed an utter lack of knowledge or capability in property and gpneral efficiencv, wh five other organizations were in very good conditiop WEEKLY I&gt;KIM. PAY Th Guard is to have efficient com panies. In order that greater financial support could be given to panies. the period of time of fncampment was shortened officers' school was discontinued, and expenses curtailed in other wax- thus enablin drill pay. lieginning October 1. HIOT. each Private has received cents, each Corporal :'&gt;0 cents, each Senre.int :::, ppm, anrt o»i, nts and each 2nd ins, each 1st Lieutenant 45 ud cadi ( tain 55 cents, for fach drill attended. As thi&lt; money in nearlv evf n ins Company fun Company has realized an income two to three time as large as and r .&gt; mo The we gives, a credit against which a charge can be made for fines and car property, thus assisting; in maintaining discipline hered a ii a beginning with Ot to have been 42.") third and 502 foi vv the total attendance of the Guard i. 4 iced that there has been a small but stead ianc^ ea'-h succeeding quarter, and asp in w k creases will be even largtr in ltu Comparisons with (&gt;ast years can not be made as the quarterly re- turns are in many eas attendance had been k very ina urate, and show that no record of It is recommended that specifii this expenditure, in order that oth&lt; fund.s have been taken in the p.ist, 1 appropriation be made to cover departments from which if not sacrificed. OFFICER'S SCHOOL. An officer'^ school was convene i July 8, niiiT. and continued in session until July 11. This was followed by an examination of officers for commissions. The state was fortunate to secure the services of Capt. Marcus D. Cronin, 25th V. S. Infantry, as instructor. Among formance of their duti Fiw organizations w indition as to zeal, drill, care able amount for we^kl arter to the man this gives, assur.m nued. that the in- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT other subjects, the school received instruction in Drill Regulations. Small Arms Firing Regulation, Administration, Military Law, Guard Manual. Minor Tactics. Field Engineering, Map Readng and Camp San - itation. Papers were read- by Major Cruse, 0. S. Quartermaster De - partment, and Capt. John G. Workizer, 2nd D. S. Infantry. SILVER SERVICE FOR HATTLKSHII' NEBRASKA. One of the most important events of the past year was the pre - sentation of the Silver Service purchased by he Legislature for the Hattleship Nebraska. The official party consisting of Governor Sheldon and Staff, State Officers and other prominent citizens of the State, numbering about 13u in all. left Lincoln by a rpecial train April 25th. arriving at San Francisco May ~&gt;. The party were gcnrrously entertained at the var - ious stops enroute, and at Los Angeles where a three days' visit was made. On May 6, the party enjoyed the impressive sight of the en - trance into San Francisco Bay of the Atlantic and Pacific Fleets. On May 8. they witnessed the Review of the combined Flfets by the Sec - retary of the Navy. The presentation of the Silver Service was made at 4 P. M. May 8. 1908, by Governor Sheldon, about 300 Nebraskans witnessing the ceremonies. The party disbanded immediately after the presentation. NATIONAL (il.ARD ASSOCIATION. The tenth annual meeting of the Association was held at Boston husetis. The delegates met in Faneuil Hall and continued theii three day? of deliberation and history making surrounded by the in spiring associations of that old historic place. It was here that tht :lments to the Dick Law, passed by Congress May 27. 1908, were formulated, whereby the National Guard received all equipment from the War Department -without charge as'ainst their allotment of federa' funds and whereby the National Guard may be called simultaneously with the Regular Army for service anywhere in th^ world without further enlistment and examination. Nebraska's additional allotment for clothing and equipage is approximately ten thousand dollars. The -tent work of the Association not only during its enthusiastic annual meetings but througout th? interim, has gained recognition from Congress, whose support has placed the National Guard on a basis enabling it to become the most powerful Aghting force in the world. SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR CLAIMS. During the biennium, the State received an additional amount $6243.04 from the Government, for payment of Officers and Band of the Regiment, and paid 1017 claims amounting to $20,659.77 from funds, leaving 833 claims unpaid, with a balance of $7,984.00. This, office has expended considerable money and time in obtaining the addresses of the various organizations to whom this pay is due, and apparently has exhausted its means, of obtaining further information. However, it is the duty of the State, to continue its search, and sufficient funds should be appropriated to effectively carry on the work. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 13 MILITARY CODE. In general the requirements, of the Act of Congress, January 21. 1903, have been complied with by the Act of the Legislature of April 31, 1905, establishing the present Military Code. In order to completely conform to the new Acts of Congress, it has been found necessary from time to time to issue General Orders making the required changes in our organization, such as the establishment of the Medical Department, and Battalion Staffs. Jn order that the present status of the National Guard, relative to the Federal law can be more easily understood, the following circular is printed in full. The act of Congress approved January 21, 1903, entitled "An act to promote the efficiency of the militia, and for other purposes," as amended by the act of May 27, 1908, is published herewith in full for the information and guidance of the organized militia of the Unitec States: SECTION 1. That the militia shall consist of every able-bodied male citizen of the respective States and Territories and the District of Columbia, and every able-bodied male of foreign birth who has de - clared his intention to become a citizen, who is more than eighteen and less than forty-five years of age, and shall be divided into two classes: The organized militia, to be known at the National Guard of the State, Territory, or District of Columbia, or by such other des - ignations as may be given them by the laws of the respective States or Territories.: the remainder to be known as the Reserve Militia: Provided. That the provisions of this Act and of section sixteen hundred and sixty-one. Revised Statutes, as amended, shall apply only to the militia organized as a land force. SEC. 2. That the Viec-President of the United States, the ofllcers judicial and executive, of the Government of the United States, the members and officers of each House of Congress, persons, in the military or naval service of the United States, all custon-house officers, with their clerks, postmasters and persons employed by the United States in the transmission of the mail, ferrymen employed at any ferry on a post road, artificers and workmen employed in the armories and arsenals ol the United States, pilots, mariners actually employed in the sea service of any citizen or merchant within the United States, and all per - sons who are exempted by the laws of the respective States or Territories shall be exempted from militia duty without regard to age: Provided, That nothing in this act shall be construed to require or compel any member of any well-recognized re - ligious sect or organization at present organized and existing whose creed forbids its members to participate in war in any form, and whose religious convictions are against war or participation therein, in accordance with the creed of aaid religious organization, to serve in the militia or any other armed or volunteer force under the jurisdic - tion and authority of the United States. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ADJl'TANT GENERALS REPORT SEC. 3. That the regularly enlisted, organized, and uniformed active militia in the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia who have heretofore participated or shall hereafter partici - pate in the apportionment of the annual appropriation provided by section sixteen hundred and sixty-one of the Revised Statutes of the I'nited States, as amended, whether known and designated as National Guard, militia, or otherwise, shall constitute the orginfied militia. On and after January twenty-first, nineteen hundred and ten, the organiza - tion, armament, and discipline of the organized militia in the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia shall the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia shall be th? same as that which is now or may hereafter be prescribed for the Regular Army of the United States, subject in time of peace to such general exceptions as may be authorized by the Secretary of War: Provided, That in peaee and war each organized division of militia may have one inspector of small-arms practice with the rank of lieu - tenant-colonel: each organized brigade of militia one inspector of &gt;mall-aniis with the r;mk nf Major, each regiment of in - fantry or cavalry of organized militia one assistant inspector &lt;ir small-arms practice with the rank of captain, and each sep - arate or unassigned battalion of infantry or engineers or squad - ron of cavalry of organized militia on;» assistant inspector of small-arms practice with the rank of first lieutenant: Provided also. That the President of the United States in tim? of pt ace may, by order, fix the minimum number of enlisted men in each company, troop, battery, signal corps, engineer corps, and hospital corps And provided farther, That any corps of artillery, cavalry, and infantry existing in any of the States at the passage of the Act of May eighth. seventeen hundred and ninety-two, which, by the laws, customs, or usages of the said States, have be?n in continuous exist - since the passage of said Act, under its provisions and under the provisions of section two hundred and thirty-two and sections sixteen hundred and tw t nty-five to sixteen hundred and sixty, both inclusive, of title sixte n of the Revised Statutes of the United States, relating to the militia, shall be allowed to retain their accustomed privileges, subject, nevertheless, to all other duties required by law, in like manner as the other militia. SEC. 4. That whenever the United States is invaded or in danger of invasion from any foreign nation, or of reiielliun ayainst the au - thority of Ihe Government of tlie I'nited States, or the President is ,:nable with the regular forces at his command to execute the 1 i\»&gt; of the Union, it shall be lawful for the President to call forth such number of the militia of the State or of the States or Territories or of the District of Columbia as he may deem necessary to repel such invasion, suppress such rebellion, or to enable him to execute such lawB. and to issue his orders for that purpose, through the governor of the respective State or Territory, or through the commanding gen- </seg>
            <seg id="p015">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 15 &lt;ral of the militia of the District of Columbia, from which State, Territory, or District such troops may be called, to such officers of the militia as he mat think proper SEC. 5. That whenever the President calls forth the organized militia of any State, Territory, or of the District of Columbia, to be employed in the service of the United States, he may specify in his call the period for which such service is required, and the militia so called shall continue to serve during the term so specified, either within or without the territory of the United States, unless sooner relieved by order of the President: Provided. That no commissioned officer or enlisted man of the organized militia shall be held to servic? beyond the term of his existing commission or enlistment: Provided further. That when the military needs of the Federal Government arising from the necessity to execute the laws of the Union, suppress Insurrection, or repel invasion, can not be met by the regular forces, the organized militia shall be called into the service of the United States in advance )f any volunteer force which it may be determined to raise SE( That when the mi itia of more than one State U of the United States by the apportion them among such States tailed President he may, in his. discretion. Territories or to the District of Columbia according to representativ population ■C. . That every officer and enlisted man of the militia who shall be called forth in the manner hereinbefore prescribed, shall be mustered for •enrlce without further enlistment, and without further medical oxami previous to such muster, except for those states and territories which have not adopted th? standard of medical ex - amination prescribed for the Regular Army: Provided, however. That any officer or enlisted man of the militia who shall refuse or neglect to present himself for such muster, upon being called forth as herein reseribed. shall be subject to trial by court-martial and shall be pun- ished as such court-martial may direct SEC. 8. That the majority membership of courts-martial for the trial of officers or men of the militia when in the servic? of the United SEC. 9. That the militia, when called Into the actual service of the United States, shall be subject to the same Rules and Articles of War as the regular troops of the United States. SEC. 10 That the militia, when called into the actual service of the United States, shall, during their time of service, be entitled to the Fame pay and allowances as are or may be provided by law for the R gular Army. SEC. 11. That when the militia is called into the actual service of the United States, or any portion of the militia is called forth under the provisions of this Act. their pay shall commence rrom the day of their appearing at the place of company rendezvous, but this provision shall not be construed to authorize any species of expenditure prsviou* the adtual service ates shall be composed of militia officers </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT to arriving at such places of rendezvous which is not provided by the existing laws to be paid after their arrival at such places of rendezvous. SEC. 12. There shall be appointed in each State. Territory, and District of Columbia, an adjutant general, who shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the laws of such State, Territory, and District, respectively, and make returns to the Secretary of War, at eueh times and in fuch form as he shall from time to time prescribe, of the strength of the organized militia, and also make such reports as may from time to time be required by the Secretary of War. That ♦ he Secretary of War shall, with bis annual report or each year, transmit to Congress an abstract of the returns and reports of the adju - tants general of the State?, Territories, and the District of Columbia, with such observations thereon as he may deem necessary for the in - formation of Congress. Sec. 13. That the Secretary of War is hereby authorized to pro - rure, by purchase or manufacture, and issue from time to time to the organized militia, under such regulations as he may prescribe, such number of the Cnited States service arms, together with all accessories and such other accouterments, equipments, uniforms, clothing, equip - age, and military stores of all kinds required for the Army of the Cnited States, as are necessary to arm, uniform, and equip all of the organized militia in the several States, Territories, and the District ot Columbia, in accordance with the requirements of this Act. without charging the cost or value thereof, or any expense connected therewith, against the allotment of said State, Territory, or the District of Colum - bia, out of the annual appropriation provided by section sixteen hun - dred and sixty-one of the Revised Statutes, as amended, or requiring payment therefor, and to exchange, without receiving any mooey credit therefor, ammunition or parts thereof suitable to the new arms, round for round, for corresponding ammunition suitable to the old arms heretofore issued to said State, Territory, or the District of Columbia by the I'nited States: Provided. That said property shall remain the property of the United States, except as hereinafter provided, and be annually accounted for by the governors of the States and Territories as required by law, and that each State, Territory, and the District of Columbia shall, on receipt of new arms or equipments, turn in to the War Department, or otherwise dispose of In accordance with the direc - tions of the Secretary of War, without receiving any money credit there - for and without expense for transportation, all United States property so replaced or condemned. When the organized militia is uniformed as above required, the Secretary of War is authorized to fix an annual clothing allowance to each State, Territory, and the District of Columbia for each enlisted man of the organized militia thereof, and thereafter issues of clothing to such states. Territories, and the District of Columbia shall be in accordance with such allowance, and the gov - ernors of the States and Territories and the commanding general of the militia of the District of Columbia shall be authorized to drop from </seg>
            <seg id="p017">ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT 17 tl xpend &lt;l f iding in value to such allowance. The Secretary of War Is hereby further authorized sue from time to time to the organized militia, under suet jnder such regula tions as he may prescribe .small arms and artillery ammunition upon the requitit on of the governor, ii iiorti&lt;ir the requ jf he gov governor, in the proportion of fifty per centum n of fifty per centum of the corresponding Regular Army allowance, w of the corresponding Regular A tegular Army allowance, without charge to the without charge to the State's allotment from the appropriation undi r sei SU the appropriation under section sixteen hundred Statutes, as amended. To provide means to the appropriation under section sixteen hundred and sixty-one, Revi.-ed Statutes, as amend. and I d Stat Jed. To provide means to carry into effect the provisions of this section, tht carry into effect the provisions of this section, tht ovisions of this scot ion. the necessary money to n, the necessary money to cover the &lt;o=t of procuring, exchanuinc. or issuin cover tt ver the co=t of procuring, exchanging, or issuing of arms, accouter- mt pm ms, clc ammunition, and ■1 ■I \ mill hanged i hereunder is hereby appro- x priated of i th r not otherwise appropriated Prov i hat tl expended im h execution of the purchase and l.d n not exceed the sum of two mll- li( ax r d also. That the Secretary of War shall annually submit to Congress a report of expenditures made by hir this section q T) w ii PI .sr War to cause to t» cers detailed by him for that I'll mi Te-ritory or of the D trie &gt;d, uniformed, and equipped w d, on the rt pay to the qua ie militia of saic for the pur P&lt; l priation ui t it Statutes ice, and shall engage i the office-s and ■d to the ■i ( :!ar Army ntitled I'nited States, and shall render his accounts through the War Department to h the proper accounting officers of the Treasury fo- settlement, and he )d an 1 bord, to the United State* In such s ms a? the Secretary cf W r fo: the. safe keeping ani payment of the public moneys so Intrusted to T 1 lu creta ho-ized to prov'dt» for p of the nized militia of any State or Ter- ritory on the Mn.i'^t of 'he finnnmr thereof in the enrnnrni ..i ni«- neuv d field instr iiction of any part of the Regular Army he report of inspec ti&lt; as offl iesignaftd </seg>
            <seg id="p018">ADJITAXT GENERAL' UKl'OKT it or near any militan. ■lefense of the I'nited States. In r&gt;articipatinK shall receive the same ri* is provided by law for the officer such case the organized militia so pay. subsistence, and transportation and men of the Regular Army, and no part of the sum appropriated for the support of the Regular Army t-hs.ll be used to pay any part of the expense of the organized militia ■f any State. Territory, or District of Columbia, while eiiRa-red in Joint • -ncimpments. maneuvery. and field instruction of the Regular Army and militia under the provisions of this section and all allowances for mileage shall be made solely from the sums appropriated for sucb purposes: Provided. That the command of such military post or camp *nd the oAcen and troops of the I'nited States there stationed shall -emain with the regular commander of the post without regard to the r»nk of the commanding or other officers of the militia temiwrarfly o encamped within its limits or in its vicinity: Provided further. That i't as hen in specified the right to command during such joint en and iield impim nstruction shall be governed by tht ules one hundr ed and twenty-two and one hundred cd twenty-four of the rules and articles for the government of th&lt; •&gt;( the I'nited States. Th sums appropriated for the organized it. maneuvers, and field instruction lilitia fi int emampmi hall (1 for tha purpose shall constitute, one fund nd the War shall f nward to I next afte mpiii 1 tailed statement of the expel id maneuver 0. That win-never an ifflrer or enlisted man of the or ,1 upon th&lt; unmendation of the governor of any I general of the District of Columbia ramandin militia, and when authorized by the President, attend and pursue * regul rty at any mi tary school or college of the United States, fuc r enlisted m: n shall receive from the annual ap- propriation for the support of the Army, the same travel allowances und quarters or commutation of quarters to which an officer or enlisted man of the llegutar Army would be entitled for attending such school ■-&gt;r college under orders from proper military authority: such officer Htiall ajeo n celve commutation and subsistence at the rate of one dol ar per day :md each enlisted man such subsistence as is furnished to an enlisted man of the Refralar Army while in .'ictual attendance upot a course of instruction 17. That the annual appropriation made by section sixteen hundred and sixty-one, Revised Statutes, as amended, shall be available tor the purpose of providing for issue to the organized milita any storev and supplies or publications which are supplied to the Army by any department. Any State, Territory ,or the District of Columbia may. with the approval of the Secretary of War. purchase for cash from the War Department, for the use of its militia, stores, supplies, material of war. or military publications, such as are furnished the Army, i» or camp or lake &lt;&gt;r seacoasf </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 19 iddition ued under the provisions of this Act, at the price at which they a i for issue to the Army, with the coat of transpor tat ion added, and f the appropriations I the Treasury, hut si the supplies sold U inds received from such sales shall be credited to which they belong and shall not be covered into &gt;&lt;• available until expended to replace therewith the Slates and Territories and to the District of Columbia in the manner herein provided Sec. l rritory furnished with material of war undor the provisions of this or former acts of Congress shall luring the jraar next preceding each annual allotment of funds, in accordance with dred and sixty-one of the Revised Statutes, as ;in every company, troop, and battery in its organized m • rnor of such State or Ter ritory. to participate in practice inarches or go into camp of instruction least five conn lor drill and instruction nil or rendezvous, or for arget pra and shall also have squired du h such company, troop l md bat battery to bo madt i h mllita or an officer of th&gt; ular Ar Seo. !:• Th;it tipoii the application if the governor of anv State &gt;I k Terr 1 ri nr under the provisions of his Act or forui&lt; retary of War may detail H attend any encampment of the irganizcd in and information to the Ulcers and mi ;ip as may be requested by the hall immediately make a report &lt;overnt if such encamp •t ry ..;' War. who shall furnish a y th Territory h on of the governor of any State or Territory furnished Act, or former law discretion, detail oe war under the provisions of thla &gt;f Congress the Secretary of War may, in his or more officers or enlisted men of the Army to report to the governor of such State or Territory for duty in connection with the organized militia. All such assignments may be revoked at the request of the governor of such State or Territory or at the pleas- ire of the Secretary of War. The Secretary of War is hereby autho- rized to appoint a board of five officers on the active list of the organ- ized militia, so selected as to secure, as far as practicable, equitable representation to all sections of the United States, and which shall. from time to time, as the Secreary of War may direct, proceed to Washington, District of Columbia .for consultation with the Secretary of War respecting the conditions, status, and needs of the whole body of the organized militia. Such officers shall be appointed for the term of four years unless sooner relievt d by the Secretary of War. h 9 &gt;u hue J. have required ixcuaed b Ive dm] won H&gt;on the applii-ii' with material o: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">ADJL'TAXT GENERA] REFORT Thr actual and i ■ board ' ' di''m to li.-hcd by the Secretary of \\ ar, s-1 of the board. The ptmhuu I the division of militia attain In (he oBce of the Becretary of war, shall ■onstitute a charge against the whole tuna annually appropriated undt ion section sixteen hundred and sixty-one, Revised u amendet and shall be paid therefrom, and not from tti appo tioned to any particular State. Territory, or the District of Columbia and a list of such expeaces shall bo submitted to Congress annually bj he Secretary of War in connection with his annual report ■)' That the troops of the militia encamped at any militar} post or (amp of the l/nited States may be furnished slier ti amounts ammunition for instruction in Bring and target practice as may be pr sciibed b the Secretary of War under the direction o military commander nd such instruction in firing shall b carri officer selected for that purpose by it the propt - That wh mmlssioned officer, or priv ate of tlu n disabled by re or incu d in the service of the I the t • .its of the pension laws existing at the time of his service ana the p in officer, noncomrr I'nited Stj ed officer, or private dies in tht after heir. of wound nins to his place of residence or at anv time, in consentient* out of suit v i consequent 1 h service, his widow and child r. r. n. it any. shall be entitled to all the benefits cf such pension law : That for t!i- of securing a list of persons especi which may : (1 organized under the authority of Congre i ! ot! is authorized ffi i time to &lt; ards of officers at suitable is amnonzea inmi lime to time ti offlren at suitable aDd ' rta of the rniroj States, who ska'- lualiflcations for the command of troops r or f&lt; : ot staff duties all applicants who shall ht served in the !t&lt; i-iil.ir Army of the I he volunteer of the United militia of anv State or Territory or District of Columbia, t f the United State led or pui f Instruct in any m v or United States Army, or shall itution to which an ofilcer of have graduated from any educational i he Army or Navy has been detailed iiperintendent or professor pur suant to law after having credltabl) ursued the course of mil'tary Instruction therein provided. Such examinations shall be under rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of War, and shall be espe - cially directed to ascertain the practical capacity of the applicant. The record of previous service of the applicant shall be considered as a part of the examination. Upon the conclusion of each examination authoi :h&lt;r ftill &gt; 'h&lt;' clerical and office expenses o ason of wound? or disabilities received 'nited States he shall be entitled to all tary of Wa </seg>
            <seg id="p021">ADJl'TANT GENERAL' REPORT 21 the board shall certify to the \V ar Department its judgment as to the fitness of the applicant, bating the office, if any which it deems him qualified to fill, and, upon appioval by the President, the name 3 of the persons certified to be qualified .shall be inscribed in a register to he kept in the War Department fo that purpose. The persons so cerfl tied and registered shall, subject to a physical examination at the time. class for commissions pursuant to such certiflcates tea hereafter called for and organized under the ithority of Cm her than ■ lone composed of organized President may authorize- persons from this class, to Jy at any military school or liege of the United States other than the Military Academy at West Point and from the annual appropriation for the support ot fition for the support of llowances and commutations as provided in this .vided in this \( organized militia: provided. That no person shall 3 d, That no person shall ieutenant after he shall ant after he shall have ■ commission as ■ scond lieutenant after he shall at thirty: as first lieutenant after he shall have j of thirty-five; M captain after he shall have passed irty-flve; m captain after he shall have passed major after he shall ha\ | the age after he shall have passed the age after he shall have parsed the age of fifty-five: r he shall have passed the age -fiv r he shall have passed the age .r fifty, or as colonel after he shall have passed the age of fifty-five: he sr That such appointment* shall be distributed pro- Kiinrm 11 be distributed pro- i.s may be. among the variooa States contributing And provided. Thai the appointments in this ng th ious States contributing And provided. Thai the appointments in this ihall not ]»■ deemed to include appointments to any, troop, battery, battalia*, or regiment of the regiment of the \v h volunteers as a body or the officers of which are fficers of which are. nted by the governor &lt;if a Stale or T rnor of a state nr Territory. ry 1 the volunteer forces of the lnited States called M ifcall, exeepl as hereinbefore provided, b. - r provided l.y the act entitled "An Act to provide v t he United States called in ;n il "All Act to provide istng the military establishment of the Tnited and for other purposes," approved April twenty- d for otr approved April twenty- red and ninety-eight. hundred and twenty-five to sixteen undred and sixty, l.oth included of title sixteen of the Revised Statute* md section two hundred and thirty-two thereof, relating to the militia ) late of its an- [I&gt; M by order of the Secrearjr of War i: M. WEAVER ieutenant-Colonei, Coast Artillery Corps. Chief of Division </seg>
            <seg id="p022">AD.HTANT GENERAL'S RKI'ORT first lint' of defense, ready for I'niiod Stales service without the dela jf enlistment and examination The iinii priation in th&lt; form of clothing allowanci will b&lt; ■ ■ pivat help in properly uniforming allowance will greatly promote tha' the Guard and the ainmunit tly promote tha important element, target prat-tie Thisoffue would recommend that appointment of officers be made ipon the basis of 1111 mental, and physical and il investigation of previous record •ars or for lifi&gt; and to 1h- retirf OfBf-rrs to be appointed for ■ M-rir hy aRO limit "r removed for good u The Kvntoin of iliMti "il V r TIimi elcmi i v* not amenable to dis- din KtMl.lSION In all matt' up .this offiee, through ili&lt;- nonrtt if the w ar 1 Ri Army Ofii( t&gt; nifestf port ci\ Net :ir etfull F 8CHWARZ Adjutan* (!«n nt This sew law practical I &gt; makes the National Guard a purs, ot tht incd through examination, mora! udlcial to iii.-&lt; ipi 1 lhr&lt; Army Officer or br&lt; in (luard »&lt; Ix ■ Hep a la m&lt;l it 1 Bcommendod </seg>
            <seg id="p023">ADJUTANT (iKXKRALS REPORT 23 GOVKKNOIfS STAFF n. t'has. K. Sr.hwarz Adjutant Genera! July l. I'tciT, Lincoln ( AujuiajiL uenerai ,iuiv i. !;•",. Q. U. &amp; Cmy den" I nspector General Jan. 9. 1903, Lincoln -Surgeon General Col. John (' Cowln .lodge Adv. General July 1 l!&lt;i&gt;7 OraaL Ool.Chas. B. \nder - foii Aide-de-C July ::. I mot. r&gt;. \i le-de-Cam.. July ::, I MOT. Cra Ool. Brail UrandeiR Aide-de-Camp Jan. S, 1 1*117. Omaha "ol. Brail BrandeiK Aide-de-Caaap Jan. ;:. l hot. Oman* Col. Thus. C. I. i \i,|» -,le-Camp Jan. i!»i)7. Omaha Col. Thos. C. Byrne Aide-de-Camp Jan. l ;* o 7 ! Omaha Col. John I'. Cameron Aide-de-Canr,. i ■ 7,TekamaJ Col. John 1'. Cameron Aide- de-('an Tekama Col. ('has. H. Cornel! Aide-de-Camp Jan. ::. I y 07. Valentin las. H. Cornel! Aiile-de-Camp Jan. ;;. TJOT. Val* Col. Georc L. Day Aide-de-Camp Ian :; i'jot s Col. G VMe-de-Camvi Jan :;, i Pol. John \l Hollinu - worth aj tc-cl«-c i Jan. ::. i:«u7. Ub &lt;"ol Charles (irotte Alde-de-Camrp Jan. ::. ]!i"7, o n &lt;'ol. Georgf Lyon. Jr. Aldp-dp-Camp Ian :: 1907* N. ''ol. John W McDon - ikII \iiii-di -( i r,,] Tkflu. VV MfCiil. loii^ti Vi'tf-di'-Camii .Ian. ::. I:ni7. oraahi it I! I 1 til Ian. :.. l»07, O Ool. Rrnral I,. Myers Alde-de-CMnp Jan. :;, 1907, V.'wpor Jan. :;. 1907. Vew Col. I'iimI C \i&lt; Is. i, Aidf-dt -Camj. Jan.;'. Jan i Ool. Henry I F'.-nfold Aid?-,' Jan. ::. 1907, On f Jan. ::. I '.to :, On Col. \lberl A. Reed \i.!.-d,-C;,ni;. Jan. ::. 1907 Lii Jan. ::. 1907, lAm Col. Landreth P. Sin.- \idi -d.-c, Jan.:!. I!ici7 Lin Ian. :',. nicir, u n Col. Herbert P. Simni wa\ Aid. --ilt • -r j an ;; if#7, l.io#iili, * a \ A Wni. B. Straub A Arthur ('. 8m Andrew F. Sturm A Jan. ::. l»07, Lin*ti Jan. ::, 1907, Llnco Ool. Wni. B. Straub Aide-de-camp Jan. 3, Ii)n7. Lin Ool. Arthur ('. Smth Aide-de-Camp Jan. ?., li»07. (); Jan. ?.. 19«7, Or O61. Andrew f. Sturm Alde-de-Tamp Jan. .'. IsKtT.'xH Col. Fred'k U Tcmplp Aide-de-camp .la:: Ool. John C. Workiz. r Aid.-' j an . ;! , ,.,,,7 Lincoln Workizrr Aid' n. .■!. i Col. Win. C. Shinn Aide-de-Camp Mar. - i \V mi Aid Mar. 2 4. I Col. Oeo. H. RoKfra Alde-de-Camp Mar. 2 ( nco!i rol. Cbaa P. Itr.s.'. Mde-di Mar 24, lH»8.Kushvill. Ool. Othnicl (i. Horn. Aide- Mar. 2 1. Othr Wm. Hisohof \i-.l.' \e Ma it H I'll. Captain Bradford I 1 ■an ir ( . in 07 Mll.lTAin HOAIU&gt; MII.ITAKV IM».\KI» Brtsadfei u.-m t«; Chartea P. Brbwarx. Adjutant Utn.r.it Rrlgadtri (itmpral Char)«a F Srbwarz, Adjutant litn.r.il a dent lent. Colonel Joseph A. Storcb, First Infantry. Colonel John C. Hartigan, Second Infantry. Colon.»l J. hn C. Covin. .ludgp Advocate CJentrnl. Rd^order. 'olonel Joseph A. Storcb, First Infantry &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 ADJUTANT GENERAI REPOR P Ml DH'AL OKIWUTMKXT COLONKI Assistant ( norji •'rank S. Nicholson St. l'aul ran Ni LIEUTENANT &lt;"l &gt;LONELS V.-v geon General John Jl. Uirknei May MAJOR-SIRHEOX lame 01 Iff o 1 limua n% \v U W'aldei Lieatrlc* CAI' TAIN - -Assista ■&lt; Fairbury lO'T A h ;in I Kmil C In1frbur« Stanton July l."i. l!t Sam 11 ■1 Stewart Lincoln FIRST \AY ITKNA.NT A ant on John I*' almaii Line May Jan. 190 Charles K. (lihboiis Koarney 190f I II Static ii Original I Olll I Rank Pat Con: if Master m iion Lincoln John M ISirkner i.i, n Ma&gt; 1 90S rant a )hn F Mix </seg>
            <seg id="p025">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT KIKST REGIMENT, IXFAXTKV Headquarters, Fuller Joseph A. Storch, Colonel, Fullerton, July 13, 1904 Joseph A Fred Ges H, t Fred Gesner, Lieutenant-Colonel, Madison. July 20. 190G. I ( [l MAJORS. MAJOF §. Edmund Baehr, First Battalion. Omaha. October is, 1 W. * !d m ii ml I Buttali 190 SECOND BATTALION. ECOX I) I ATTALIOX George A. Bberly, Third Battalion, Stanton. August 3, 190C. George H. Holdeman, Captain-Adjutant, York, July 22, 1904. Morgan .1. Flaherty. Captain-Quartermaster. Fullerton. Aug. 10. l '.i Otis E. Davis, Captain-Commissary. Geneva. July 22. If FIRST LIEUTENANTS-BATTALION ADJUTANTS H EUTEN ANTS-BATTALION ADJUTANT Jerome A. Lillie. First Battalion. Omaha. January l. 1!" Jerome A Llllie, First Battalion. Omaha. January 1. 190S SECOND BATTALION. Howard H. Antles, Third Battalion, Pilger, January 13, II SECOND LIEUT. -BATTALION QUARTERMASTERS AND How (1 Sf COND 1 IF 1 BATTALION QUARTERMASTERS AND COM fll F. Loach, First Battalion, Omaha. January |, If Dell F. Lough. First Uattalion, Omaha. January 1, 1! »i SECOND BATTALION. SECOND BATTALION William E. Ketao, Third Battalion. Wisiier, January 13, William E. Kelso. Third Battalion. Wiener, January 1". 190 \\ Fletcher M. Sisson, Captain-Chaplain, Nebraska City. March 2". 1» NON-COMMISSIONED STAFF. Fletcher M. Sisson. Captain-Chaplain, Nebraska City. Harch '.'" 1 y ON-COMMI IONED STAFF Dale F. Mi Donald. Sergeant-Major, York. July 24. 1 Dale F. McDonald. Sergeant-Major, York. July 24. 1 '. York. July John F. Steel. Quartern* seant, Ohiowa. July 1. 190ii. ermasl nit, Ohiowa. Julv 1. 190t, Hugo B. Wunrath. Commissary Serjeant, Omaha. Augu.-t 10, i»iit Hug \\ Omaha. Augu-t 10, 1&lt;H Milton E. Cornelius. Color Sergeant, Lincoln. July 2*:. 1'tin;. BATTALION SERGEANT MAJORS M ant, Lincoln. July 26, 1 !t ( ATTALIOX SERGEANT MAJOF Harrie Remington, First Battalion, August 12. l»07. Harrie Remington, First Battalion, August 12, 19mT Roy V. Pepperburg, Second Battalion, Lincoln, July 23, 190G. Walter G. Sonnenshein, Third Battalion, Stanton. July t9, 190\ American Checima) S' </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT FIRST REGIMENT INFANTRY FIRST BATTALION . U. Edmund Itaehr. Miijor Harrie Remington 1 2nd Lieut. Hat. Q: M. &amp; Com 1 ? Dell V. Ixmgr Station Original Date Officers of Muster Rank Date of Commission Capta W png Water John T. Crozier Mine r,, 1900 Osborne D. Latta 1st Lieut. ! Mar. 30, 190T 2nd Lieut. Mir. :!0, 190T Captain 27. 1907 1st Lieut. Mar. 27, 190T 2nd Lieut. Mar. 27, 190T Captai July 8, 190 1st Lieut. ! .luly 8, 190f id'L L ing F.Klsasser L. Hurmeiste \V. Schulti Captain | Jan. 1 1st Lieut. A 190* 2nd Lioul Jan SKIXJ.MJ BATTAIJU.N Major 1st Lieat. liut. Adj Co. G. Geneva 1st Lieut. Mai I, i»«i; Harry E. Ford 2nd Lieut Lieut, bat. Adj. Jerome a lalli. John M. Crandell Robert C. Chapman .lum I. ifcS* John W. Wickerataas Co. I. ibert Rushvillr Chas. L. Hopper \pr 18, t»05 Ray Hell Feb. 15. 19&lt;l&gt; !V|ip(TburK 'Jin! Lieut, hat. Q. M &amp;. COB Station Original Date off] Rank I)at&lt; of of Muster CommlMiOD Ho A ("has. A. Calkins Captain M;ir ... l»i) York Blbert G. ftutterfield 1st Lieu! June I, 1881 Jesse \V. Me Pherson 2nd Lieut. I. ! Mi Albert H. Hollingwort!; Captain Mar. L'7, Iflu Beatric. Charles L. Brewst«-r 1st Lieut. Mar. 21. 19B June 1. 1881 Klmer L. Hevt lone 2nd Lieut. July L&gt;2. i :mi .Taco. Captain July 15, Wilbur Jacob A. Halflerson 1st Lieul. Jan. 10, 190 Vhf. 27. 1S9S ( rlrnm 2nd Lieut. Jan. 10. 190 0u. Q Captain Apr. 18. 1882 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">D.IITANT liEXKRAL'S KKPOH1 THIRD BATTALION \. Eberly 1st Lieut. Bat. Adj. Howard 11. Anu&gt; = Major Geor A. Eberl Ha Major Walter G. Sonnensc nr Walter G. Sonnenschein 2nd. Lieut Bat. Q. M. &amp;: Com'y Wm. K. K Station Ofti' ' Rank Date of Original Date Ofli Rank Date of f M Com miss 101 Com miss 101 Iver S. Johnson Captain Auk. 27 . Can la Auk. 27, 1 Si August \V. Loerk. ! 1st Lieu' Aug. 5, 190? st Lit Auk. •"'■ 1U0 William N. Orris 2nd Li. ut Auk. 27, 1906 t ml I. Chris U Anderson 2nd Lieut. July 25. 1900 -tirl Li ("has. E. Fnm Ca;.&lt; \o« Chas. E. Fra .1 Ivan Me Kay 1st Lieut .Tune 13, 190* Me K st Lieu 1 »0 \ Harry B. Hobbs 2nd Lieul. Jan J, l»9t nd Lieut. .Ian 3, It") Siiinu Kler Cap Mar 1, 19UT uel K. Y Capta Mar. 2. 19U Wynwn Frank E. Cr Frank E. (Tawfo-J 1st Lieui Dec. 1G, Roy II Woodard I Lieut Dec. 16. L'nd LJeul Dec 16, 1 N( 3. L. Holla Dec. 28, Co. M I. L. KollamUu.i Capt .i Dec. 28, 190 LUkura F. Oxford 1st Lieui July 29, 1H»&gt; burn F. O 1st Lieui July 29. 190 Mav If.. I K96I II. R. .lovr 11. R. Joyner I, 198* SKCOXl) UK&lt;iI.MK\T, INKANTin Headqna 1 I.iiui Dec. 28, 1 SKCOXD ItKtilMKNT 1\&gt; ANTin Headqu ;an. Colonel, l"airl&gt;ury, Jaoaa o i! lie Lieutenant-Colonel, Janm MAJORS. MA.IOF t 1 First Battalion, Albion. H od liuttalion. St. Paul, Feb. 10. M *rt .1. Paul. Second Battalion. St. Paul. V A ■sons. Third Hattalion. Kearney. K« -ij. -0 11 1 ■ . Captain-Adjut A U.n C V Tho? A on, Captaln-yu I y. July 1H, 1907 i(lt idii. rapIain-Coiuiiiissary. Uncolu, January. 24, CHAPLAIN IT I.IKl TK.NANTS-HATTAI.ION ADJ ITANTS . Kirtft Battalloa, Albion, Janaan -'•' ' Jecond Battalion, N&lt; Ity. Jannarj 2ft. I'- N lfto^ \ ■ t P. MadKett, Third Battalion. Hastinga, Febraary 1. l»0S Btt, Third Battalion. Hastinus. l-Vbiuaiy 1.1 KIT UATTAUOX QUARTERMASTER ANU CO fTALION i \\i ASTER AMI COM iter. First BattaUoa, Albion, December 19, l •'irst I!;itti'!ion. Albion, December iy, 19( h dy. Second Battalion, St. Paul, January it, I A B;itla P January it, 190 i. Third Battalion. Kearney, Jul\ 14. II NON-COMMISSIONED STAFF. uiirti. Third Battalion. Kearney, Jul\ 14. I NON-COMMISSIONED STAFF msey, Plattamoutb, Serpent-Major. A.ijtust 16, '.HOT &gt;uth. Sergent-Major, A.ijtust 10, '.HOT torse A. Withers, Lincoln, Quartermaster-Sersent, July 2.S, IMI in rs. Lincoln. Quanermaater-BerKent, July -'.s. 1M&lt; • leorse 1 »•&lt;•. Beatrice, Conital— ary-Sartceaat, July -'S. 190B Jasper !• Cole, Aurora, Color-Sergeant, June 1, 190«i B.rt E. V e, Linooln. Color-Sarg^ant, August 10, 19 Charlt Bull, Sargeant-Major, First Batallion, July 11, 19 Sutton H Martin. St. Paul. Second Lieutenant iP-and), Ausub </seg>
            <seg id="p028">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT SKCOXI) UIXJ1MKXT IXFAXTIIY FIRST BATTALION Major Fred J. Mack Ilat. Sits. Major Cham. A. Hull Station Original Date Officer: of Muster Ran Date of Commission Co. F Monte E. Lum Captain ! July l, 1907 1st Lieut. July 1. 1907 1'nd Lieut. Nov. 11. 190S Lincoln Guy B. Gould Apr. 22. 1895 Chas .G. Adams Co. K Chas H. Johnson aptain Auk. 9, 1904 Captain Dec, 14, 1908 1st Lieut. ' Dec, 14, 1908 2nd Lieut. ' Dec. 14. 190ft Apr. 11. 1905 Robert L. Billing M Frank F. Wlllott Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut Oct. lfi. 1907 Albion l&gt;ee. Z t. U.'iit. Mat. Adj. Leon H. Davi :nt\. I-iiul. Bat Q. .M. k Com'; .1. Frank Poynter Schuyler James F. Hashber- 1st Lieu!, g. 1, 190S July 6, 1SS7 John W. Longwith L'nd Lieut. Aug. C, 1907 Co. L. Arthur Kimborling Captain Dec, 14, 1908 Alma Arthur E. Liberty 1st Lieut. Dec, 14, 1908 SECOND BATTALION Major Herbert J. l'aul 1st. Lieut. Hat. Adj. .hick ! ted. Lint. Hat. Q. M. &amp; ( Addison K. « Original l&gt;ate OH. Rank Date of O f Mm Commission Clyde E. McCormfek 'tain Oct. 9, 190 \&gt;br. I Lee M. Halvorsen 1st Lieut Oct. !t, 190 May 24. 1887 Chas. K. Morse 2nd Lieut Oct. !'. Co. E. John O. Larson 'ain F.b. 25, Tekamah George P. Thomas 1st Lieut. .Tune •». 190fi 19, 1901 Walter T. Ileum 2nd Lieut^ June 20. 1906 Farl B. .-■'erricker Captain .luly 1 :i, 190 Omaha ' Andrew H. Clark 1st Lieut. July IS, 190 Oct. IT. 189 3 Fred R. Shearer 2nd Lieut. Dec. 2,_190_ Co. I. Julius A. Wiig Captain May 14. 190 Omaha Herbert VosberK 1st Lieut. July IB, 190 Vov. 11, 1901 Chester W. Harlan 2nd Lieut. July IS, 190 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">ANT GENERAL'S RKPORT 29 THIRD BATTALION Major Walter F. Samuions Is Lieut. Hat. Adj. John P. Madgett 2nd. Lieut. Bat. Q. M. ft Com'y Harry Schmidt tatk Original Date OfTiror-! Original Date Rank Pnto of *•-— "'■■low . ... 1. 1907 Rank r&gt;nte of of Moater ion Co. A. 3. Frei McNee, Co. A Kearn May S X. 190? Kearney Carl Abramson Carl Abramson Delbert Hibberd 'st Lieut. Mar. 6, 1907 I 6. 19( May '.'. 1881 Delbert Hibberd 2nd Lieut. June 12. 1907 ain 1, 190R 2nd Lieut. June 12. 1907 Co. H. Willar.i S. Paul St. Paul Chas \V. Dobry '00 Alfred J. Ward 1st Leut. Apr. 13, 190S Alfred J. Wa 2nd Lieut. Apr. 13. 1908 tin Jan. 11, 1908 Co. D. George E. Bogss Co. D E. Ho ( Hastings Henry P. Rrown Hastings Henry P. P.rown July 2. 1906 Ira E. Ball 'st I.'Piit. .Ian. 11, l!&gt;0fc n. 11, 190fc Jaly 8. 1906 Ira E. Dall E. Ball 2nd L Tan J '. 1&gt;&gt;g Feb. 4, 190: 2nd Lieut. ! Jan. 11, 190S Co. H. j Otis M. Newman Otis M. New Feb. 4. 19 Aurora j Myrl S. Mather lath 1st L'eut. May 30. 1901 Lieut. May Jan. 0. 1S!&gt;9 John M. Woodw )dw !nd Li May 38. 1907 .'nd I.: May 38. 19 SIGN'Al ('OltFS Static &lt;" inai Dute OfBce-s Rank D-te of of M FIKLD HOSPITA I. ( Fremont Henry A. Jt Ma Wm. C. Mallownee -nd Lieut. Dec. -1. 1 FIRST SEPAR ATE COMPANY M. Birkner Lieut. Col. May 15 Feb. 10, 1903 Jahn F. Spealman 1st Lieut. 15, 190S ECONU SEPARATE COM PAN Captain 2nd Lie Kenesaw July 20, 1908 Harry N. Jones 2nd Liei IRD SEPA ATE COMPANY Frank A. Anier Holdrege James L. White 1st Lieut July 4, 190 Jul 2nd Li.i MILITARY BOARD Charles A. Vickere Roy H. Ojers Captair July 29, li»l&gt; Crete 1st Lieut. July 29, 190 July 29. 1908 2nd Lieut. tain Apr. 9, 1! Lieut. Apr. 9, II Lincoln ptain t Captain July 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">ADJl'TAVT GENERALS UKPORT m:I!K\SKA NATIONAL &lt;JIARD. OfrYKB (W THK PMHCIIW C.KNKRAL. Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 190X To The Adjutant Genera!. Lincoln. Nebraska Sir: — I have the honor to submit the following report of inspec - ting made during the bi-ennium 1907-190S: The inspection oi tin- companies of the National Guard for the year 1907 was made in February and March of that year under General Orders No. 4. by the officers named in that order, also, in the same year, pursuant to General Orders No. 17. by officers detailed for that purpose. Thc&gt;« 1 inspections made under the requirements of the war department, are made to ascertain if the companies are armed, uniformed and &gt;nuippeil for service in the field, and they were found be fairly satisfactory in that respect The inspection for li'Os was made by the adjutant general, pur - suant to General Orders No. 1, concurrent with the inspection for the war department, made by Major L. P. Davison. U. S. A., retired. The present .ind absent are shown in the following table Organizat Station I'rcs M). I V^'utiv ■' \ distant General's m«&gt;ni Lincoln Quartermaster's Department Lincoln I ;. n«T:il .- Hi ;■ men! Lincoln idsr Advocate Uen&lt; Omaha -(I ic.il Department Lincoln 11 1 1 field Hospital Lincoln !!&gt; | 11 -'iKnal Corps Fremon' -Ill 17 • •7 »• First Infantry llt-adqaarU-t? Fullerton 10 1 14 Oonrpany A York 35 31 I Company It Stanton m ** « •&gt; Company C" Beatrice 40 10 -,o fTnmjmaj 1&gt; WeepinK W»tw rvompany E Wllber rompany F Madison M 30 34 19 47 40 3K Company G Geneva IS 23 4 "2 Company H Nelson Company I Rushville Company K Wymore Company L Omaha 26 31 18 22 3.1 I 20 r,i tit; ZS 42 67 4D Company M Broken Bow •2B 27 f»3 ,0 ToUl. ToUl H39 258 5»7 ~- &gt;nd Infantry H&gt;ad- nuartors Fairbury </seg>
            <seg id="p031">ADJUTANT r.KNERAL KEPORa it will be noted that but four companies had less than 10 per cent jf strength absent, which is considered all that should be absent from in organization at these annual inspections. In ten companies there were r.O per cent, absent. It is not thought that a company can be enthusiastic, nor efficient, nor available for duty, where the member - ship is so disinterested that it will not appear in some semblance of strength, for these important annual inspections, and our state troops ire strongly criticised in this respect by the war department. At this inspection a careful checking and examination of all pro - perty was made. It was found that the blue clothing, which has been lsed by the Guard for a number of years, has become so worn and obsolete as to practically necessitate its being abandoned, which should !&gt;e done through the action of a surveying officer, and the Guard supplied with the olive drab wool uniforms. It is also recommended that each man bo supplied with 2 kahaki uniforms, so that one may al ways be clean. There is nothing which can be done that will go farther toward encouraging and keeping up an efficient National Guard, than the pro - riding of suitable armories in the principal cities and towns of the ■rtate, and I renew my recommendation of two years ago. that the leg - slature provide funds for this purpose. The armories were inspected .is to suitability for drill and the safe keeping of public property. Some were found to be deficient in these -espects, neither furnishing a proper drill flloor. nor were they pro - vided with secure fastnings to doors and windows. In some companies it was found that the men were allowed to take property away from the armory, this, in addition to being against die law of the state, results in its loss in many Instances, and should to positively prohibited by commanding officers. It is recommended that companies be not located, or maintained rtere suitable armories, are not, or cannot, be furnished. Ban 1 1 St. Paul 27 lompant A Kearney 38 Company B 3t. Paul 45 34 Company C Nebraska Cltj :,-i in Company D Company F Hastings Tekamah 22 19 21 t!&gt; Company f! Lincoln 4 2 t II Company K Omaha 29 '■ompanv II Aurora 57 o ■.Company I Omaha 11 IS Company K Schuyler 28 II 4fi Company L Alma 26 .'omoany M Albion 30 37 •;: Total 456 227 t&gt;$3 Crand Total a </seg>
            <seg id="p032">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT Tin- Guard has recently been supplied with the new model maga zine rifle, and in othet equipment is practically supplied with that of 'hi- regular army. Very respectfully, C. J. BILLS Colonel. Inspector Generis I </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 33 \ KKI'OKT OK SJIMiKOX (1KNKRAL, COLONEL PRANK S. NICHOLSON ON THK MBMCAli DKI'AKT.MKNT OF THK NKItKASKA NATIONAL Cil'ARD FOR THK VKAKS I9M7 ANI&gt; 1JMW. Paul. Nebraska November :i0. 1908 Governor George L. Sheldon Lincoln, Nebraska Sir: — I have the honor to submit a report on the Medical Depart - ment of the Nebraska National Guard for the years 190" and 1908. The Mediral Department still continues to improve in efficiency, due largely to the enthusiastic devotion to their duties of the officers and men and to their careful training in the past. Another factor in the increased efficiency in this Department is the fact that in the last few years the personnel has not been changed so frequently, and consequently the pre of several years experience. nt officers have had the benefit While I was not present at the 1907, I am credibly informed that th encampment held in Lincoln in several camp-grounds were kept in a thoroughly hygienic condition, and free from any serious cases of sicknes: al Order No. 23 was issued from tfie On Decem zing the Medical Department of the Nebraska N ard to conform to the Medical Department of the ianizej Medical Department to consist of V. S. Army, th 1 Surgeon General with rar 5f Colonel with rank of Lieutenant Colonel. Assistant Surgeons Gene 4 Surgeons with rank of Maji -istant Surgeons with ran 3f First Lieutenant s Assistant Surgeons with rar Paragraph V. of the same or sr relieved all the Medical Officers anizations and transferred them to them to report by letter for as- i from duty with their respect iv signment to duty the Ambulance Company to a ing change in its personnel. Paragraph VI. of this order Field Hospital, with a correspond The changes made in the M gard as the most important advan •e in the right direction that has been since its organization. made in the Medical Departmen They will tend to do away with the influence of politics on appoint - ments to the Medical Department, and the Medical officers feeling more sure of a long tenure of office will naturally display more interest in their duti- In compliance with G. O. No. 4, A. O. O., Lincoln, dated July 10. IMS, I reported at the State Rifle Range on August It, for the purpose of inspecting the site and sanitary arrangements prior to the en - campment. ifliiT, Gent Adjutant General's office, rcorgmn k of Captain the Medical Department, orderin dical Department by this order I re- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">AIUTTANT GENERALS RKPORT found ihi' sit.' an ideal MM for the camp, the soil being sandy rid covered with a good growth of short blue gra The water supply wax furnished from driven wells one of whic&gt; was operated by a gasoline engine which pumped the water into a sup - ply tank from which it »a.&lt; carried through pipes to faucets located in &gt;he Company streets An innovation for State Encampments was introduced in th hape of a shower bath tent, which was very much appreciated. ■litary arrangements at this camp. I consider were among -! we hav&lt;- ever had at a state camp, and the sickness was if •luced to a minimum The small number of cases of stomai h and bowel trouble as coin pared with other encampments, may be party ascribed to the elimina tion from the camp canteen of such Indigestible articles as pies, cak greet Fruits, etc., which have always lieen a source of much sicknea n the past he Field Hospital w;is situated in an ideal location, and was con Incted In a manner reflecting great creclii on the oActra and men ot 'hat. organization This camp lite w.i&gt; occupied iiard for thirty days, bur wing to the careful sanitation the camp wa urn sicknes luring the la.-t In days period, than during the first l'ii days, whlct contrary to all precedent for camps occupied that length of time. In coucl union I wish to express my appreciation of the efficient an ireful manner in which the officers and men in the Medical Depart v. performed their duties during my term of office as Surgeon ml it is my belief that the Medical Department of the Ne Sid: — The law designates the Judge Advocate, as the legal advisor of the Military Department of the Stale of Nebraska, in such matter* pertaining to the Militia and National Guard, as may be referred tc him by the Commander-in-Chief. He is also required to review pro ceedings of court-martial requiring the action of the Commander-ln Chief. He is also required to bring such suits or actions as may b&lt; ordered in writing by the Commander-in-Chief, and is required to make an annual report to the Conimander-in-Chief through the Adjutan General. National] Guard stands on a higher plane of efficiency than it ha t &lt; v. i Wry lt&lt; &gt;;&gt;i ctfulh . FRANK S NICHOLSON. Colonel and Rnrgcoa General. BKPOKT OF ji ik;k \i)V(H'.%tk &lt;;k\kkai., johx &lt;-. cowin. November "it, 1 y (i s. To (Jein'ial C. K. Schwarz. Adjutant-General. Nebraska National Guard, Lincoln. Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT During niy term of office there have been no courts-martial re quiring any action upon my part. It has not been necessary to brin It has not been necessary to bring any suit tions. The eGlcien the Adjutant-General's depart- ment is such that my gervlcea hav but little required. I hare he ma •cha enlisted men, and when they are entitled to be honorably discharged, and with respect juementa as to character. Also us to enlisted men refusing to deliver public property upon discharge. Also with respect to pro- i. inis. and some other minor mat- writing and me to furnish you with the accom - hc remarks of Captain Charles W. ■ ting the condition of the or- panying memorandum containing Castle. Thirtieth Infantry. V. S. A ganizations of the Nebraska Militia, with regard to their appearance, zeal, efficiency, and reliability, as observed during the inspection mad« by him recently under the provisions of General Orders No. 71. War Department, series of 1903. I am also directed to invite your attention particularly to the re - marks relating to Company H. 1st Infantry, and Company K, 2nd In - fantry, which organizations appear to require administrative action to bring them to a proper state of efficiency: and also to the fact that It is noted that in many of the organizations the War Department standard of physical examination of recruits, as prescribed by Circular of Febru - ary 8. 1904. has not been observed. Very Respectfully F. C. AINSWORTH The Adjutant General Extracts from memoranda of inspection of the organized militia of Nebraska, giving remarks of inspecting officers with regard to con - ditions of the several organizations of the State Forces. KKl'OUT OK &lt; \1T.\I\ ( HAHI.KS W. CASTLK, :IOTH IXKAXTRV. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT Troop A Battery CAVALRY. The troop has recently changed station from Seward to Milford. Old members have been discharged, and a new per - sonnel is being secured. Each man is required to have his own horse. State law prescribes compensation for horses used in service of State. Squads are being organized in Neighboring towns. Inspection incomplete, there being no formation of troop. New captain is a clergyman, and had experience with Ne - braska Volunteers in the Philippines. Prospects for improve - ment over past conditions are good. Section IS, Act of Jan - uary 21. 1903. have not been complied with. Present captain is accountable only for property actually found in the armory. Considerable deficiency probably exists in accountability of his predecessor. Armory and two store rooms are rented on second floor of business block. Hall too small for drills. Con - ditions poor at present. Expense exceeds state allowance. An additional room is to be secured for use as club. ARTILLERY. A. Physical appearance of most of the members, very good. No physical examination. Character apparently good. Some - what backward in zeal, but prospects of great improvement in future. Battery has been reorganized during past year, personnel having changed almost completely. As a social organization, it is a great I It owns property worth about llO.oiHi.oii including gun shed and lot. Base ball team is being organized, and tennis court is to be built near gun shed. Military efficiency at low ebb, on account of con - tinued disappointments regarding an outfit of modern guns Two mounted drills held during past year. Good progress shown in school of the soldier, and movements of gun detach - ments. Inspection was dismounted in armory. Section 18 Act of January 21, IMS, has been complied with, battery having spent nine days at Fort Riley maneuvers, August ]9o(j, and assembled for instruction 2N times during the year. Officers have no doubt of reliability of men in domestic emergencies. Many men are railway employees, this town having shops and division headquarters. Citizens in general appear to have unusual interest in the organization. Armory consists of fairly large hall, without other rooms Property is well cared for by quartermaster sergeant, who acts as janitor of hall, and devotes most of his time to the work. Accommodations are inadequate. Rent is covered b&gt; state allowance, but considerable expense for other purposes* </seg>
            <seg id="p037">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 37 is born by battery. No target practice nor firing of any kind during past year. Captain states that on 2 4 hours notice 90 per cent, of strength can be turned out. KIKST INFAXTHY Band. F 'hysical appearance and character, very good. High standard of zeal and efficiency appears to exist. Band has just changed station from Wisner to Lincoln, and is not yet settled in aa armory. Complete inspection impracticable. It is an old or - ganization, and claims to be the leading band of the state. Chief musician, principal musician, and drum-major have had long experience, and many members are proficient musicians. Section 18. Act of January 21. 1903, have been complied with. Band attended Fort Riley maneuvers, Angus:, rtoc. and during most of the year, meets twice a week No target prac - tice. All members would probably respond to a call in emergency, and be found reliable. Company A. Physical appearance, good. Men examined before enlist - ment. Character apparently good. Great zeal shown by some men traveling long distances in rain storm to attend inspec - tion. General interest and efficiency below average. Some members were in a hurry to finish inspection and get away. No doubt of reliability in domestic emergencies. Captain estimates that in emergency 0 per cent. o[ members coiili d i inn 18, Act of .January 21. D complied with. Company attended Foil Riley mbl. &lt;1 for drill 4". limes und tnrre i Kent covered »te allowance, but ( i paid by com pan All property kept in armory wall lockers ;ind arm racks with exc locked. i with wooden doors th can Quartermaster sergeant exf id industry in inic alter property. Alter probably diminished by d members h work Saturday evening. y Company 1 appearance v iod. Prescribed physical ex- aminations held by regiment urgenn. Z«h1 and interest above the average shown by manner of going through inspec tion and drill. Efficiency apparently up to standard of com panies in this state. No reason to doubt reliability in do- mestic emergencies. Captain estimates that on short notice 70 per cent, of strength could be assembled. Section 18, Act January 21. 190:;, has been complied with. Company attend- ed Fort Riley maneuver. August, 190C. and during past year lias had •"&gt;. drills and a number of extra formations. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT Company Company Armory ronsists of drill hall, too narrow lor movement* Rent covered by state allowance. \o store moms. Arms kepi in racks, uniforms and equipments in wall lockers. Ex tra property in chests. Armory very neat and property wel taken rare of. No attractions provided as place for socin pathe. iims. Several men are well instructed in signalinp Property accountability of captain all checked at inventory C. Physical appearance good. No physical examinations Character of men satisfactory to officers. Members said t&gt; be all young men of food standing in community, without affiliations that would make their reliability doubtful in do emergencies. Zeal fairly high: efficiency up to average Section is. Art of January LM. 190:t, has been complied with company having spent nine days at Fort Kiley maneuvers August. 1 9 0 1; . and having assembled ~i« times for instruction during past year Captain states that 7.". per cent, could b&gt; turned (ml at short notice, and for service in war. about en - tire itrcBfth. Qaltery practice in armory. N&lt;&gt; range foi range practice. Armory is commodious and convenient; large drill hall two recreation rooms, and two store rooms. In addition t&lt; the stat. allowance, company pays 1350.06 rent per annum partly made up liy renting h kept in racks and equipment forms kepi al homes of m lockers all for other purposes. Arm: hung up in store room. I'ni •mbers. there being no wal D. Physical appearance very regimental assistant surgeon, state of collapse since August . good. Exaniinatiom held b; This company has been in ; lyot;. old members were al discharged and about the end of March, liti'T. a new organiza tion was started. The superintendent of schools of the town is captain of the new company and is without military ex perience. but with his position and influence, should make it a sum-.-. Members are all of excellent character, and showed zeal by the showing made after only four drills. The oM company attended the Fort Kiley maneuver. August. 190G To com pi j with section 19. Act of January 21, im&lt;i:5, it will be necessary for the company to hold Zfl more drills befon the allotment of funds is made. A :;imi yard target range is available on property of Captain HutiHate. Surgeon. N. N. G. Armory consists of two stories of husine-s block. Dril hall is too narrow for movements of company. Some gymna- sium apparatus, liood store room on second floor. Property is in great confusion, everything having been thrown in tht store rooms in disorder upon return of company from Fort Riley last August and left without care. Greatlv damaged by dirt, mould and rust. Former captain has not settled ac- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 39 &lt; Con 1 ntabllity. Quantities reported are those actually round at nventory. New members have done excellent work restor ing armory and property to orderly -shape. Present Beaker would all turn out and be found reliable in emergent E. Physical appearance, very good. Physical examination preceded enlistments. Character appears to be satisfactory Considerable zeal shown by men coming Ions distal his inspection, but apparently rather lacking at ordinao Mines. Efficiency up to the average. Reliability in doniesti. Some members live at great distances from town, but telt- phone communication is excellent, and captain claims that entire Strength could be assambled in 12 hours. .Section IS. Act of January 2 1 . l»«3, has been complied with. Compan&gt; mended Fort Kiley maneuvers. August, l HO)'., and hi lembted for drill about 50 times during past year. No armory except one store room, inadequate and in.- Drills held in halls rented at $11. On per night. Till mi state allowance is raised by company. Outfits of men appearance and character apparent! Physical examinations held by civilian physician »t a tost one dollar per man. Zeal and efficiency above aver. son to doubt reliability in domestic emergencies. Captain imates that mi per cent, of members could be assembled on hours notice in emergency. Section IS, Act of .lanu n compiled with. Company attended For' pparently good. Zeal and efficiency in low stat. Many members including captain Ihe in distant cities durinu ivinter. which is dull season for business here. No reason o doubt reliability in domestic emergencies. Section is. Art Ian has been comppied with. Records show lrill during past year, and company attended Fort Riley maneuvers. August. 190(J. All members to b. d at home could lie assembled on 12 hours notice Arn three rooms with use of drill hall rented allowance. Property securely kept. All property habit ally kept in armory. Arms in racks. No gallery nor tat nergenctea positive. Men have no affiliations to inti'rfen •M't ;it bones, on account of lack of armory aeeoumodatk I". Physical apuearaBCe and rharactor — — — -»»- „. uii.'.v maneuvers, August, 1 tto.;. and has assembled for drll IS times during the past year. Armory comMUou eaceHeat Hall. office, tad More nxm in well lighted building built for the purpose. Arms kept u nail arm racks. Iniforms and equipments of men kepi :: wall lockers. Property well care tor. Armory supplied wit: NNM gymnasium apaarataa. 0. Phr steal appearance average. No physical examiiiatma </seg>
            <seg id="p040">ADJl'TANT GENERALS REPORT 40 Company Com pan Com pa H. Physical appearance, good. No physical examination. Character appears below average. The 1st lieutenant and one duty sergeant present show unusual ability on duty, other - wise zeal and efficiency are entirely lacking. After sending out patrols and waiting until 10 p. m., only 15 men could be assembled. The captain resigned recently, leaving the com - pany in a state of collapse. There is nothing to interfere with the reliability of command in domestic emergencies. Some members live at long distances from station of com - pany, but the lieutenant commanding states that 75 per cent, could be assembled in 12 hours. Gallery practice held; no range practice during year. Section 18, Act of January 21, 190S, has been complied with. The company attended Port Riley maneuvers. August. 190G, and assembled for drill 30 times during the year. Armory consists of one room on fir^t floor of store build - ing. Arms are kept in regular barracks arms rack. All pro - perty is kept in armory, in wall lockers and chests. I. Physical appearance and character very good. Zeal and interest on part of most numbers lacking. Material appears to be excellent, and with training should be efficient organ- ization for active serviie. Captain estimates that 90 per cent. would volunteer (or service, and that in sudden emergency every man to be found at home would turn out on short no- ce. This company is stationed at town remote from other neuver.-, August, UOC. No physical examination om pan lea and interest of members was almost destroyed by :einj; left out &lt;if expedition to Fori Uilcy maneuvers last umnier. Company ipenl el Kb I days In camp last summer, md held i;n drills dir.ini; past year, thus complying with Sec- :on 1--. Ad of .lanuaty 21, !&lt;tn::. No doubt of reliability in lomeitlc emergi \o physical examinations held. Armory rouiata of hall and store room in store build- n:.'. small and inadequate. No attractions at meeting place. Kent covered b&gt; I'nifornis and equipments Lent in wall lockers. Arms in circular racks. Condition of recordi and property accountability far above average. K. Physical appearance and character good. Somewhat backward in zeal and ins. ruction, but prospects are that in- ti rest will increase in the future. Members residences are .1 and it is difficult lo secure regular attendance at (1 ills. Captain estimates that , .'&gt; per cent, could be assembled on a lew hours notice. Officers appear to be far above tin- average in experience and interest in work. No doubt of reliability in domestic emergencies. Company as- sembled for drill 24 tini. alar meetings during the ■ •ar. besides extra formations, and attended Fort Riley ma- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 41 Compa ( Armory consists of hall covered by state allowance wall lockers. No arm racks. Members expect to Join Y. M new building planned by that and two store rooms. Rent Arms and equipment kept in All property kept in armory. C. A. and arrange for use of organization, as armory 1.. Physical appearance good. No physical examination. Character apparently satisfactory. Zeal and efficiency about average. This company has excellent record and reputation, but showing at this inspection was not up to standard ex - pected. No doubt of reliability in domestic emergencies. Captain states that in emergency entire strength could be as - sembled on short notice. Section 18, Act of January 21, 1903. has been complied with. Company attended Fort Riley ma - neuvers, August. 190C. and has assembled for drill 54 times during past year. Armory consists of fair locker room, office, and small itore room. Drills held in hall in same building. Armory ssembled for drill 28 times during past year. Captain esti - uates that '."&gt; per cent, of strength could be assembled on 12 oars' notice in emergency. Telephone communication ent. |300. At par annum. Accommodations inadequate. No ■a nut- practice. M. Physical appearance, good. No physical examination. 'haracter of men up to »• Zeal and efficiency, fairly ligh, improved daring past year, from statement of officers. ton to doutrt reliability in domestic emergencies Coo- -iderabli- interest appears to lie taken in social features. Section is, Act of January 2 1 , 1*03, has been complied with. Company attended Fort Riley maneuver 1 !&lt;"•;, and Armor} consists of one hall rented by state allowance. ised for drill and all other pun&gt;oses. provided with piano and gymnastic apparatus. Arms and equipments kept in wall lockers. No arm racks. Owiim to hours of arrival and departure of inspector, Inspection of this company was hurried and incomplete. Residence! of memb. .ittered, the town being small and the vicinity thinly settled. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">H.-iinl i Con Com pan ADJITAXT GENERAL'S KKPORT KKOOXD IXFAXTKV 'hysical appearance and charact hi service higher than usually IK-rformed in soldierly manner. at concert show instruction to r very good. Average length found. Duties at inspection ;md several selections played in satisfactory state. Con siderable interest evinced in both military and musical part of work. All members to be found at home would turn ou' at summons in any kind of emergency. Members are of vari - ous occupations, but have numerous engagements to play and practice at armory at regular weekly meetings. Section is. Act of January 21, IMS, has bet attended Fort Kiley maneuvers, examinations. So target practic n complied with. The Band August. 190i;. No physical Armory consists of a hall and two store rooms. No lockers. Property securely kept ;il home of member*. Kent con 1'niforms habitually kept red by state allowance. ;mk of 2nd lieutenant, was Chief .Musician, who ha cput of town. A. Physical appearance, good. Character appears up to average liciency shown by those present .inns far above average. Appear No physical examination Considerable zeal and ef Drill, especially manual o to be no doubt of reliabili ty in domestic emergencies. Many members live at a distant from town, but within telephone communication. Captain estimates that M per cent could be assembled on short notice in emergency. Section lv Ait of .January 21. IMS, has been complied with. Company attended Fort Riley maneuver August, 1{mm;. and has assembled for drill M times durin past year Armory has just been moved to old roller skating rinl Kent of $.",11.(1(1 in excess of by company. Fair drill hall equipments kept in wall Im- itate allowance per annum paid but no store rooms. Arms ami era. No arm racks. I'niform- kept at homes of members. Uon keep arms and uniform Detachment of 1.". men at Gib there. H. Physical appearance and character of men. very good Zeal and efficiency appear to be fair. No doubt of reliablUt) in domestic emergencies. About 7." per cent, could be relied upon to assemble on 12 hours notice. Many members live at a distance from town. Company attended Fort Riley ma - neuvers. August. IMC, and has assembled for instruction :!." limes during the past year. No physical examination Armory in rented store building. Too narrow lor dril hall and without store rooms. Kent covered by state allow ance. Anns kept in wall arm racks. Xo lockers. Propert' habitually kept in armory. Property found more complete ;ct inventory than usual. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">AD.H'TAXT CiKNKRAL'S RKIORT 43 Com par Coi r C. Pkystcal appearaaee, very good. No physical examina - tion. Attendance at inspection poor, and zeal shown by Dumber of drills held and interest of men present is consid - erable. Oood material and fair progress in instruction. Cap - tain states that 7.". |&gt;er cent, of strength could be turned out on three hours' notice, and 9n per cent, in 12 hours. Probably perfectly reliable in domestic emergencies. Section lv of January •_• 1 . IMS, has been complied with, the compan&gt; having been at Fort Kiley maneuvers nine days, and having the unusual record of .12 drills. 14 extra drills. :; marches, and &gt;; assemblies for target practi' Iteiited armory consists of officers' room. re&lt; reation room minis, aind locker room. All small and inadequati w Id in locker room and drill on street .Most of the men appear to be of shiftless character and lack iiiK in zeal. (efficiency at Vow stase. Company is being re organized, and with change in personnel, there are prospect ot great improvement which officers are determined to achieve. Nn reason lo doubt reliability in domestic emergen - cies. Captain states that on sudden call in emergency, prac- tically the whole strength could be turned out. Section IS. Ait ol January i' I . inn:'., has been complied with. Company attended Kort Kiley maneuvers. August. I&gt;OC, and have drilled -■"■ times Caring the past year. A rii nsists of hall in store building, with stor m. Kxpenses exceed state allowance. Wall lockers auil inks provided. Hall to&lt; drill. Xo attrai in it ii .inv K I'hysiial appearance, good. Zeal, &gt;mall. Character of men up in the average. Backward in military training, but mI material. Reliability in strike and riot duty unquestionable. Kntire strength could be turned out In emergency, but assembly would be slow Section IN. Act o Jannarj 21. lHo:;. has been complied with. Company has assembled for drill :!U times during past year, and spent nin days at Km t Kiley maneuvers. Xo physical examination .1 recruit Armory is :i small one story frame building. Inade - quate for drill and storing property. Kitles kept in wall arm rack. lniforms kept at homes of the men. there being n&lt; linkers. No range practice. Deficiency in uniforms may t&gt;» supplied when the affairs of a former captain, who abgcoDd ed, are settled. Kood. Xci physical examlsatlon </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 AD.IITAXT GENERAL'S REPORT Company Compan &lt; 'ompany F. Men appear young and strong. Displayed interest and attention during inspection. Zeal at low stage during winter months when drill in manual only is possible. Drill hall con - sists of long narrow room on third floor of office building State allows $250.00 per annum for rent. Company pays $110.00 additional. Drill hall very unattractive. Club room fairly furnished. Guns, clothing and equipments of men kept in wall lockers. Store room inadequate and insecure. Stored property in considerable confusion. Since the inspection, the captain has reported a large box of unserviceable cloth - ing that was overlooked when the count was made. The captain showed ability in handling company but lacks experi - ence regarding property. The 2nd lieutenant was present but not in uniform, not having procured it since his appointment January 21, 1907. Some range practice held, but not sys - tematically, the State officials forbidding use of range on Ennday, which is the only day available for most of the men. Prescribed standard of physical examination adopted by state, but little observed in this company. About SO per rent of strength could t&gt;e mined out on a few hours' notice in emergency. Section is. Act of January 21, 1903 has been ((implied with. Company attended Fort Riley maneuvers, August. 19»(;, and during the past year assembled for in - struction 51 times, and held one practice march. (I. Physical appearance good. No physical examinations held. Character of men and class from which recruited, ex - cellent. Zeal shown by inspection and record in past, very good. J4.3 of enlisted men present. Great interest and direful instruction shown in drill in armory. Material for efficient field company with tr hours' notice IS per cent, can that members could be relied D 1 g, Act of January 21, company having assembled fo • ar. and spent nine days 1HOU. lining. Captain claims on 3 lie tinned out. It is believed ■poo in domestic emergency. l&gt;03, has been complied with, drill, etc., "j4 times during n camp at Fort Riley, August Drill in winter in rented hall: in sumn tr Very attractive recreation room, and crowded but well kept • and locker rooms. Property managed with more system than in most organizations. Slate pays IX60.0S per annum lor rent, company pays about $60.00 per month additional, which is a great burden. Gallery practice held in armory. No range practice, there being no range. H. Character, zeal, and efficiency appear to be far above average. Physical appearance, good. Physical examination held, except for men recently enlisted. Apparently no doubt </seg>
            <seg id="p045">ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT 45 Compa Company having assembled for instructions 5s times, and spent nint days at Fort Riley maneuvers during past year. In an emer - gency, CO per cent, of strength could be turned out on short notice. For service in actual war, captain believes that every man would go. Armory is in rented rooms, conveniently loraft*1. Offi rooms and recreation room attractively furnished. Twt me and well kept. Drill hall and lock n&lt; ugb for formation in line, but not for mov ments. Drill in summer on streets. Appears to be consider able interest in company as a social organization. Rifles uniforms and equipment of men kept in wall lockers. K. Physical appearance very good. Physical examination held by captain, who is a physician. Character appears to be rather poor, most of men of a shiftless disposition. Offlcer&gt; arnest and zealous, but in general zeal lacking. Efficiency in the field would probably be below average. No reason known for doubting reliability in domestic emergency. Cap - tain states that in case of sudden call every man within reach would respond. Section IS, Act of January 11, 1903, has been complied with. Company attended Fort Riley maneu August. 1906, and assembled for drill jo times during year. Armory conditions excellent. Large store room on first floor of business block, and fairly large hall on second floor. Arms kept in wall rack, provided with lockers. Uniforms and equipments in wall lockers. Rent covered by state alowance. Property in store room well care for. Property in drill hall in great confusion, due to carelessness of men. t&gt;f reliability in domestic emergencies. Section lv. Act of jilitv January 21. 19"::. has been complied with. Company attend- ed Fort Riley maneuvers. Augu.-t, IMC, and has met for drill .jo times during past year. Captain estimates that in emergency Si per cent (if strength could be assembled In 12 hours. Armory consists of drill hall and one store room. Rent covered by state allowance. Hall very neat and clean. Arms kept in well made arm racks. I'niforms kept at homes of members, armory having arms and elementary movements in close and extended order, very well executed, except load- ing and firing. I. Xo physical examinations before enlistment, but men appear young and strong Show zeal and interest above the average. Efficiency fairly high, considering facilities. Ap- parently reliability in donestic emergen. ion 18, Act of January L' 1 . t 3 • « : ; , h;i.s been complied with, the company </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 A1UI TANT GENERAL' UKI'OK'I Com | Am bill a IK I.. Physical appea ranee wry good. Zeal mid efficiency ap pear ki be far above the average. Instruction varied beyond limits usually reached by companies in this stat". No reas on to doubt reliability in domestic emergencies About 7: per cent, would respond Nearly all members are within tele phone communication. The company assembled for drill :;t: limes daring the past year. Armory consists of one room for all purposes, too smaTI drill hal! No place in town available. Rent covered bv stale allowance. Arms and equipments are kept in wall lock &lt;is; uniform* kept at home of members, (here being no plan to change clot hen at armory. mpan&gt; M. physical appearance and character. Rood. No Physical examination. Considerable interest in work appears to exist Material afforded by personnel appear to be excellent. N&lt; ■ f ■" "&gt; &lt; .mi urni. -&gt;»' eason to doubt reliability in domestic emergencies. Captain stimates that Un per cent of strength could be assembled on short notice In emergency. Section lv Act of January 190:1, has been complied with. Company attended Fort Rilev lanetivers. August, l»06. and tnes during past rear. has assembled for drill year Armor} consists of stor&lt; '"in and locket room. Arms m -kers. No arm racks. Pro - held during winter in opera during summer drill is held t id equipnaentH of men kept in I ■rty well taken care of. Drills lii.use rented at $ln per night Haslinas Kill. Physical appearance, very ;ood Prescribed physical ex - neon. Considerable zeal and ■any old companies. Men impair reliability in domestic !»i&gt; per cent of members could 'mergency. Section 18, act of amination held by civilian stir; efficiency shown; greater than have tin affiliations that would emergencies. Captain believes mbled &lt;in shoi t notice in t January 81. l»»&gt;3, has been complied with. Since muster in July S. 1»im;. company has attended Port Riley maneuvers August. 1!*ih;. and a-senibled for drill 3C times Armory consists of drill hall with offices and store room partitioned off. Rented by the state allowance. Hall too small for drill. No lockers or ami racks. Uniforms kept at homes of members. No gallery or range practice. No range avail - able. Character of men appears to be above the average Hospital Corps. &lt;■ Company. Physical appearance averages high. All men required to undergo physical examination of prescribed stand - ard before enlistment. Men are of various occupations, medi - cal students being found desirable material. Character and zeal as shown by results attained remarkably good In - spection, drill, litter drill, and exercises in first" aid showed skill and knowledge on part of officers, and interest and training on part of men. From experience i nthe past the major commanding states that they can be relied upon for anv service required. On short notice 75 per cent can be turned out. and in case of real emergency, practically every man would be found present. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">ADJTTAXr C1EMCRALS REPORT 47 I Armory is small and crowded. State allows J2."&gt;0 i&gt;er an - m for rent: company pays J7n additional, besides J4n (or iehts. etc. Uniforms and equipments in hands of men kept n wall lockers. Extra clothing kept in small store room, icatly arranged. There is an attractive recreation room. The wo ambulances are kept stored in loft of livery stable and ire worthless: besides there is no provision for animals and and the lack of ambulance drill is a matter of re- ret to Major Brinkener. who is an enthusiast on military ITai Two sergeants reported present at muster, wore civilian lothes, being unable to attend the entire inspection. Thf equirements of Section 18, Act of January 21, 190:;. hav* &gt;een fulfilled, the company having attended the Fort Riley ineuvers in August. 1»»6, and having assembled f( action every Monday daring the year. uneuv Signal Corps. ante au«i character, very good. Zeal appears to b above the average. Bearing of men during inspection, rerj soldierly. Personnel reported to include four professional lelegrapb operators and two professional electricians: in ■ofirient men proficient in bellorgrapg and flag signaling: 10 mer making progress in instruction. x o reason to doubt reliabi n domestic emergencies. Captain states that in emergeni ■&gt; men to be found si home could be nssembled on short nn - (, probably 80 per cent Section 18, Act of January Jl, •03, has been complied with. Company attended Fort RMe&gt; lianeuvers. August. 190G. and has held 52 regular drills dur t year. Considerable instruction given at extra mt tended voluntarily. No physical examination* Armory consists of hall and two store rooms in rented milding. Rent covered by state allowance. Clothing and •quipments kept in wall lockers. Rifles in racks. Revolvt ocked in enclosed rack. Property well cared for. August 17. 1907 uphy, and 8 others fairly proflciei </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 ADJITANT GENERAL'S REPORT WAK OKI'AHTMKNT. THK AIUITANT UKXKKAI/H OKKICK WASHINGTON. The ('.• i if Nebrask Lincoln. Sir: Tlir A&lt;tinK Secretary of War direct! mi' to transmit here - with ropy of tli^ report rendered by Major Daniel 1.. Howell. Eighteenth Infantry, of his tour of duty with the orgaalsed militia of Nebraska during the annual encampment held at Lincoln Nebraska, from Au - ■:' to 17th. inn?. Very Respectfully, All these camps were in or very near the city, on street car lines. Camp Robert W. Furnas, First Infantry and Battery A. was on sui'able groud ample in size and laid out in accordance with regulations. There was no room for any drills except company, close order, in or near this camp. No permanent buildings. Camp on private land. Camp Rob ert A. Clapp. Second Infantry, was on poor ground, inadequate in size and therefore irregularly laid out. No room in or near this camp for any drills or maneuvers, except company drill in close order. This ramp was in an Epworth League Park having a number of permanent buildings, some of which were utilized by the troops. No regular troops participated in the encampment. H. In Camp Furnas, water was supplied by pij&gt;es from near by amusement park, but the supply proving insufficient, it was sup - planted by hauling water from the city mains. In Camp Clapp, the Epworth League Park water supply was used: in City Park Camp, the city water. All was of good quality and not boiled. In all camps garbage was deposited in galvanized iron eoYered cans and removed daily. Sinks dug on far side of camp from cook tents were used in First Infantry camp. In the Second Infantry camp, water closets of the permanent plant of the park were used. KKI»&lt;&gt;IJT OF MA.IOK IIAMKLII I.. How III.. 1HTH I". S. INKANTKY i:\&lt; AMI'MKNT. IW»7. October 22, 190 .S The Adjutant General. I arrived in Lincoln, Nebraska, August 16, lHn", :md after report- .riKir of the Suite, went into ramp at City Park, where hiter on, a company of the Hospital Corps, a company of the Signal ■ General Staff encamped 1. All organizations reached camp by rail on regular passenger Jlrecl from their home stations. The movement was lie adjutant General. Compan'w were taken from ramp bv street cars Details from each com- inl bacgage to prepare camp. Dtraining and detraining owing to methods During this encampment, from the 12th to the 17th of August, there were four separate camps: The Rifle Camp. Camp Robert W. Pumas, First Infantry and Battery A: Camp Robert A. Clapp. Second Infantry; City I'aik Camp, General Staff. Hospital and Signal Corps. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">RKl'ORT 49 A I TANT GENERAL ■&lt;1 All camps we whs us r i 4. KhaV: clothing and field equipment were taken into camp, No overcoats All clothing and equipment 1 iin Id atlil new. Rifles, except ii ■one loops subsisted on Army rations supplied by Chief Commis- he Mis-our :1 to Camp Com- sary Ht adquar ment of missaries by Chief Quartermaster and Commissary of &gt;ops, and prepared by company cooks. All company kitchens were inspected. Food was well cooked and t (1 rook i condit Guard mounting, company, battery, battalion drills, and dre let Ice march with shelter tents One si pitching had by First Regiment. One review of all toopa by Governor a ler. fair. Review xtended N mmediate steps to procure by pur - act of land for annual encampments I fficers and men were young and in good physical condition and enthusi- 1(1 A I id on the d neither observed or hen drunken- Men and offic. 1 at all times careful about saluting and 1 in ind was performed in a A however., that either li ted. Noncmmissioned officers have ifficers lad son it post duty, etc., in winter schools. li The only target practice held was that of the competitors Nebraska Rifle Team. The range was partly on state and tr tr .nu- o yards in length. Four targets. This ll pr l 1 answered its purpose fairly well. There range w il s rins; had &gt;ughly exercised in pointing and t Morning Report books. Sick Report books and Duty Rosters speaking, officers and men have little knowl- fficers and men have little knowl- edge of rfcdi-d keeping, ;md other paper work. 11. I was not asked to nive any pract'i nd other paper work. i otht edg I per w d to give any pract ; cal Instruction to troops I talked f'eely with the officers and made nv pract ; cal instruction to troops I Wi during the encampment. I talked freely with during the encampment. I talked freely with and made suggestions as I thought might be of use lu. The Nebraska Natloaal (luard c&lt;in?i ns as I thought might be of u might be of u National (luard consi-ts of two regiments of Nel I'll. infantry. i&gt;nc batten' '- fi'* 1 '! K»&gt;' s - muzzle i field Buns, muzzle-loaders I. one cjDmpanv field guns, muzzle-loaders I. one company infant 111! Signal Corps, one company Hospital Corps. One troop of cavalary i on paper only. These organizations are widely scattered throughout hi together only once a year, and then for a the state, and are brougr wance for armories, target ranges, ammunition. The Signal company is made up of a good lot of short time. The allow* etc., are inadt Lit GIC., ait' IUilUri|llclU. I I!*' .-Mf.ll.Il Vl.lll|/UU.. 1O uiu.lt l.J. •-. ». — — - young men and is capable of excellent work if properly equipped mpany is thoroughly equipped, well drilled, and 1 am sir. very respectfully. Your obedient servant. D. U HOWELL. Major lMh Infatry tisfactory 1*r. Nearlv all The Hospital ( «-fHrient. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">AD.IITA.Vr GENERAL!* RiJPOKl FIRST INFANTRY Fullerton, Nebraska, A i r»o SchvVMI Z. Adjuiiint General, Lincoln, Nebraska Sir: 1 have the honor to submit the following report of tin •ncampment of the First Regiment Infantry, N N &lt;;., as ordered ii G. O. No. 16, C. S lt*7, and arrived at the place 19H7 The camp was named I lei i in &gt; lionie station Augu Dated for the camp. Angus) Camp Robert Furnas The details ordered to report with the company baggage arrived ii schedule time and in part were able to pitch camp in a military manner, some of the company details seemed to have no idea of how tc commence to pitch a tent, and other details were not complete as or dered. These defects in the details caused a considerahle delay ir pitching tamp. The tents with the exception of one company, which was not or - dered to send their baggage in advance of the company were pitched Sunday evening. (August 11, liti'T.i The companies arrived in camp promptly Monday, as scheduled and were in good condition to go to work immediately. Verj little work was attempted Monday; company drill, guard mounting and battalion parade at retreat The work beginning with August 13, &lt; Tuesday i, was taken up a.-. described in Field Orders. I copy of which was sent to your office, and an endeavor was made to Ret the most food out of our limited time, and the limited ground* we had for drill. Company drill was taken up for a short time each day to steady the officers and men for the battalion and regimental drill in close and extended order that followed each day as we could get to it. Advance and rear guard and outpost duty was given attention also shelter tent camp was pitched by battalions. Not a great deal of time was spent on ceremonies Guard mount ■ b day at retreat, and one battalion parade each evening begin ning Monday wilh the Hist battalion, second Tuesday and third Wednes day. Thursday afternoon the regiment was paraded in line and reviewed by the Commander-in-chief, and staff. Friday afternoon 1 turned the command of the regiment over to Lieut. Col. Geg»er, and took command of the review of the Nebraska National Guard by Governor Sheldon. Commander-in-chief, and staff. With Lieut Col. Osborne. 2nd Regiment. N. N. G.. as Act Adj. the brigade. compoMd of the 1st and 2nd regiments of infantry, the Signal Cot pa, the Ambulance company and Battery "A", were formed in line of musses ""rl reviewer! bv the reviewing officers The encampment was of too short duration for a marked improve - ment in all lines. There was a great improvement in the execution of all drills in the field, but the subject of guard duty seemed to have been neglected by most commanders at their home stations and very little could be done in three days camp. NKHilAHKA -NATION A I, CU"AKI&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">ADJI TAXT tIKXKK.Vl.'S KKPORT 51 camp ;m«l the genera] sanitary conditions was &lt;■!•&gt;• jrood. The regimen! was fully equip|.ed for field service The ration;, and their preparation w;is first-class and »erj satis- ctory to all The general deportment of the men was Rood and they m pood class of vouni men and will ■««» va.v. ■ •• ;&lt; BOOd class of young men and will BTenge rather under twenty - ne yean of age. The camp was struck wiihoi h. it the Qmeral as the tentase was iinui wa k wiihoi the General as the tentase was (lamp and each company struck the The facilities for handling th« d each company struck th mp a i ir tents in time to reach their train. ir tents in time to reach their train. ■ hng—gin were pood and there was h, facilities for handling th ■ tmn» b* were good and there was DO trouble in getting all the compai lies inn of camp in plenty of time to lies out of camp in plenty of time to make their trains. Headquarters b«aage, Ike hi make their train II. dquarters l.a ■t to leave the tamp, left canip at Ijaspime was stored at the State to leave the (amp, left camp at ■'■ ]). ni., August I", l«)ii7. The baggage was stored at the State House and I returned to my home station tation Very respectfully. ./. A. STORC'H, Colonel 1st Inft. N. N. G Very respectfully, I A. STORCH </seg>
            <seg id="p052">AUJITANT C.EXERA1.S REPORT ( ; rand Total 96 »•« 10 365 142" STRENGTH OP THK NKBHASKA NATIONAL (ilAKI*. (AMP OF I.\STRl/(TIOX, LINCOLN, AKIIST 1(1-17, UM»7 Aggre- Present Absent K ate Com. Enl. Com. Knl. P. &amp; A 1st. Rest. Hdqtrs. 14 I ;; 23 Kand. 1 2 7 (g Company A If | Company H :: :: n 10 52 Company C 1 2 4 i i r, 4" Company D 2 .'!4 7 43 Company E 2 38 12 51 Company F 3 33 13 49 Company ('» 2 :::' 1; 411 Company H 2 ?,:, 1 J] ;,ii Company I I J7 21 (] Company K 1 II 2 23 4.". Company I, I JJ |g -. L&gt; Company M 2 SC 1 {3 (] Total 42 40t; :, 17;; ,-.26 2nd. Rep. Hdqtrs. ]4 8 1 |] Hand 1 2 7 company a :: :::, i:&gt; -,1 Company B SI 1 f,:. Company C 1 :!1 14 47 Coini&gt;any n 35 H 6« Company E :: 2S 1142 Company F .'! 31 in 4H Company Q 2 .'12 1 1(1 4.", Company H :: 3T&gt; ( 44 Company I 2 41 11 r,4 Company K I 27 IT 41 Company L 2 31 1 12 46 Company If I 41 1 |( 70 Total 46 4.~&gt;4 4 1 T, 7 fifil Battery A Battery A 2 27 1 12 4 2 Signal Corps .'{ 3 b 11 :,o Signal Corps Field Hospital .', Field Hospital 3 37 12 5 2 1 ,i </seg>
            <seg id="p053">ADHTANT GENERALS REPORT ((1ST OK (AMI 1 INHTBICTIOK, 19O7 Paid from Paid from Paid from li. ins of Expense Total State Total State I" Appr'n Appr'n Allotment Per Diem !i747. ."".!&lt; - 1452.70 Per Dk 747..~&gt;!f 3452.70 34 R. R. Transportation 4734. 6S J.K&gt; .7:: R. R. Transportation 4 7 .'. 4 ..",:, J^K. .7:: 251S 1 Wagon Transportation IIIS.'JJ IS.M -Subsistence IM7.CI Expense of Range . 1 ."&gt; 15#.1S Exiitnsf of Ranst' '. 1 ■"&gt; 350.15 Horses tit Hors Fuel and Forn 184 . &lt;• 1" 131 Fuel and Forage 284. m 4" Misrellaneous I . 4.', - 7'' Tota 1 7 IT :; 4 ..",7 6722 . In 10512 - </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 ADJUTANT KEXERAL8 REPORT ( &lt;&gt;\SOUI&gt;\TKI» RKPIIRT OK SI IINISTKM K ■wetvrri ami l&gt;s,,,.,l »t (an,,. ,,f Instruction. |.i n ,,.l,,. STORKS Nebraska. All "si 1 2 lo IT 11HI7 ISSUED it 7. r. No, of Ration £&amp; f I | 1 | - f n-f. it. r-r- .:: :r *"! tkKi '«• OH I'.!.". J.Il I ;,,. ssr-'ft he e s -a t-: , •wans ii. - , : ;*' * t: lt; |:&gt; - ISruns l}» !4ti - iai 43 lain, lli* il IN in III 1 l'.i in 1 w u i -«■'•'■■ lb». Mm "., ■: ".!'■' 'I .'- ' J4 Safar. Ibk i.m s " :i i&gt; ii inn ,„, :I;| 4 V -'; , i-" 11 4 Soap. Um I si Candl i -», 1-" I" 4n 13 Tomato, •-. ,•;,„- mm jut y^ :i o ,," . .,, TomaUn*. can* mm j, i4 .&gt; li4 .,., ." . -' asris i * i I | | | I'otati 1 ,1 H H t ii Salt. II In IVp|Hi- v. im-|f«r, ml .;,, | , ... ' . j* I I I) pap« Klmir. Him "•*?«' llls -"'i-i 2l« iV»i iir. i&gt;'&gt; UMi iir.-a.l. ll» ■MTBH. IDS ,1«1 L n; r j ,- )4 | I'oilct Caper, pkgs 2") " •&gt;;, l&lt;iil«-t I 'a per. pk^M 2o ■■-, '*'*! 1 ?.*r" w .i ** --'""" '""•" ;imi -" |(H&gt;&lt;( I"*"' ■••M'&lt;. Sy mw , ** 230*1 UniTil HUGH HUM Iikh i Tol;il Cost of SuhsisiiMii-c Skuvs. . », K ? Cori Per Ration &lt;&gt;M </seg>
            <seg id="p055">AOJCTAXT GENERALS REPORT WITH THK OIU.A\I7.KI&gt; MILITIA Ol NEIIKASKX INHPKtTION OK \. \. &lt;;.. IIM&gt;H. al organizations have had only desultory target practice, and spasmodii nltenipts have been made at gallery ptacii Neither ieginient is in condition to participate in any maneuver camp, and should not be sent to such camp until there has been some preliminary instruction for officers :&gt;nd drill for men. Company officers are Kenerally without field equipment Section lfc. Act of January 21. 19&lt;&gt;3. has been complied with KKPOKT &lt;&gt;l MA.IOK I.. l». ItAVISO.V r. S. A.. KKTIKKO. OX WT1 WAR DEPARTMENT. DIVISION OF MILITIA AFFAIR* WASHINGTON. N&lt; tvniber 1 !t. I Tin- Adjulani General. Stale of Nebraska, .Sir: -I Bin directed by tbe A^sislanl S of War to tranamil herewith extract* from the report! Bubmltted by uRcen of the arm&gt; who made the annual Inspections of tl sed Militia of Xebn in inns, with the dial il and eBI illy, B. M. WEAVER, Lieutenant Colonel, General S'aff Corps, Chief of Division. Extract* from reports of Inspection of the organised mili' . . ehraska. i \ i t » ii remarks of inspecting officer with regard ro condition of ih«- several organizations of the ptate for Tin- work of all departments is attended to in the Adjniam Gene- ral - iitliic No i&gt;t her corps or departments are organised]. The Guard is not at present admlnlatered either eArtenl economically, Inn plans are under i-onnlderation which it is \t&gt;\ will remedj theiie defect* In a Kreal me««nre. if not entli .1. There is practical!) no regimental organization or authority. Or- ders have beta isueil oi^anizins; the battalions of both regiments, bat little has been done Battalion staff appointments have not been con- tinued even where recommendations have been made Physical examination! of enlisted men have been instituted In one company There are no general facilities for target practice p to this time Members selected for title teams are ordered in to Lincoln for such practice as can be bad on a range thai has practically been abandoned as dansi'iiiib. An attempt will be made to hold target encampments b&gt; batallion daring the summer, and to secure suitable ranges. Individu- </seg>
            <seg id="p056">ADJUTANT GENERMV REPORT 56 Company D. Physical appearance of men, good. Character, very id. Zeal, lair t-j good. Efficiency, poor. About '&lt;» pe: t would probably turn rut in an emei - Firs'- Infantry. 'oinpany A. Physical appearance :md character, good: zeal, fair; ef- ficiency, poor: reliability in case of an cinerpMii ; , question- able. Aboal SO per cent would probably turn out in an emergency. There is lack of Interest manifested, due in a large nr»«s-- ■us- ure in lax End uncertain administration of ilie Guard as a a \. liiilc. The i:esi mill seem disinclined to join the company i r leinain in il long Discipline is not understood and instruction is prac- tically nil. what there la being Inexact and otherwise faulty. This company as it exists is not worth, either to the St. He or to the Nation, the time and money devoted to it. 'ompany I&gt;. Physical appearance and character of men good. Zeal. lair in good. Efficiency, fair. Reliability in case of emer- .\. poor; about |@ per cent would probably turn out in It is questionable wlic her the town is large enough to siipport more than a platoi n organisation. 'ompany c. Physical appearance and character of men, very good. Zeal. pood. Efficiency, fair. Reliability in case of emer- g&lt; my. poor: probably mi per cent would turn out in an emer- "&gt;. Th:s company has been reorganized during the month. tn the extent that it is actually a new company. The outlook ins good for maintaining a proper company here. It has had no target practice Thi; town is too small lo maintain a company or even an efficient platoon. Both for e2Bcl&lt; ncy and economy, this company should be Phyriial nd :'e;i! of men. fair. Character, fair to good. Effici* i:cy, poor to bad. Reliability in case of c mergency, questionable: aboat !" per cent would probably urn out in care of an emergency. It is evident that not the better element of ihe community is enlisted in this company. Discipline is n&lt;;t understood, and instruction i- had, worse than none. This eompanv should be mustered out of the service. The town is too small to maintain a company or even an effi- clent platoon. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">A.D.) ITA T GENERA REPORT Company K. PhjM.al appearance of men. good. Zeal, fair to good Efficiency, fair. Reliability in case of emergency, poor; Efficiency, fair. Reliabil about 60 per cent would probably lurn oui in an emergency. about 60 per cent would probably mrn out in an en It is questionable whether the town is large enough to support whether the town is large enough to support &lt;1 more than a platoon organization. aniz. Company G Physical appearance and character of men. poor to fair. Zeal, poor. Efficiency, bad. Reliability in n Company G Physical appearance and character of men. poor t&lt; Ya Efficiency, bad. Relial (emergency, not reliable; about 40 per cent would probably turn out Of the enlisted men pn one was drunk, and several were more or less in liquor. The officers seemed to have no proper realization of iheir dm ponsihilit ;• This company should be mustered out for the good of the service. le was drunk, and several were more or less in liquor. The no proper realization of their d itti ions This company should be mustered out for the good of th Company H. Physical appearance of men, fair to good. Character, good. Zeal. fair. Efficiency, poor. Reliability in c:, emergency, questionable: about 4n per cent would probably I emergency, questionable: about 4n per cent woti'd probably turn out. Apparently interest is not well sustained. The better class of young men do not seem to remain but prefer to join the local band. The town is not large enough to maintain a company or even an efficient platoon. Both for efficiency and economy this company should me mustered not. Company I. Physical appearance and character of men. fair to good. Zeal. fair. Efficiency, poor. Reliability in case of emer - gency, questionable, about 40 per cent would probably turn Apparently interest is not well sustained. The better nen do not seem to remain but prefer to join ke local band. The town is not large enough to maintain iipany or even an efficient platoon. Both for efficient and economy this company should me mustered not and character of men. fair t" Co I. Pt iippearar Zeal. fair. Efficiency, pom*. Reliability in case of em cent would probably turn ■ out in an emergency. Interest is not well sustained, men not all of the better class. The town is not large enough to in an emergency. Interest is not well sustained, men The town is not large enough to maintain a company or ev n an efficient platoon Both for efficiency and economy, this company should Company K. Physical appearance and character of men. good. Zeal. fair. Efficiency, poor. Reliability in case of emergency, ques nt would probably turn out. There ■i ;i lack of ir tBT was mustered out as a light battery and auized as an infantry company. The better el men in the town do not seem to cart; to be identified with ny. The town is hardly large enough to maintain a possible that an efficient platoon organization nil might be maintained in conjunction with one at un adjacent </seg>
            <seg id="p058">t'ami Company I f i ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT I.. Physical appearance and character ot men. good. Zc fair to good. Efficiency, fair. Reliability j n eMC of domest Nrr— d liir.niii.t . Hand Physical and Reneral appearance, character and efficient Rood. Zeal, fair lo good. Reliability in case &lt; • t i-m fair as a band! about so pet an emergency. This band si mililan band lent would probably turn j nis to fill the reqiiir.-men nt mipany ■quired lo ca the hand in its stiengtr i&lt;&gt; that the band may h wha considered a sufficient number of met No gallery or target practice. A. Physical appearance and character irf men. good nd efficiency, fair. Reliability in ease of emergency bout :.ii per cent would probably turn out in an erne With better administration, an efficient company ml maintained here. B. Physical appearance and chars men. miiiil and efficiency, fair. Reliability in case of emergency, |«)O iibout 60 i«'i cent would probably respond to a call \Y better administration, an efficient company might b. in. i lained here, six of the reported absentees of this con upar were present with the Band. No target practice C. Physical appearance, character, and zeal of men, good Efficiency and reliability in case of emergency, fair; :ibou SO per cent would probably respond lo call. A company might be maintained here; the prospects are good. D. Physical appearance and character of men, good. Ze;&gt; efficiency, and reliability in case of emergency, fair; about ■?• per cent would probably respond to call. The attendauct at inspection was small, but those present were good. An efficient platoon is about all that can be hoped fo under the circumstances. pmergeacr, poor; a bom 5« per cent would probably tun out. Discipline and instruction show a slackness in detail! No tar«et practice. M Physical apa««nwee and character &lt;&gt;r bmb, (air to tool Seal, fair. Efficiency, poor to bad. Reliability in emergency, questionable: about |« per eeal would probabl] lurn out. The better element of i be community is not interested ii I his company. Discipline is not understood and there is no instructioi worthy of the name. Xo target practice Roth for ef7iciency ;,nd economy, this company shouli; ie mustered Oil I </seg>
            <seg id="p059">A D.I I r.WT (JEXERALS RKl'ORT ■■•■■•■ ..,,.,„,, ,,, [U en, goca. unan I. Zeal, fair to pom Efficiency, noor. RpU.hin... . —.".. mmm., i.m 10 poor Kmclency. poor. Reliability i-i ease of emergency, anestioaable; about 36 per cent would iii.se of emt probably res) ,1 to a .-all. lateral U at ■ very low ebb Mil better class of m in Ike community evidently not Included &gt;n inanity evidently not included Ib.- town is too small to maintain a company or .■ven an effici- Ilie town ven an effii ent platoon. Both for . fficiency and .-. ..ik.ii, inpain should nr i fficieiicy and n-oBoai itmpan li«' mustered oat. X« target pmi P. Physical appearance and character of men. good Zeal Zt and efficiency, fail Reliability in case of emergency, poo, in ■my. poor About mi per cent would probably respond to .-, , al | About mi per rein would pond to a call. Ar efficient cnmpain might he maintained here. tained h U. Physical appearance and clia: „„.„ G. Physic Zeal and effi. ie,,,y. fair. Reliability in ,, 1M . ot ' dome- domes "'■ '■""■w'H-.v. po«r: about s,, pe r ,,.,,, w (1 probabl , respond to a call. In streii.mh iliis compain would Diaki Platoon Sufficient Interest seems to be I platoon. Suffi build organisation up t&lt;, proper strength. There is a notic slackness in details lhat ought not .,, ,. xis , | n ;m ol(1 ,„ i ;u zatinii. If not recruited to prope, urengtb. tbii company should If no design lie designated a platoon i,, i onnectton with M.nie adj n &lt; ompany. \'o target practice. H. Physical appearance and zeal &lt;,r m.i,. Ku od. Character &lt; o in pan \&lt; H. Hh very good. Kfiiciencv. lair io good. Reliability in ,■,- very good. Kffi.ien.v. fair io Hood. Reliability in face ol emergtncy, fair: about sn per cent would probably respond iuergtn to a call. With better administration, an efflciem con.pam in pan might be maintained here. The prospects an- excellent. I. Physical app. arance and character ul men. good. Zeal, migh Xrellen I. Physical appearance and &lt; fair. Efficiency, and reliability haiacter of men. good. Zeal fair. Kfficiency. and reliability i,, case of emergency, poor about To per cent would probably respond to a call. Suffici- about To per cent would probably respond to a call. Suffici ent int.. rest seems to be lacking to hold the man... „„ ,,, to hold the company up t, proper strength. There is in evident lack of enre iu in- structions and detail* If not recruited up to proper strength, this company n and joined to an organization should be designated a platoc adjacent. No target practice </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Oiniiiiii C'nmpa 1 I'l Company ADJl'TAXT GENERAL REPORT K. Physical appearance and character of men, fair. Zeal and efficiency, poor. Reliability in case of emergency, ques - tionable: about SO per cent would probably respond to a call. The better element of the community does not appear to be interested in the company. Discipline is not understood and instruction is poo:, — all wrong. Both for efficiency and economy, this company should be musten I.. Physical appearance of good. Zeal. poor. Ufficieiu emergency, bad; about SO p to a call. It is evident that miinity is not intersted in the thai the Interest had eve- li m t understood and instruct!) pea red to be demoralized. men, fair. Character, fair to bad. Reliability in case of cent would probably respond v the better element of the com- company. There is no evidt •en much better. Discipline is n is bad. The organization ap- mustered out of the service Physical appearance and f men, good. Zeal and efficiency, poor. Reliabili tionable. About 4n per cent call. Interest it at a low ebb; nmnity. No gallery practice; lar drill hall. y in case of emergency, ques - would probably respond to a not the best men in the com - 10 accommodations. No regu- Company should be must r efficiency and economy. 1 (Hit of the serviie, both Field Hn-pil ;il. pearance of men, very good Character and zeal, good it y in case of domestic emer Efficiency, lair to good. Reliat n consists of a fine appearing : and business like. Their body of young men. inti IHgei drill and such floor tests as J be given in first aid well conducted, showin d continued stmction No gallery or target pi tic fa Signal Corn earame. character, and zeal of men. good. Efiiciencv, fair so far as it was possible to judge. Reliability in case of ergtney, fair; about mi per cent would probably respond to a call. Th ; s organization consists of a fine appearing body of young men. intelligent and business like. It was impossible lest their efficiency in signaling This company should b gancjr, fair to good. About 80 per rent would probab spond to a &lt;all. This organizati No gallery or target practice, no facilitu </seg>
            <seg id="p061">ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S REPORT 61 REPORT OK BOttJEOX GENERAL, LIBIT. ( ■()!,. V. S. NICHOLSON. one kitchen, was an innovation and, while it has its good features, I would recommend in future, a return to the individual company kitchen and mess, on account of the battalion bm being rather unwieldy and harder to keep running smoothly. The water, white pure, was largely impregnated with sulphur and iron salts, which made it objectionable to some on account of its odor, taste, and color. This could be easily remedied I believe by driving the wells deeper, and I would recom - mend that this be done before another camp. In case this site should be made a permanent campground, I would recommend the installation of a sewerage system or the sinking of per - manent cement lined sinks, the former of which would be flushed out and the latter pumped out at frequent intervals. A very good feature of this camp was the shower bath tent, which was fairly well patronized and would have been more so, had it had a separate tank in which the water for the shower could have stood during the day exposed to the suns rays, and become somewhat warmed be - fore being used; as it was, however, the tank was a small one, and the water in it had to be replenished at frequent intervals thus making it almost too cold for comfort. KX( WMI'MKXT TAIMJKT, UMWi. Bt Paul, Nebraska, August 29, IX The Adjutant General. Lincoln, Nebraska. Sir: — I have the honor to submit the following report of the en- campment held at the State Rifle Range. Ashland, Nebraska, Jul to August 1 !i. 1 »ii\. As will he seen by referring to the attached report of the field Hospital the sickness in camp was practically nil. most of the stom- ach and bowel troubles being produced by indiscretion in eating and drinking on part of the men. We had feared that the third proridoaal battalion would hare more sickness than the two preceding battalions, on account of con- tamination of soil, etc., but as the event proved, these fears were groundless, which speaks weli for the sanitary methods pursued dur- ing the earlier periods. The food furnished the ni&gt; n was Ike bcart of Ml kind that could be purchased, and gave no cause for complaint. The plan of having the food for the whole battalion prepared in </seg>
            <seg id="p062">ADJTTAXT CKNKK * U K I'ORT SUtf Kill.- Ranee at Ashland furnished a thor I ihr suitability of ihc ground for a permanent k r.iUK.. iind ctlB| The soil itself is round an ideal one from a unitary point of view. beiu&gt;, - r.-foif tic- from mud. dampness. He.; while the hich ii is covered makes it &lt;1i.:.mi, ...,.i ;__ ._ nd tin nod «ii| i makes it cleanly and pleasing tr h. Should tin. sit. 1 made a per manenl ramp-around I would recon nouKh lo one side of the rille-iaiu to remove them from ,ill danger of i ray bullets from tli rang As a rendevons t Ashland one of ihc me st the state, and a careful computation f the mileage from the different ' ; ' ! ' "" '••■'• 1 •■M'-i&gt;ive locations in the .UU for an 'encamp n Very Respectfully, FRANK S. NICHOLSON, Ill* &gt; . I 1 1 1 j ■ , 1 I I ) "" ■"- Purcfcm* ,,t eao.rt ,,„„,. )and s(1 tha , Ih(Jre wou]f] am '^ ice for two u^n,.,,,.. .ml to allow (lf ,(,,- toita M M .mrhed far &gt;!■ tin- different companies &lt;&gt;r the guard nil paints in thi- «Ute. and ;i .•iin.fnl ,-, home -unions of companies, shows Colonel and Burgeon Oenera </seg>
            <seg id="p063">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S RKI'ORT KKfOItT OK MUST MM T. JOHN K. SI'KAI.M \\. MKI.I1 IIOSI'I T Al. n. I had seventeen euli-ted men and during the tour of the ::rd Provisional Battalion 1 had eleven enlisied men of the Hospital Corp: I pitched only one hospital tent as this was thought to be sufficient which proved correct as the niosi patients we had at any one tini During thi' tour of the 1st Provisional Battalion there was rt ived onh one man in the hospital, Joseph Kottal. Co. I.. 2nd who was uffering from severe pain and some swelling over the l?ft mastoid Remained in the hospital two days and was then returned to command During llie lour of the 2nd Provisional Rattalion there were eight patients. Six of these wire cases of stomach and bowel trouble, one of heart trouble, and one of inflammation of Ihe right inguinal glands One of these cases of stomach and bowel trouble was the citizen cook from the Headquarters mess. During the tour of the :ird Provisional Battalion there were re - ceived eight patients, tkrea cases of stomach and bowel trouble, one heat prostration, one with puss-pocket in left forearm three inches below the elbow, one of fever and chill, one injured shoulder from wrestling match, and one alcoholic. The heat prostration was caused by drinking ice cold drinks just before going to drill in the hot sun The case of fever and chills was George McConnell. Pvt. Co. 1. 16th V. S. A. As he had very strong symptoms of Typhoid Fever he was sent to the post hospital at Ft. Crook on Aug. IS. All cases of stomach and bowel trouble gave a history of having paU'oni/.ed the Canteen for pop. etc. TAIUJKT K\&lt; AMI'MKNT. UH)H. STATK RIKI.K RANOE, / Aahlnnd. Nebraska, Aue. 19. IMI. \ 'ol. K. S. Nicholson. Siii«hiiii Qencral, X. X. ('■. Sii : [ have the honor to make the following report of the Kielc -ioapltal Detachment, and i!s work while on duty ai the Stale Kiflc iaime. near Ashland. Nebraska, July L'u to Ausnsl 1!). I»«X. I reached the .Stai ( - Rifle Kaniie al ii:;ii a. m.. July 2'» with ful qui]).m i.t (I htld Hospital for etghteea lied-patients and with flfteer neo of tin Hospital Corps. Daring the tour Of the 2nd Provisional </seg>
            <seg id="p064">AD.M'TAN'T CEXKRAL'S REPORT 64 Ill ;ill there were seventeen cases cared for in the Hospital, classi- I ill lows: ;ill thpre were »eveateen cases follows: Stomacb and bowel 9 ii Suspirioned Maitoldltii 1 i&gt;l Heart trouble 1 Hea Inflammation of inguinal glands 1 Heal prostration 1 proRt ration Pus-pocket 1 I'us-i Chills and fever i typhoid I 1 Chi Injun to shoulder 1 Ali-ol 111 ■ companies having men in the hospital were as follows ith r. s. a Co. I ( inf l Co. II Inf 1 Co. I t Inf. si Inf 1 1 Co. M 2nd Inf .'nd Inf. 1 Co.n 1 i'ii C, 2nd Inf 1 CO. K Co. II ml Inf 1 1 nd Inf nd Inf Co U Citizen 1 parate ( Cook . . I 1 Total IT T here were two commissioned. 14 enlisted, and one citizen rook uneiit in the hospital. Total 17. receiv Respectfully JNO. F. SPEALMAN 1st Lieut. Field Hospital Detachment. N. N'. ( </seg>
            <seg id="p065">AairTAXT GENERAL'S REPORT ME1«OKT OF MI.K1I! «EO. A. EBERLY. 1ST BEGIMEXT INFANTRY, TAIMiET KN« AMPMKNT, 19O8 HEAnQUARTERS 3RD BATTALION, t tanton. Nebraska. Sept. 17, 1908. ( Adjutant Genet (Through Military Channels Lincoln. Nebraska Pursuant to the dlreettoni contained in your communication of September 11, requiring this undersigned "To furnish this office a report in writing." on the recent tour of duty at the State Rifle Range, near Ashland. Nebraska, under G. O. No. 4, and also "To give recom - mendations for carrying on future camps of the same nature, point out the good things as well as bad. in this Camp, with suggestions for the obviation of the bad," 1 have the honor to submit the following: On the 19th day of July, I reported for duty to the Adjutant General at the State Rifle Range near Ashland. I was accompanied by 1st Lieutenant Howard H. Antles. Battalion Adjutant. Lieutenant W. E. Kelso. Hattalion Quartermaster and Commissary, and Battalion Sergeant Major Walter G. Sonnenschein. The responsibility of com - mand was divided. The "General direction of troops" was retained by General Headquarters: all matters of instruction and practice was committed to Captain C. W. Hundel 10th Infantry V. S. and Lieutenant L. R. James; Lieutenant Colonel Birkner was assigned to duty as Chief range officer and officer in charge; and the undersigned assigned to the "immediate command of the troops. After consulting with Cap - tain Buudel. Lieut. Jum and Lieut. Col. Birkner a list of service calls was adopted for the tour of duty ending July 29. Detachments from the following organizations reported for duty during the 2nth. viz. Company B. D. E. F. and L of the First Regiment and Companies E. I, K. M. of the Second Regiment and also detach - ments from the Signal Corps and from the Field Hospital. Owing to the delay in handling the baggage and tentage Company B. 1st Regi - ment did not arrive at camp until late in the evening and wire compel - led to sleep in shelter tents. Their tentage was not transported to camp until the next forenoon. Lieutenant Col. B'rkner had the Camp laid out prior to the ar ival of the first companies and was established practically as planned Only two men from Co. ( : 2nd Regiment reported for duty and they were assigned to Company I.. 1st Regiment. Five provisional Com - panies were organized and scator officers with each placed in charge of the same. * The first problem presented to the "Commander in immediate i harge of the troops " was that of subsistence. A consolidated mess was organized. By authority of General Headquarters two cooks were en - gaged at |t.M and $4. mi per diem respectively, the mess was orga - nized and so far as the preparation of the food was concerned, the question was practically solved. And from the noon meal on the 21st </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT &lt;if July to the close of the tour of duty no serious complaints were made as to the food served either as to quality or quantity. This con - dition was largely due to the untiring zeal of Lieutenant Kelso. who with the means at hand, certainly accomplished wonders. The duties devolving upon the Provisional Battalion Headquarters were almost wholly administrative The exactions of the Range Officer were such as to preclude drills and in some instances prevented '•Guard Mount" and the proper service of the ni' The sole exception to the statement that the duties of the "Com - mander in immediate charge of the Troops" were wholly administra - tive, are that he officiated as commanding officer at one dress parade, one inspection, one assembly of the Battalion for "Setting up Exer- " and by special permission took charge of the instruction of cer tain enlisted men. who after firing two or more scores at two hundred three hundred and five hundred yards failed to secure a total at al rangers (it sixty-three or better. At the request of the undersigned details of non-coniniissioned officers were furnished by Company I 16th U. S. Infantry, and the "«3" class were given four drills in tripod exercises and also in position and aiming exercises. I am informed that h majority of those in the "6S" class showed considerable improvement and in some instances the improvement was decidedly marked. At least one of this class qualified as marksman 1 believe it but fair ti hat the expcM-iment certainly established the value of the prelimi nar&gt; exercises. Copies nf i rden aa issued were promptly transmitted to "General Headquarters and their contents will not lie re-capitulated in thi. - report. The tour of duty rlosed on the ttth of July. The several organ! /.ations entrained for their home stations as directed by orders issued a &lt;ien&lt; ral Headquarters, some at Ashland and some at the "switch." Thi management of transportation was entrusted to Lieutenant W. E. Kels&lt; and 1 believe it is but fair to say that he "made good." The undersigned desires to acknowledge his indebtedness to the Adjutant General for kind and courteous treatment extended during tne tour of duty, to Captain Bundel and the members of Headquarter's Staff for their many helpful suggestions, and to Adjutant Antles Quartermaster Kelso and Sergeant Sonnenschein for their faithful ser vices during the progress of the encampment. One feature of the camp was decidedly marked. There was almosr a total absence of drunkenness. Not a single guardsman was placed in arrest during my tour of duty. There were no trials by summary court or otherwise, during the period of my command. The most important qualification of a Guardsman, is familiarity with the rifle and ability to "shoot It straight." A "Target Camp" tends to advance the efficiency of the "Guard" as a whole in this important particular. The matter of target practice has heretofore certainly been somewhat neglected. Those, whose situation or location prevented pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">ADJITANT GKNERALS REPORT 67 1»er instruction at their home station, had heretofore been deprived of instruction in certainly what is an essential in a soldiers qualification A target camp is therefore certainly to be commended. The camp was certainly fortunate in having as a part of its mem - bership Captain C. M. Bundel and Lieut. L. R. .lames of the L". S. army and their command. The relation existing between the enlisted person - nel of the Gauard and of the Regular detachment was so far as I ob - served excellent. Almost without exception, the quality of the ration furnished was ;ood: and. in quantity, all that was desired. Even coffee which I un- ierstand was objectionable at General Headquarters, when prepared by our cooks merited no complaints. The supply of water was ample and quality was certainly of the best Now as it is made my duty to pare results atained in the I)istri&lt; tained in our own Camp point out defects. I will briefly com t of Columbia with the results at- The D. C. Tour of duty on th» Rifle Range commenced May ."&gt;, ours July 2( In the D. C. the tour of du range: with us ten days. fur each man was two days on the The D. C. qualified as marksmen or 1 Nebraska qualified as marksmen or better in a ten days tour of rtuty under my command, hut:!- 1 , I am creditably informed through the public press that the per - centage of those qualifying in tours subsequent to my own was even less than the percentage attained in the one I commanded. If we go still further into the results we find that the D. C. team secured something like ninth place, while Nebraska team had to be content with thirty-eighth place, at the National Competition at Camp Perry. To approximate the State of Nebraska paid for five times more than the D. C. did in per diem and received one-half less, to put it mild. I do not care to go into details in the matter of criticising that which did not pertain to my department. I will say however that the work should be carefully planned for the entire year. Companies hav - ing ranges at their home stations should be encouraged to use them. They should receive competent instruction at their home station. Omaha and Lincoln and neighboring companies not having home ranges could be conveyed to Ashland for their Company practice in April and May after having received the preliminary work in January. February and March. A brigade encampment could be held at Ashland in July where contests between companies and Company teams could be shot on the range, and fie members of our next team to the National Competition receive pr«pfr instruction and practice to take a position somewhat higher up thr line than heretofore. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT I would further recommend the construction of a »qu_re "Cook House", in the event Battalion Camps are to be continued with a con - solidated mess. These to be made ofmatched lumber and screened, a portion of CMk side to be detachable so that when these portions of the four sides were removed four lines of men could be served simultane - ously. In this way the time necessarily consumed in serving mess could be reduced to the minimum. 1 would further recommend that Company organization be pre - •d intact, us necessary to the preservation of proper discipline. ] would also recommend that the provision of our statute to the effect that "No member of the Nebraska National Guard will be excused from attendance (at camp of instruction) except upon Surgeon's certificate of disability or dangerous sickness in the membership of such family be so far as possible strictly enforced. Respectfully submitted. G. A. EBERLY Major 1st Infantry. N N. G KKIHUtT Of MAJOR K|{KI&gt; .1. MACK. 2X1) IXFAXTRV. N. \. O. TARGET ENCAMPMENT, I»OH. Albion, Nebraska, August 15, 1908 Adjutant General C F. Schwarz. Lincoln. Nebraska Sir: - 1 have the honor to report, that on .Tuy 31. 1908, pursuant to orders, 1 reported at the State Rifle Range near Ashland. Nebraska, with my staff. August l. lSiis. I assumed command of the Camp, and on said last mentioned date, the Companies assigned to the Provisional Battalion which 1 had the honor to command, reported for duty. I found the camp in excellent condition, and the grounds especially adapted for the work outlined, which was largely target practice. The organizations comprising the Battalion entered into the spirit of the work with zeal and I was greatly impressed with the degree of interest taken by both officers and men in target practice. A general mess was established for the enlisted men, and I con - sider the same a success, although the same could be improved upon if the State owned the grounds, and would construct permanent store rooms and mess halls thereon. Guard mount and Battalion Parade were had each day during the tour, and at such times as the men were not engaged on the range. Company and Battalion drills were had. I wish to commend the officers and men of the Battalion for the efficient assistance rendered in preserving perfect order, through polic - ing and otherwise in making the came a success. August 10, 1908 as ordered, camp was broken, and the companies entrained for their respective home stations. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">AD.UTANT GENERALS REPORT 69 I do not hesitate to liionuunce the camp a success; the officers and men with whom I conversed were unanimously of the opinion that target practice, not only increased the efficiency of the Gunrd, but that it interested the men to a greater extent than the duty prescribed for for the past several yeais for the Guards of the stae, i. e.. drills, at close and extended order, practice marches and problems. I would recommend that target practice be made largely the pro- gramme for the future camps I recommend that both regiments be encamped at the same time- on the same grounds used this year, that the range be extended to in eluded at least twenty-four targets: that the regiments alternate daily on the range; that the regiment not en duty on the range be engaged in regimental and battalion drill In order to eliminate confusion, possible accident and to obtain the best results generally, I would recommend that an efficient Range Officer like Cclonel Birkner be given absolute command of the range, that he requisition daily the Commanding Officer for the men and offi - cers needed by him on the Range, both for duty in the pitts and for target practice; that however his authority cease off the Range. I have the honor, sir, to be yours respectfully, F. J. MACK. Major 2nd Infantry. N. N. G KKI'OKT OK MAJOIt H. i. PAUL INFANTRY, X. X. G TAKCJKT ENCAMPMENT, 1008 t Paul. Nebr., December 7, 1908 Adjutant Genera Lincoln, Nelir 1 have the honor to make the following report of command of State Rifle Range, near Ashland. Nebraska. of General Orders No. 4. I. with my staff, re ported for duty at State Rifle Range on August S. IMS, and assumed command of same on August Id, l!&lt;ns. From their view point the men give to the state all their time dur 2. Found camp ground in good condition, everything having been thoroughly policed and inspected under command of Major Fred J. Mack, commander cf second peiiod. 3. I have always been an advocate of camps being held away from the cities and am of the opinion that, from a moral standpoint, this is cne of the 1» st eampa ever held within the state, but seriously doubt if the interest of the men would ever take them back to another like it. as since the (amp, I ha.e learned from the men that there was general dissatisfaction in regard to the following: The camp was located too far from a town or city where the men cculd go for pleasure after the days work was over. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">AUJl'TANT GENERALS REPORT 70 ing the year and receive nothing for it, and about ihe only thins that keeps any of them In the Guard is the thought thai they will derive some pleasure from the annual encampment which they claim they did not do at the one near Ashland. The battalion mess was not a success for the reason that capab looks could not lie obtained to do the work in the time granted for caring the same and for ihe reason that the men were all so bitterly op posed to doing the detail work in the kitchens, all of which could 1&gt;&lt; eliminated by hiring civilian help to relieve the men of this detail work in«l by announcing the time of the camp at least two months ahead of lime, and by publishing what was or would be expected of the con mandlng officers that lhe&gt; miijht have ample lime I &gt; secure capahl&lt; ooks lo do the work It seems to lie the opinion of the men. and most of th officers, that the way of mobilizing the troops. regardleaii of organii: lion as was done at this camp, is very detrimental in as much as all Major Commanding -ml ivriod Lincoln. Nebraska. Sept. 7. 19 The Adjutant General. Lincoln. Nebiaska Sir. I have the honor to submit the following report of the worl done at the State Rifle llauge near Ashland. Nebraska from July 15 190S to August 19. INI while on duty as Range Offlcer. In compliance with S. O. No. 11. A. G. O.. July g, 19ns. I proceeded to Ashland July 1&gt;, 19us. u&gt; prepare the ground selected for the Stat«&gt; Rifle Range. 2 l-l miles N. E. of Ashland, Ne.br. The grounds are on Ihe west side of the Platte river on the farm of Mrs. M. J. Rose, con - sisting of the so-called Rose Island, an old bed of the Platte river. havp an Interest in their personal organizations and take pride in tr&gt; - inn to make ii ■'the brat" and. personally, I am iif the opinion that the reKiim'iital commanders should have been placed in command of their mpectlvp regiments. t. The urnuads are ideal Rinandi for rille praciice and by taking a regiment there at a lime nun h could lie done as there would be ample time for regimental, imitation and company drill aside from the work done on I he rifle range and this would take up more of the men's lime thus eliminating a Rival deal of objection made ■boat I heir be- ing loo BlUrb time in whirl] tin re was nothing in do ■V In case there is to lie another ramp in which rille practice is t be ihe main feature. I would respectfully recommend that civilians b. employed to do the work in the pits, as this would sir* all the M better chance to yei their lull share of practice and I think would Kiw more even and fairer marking* Respectfully submitted. H. .1. PA1I.. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">AILM-TAXT GENKRALS REPORT 71 &gt; which had been closed by a dyke erected by the C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co. In order to transfer the Platte river bed further east and thereby protect the approaches of the railway bridge on the C. B. &amp; Q. Ry. to Omaha. about 2 miles east of Ashland. A map of the Grounds is hereby at- tached, which has been surveyed and measured by myselt and l.leu been furnished the Quartermaster Department V. S. A., by I.ieut. L. R lames with his report The camp Grounds and Rifle Range include the old river bed ami ■ pasture of very sandy soil, in places entirely bare and full of sand dunes. Rose Island as shown on th* map could be partially used to an advantage as Camping Ground. The first day after my arriv; necessary teams, scrapers and men was consumed in procartmg t hi transport the necessary lumber i-cond day work was commenced the place of construction. On tin 10 transform tin- dyke into a rifle I'i and Butt by placing post ipart for the langth of |»o feel m north side of the dyke, backing ichoring the posts With wire rope? Ming in the space with sand, whicl over the top of the dyke, and then I I' ' was dragged by scrapers from the n th end of Rose Island. A sketch of the work as done is herewith i h&lt;-d. Tii- i prepared al - ■get frames IS feet from center to lowed the placing of \ Aiken steel •enter of targets As the w hoi work had to be done in sand and with sand the posts had iipeded the workings in the pit afterward The Range occupied the old rivet bed as far back as th yard firing poll f I'm- being about 6 degrees East of th Magnetic North I have the river as backstop. AboiH 1-2 mile up the river a part of an unsurveyed island in the river prc jected in the line of fire, farther up the Platte river served as backstop for nearly :; miles The range was perfectly safe and Do stray or ricochet bullets could possibly strike or do any harm to any inhabita- tion or any farmland in the neighborhood. The range is an ideal range for Military ride practice and perfectly saf The firing points at ■&gt;«&lt;&gt;. 300 and 509 yards had to be graded anil raised to allow the men to lay on dry and even ground. The tiring- points at SOU to liniti yards were located in the sand&gt; part of the pasture with loose and rough sand runs, very uncomfortable for the men to lay on but time did not permit any more improvements. On the second day, I had also two wells sunk on the Camping Grounds, which both furnished an ample supply of good and healthy water for drinking purposes and at the one point a pumping station and shower bath tent were erected There were also dug three Latrines, which were enclosed b&gt; wooden frame shanties and covered with board roof The grounds and range were ready for occupation and us* on Monday, July 20, 190S. On rTiis day the first provisional Battalion !.,. R. James, Co. I, ltith IT. S. Infantry. U. S. A., of which a copy ha* ihe posts with inrh braced with 4x4 braces to preve iviiiK in. whi&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p072">ADJITANT GENERAL'S RKPORT arrived and went into camp. On July 2 9 the second Battalion changed with the flist and on Auk. 10 the third Battalion changed with the sec - ond. As the new Springfield rifles had to be issued to the troops after arrival in camp, each Battalion lost one day of rifle practice. From .luly 21 to August M, 19'iv when the last troops had de - parted, the range was continually used for rifle practice with the exception of the days the troops changed, and all organizations were made to shoot at least twice, some even three times through the marksnitu course at 109, :idii and 5un yards, firing two scores at each point A pord deal more time could have been used for shooting but as the supply of target frames was limited to only one set for each target, the changing frcm one target to anoher always consumed several hours as the frames had to be repasted every time. All the men shooting leceived all possible instruction, Capt. Bundel and Lieut. I-. R. James of the 10th I'. S. Infantry devoting most of their time on the range for that purpose, and furnishing a detail of experienced men to each firing point daily for instruction and also details to the Pit for inst:uctic-n in proper marking of the targets. With this excellent help he range officer could insruct all the men in the intricacies of Target Practice, as sighting, use &lt; f the sling, proper position and the theories and use of windage and elevation, under the vatious conditions. The troops si 1 1 showed a great interest and did earnest work and a great deal of worthy rivalry was created. The efficiency of the troops was gratifying, nearly 50 per cent qualifying as marksmen, a number as sharpshooters, and some as ex pert riflemen, as the annexed report of target practice shows. Out o the best marksmen all who scored ISC points or mere were given an opportunity to try for a place on the Nebraska Team and during the last few days, all those men were given an opportunity to shoot on the long ranges. SO0 and lOofl yards and timed fire at 200 yards and skirmish runs. The men scoring the 12 highest scores constituting the members of the team, the next three highest being he alternates on the team. This being the first rifle camp ever held and being an experiment It certainly proved a success and will greatly improve the status of the Nebraska National Guard. e e A good many points have been learned which require improve ment f( llowing recommendations are respectfully submitted for (oatlr'rtatlop. The ground should be acquired by the state as soon as poetible : rd If &lt; -on verted into a permanent Camp Ground and Rifle Range The temporary work in the Pitt and butts should be immedi ately improved and made permanent by erecting a concrete wall as shown in the attached sketch, the length being extended to allow the </seg>
            <seg id="p073">ADJITANT GENERALS REPORT placing of at least 2 4 target frames, the firing point should be improved and graded, and the whole ground be sowed in blue grass to avoid the impediment of the loose sand. At the next camp an abundant supply of target frames should he provided to allow a rapid change from one target to another. For marking in the Pit, a Civilian Service Corps should be provided and trained to insure bettt- r marking and allowing the troops to devote their whole time to practice shooting and not be compelled to furnish tire - some details for the Pit and marking. If the range is so improved, it would permit the calling of at least one regiment or the whole brigade into camp for maneuver and target practice and the men could get a longer period for target practice ■without any more expense. Respectfully submitted. .1 M BIRKNER. Lieut. Col, Range officer </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 ADJITANT GENERALS REPORT ii K M. i AgRT I ■ &lt;Sc \ I • 6 1 I 4 t ts»i KTRKMJTH OF THK XKBKASKA NATIONAL, Gl ARD State Hiflt- KaiiK&lt;&gt;. Ashland. July 2O-Au|(ust 19, 1908. I'r.-s^nt Absent 111 oni Knl ) 1 4 44 :i \ ! 1 is i&gt; iny m 4" K. A II v I lanv ( ai 24 K 11 liny F ft II t J Hi II V i 'oni|&gt;Hiiy I ::i m|tany I. l'oni|&gt;auy .\! otal 34* i Sept. Co l 14 if) Sf'in. Co. il Sept. Co. ?n;il Corps eld Hospital -di&lt;-;il I&gt;«-;&gt;t ■n« ral Staff 28 16 I 4 (irnn.l Total S4 I* ■9 Coni I lal Kes'i. Hdffirs in roniiiany A 1 c iniiuinv li 4 Company &lt; :; Company I&gt; t'oni|iany K :: ( "»&gt;ni [t.'iny F Company &lt;; I o!ii|iany H i°oni|mnj I &gt; K Company I ('oni|iany k &lt; 'oil! lr.m\* I. 73S </seg>
            <seg id="p075">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S RKI'ORT CDS! OK KIH.I-: ('AMI'. 1IMIM J'iiid from I'aid froi Total State r. s Aiipr'n Allotuit 112.4:: 2.889.O7 1J.2 1::.: 1 .' 1'er Dip R. R. 7 42H Misoella Itemi of Kxi&gt;ei Wagon Trans|iortat Kxpense of Rang? Rent of Range </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S REPORT OOXSOI.II&gt;ATKI&gt; KKI'OKT OF SlllSISTF.X&lt; K STOKKS KKCKIVK1) \XI&gt; ISSl"F.l&gt; AT NTATK KIH.K KAX(iK, XKAIt ASHLAMt. XKBRASKA. 41I-V 2O to AKUST 1», 19OH ISSIKO 5 c oo o o o 5 jj |1 If 11 &gt; i« H_ ill HI ill Is ! Sll III II ■- l_ Number of Rations 2 :; :« :* 2256 | 2997 Number of Rations Fresh Apples, pks. Apples, dried, lbs Hacon, lbs. 2399 Fresh Apples, pks. I 4 I Apples, dried, lbs !i7 22 4&gt;i 35 »7 Hacon, lbs. 1952 588 ."» r, 1 813 195 588 Means, lbs. 665 280 185 Means, lbs. 665 280 Haking Powder, lbs. Haking Powder, lbs. 3 2 1 Heets. lbs. Beets, lbs. 239 91 48 !•( 239 01 Heef, fresh, lbs. 6756 1848 ! 1875 2033 Beef, fresh, lbs Bread, loavts Butter, lbs. 575G 1848 Bread, loavts 4 ."&gt; 1 f. 1700 12ft 1518 Butter, lbs. Ill II 61 66 Cabbage, lbs. 837 13] 221 384 Candles, lbs. 157 52 49 56 Corn Meal, lbs. 7 Corn Meal, lbs Coffee, lbs. Coffee, lbs. 783^4 171% ttt 2 7 783^4 271% 239 C. Wheat, lbs Cans. Corn Eggs, doz C. Wheat, lbs. 21 10 1 SI Id 11 Cans. Corn 10 H It 10 Eggs, doz 286 85 ' 86 11 J&gt;« 85 86 111 Extract, bottles 6 Extract, bottles Flour, lbs. ( I Flour, lbs. 200 62 70 6 200 4ii TO 68 Hominy, lbs 184 M 4 4 10 Hominy, lbs Ham. lbs. 184 44 I 100 Ham. lbs. 113% 17 •'«* 113% 2 1 3 6 r, l«« Ice. lbs. 2 1 3 6 r&gt; 4756 8330 828 Ice. lbs 3?&gt;o 8285 Lard. lbs. 2:f I 1" io 8 Lard, lbs Mustard, btls. 7 7 Mustard, btls. Mitehes. boxes Milk, gallons Oat Meal, pkgs Onions, lbs. Matches, boxes 61 22 1 S 61 1 a ■n Milk, gallons 214 1!&gt;4 21 ) lit 4 Oat Meal. pkgs. 18 is Onions, lbs. 171 '. ki 1 7S ' 27«% -10 1 TV i T. nper. ounrcs 124 14 40 4 124 4 I 40 40 Vt uper. ounce* P'ffcles. anartB Ptache^, dried Prunes, lbs. P^kles. Quarts 1» II lit It P.achea, dried ifiOH I 15% M lfiOi^ v Prunes, lbs. 158% 43 ".'j 1^ 158% ' «* "'''• Potatoes, lbs «419 I75« 2i«7 22' »»*" Potatoes, lbs P^isin. lbs. Rire. lbs. 1 4 1 9 56 P^isin. lbs. 107 I II 2" 7 T. 107 1 Rire. lbs. ««7 1?' ' ' ' ]i 407 1 :»i 14i Silt. lbs. US 77 II 4 81 47 Salt, lbs is.". R-rrnp, runs ' xi ■'■" Jl RTrop, o«ns Sugar, lbs. Tea, lbs. 1 x i 1 1 Sugar, lbs. 1645 '-i 1*3 "72 l«45tt ItS "TJ Tea. lbs. &lt; 4 Tr»nvntn«»R. pans 4 ?&gt; 141 1 4.» 4P,s I 4S Tomatoes, cans Toilet Paper, rolls Vinegar, gallons. Coal 40 20 T2 1SMQ 4030 377 7o "200 $2,153.95 Total Cost of Subsistence Stores $2,153.9^ Cnet Par Ration Cost Per Ration </seg>
            <seg id="p077">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S RKI'ORT KKI«OKT OK COL V. S. NICHOLSON, SI fUiEOX OBXBUUi OH THK SKVKXTKKXTH AXMAL CONVENTION OF MILITAR Sl'RGEOXS HELD AT ATLANTA. &lt;iA., OCT. 13 TO 16, 19O8. St. Paul, Nebraska, Nov. 30, 1908 The Adjutant General Lincoln, Nebraska Sir: — I have the honor to report as follows regarding my attend ante on the Seventeenth Annual Convention of the Association of Mili - tary Surgeons of the United States held at Atlanta. Ga., Oct. 13 to 16 1908. Leaving my home station of St. Paul, Nebraska, on the morning of October 10, I arrived at Atlanta on the r-orning of October 12. On the evening of October 1 2 an informal reunion was held in the lobby of the Piedmont Hotel at which old acquaintances were renewed and new ones made The regular session opened on the reading of reports of various followed by the reading of papers profession. the morning of the thirteenth with officers and committees. This was of interest to the medico-military One of the most interesting papers was nn account of the sanguin - ary assault by the I*. S. forces upon the Menus ;it Pud Dajo Island of Jolo, P. I., as observed by the Surgeon, showing a description of the wounds and the number of killed and wounded in the U. S. forces, that it was not a one sided slaughter of the Moros. as has been charged by enemies of the Army, and of the Administration, but that the losses in the I". S. forces by killed and wounded amounted to S5&lt;; of the total number engaged. Another very interesting paper was read by Col. Jos. K. Weaver. N. G. Pa., entitled Hygienic Maxims for the Soldier in Camp and Field. Colonel Weaver emphasized the importance of the examination of the water supply in camps, before the forces occupy the camp site. He also laid great stress on tin- hygienic- instruction of th.- individual soldier saying "He must be educated to keep clean.'" He also suggested using pieces of cheese-cloth for covering food meat, etc.. in the company kitchens, in order to keep the flies from it Major G. S. Crampton read a paper on a Segregation Latrine which could be manufactured at small cost, and being transportable offers a ready solution of the problem pertaining to the disposition of feces in semi-permanent camps. Ry the use of this latrine, all solid matter is burnt and the fluids are carried deep into the ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S RKF'ORT During discussion of this paper, ii was stated that the incinerator tused very successfully in the Pennsylvania National Guard encamp- 1 i-nts, both for feces and kitchen garbage Lieutenant Col. Alejandero Ross of the Mexican Army pave a de - triptiun of a new whet' led litter, especially adapted to transporting -minded from the tiring line to the dressing station. It its very similar to one used by the British Army in South Africa, and 1 believe would be of great service in expeditiously transporting the wounded for short distances regardless at the character of the ground, as I have seen the Knglish litter glTe equally satisfactory results on both rough and -mooth ground. Its use would also allow of the work being done by half the number Hospital Corps men. the ordinary hand litter requires From what I could gather from discussions and talking with _;ite* from other states. I am led to believe that the Medical De - partment of the Nebraska National Guard compares favorably with the Medical Department in any of the States and is vastly superior to -nme, both in its organization, personnel and equipment, and I venture ty that in event of hostilities breaking out. the Medical Department if the Nebraska National Guard will acquit themselves in ■ manner to make the people of their state proud of tehm. Among the social entertainments provided were an automobile, ■round the city, a public meeting in the Legislative Hall, State Capitol, at which addresses of welcome were made, and the annual ad - ■ I the President. Col. Geo. Tally Vaughn was delivered. The foreign delegates were installed at this meeting and presented with the insignia of the organization. On Wednesday evening. October 14. a reception was given at the I'iedmoni Driving Club by the Fulton County Medical Society and on 'he last day of the meeting a Georgia barbecue was given at Oakland city by the officers of the Military organizations of the city. On the last day of the meeting Surgeon-General. Presby M. Rlzey inanimously elected president of the Association for the ensuing roar. The Atlanta meetng will be long remembered by the visiting dele - gates as one of the most pleasant in the history of the association. • haracterized as it was by such a lavish display of thiit far-famed Southern hospitality. Very respectfully. FRANK S. NICHOLSON, Colonel and Curgeon-General </seg>
            <seg id="p079">ADJITANT (JEXERAL'S RKPORT 79 I HK FI.NAXtiL TRANSACTIONS OF THIS OFFICE. For ih.' p. rlod December 1, 1906 to November 30, 1908. are as follows 1905 Appropriations OFFICE EXPENSE 19 0ti Balance $ 4U.74 Disbursements 413.74 INSPECTION, TARGET PRACTICE. ETC Dec. 1. 1906 Balance 196.68 174. 88 Disbursement Amount lapsed to State General Fund $ 21. SO ARMORY RENT Dec. I . I'.tOt; Balance . . . $4,129.17 4.125 i&gt;. i Disbursements Amount lapsed to State C eneral Fund 4.17 PER DIEM OFFICERS AND MEN Dec 1 1 f»u»; Balance Disbursenien Amount lapsed to State General Fund PAYMENT FOR HORSES Dec. l. 19IMJ Balanc Disbursements Amount lapsed to State General Fund SALARY ADJUTANT GENERAL 90i; Balance Dec. 1 . 1 Disbursements Amount lapsed to State General Fund SALARY ASSISTANT ADJl TANT GENERAL Dec. 1. 1906 Balance $ 400.00 Disbursements 400.00 SALARY ASSISTANT QU ARTERMASTER Dec. 1. 190C Balance $ 408.39 Disbursements 291.66 IK* </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Apr. 1' Apr. 10. 1H Apr. in. r.t'M Apr. 10, m Apr. 10, l(t"«; Apr. 10. l»«4 SAI AD.HTANT (iEXERAL'S REPORT Amount lapsed to State General Fund $ 116.7 SALARY STENOGRAPHER 1 . 1 H"0 Balance $ 2SO.O0 Disbursements 80.00 1OO7 AI'IMUWUIATIOXS. DEFICIENCY ARMORY RENT Apr. 10. l!*06 Amount of Appropriation $ 62E $ 025.00 Disbursements 625.00 OFFICE EXPENSE Amount of Appropriation Disbursements $ 3.000.00 266.70 Balance 733.30 INSPECTIONS $ -, ooo. on Inspections, Target Practice, eti Disbursements 6,20 792. 2X Balance ARMORY RENT I15.S00.00 10,332.16 Amount of Appropriations Disbursements Balance .-,,467.84 PER DIEM. OFFICERS AND MEN Amount of Appropriations »2. r &gt;. 000.0" 18,214.14 Disbursements Balance RENT TARGET RANG? Amount of Appropriation. Disbursements Balance SALARY, ADJUTANT Amount of Appropraiu Disbursements ( EN ERA I. ii Balance ARY. ASSISTANT ADJt TANT GENERAI Apr. 10. l»nt&gt; Amount of Appropriation $2. $2,400.00 Disbu rsements 1,900.00 Balance $ -&gt;00.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">\[&gt;.HTA\T GENERALS REPORT 81 \ M UNITED STATI I). AKV. ASSISTANT QrARTERMASTER Amount of Appropriation .$2,000.00 1,583.32 416 68 SALARY. STENOGRAPHER Amount of Appropriation $1,680.00 1,330.00 nit-iiis 350.00 APPROPRIATIONS FOR ARMING AND EQUIPPING THE MIUTIA. t'PPMES. ACT OF MAY 27, 190K Allotment. Fiscal Year. 19n&lt;&lt; $10,732.90 Value of Supplies Received Value of Supplies Reeetred 637.25 Haliinc- . . $l«,095.65 Halam $lt;,09, r ).fi5 AMMUNITION. Allotment, Fiscal Year. 19u9 $8,648.60 SECTION ICC1 REVISED STATUTES Balance $ 9.725.66 Re-crcdiis. Cash by I&gt;isbursinR ofllcer Allotment Fiscal Year. 190S 6,194.63 1,916.32 Allotment Fimal Year, 1909 1,409.51 Re-credit. Ordinnnce Stores returned. Ke-credii. OrdinaiK e Stores returned 174.50 1,955.15 $M, 376.77 \"alue of Stores received $25,891.28 Value of stores iharsed on re - port of Survey officer 1,251.54 Cash paid Disbursing Officer 38,000.00 $t;5,142.82 Balance to credit of state $16,233.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">BRASKA NATIONAL Gl'AROj t General's Oflkv \ \ lu Nebr (hen No v * made of the death of Captain SanitiH II. Davis. \ ai Quartermaster in the Adjutant c office, wtid answered I nil Sunday morning January I ::. 1 »i»7. His dea wa&lt; due to blood I i used n 1 ivi I ;»ni|&gt;- he Nebraska Xatkinal ( id last August, from which he has 1 the rifle competition at Columbus. iffiri ci r-iini lie however, atten here he made the neressar\ hcoi i&gt; mpetitlon ;n Columbus I! N Team \ n« fmiu tl he icrew gradually worse, Imt per formed his duty until in Deoeoib* His work was taken un and m-il'u when In- was confined to his home |i and perforn ed by tin- office force, who tppreci his »i rib and desired him to ■ontiniie in the serv Th look pla in.. Monday, January I 4. at Willie. Nelj he 1st Infantry. artiBK as military leaves a wife, one son and out- Captain lia\is was born in K In 4.".. and died ,n Willier. Nehrask field County, Ohio, on A u Runt 1 :: ii t 111., .laini 190 He enlisted in Company I), of th Tilth Ohio Infantry, on February n of Atlanta, and others partici - atered cut with his rcpiment at He served in (he cam pated in b\ his regiment. Was Louisville. Kenlncky. on .Inly 15, »ai mn 1M He cam* to Nebraska in the fall f ISC6, and homesteaded one-half he has since resided. Mile south of Willier in IK68, wheu&gt; He was appointed record clerk and custodian in the Adjutant &lt;;«'iieral"s office in .Inly. l!in|. and continued in that position until May i. 19H",. when In- was appoints*] Assistant Quartermaster, with the rank "f Captain, and continued in that capacity until bis death. Captain Davis was always in demand at Q. A. R. tamp fires, and wrote some very good verses Those who visit the Adjutant Generals offloe and inspect the war relics, will observe the following, pinned to the tattered colors, contributed by him, which voices the patriotic x-ntiment.s of his heart: HKADQIARTER3 NT Adjutan marksman, and Mien waa si-ni Company K of . m-iiii ;ii ihv burial wrvlcwt. h ■lauKhtcr. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Ml TAX GEN A I HKI'OKT 83 ns I. lit i,l i h r &gt;• dead i (1 v ti a nd :n) loyal. He was ■ tireli - and id ad ml War f tlu- i; that a trust in H. ( II.VKR KTKf A N.&gt; With ■ desire io stimulate drill nnd Interest every enlisted mai ii n &lt; t V he company, the following pro- gram has 1 i (in id dril that every company has been dividei Into squads in eonlunce with previ an Instruct!) impany commander will esiRnate the hours for squad dr d drill, which will be be continued up to he time of &lt; cutest. »Mch will tat rtuins: the we-k ronmraclBg Marxh 1 lth. the exa&lt; t time to be dt isnated by the company cunmiander 111 The Oral contest will bt confined to that portion of the in- inp with "DeBnitinns" and conclud- ing with pace S». whlwh contains information that »-ill be found im- by the V. S. Inspector, and cannot be too thoroughly studied The second contest between the squads in the company will cover he "School of thw Squad," and will take place during the fourth week ia Apr IV. A prize will be offered by the Military Board, to be presented to the successful squad in each company, the commissioned officers acting as judges, unless tin services of other officers can be secured. (I blessing, di Adjutant Uci.pra EBRASKA NATIONAL GI'ARD) nt Geseral'a Oflee Lincoln, Janu;i:v 19. IS tantry Drill Regulation*, i-omiuen portant. when plied with question </seg>
            <seg id="p084">ADJl'TAXT (JEXKRAL'S RKI'ORT 84 V The Xntioual Guard will I divided into groups of four com c conveniently assembled, withou to he designated hereafter), and Id between the MMMMfml squad? be awarded to the successful bat h. or battalions, that ran t I' regard in r&lt; uinniii. (time and place competitive drill and examination he i company. Another p:ize will talioii squad. uttst will include ■■Definitions VI 'I'll.' lialtalion and Principles." "School of the Soldier.' and "School of th. Squad." and t'&gt; be held prior to .1 1st, dates and places to be her* signaled, the wiimii VII My an appeal to the patriotism of'the people and a tactful ■filiation of the benefits that may accrue to the business intt ■ hnnts and professional men of th. #«r additional prizes, and a smal the final competitive drill and thi by holding these contests, the inert home t iwn may be pursuaded to &lt; nd mission iv. might be charged at help defray expel d that sufficient appropriation wil to warrant B state contest betweet the preceeding paragraph. VIII li is confidently expect IX The diills for the company contest will be arranged by th mpany officers, with a suggestion that the Bergeantg commanding tlu liffetent wctionn should become thoroughly interested in the succes eitions. sad if the plan is vigorously •oinpany commander will realize th. well informed and thoroughly drilled of the squad* ol their respective and sucressfull) &lt;:inie.l out. the Mtrfsfactinn of having at the end a lie Govern .1 H. (TI.VER Adjutant General HEADQUARTBR3 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GIARD) Adjutant General's OfBc \ Lincoln May C. IM Circular ) No. ». s That peerless volunteer i-oldier. General John A. Ixjgan. as Com mander-in-('hief of the Grand Army of the Republic, issued an order i designating the thirtieth of May of each year as Decoration Da&gt; and requesting all surviving veterans and patriotic citizens to unite i decorating the graves of our country's defenders with the "choices flowers of springtime," and by other appropriate exercises emphasizin t*e memory of their valcr and heroic sacrifices. At tbe sixteenth annual national encampment of the Grand Army n{ the Republic in 1882, tbe name was changed from that of "Decoration" to "Memorial Day," for obvious reasons, and by which it is now designated and legislative enactments have made it a legal holiday for the purpose indicated. i to receive a capital prizf In- made b&gt; (he |&gt;:e»eni leeiulatu tli..&gt;. winning prizes designated in ■ II. j' H&gt; cudt'r of </seg>
            <seg id="p085">iDJl'TAXT UKNKRALS 1 r ih inn 11 I he thirtieth day of \!a&gt; to the Grand Army of the Republic or local il&lt; v EADQIVKTER3 NEBRA8KA NATIONAL WAR Vdjuiuiit General's i (): *■ HEADQl'AKTERg XEBF Adjutur n. N December 17. IS Officers ordered toe examination under O. O No. 22, A G &lt;&gt; r s v;Y in id l)« r of the Hoard, mat do writing to the F'residt Board n II. Officers receiving orders which require travel, will niak.- r&gt; quisiUon on the Adjutant liener;il for requests for trausporiati III. ReloadiiiR tools, cartridge prim* round u i-d to this office by freight IV. All shipnieins of public property should show on the p:u the name of the shipper, and tl receipt m-ih to consignee by ma n vt \ 'I Winder Armory T;ircet. wil ■y amunitlon sufficient for si to u ■u ; ■i mid. immediate!) after use, bv • leaned with a mild si lution of tepid oda water, then wiped dry and illowed to staud a day before bein« oil i should be cleaned with a wire brn VII. Referring to Paratranh 3 of G. O. N a &lt;; c •fficerb are required to receipt for or rjr such propert; tl iTior' Till. All orders should be published, explained by the coinpan; commander, and placed on the bulletin beard; especially should (i. &lt; No. 2IP. A. G. C gone over in this way. and particular stre* placed upon Pur. XIII. which all members should understand. There i&lt; no reason why all concerned can not be educated to comply with thi&gt; \SKA NATIONAL G1AKD I'flfill s Office MIIMIU1 MIUH I'll lilt* |l«H hil^» and transportation ro»paaj' niimr h&gt; VI Stevens- Pope rifle barrel oiled, ir the barrel Ijei ; mm )i-;ule&lt;! irtish. ule us to discharges for Non-residence and Applicatioi </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 ADJt'TAXT GENERAL'S RKPORT IX. Coder the head &lt;if "O&lt; me listing officer should dhow the partW-ula I pat ion a man is engaged in: for instance, do noi say "Clerk." ''Student," Dr ' \k&lt; bu; ■ay "CniiT'v Clerk." "Drug Clerk." "Klre ins. AKent." "I. \-&lt;"i. l.ifc Insurant Agent." ■•Hook Ayent." "Medical Btudent." ■■!.«■ Student" Agent. " ■•Hook Ayent." "Medical Stilden Common School Student." etc. Enlistment pane s must shi.w pie\ iVh in in i 1 i I a r ♦■xp -Miitni of :i non-&lt; oniiniss (1 (iffl&lt; if t h&lt;- Mildier is in be continued in die same i- :; 1 1 1 • - . uotati if th t&gt; Bade accordingly. X. Hisi ! pirs for "Application" and "X; niin X. DiM'hciri^e p;w should n:i Up written until rder nutho'izii should has 1 d from I his i I puch di» ha« fer to thr n umber of order roverin XI. With ;i view in improving the p&lt; . ih, X \\ nil ;i vii « men. when shins, khaki routs, khaki trousers--, or !&gt;. I m&lt; inK. ill is ortiti- should be notified of the nun rh oL I np il.l * with Htatemetil &lt;if the ciwl |&gt;er article for Inundcrin; will with the name uf the laundry or pi rscn making the pne •■ XII. W'iili refere to Section in of &lt;; O. Xo. :,. A. wit XII. W'iili I. fin in Sft-I to rniitli- oltic is and non-ronimisj-ioned oi!ic&lt;]&gt; to to Uve pay. included In their dutieti are the followinK: a. The Captain shoald niRn hai the morning inerly wjritten uu on il. drill: that rompnn.' tiv, The Ciiplain sliip«ld si^i is s preserved: rajturna and repc»rtg m:ide up and forwarded o ■ d promptly and rorroctly, and thai ill pr cor - and rirrularx affe&lt;-tinR the company are publinhed. o. The let Senceanl ehould make up the mornini clrci f. every drill, on the day ot the drill. r. The QiiarternniKter Berxeant. under direction of OM (I mi Captain should l&lt;i&lt;ik ai'iir all company pn&gt;pe:t.v. and the quartern should k xart record &lt;if all fccues &lt;if Btores. Ketting receiplK i r itame: iinu "i rty to be carefully stored ikij i&lt;&gt; avoid mildew, niothx. ru lew, motlis. ru*t. etc., and w n I us-sii-i the company commander in Hie quaiterl} property re XIII. Thf artificer should mc that the FaHtenlntci on ■Esisl rlii com pa I nder in • mil XIII Th lit should il m dows, kickers, desks and boxes are sec-lire: that all ordimm iid III Xt art k«)t in Rood i-epair: all company imils in the company uh kW in Rood repair; all cum pan x midt lo&lt;-k nixl I By order ol the Governor: By order of the ( C. K SCH WAR/. Adjutant ( </seg>
            <seg id="p087">ADJUTANT UENKRAL'S REPORT 87 om&lt; \ n ot • r \v 1 ( ( A ill. •-(!»•-( M \V'orkiz( I Richards y l!i. iras tr ami iatn wr wljn wi ;int recollections of his offl.-inl military fam iiui l?«ted Maiid;irel :u evi in net vations stienithe thr mar lbl« soldier: that patriotinm. I Mended w of ttalwar "oil as that KJl'ARTER3 NEBRASKA X ATIOXAI. fiCARDl litani Adjutant General isi;ini Quartenni ms. the Comnuinderin-Chie ff that he BpprwintPK their hi* administration, ami that he will &lt;l iiy h raottvi National Gnnrd his onipliment them or &lt; h and wotth. »s tin- mainstay of an &lt;1 be nraestly desires thut the s;iae deroil.n </seg>
            <seg id="p088">ADJUTANT CKNEHAI KI'ORT 88 HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) Adjutant General's Offlct Lincoln, .lit n in: :1 Orders / No \ I. The General Staff of my predecessor, consisting of Btisjadler Oeneral Jacob H. Culver. Adjutant General Colonel George E. Jerkins, Q. M. and Commissary Genera Colonel Charles J. Hills, Inspector Central. Coloael Carroll P. Evans, Surgeon General. Colcnel John A. Ehrhurdt, Judge Advocate General a e roqneated to serve In their several official capacittea intil further orders. II. Upon the recommendation of the Adjutant General, the follow - iianicd oMctra are reai pointed, and wttl continue ».o tBTTt in their ■I positions, until re-'ulailv relieved: Emegi H ['helps. AFtistant Adjutant Genera n Hrad I' Cock, Arelstant Quartermaster. By ('rder of GEORGE LAWSOX SHELDON Governor and Commander-in-chief •QUARTER? NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant General's Office i Lincoln, February I 190 ;;1 Orders / No. I. 1. By authority of Section 7- IT. Cobby's Supplement to Revised SiHtutes of Neb ; pka, and in accordanct with General Orders Hi 1 f nil '•■ "d stre-&lt;-th of the organizations pravided for in .-. -tions 7224. 7225, 722C. 7227, and 7228. will be as follows: For ■ company of Infantry, total enlisted, fifty-eight, based on up master sergeant, four sergeants, six corporals, two cooks, two musician" ard forty-two p'ivates. grades as follows: one first sergeant, one quartermaster sergeant, four sergeants, six corporals, two cooks, two farriers and blacksmiths, one s; Mler. two trumpters and thirty-nine privates. to dutj may ch» the Nebraska National Guard In the futur hs it has in the past, and that a still higher plane may | M &gt; reached clur inn he incoming administration. JOHN" H. MICKEY. Cioverno! and Commander -i:i-('l OFKICIAI. .1 II Cl'LVKR. Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">\l TA\T GENERAL'S KKPOKT 89 Itattery of Kield Artillery, total t nlisted, one hundred and thirty idei as ti Hows. viz. one Hist sergeant, oae prgeanta, twelve cor ( two musicians, four aitiflcers. lw&lt;i cooks. OM hundred and four is. whlrb may be divided into two platoons, located at different Signal Corps, total enlisted, fifty-eight, apportionment to grades ws. viz: five sergeants, first class; five sergeants, ten corpora inks, eighteen privates, fiist (lass: eighteen priv Vmbulance Company section, total enlisted, forty-fhree, apportion- Con V. z. two first Bergeants. first d; nts. thirty-four privates, first (lass and piiv u order to pass inspection, it will be nec»s-arv to keep th. h.- number as stated in Paragraph I and have tht tired number of drills each month III. ( Orde No. :!. War Depart num. referred to in Department, referred to in Para- ph 1, wh has been previously sen vviously s&lt;? nt to company romnianu - troop, battery, signal rorp* ami ambu to company commanders, will be 1 bfort li company, troop, ban ry. signal corps and ambulance first meeting for drill ing for drill after the receipt of this ord after the receipt of this order By order of the ( er of the Governor: 1. H CCLVEK. overnor J. H. CULVEF Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 AIUI TANT CJEXKRALS Itl.I ORT . HEADQIARTER3 NEBRASKA NATIONAL Adjutant General's Office Gl'ARDj j Adjutant Genera I i ottii Lincoln. February I .",. | :nt7. Generul Order* / Orel ■ No. I. , I. The annual Male Inspection of the Nebranka National (^h;i be muds in the following order, by C'uptiiin ('. K. Planer, 1 si It and ' F, Shannon. l'ikI Inf., »ho are detailed a» ln*i&gt;ectorg: any F. Si Inf.. Lincoln. Thursday. March Amb .! mi-.- Ciiiniiaiiy. Lincoln, Friday. March |&gt;any, I... let, Inf. Omahi, Monda-. March ii. End. Inf. Oman i, Monday, March any E. L'd I nT . Tekaniah. Taesday, Company I, Jd inf., Omaha, Wednesday. March my C. 2d Inf., Nebraska City, Thursday. Varr-h Company C, l«i Inf.. I'eati Friday. Battery A. Wyni Saturday, March inj K, \»\ 1 11 ■ . . Wiibi-r. Monday! Msrrh ny «;, Isi Inf.. Ctneva, Tuesday, \'arch n &gt;' H, Isi Inf. Nelson, Wnln, . Xt&gt;. I X will I hf following ny F. :M Inf.. Ianco t u rsd Amli .linn 1 Company, I.inco Kpjday Monda M on i u Omal n&gt; C. L'ml. Inf. Omal M Tt kai Omal Wed in s ■ y I", -il Inf.. Xebras ore |. any c. isi Inf., I Vat Frida Battery A. Wyn ( nnipany I) I'd inf.. Palrbury. Thuntday.! ■ \\ ny L, z&gt;\ Inf., Alma, Saturday, April :» l{:ii.s. hiastinzs, Mon April ny A. I'd Inf., Kearney, Taesday, Aprol any M. is; Inf. Itrokeo I: &gt;«\ Wednesday, April ny !'•■ -d Inf.. St. Paul, Thursday, April l«ny II. -d Inl Aurora. Friday, '■• !-■ Is' Inf., York. &gt;,atu: April ;i Monday \. -il Inf., Ki arm* ( ( fuesday, a Wednesday . \ Friday, a i Saturd; \ Hani. 2d Inf.. Osceola. Monday. April K. isi Inf.. Columbus, Tuesday, A.ril mi U. !id Inf., Albion. Wednesday A;.ril l Momla t'o K. Isi In Tuesday, a iii&gt; M. lid Inf., Al W'tdiK \ Company «;. 3d Inf., Madl Saturday. April 1 Conijianv C. Inf.. Madis Saturday, \ lie RinV». Rumhrillt-, Thursday, April I Ri Ri islivi urstlii ( anv ii, ist Inf.. Stanton. Monday. April I Monda) Signal ('(■ Premont, Taei r'l 1 Tuei &gt;an\ K. jd inf.. Srhuylpr. Wednesday, , r 'l I Well \ Company D. 1st Inf.. Weepln; \V;r. Thursday. \-,-M I Company D. 1st Inf., Weepli A Troop A. Milfor.i. Saturday, :il 2 Tiooji A. Milfo \ II. Company rommanden will a «pective armorins on the date dettiKn II. Company commanders will assemble their commands ;it tin live arninrins on the date designated, at S:»t« p. m. Bible tlicir rommandi •d. at S: mi p. m. III. Thi- (iuard will be Inspected in heav» niarchine order, bli heavy in. in hint or uniform, campaign hat. and legxlBa-s. IV. Company commanders will see thai the armory, records, or uniform, campaign hat, ;md li-swin^ IV. Company commandera wil thai the am »aii&lt;&lt;- and qsartenBaster Btorer, and equipax-nta arc in r«sdines&gt;x t inspt'i-rton on tin- sniral . t the Inspecting officer, who should be met the depot by some designated oftlcer. and every facility o.Terad to ■• l»edite the work of Inspection. V. A list of the absentees and im for such alisvm be prepared and liand«d to the iispi I n his mriv VI. Bftnk laapex-tii n reportg a forwarded with this ord« turned ov«r to the Inapeato </seg>
            <seg id="p091">* "» 91 O. () *:&lt;■!!. Pay n lis will I »■ siuncl. v«-rl i VI 1 I.VEK HEAIXJl .'UTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL WARD/ Ail , Line In. v G'i:cr;' 1 Orders / No. :, 1 ''"■''&lt;■ annual Im ., National Guard, under G \ id. under Sectim I I of tin- Act hi Congretw approved Januai , ; n be will bt made bj Capt. Charlrv VV. (Vstli\ : ; • • t li r. s. Infm II. Com pan) commandem will Rxvembk- i In i r respective coni- n mi mandK at the pi mpani armories for ins] i-iiiim gg follows Si-jnal ( orps. Fremont Wednesday February J$ Company E, Jd Inf., Tekaniah Thursday, February 21 Company E, 3d Inf., Tekaniah Thursday, February Hand. 1st Inf. W'isner Friday, Februar&gt; Company B, IK Inf.. Stanton Saturday, Ptbmr] Company B, IK Inf., Stanton Saturday, Pebnary Rushville RiH.s. Rushville Monday, romiiany A, L'd Inf.. Kearney Monday, Comiiany A, Jd Inf.. Kearney Monday, February Company F, 1st Inf., Madison, Tuesday. February :»&gt;; Company F, 1st lnf , Madison, Tuesday. ruary Company M, 2d Inf.. Albion, Wednesday, Pebrnarj Comiiany M. Jd inf.. Albion, Wednesday. February Comiiany K, 1st Inf., Colnmbn, Tliursday. February 88 Comiiany K, 1st lnf Comiiany B, -d Inf. Company M. 1st lnf Company G, 3d Inf. Columbus. Thursday, February Company B, Id Inf.. St. Paul. Friday. " Ma- Company M. 1st Inf. Hroken How Saturday, March Company (;. Inf.. Omaha. Mon I March ] Company L, 1st Inf.. Omaha, Tuesday. March Omaha Tuesday. March Comiiany I. 2ii Inf . . Omaha. Wednesday. March Omaha. Wndnesdar. March Company K. I'd lnf Company E, 1st Inf Company K. I'd Inf.. Schuyler. Thursday, March Schuy Thursday, March Company B, 1st Inf., Wilbur, Wednesd nary 2* Wilbur, Wednesday. Februarv i'H ("•mpany O, 1st Inf.. Oeneva. Thursday.' February i'1 ("•mpany (1. 1st Inf.. Oeneva. Thursday. February :'1 Company H. 1st Inf., Nelson. Friday. February 12 Company H. 1st Inf.. Nelson. Friday. February Company I), L'd Inf., Fairbury, Ratnrdav. February Compai Cos pasty C. 1st Inf.. Heatrice, Monday. February JS Cos pan y C, 1st Inf.. Heatrice, .Monday. February I'attery A. Wvmore. Tuesday. February SC Patter* A Wyntore. Tuesday. February Comiiany L. Inf.. Alma Wednesday. February Company L, Jd Inf.. Alma Wednesdny. February Hastings Rifles, Hastings. Thursday. February l&gt;» Hastiiifis Ritle* Hastings. Thursday. February L&gt;» Company H. 2d Inf., Aurora, Friday. March i Company H. 2d Inf., Aurora, Friday. March Companv A. 1st Inf. York. Saturday. March Companv A. 1st Inf York Saturday. March Pand. I'd Inf.. Osceola. Monday. March Corapiny F. Inf., I&gt;inoo)n. Tuesday. Marc'i 4 Ambulance Company. Lincoln. Wednesday. March Company I, 1st Inf.. Wahoo. Thiii-slay,' llarch Company I). 1st Inf., Weeping W'tr. Friday, March Troop A. Milford, Saturday. March g Company C. Jd Inf. Nebraska CityMonilay. March !• </seg>
            <seg id="p092">AD.IITANT GENERA1 REPORT he Ambulance Company, Signal C'or( III. Ten nfantry companies, will take place at mimi p. m : Battery A aud Tr \. at 3:00 p. in.: and will be in heavy man -iiins ordrr. Mm uniforn anipuign hai and l&lt;j;!;iii«s IV. Kit hi and sniff omren will report at the mus 1 report at the rn ir the Inspection. IV. Kit Id and staff oncers wi ompatiy station »n II nued for Ike Impectlom. V. All i|uaitenB8Eter and ordinance etores, camp eau V All iluaitermsEter and ordinance rtore* camp equii ecords. and trmoriei must be in readlneaa for laap ecords. and irmoriea ninsl be in readiness for laapectk ival of the inspecting officer on date ol ii:sp.-&lt; t i n. or at ival of tin- inspecting officer OB &lt;!at«- of iiispecti n. or at I nay be designated by him. VI. Tin' moralnt! repoil for da) Inspection, and sick lay !&gt;*■ designated by bin VI. The morning repoit for da) Inspection, and sick report, r « written up. read) for inspection. A list of absentees written up. read) for inspection. A list of absentee*, ai herefor juiim be prepared and delivered to the inspector, herefor musl bv prepared and delivered to the inspector, and a Aui d ale copy vein lu Uie Adjutant General without delay. VII. Orhie.s and men complying with this order wi .He copy mih lu the Adjutant General without dt VII. Offlic.s and men complying with this order will be alljw wenty-rive lenls (C5rl tor each sirvice: Ihe same pay rol wentv-rive lent is for state inspection, and promptly forwarded to tile Adju s for state inspection, and promptly forwarded to the Adjutant Genera i'ay Rolls must lie signed on the date of inspection. VIII Every facility should be cfered the inspedm- in ordt i'ay Rolls must be (i£Bed on the date of inspeclion. VIII Kvery facility should be cfered the inspedoi xpedite Ins woik. Kquipments. ordnance and &lt;iiiartf.ii tnust be assorted and arranged for easy countinf All companv commanders have been previ nust lie asscjrted and arranged for easy counting. All coiiipain conimanders have bt en previously advi .■quiHition for anything lacking in equipment. IX. It is very important that every man should lie present, and hat each company should pass a creditable Inspection. The W»t De- partment takes this method to ascertain whether the National Guard is under proper discipline, well drilled, and fully equipped for activt &gt;ervtce; and the financial assistance rendered to the Qaard by tht c.overnment is largely determined by this inspection By order of the Governor J. H. (Tl.VER Adjutant Genera OFFICIAL Asst Adjt. Genl. HKADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GTARDf Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln, April !'■.. 190 '".eceral Orders | No. (J \ I. The attention of company commanders is called to General Orders No. B, series of 190(j, regarding target practice. Requisition should be made for the necessary- ammunition, if not already supplied II. A report of the competitive squad drills, pursuant to Circular No. 2, c. s., and ptevious letter of instructions, must be made May 1st </seg>
            <seg id="p093">ADM TANT OEXERAL'S REPORT and the first of each Bucceedtag month thereafter, until tba complet &gt;f hi&gt; appropriation not being sufficient to pay for the month rmittcci by Section 4 1. General Orders No. », scries 190"- lent* will be made on the following plan, until further ordc: "ins with May 1st. ipaniea having four drills a month, of at least two hours earl wi dance &lt;&gt;f fifty per cent will be allowed ten tent hose in attendance. Hay rolls will b. iRiied by those attending drill, to be marked •Present" or "Absent' inder proper date, and will be fo-warded at the end of each quarter (1 IV. Service pay will he allowed under Section 4". General Order No. :.. &lt;eri&lt; s of 19nf,. providing that orders have been properly obeyed irterly reports made, in accordance wit], Section of said this payment will he made upon printed vouchers, furnithed by the Adjutant General on application, and to b. d by the cert in puny con mander thai the non-com mi.-sioned officers referred '&lt;&gt; hare each faitl « G I. (T1.VER Mj Adjutant General's Offic ncoln. May :!. 1907 I. Captain Edmund H. Mull wney, of the 2nd Infantry, is detai! -d as Inspector of Small Arms Practice, and Surveying Offlc r. fur 1&lt;* He will rc-poit to the Adjutant General for duty on May Mil. 1 **H7. II. All officers ha\ins: in their pouraaloa unserviceable pnipertj or whu have sustained losses of KOvernment or state property, will ap ply to the Adjutant General on or befoie June 1st, l!&gt;07. for board over necessary hotel bill. Transportation requests will be furnished &gt;r state properly reported to be serviceable I. H. CULVER. Adjutant General uniundin^ officer «&gt;f thp company HEADQIARTER3 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) By order cf the Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 AD.I I TANT CKNKRA! R] K.\ NATIONAL ClARO Otti Major Ermsr H. Phelos. Assistant Adjinant Gt-neral Major John kf. Blrkaer, Anibulanie Company. Major Frfri J. Mark. 2nd l"f:-ntrv. Captain Otis M. Nt-wnian, 1'nd Infantry Capiain Charles K. Kraser. 1st lnfantr&gt; Captain jleaa* C. Pernod. 1st Infantry. II. The following named officers of the Nebraska Naiional Guard Colonel .lo^e|ih A. Storch, 1st Infantry - i No. v I. Tlic Oflhes St-ti&lt;M&gt;l of ill.' Nebraska Natonal Guard for rt&gt;7 will convene in K. pr&gt; -sensitive Hall. Capital Building. Lincoln, hi vm I&gt;. in.. Mondajr. July s. l»«7, and runtinue In Kewion until July llih. II. Kiidi iiHi&lt; it in attendance will bo allowed s :: n n per day t( cover i hotel bill. Transitcrtaticn requests will be furnahed ;md if not used, will be n-iiiri ., •-,,]■* once with out deli) . III. No officer will I e ( xi n.-i el f.oni H'lendan |&gt;reveot»&lt; liy one of ih«- I . llowirp '■&gt; ■ .-cn- girknetg »f hinrelf or member «i liis Immediate lainily. in whicl insli insi;uHc. siirgi on'a i-ertlHcate nhould 1. riirriched. Verj inipoiia! i busin»&gt;a i:r \ rofessional eiiKaRenu-nt. which will 1» t-onsidt-red l.&gt; tl &gt;■ Militarv B&lt; \\. OSjieiK ehoulj (cmic with lull sii|i',i IiooU&gt;. Hud \ tt I. (M.I prepared to sii'ke the m:&gt;i of the lime allotted. V. Siivii.. nrili rm .-nil side arms, will bt- worn. If;, urdcr i l' i lie Governor, •1 II CII.VBR. Adjatanl General. HEADQI/RTERJ NEBRASKA NATIONAL (HARD/ Adjutant General's Office ( i Lincoln. June 17. I !i &gt;7 ral Ordfts i No. !i \ I In ;nordaiHf with tin- Militay Cod ( . c; f i lie Stale of Nebraska h Board of Examination will ecnrene at the Adjutant Qcaerml'i Olfic-i t'apitol Unldiim, l.inreln, Kebnaka, at t:«u p. m .. Thursday. July II 190". consisting of: </seg>
            <seg id="p095">( &lt; I ( I f 1 1 1 HKI'OKT drat of ii I li TRY \ ANT &lt;;K\KK \1 I" .1 FIRST IXFAX Kb M Mi K l( li H. Brock K Ivlnnuid K ml A. Oilht ieuteiiant Williun \. Or 1 Lieutenant G. Albert Fun; k 1 Lieutenant Us borne 1). Latta i I Lie ;teikHiit Joseph I., (iriinni i 1 Lieutenant lohn \V. Wirkersha: id Lieutenant John I'. Dullmghan nd Lieutenant Hillyari C. Wilson nd Lieutenant Henning F. Klsasst d Lieutenant Harry Pritrhard lonel .John C. Hartigan lajor Walter F. Sanimons ai)taiu Thomas A. I)e.\oon .iptain (leorge A. Heath Rptain J. Fred McNee. Jr. attain Harry J. Kngels aptain Albert H. Marker aptain Julius A. Wiig st Lieutenant Carl v brahamson st Lieutenant Horace M. Ivey. st Lieutenant George P. Thomas st Lieutenant Byron W. Hart. 1 H \! Colonel .John C. Hartigan I :,Mit. Coloner Oliver G. Osb«in&lt;&gt; Major Herbert J. Paul Vfninr Walter K 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">( I i 1 ADJUTANT GENERAL KKl'OKl 1st Lieutenant Bayard T. Eller. 1st Lieutenant Otho B. Shelburn. lsi Lieutenant Howard B. Heath. 2nd Lieutenant Joseph F. Hulka. 2nd Lieutenant Walter T. Heuni. 2nd Lieutenant Cny B. Gould. 2nd Lieutenant Edwin E. Sterrickir 2nd Lieutenant Herbert E Vaabttrg. 2nd Lieutenant Arthur KlmberllBK. 2nd Lieutenant Leon H. Davis. TKOOC A HATTEHY A Captain Samuel E Voder. 1st Lieutenant An hie I'. Tempi SIGNAL COK1 nd Lieutenant William C. Mallonee HASTINGS RIFLES Captain John P. Madgetl. 1st Lieutenant George E Bi 2nd Lieutenant Henr&gt;' ' l Browm III. The examination will be conducted inlets Nn in. rerlea l 804. IV. The nflccn reporting: for examination will be allowed -auie compensation as p escribed for those attending Offii ■ n General Ol dt-rs . o. s. v. s. The Board of Examination will be allowed mh h con resc Tilled by the Military Board. By order of the Governor H. (TI.VEK HEADyiAUTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant Generals Offl Lincoln. June L'H. 190 General Orders j No lit. I. The resiRnation of Brigadier General Jacob H. Culver. Ailj taut Geneal. is accepted, to tatae effect July 1st. 1907. II. General Culver enlisted in 1 SCI . at the age of sixteen, in Con pany K. of the First Wisconsin Infantry, and served until the must' out of his regiment. Was a member of the University Cadetes of Wi eonsln. Organized Troop A of the Nebraska National Guard in ISs and commanded t. until LS98. when he was mustered into the fniti Captalu Allx ri S. Hlsey Captain Louis H (lage. 1st I.iiiiitiiani Henr) A Adjutant Gener </seg>
            <seg id="p097">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 97 States mike with his troop, commanding the same through the Span - ish War. Was recommissioned as Captain in the 32nd U. S. Infantry In 1H9«, and served through the Philippine Insurrection. Appointed Adjutant General on February 20, 1903, and has served with credit to himself and the state in that capacity, until the present time. He is therefore, at his own request, and under the provisions of Section 7 2 4 .""• of Chapter ::::. Statutes of Nebraska, palced upon the re - tired list, with the rank of Brigadier General, to which he is entitled unde the law, and by reason of long, honorable and meritorious service By order of GEORGE LAWSO.N SHELDON, Lincoln, June 29, 1907. General Orders j No. 11. i I. Captain Charles F. Schwarz is hereby appointed Adjutant General with the rank of Brigadier General, to take effect July 1st, 1907, vice Brigadier General Jacob H. Culver, resigned. He will be obeyed and respected accordingly By order of (1EORGE LAW'SON SHELDON, Governor and Commander-in-Chief. OFF1CIA1 .1 II. CULVER. Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD} Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, June 29, 190" General Orders / N \ I. The Nebraska National Guard will assemble in camp of instruc- ection 7l'4."&gt; of Chapter ::::, Statutes of Nebraska, placed upon the re f.it II. Company commanders will make requisition for the necessary i i(|itipments with which they are not already supplied. hould tie secured at once, and if possible en lie usual mle may lie observed as u discharge of cooks after Nil enlistment* will be permitted previous to encampment w 1. and companies should te recruited at least to th^&gt; H&gt; order c:f th Governi I H. CULVER Adjutant Gel </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 ADJITAXT GENERAL'S KKI'ORT i HKADQIARTERS NBBRA8KA NATIONAL GCAHDj Adjutant General'! Offic Lincoln. Jnly 1 1, l Qmeral Orders / No. 13. . I. The board of Mfeen wtwilj under General Orders Xo. '.&gt; «.. for the buipoaa ot examining I Been as to their qualifications tor commissions in the Nebraska National Guard, having reported that thf following office:! passed a that they be commissioned, is hereby approved, and tin (heir present appointment. satisfactory examination, and recommended Ilie report and recommendation of said hoard ird ltd ( (fleers ;ire commissioned. to dat oni viz I IKST INFANTRY George A. Eberl.v .lames .1. G:imin Maj Major Iver S. Johnson . . John M frandell. Sanford H. Garey . .Ia&lt;oli C. Ferguson Ivan McKay . C'aptun . Captan First Lieutenant First Lieutenant Kiist Lieutenant Ralph S Kdinnnds &lt;i. Albert Funck . Hennlng K. Elaaase First Lieutenant Second Lieutenan Second Lieutenan h (ON1) INFANTRY Oliver g (Mane. Herbert .1 Haul . . . Walter F. Saminons Thomas A. DeNoon .1. Fred .Mi Nee. Jr. . Lieutenant Colon* Major. Majo .Captain, Coramia . Captain Julius A Winj;. Albert H. Barket Captain Captain Captain CaKti'i'i Captain Edmund H. Mullownt Monte E. Luni Albert S Hiss. Charles K. Gibbons George P. Thomas . Myrl B. Mather. . . . First Lieutenant. First Lieutenant. Second Lieutenant Otho B. Shelburn Leon H, Divis TROOP A ( aptain HASTINC RIFLES Captan First Lieutenant Second T.leutenant Kirst Lieutenant. Asst. Snrgi First Lieutenant. Albert S I John P, Madgel George K. Hujj Henry |{. Browa . . </seg>
            <seg id="p099">ADJUTANT GENERALS REPORT 99 II. On the recommendation of the Board, the following namod officers .re . ..mmissioned without examination, by reason of previou, exam na ,o ns . commissions are service it, the Nebraska National Guard to date from their p:esent appointment, viz Captain Samuel E. Voder. Battery A Colonel John C. Harti S ;,n 2nd. Infantrv &lt;'aptain Georse H. Holdeman Adjutant 1st. Infantry Captain Samuel E. Voder Battery A -'ml. Lieutenant Elbert O. Butterfield 1st. Infantry to „., ; 7k d **"■ reported that the following officers failed '"°! '" th h " ieq " Ired &gt;»■■■ «*■« '" the the examination, and recom ZoT H &gt; -examined, the report and recommendation are Z - s,ch ,,„ '^ TS m ~ m '"" " rderf " 1 '" reI)Ort for examination T Mich time as the Adjutant General may direct: Colonel George K Jenkins. Fairburv. re.ppninted Quartermaster tismzr ■"* Hi rank from date ° r his ° riKinai ~^ Colonel Charles J. Bills. Lincoln, reappointed Inspector General to rank from date of his orignal commission, januarv 9 ,90 - the rfnT' r f rT" f Nkh °' 8On ' St PouI - to Surgeon Genera., with the rank of Colonel, to take effect July 1 1907 the r G \ ne 7' J " hn C Cowin ' Omaha, to be Judge Advocate General, with the rank of Colonel, to take effect July 1. 1907. II. Major Ernest H. Phelps. Lincoln, is reappointed Assistant Ad- Zst ,- Z™ t0 raDk fr ° m tHe d3te ° f hiS ° ri8inal commission. Au- 5l23ft(m I- Captain William A. Myers lst Infantrv | ;; 1 ; 1 ! iiKosb "- :::£SSS: •s. ... Rnber, V. Chapman Is,, .nfantr^-. 1st. U. carl Abrahams.... , nd Infantrv 2nd. UWilMam x. orris WtTl^ . " d £ O , Sb h ° rne ° Latta 1st .nfantry. ' Ohn C Dlllla « han 1st. infantry. 2nd. I.,. Arthur Kimberling 2nd Infant 2nd. u. wuiiam H. dark 2nd. InfantrT By order of the Governor, C. F. SCHWARZ. Adjutant General. HKAOQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GIARD, Adjutant General's Oflice ._ , Lincoln. Julv i&gt;n lyiiT General Orders / ' No. 14. \ Phi / T h P f ';" OWins a l'l'"»"n.ent. .,„ the staff of the Comraander-in- Cnief, are hereby amended. e&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT Bradford P. Cook, Lincoln, is reappointed -Assistant Quartermaster, with the rank of Captain, to take effect January 15, 1907. By order of the Governor. C. F. SCHWARZ. Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln, August 1, 190 Central Orders f No. IS. I I. The State Rifle Range for the season of 1907 will be located south cif the penitentiary, near Lincoln, where the state contest will be held, commencing August r&gt;th, and the following officers assigned to duty thereat: Commander and executive officer, Capt. Edmund H. Mullowney, 2d Inf, Quartermaster and adjutant Capt. M. E. Lum, 2nd Inf Statistical officer Capt. Louis H. Gage. Signal Corps II. The following named officers and men having qualified as marksmen, are entitled to take part in the state competition to de - termine those best qualified under the rules to form the Nebraska Rifle Team for the season of 1907, and those desiring to enter the contest will report to the camp commander on above named date, at the state range; Lieut. Col. Fred Gegntr 1st. Inf. Major Fred J. Mack 2nd. Inf Cap!. Iver S. Johnson . 1st. Inf. ('apt. Charles E. Fraser .1st. Inf. ("apt. Ernest Aubort . 1st. Inf. ("apt. August Wagner . 1st. lnt ('apt Martin C. Shallenberger. 2nd. Inf. 1st. l.ieut. William E. Osborne . . 1st. Inf. 1st l.ieut. John H. Brock . 1st. Inf. l*t. Lieut James. F. Hashberger . 2nd Inf. 1st. l.ieut. Howard B. Heath. . . 2nd. Inf. 2nd. Lieut. Osuornc D. La'ta . . . in. Inf. 2nd. Lieut. Harry B. Hobbs. . . . . 1st. Inf. 2nd. l.ieut. Arthur C. Boone. . . 1st. Inf. 2nd. Lieut, Ijeon H. Ua\i&gt; 2nd. Inf Seri?!. Rcillin T. Smith .Co. \. 1st. Inf Sergt. Chris. L. Anderson .Co. B. 1st. inf Sergt. Walter I). Jensen .Co. I). 1st. Inf Sergt. Edward A. Zessin. .Co. K. 1st. Inf Sergt. Louis E. Skala .Co. V. 1st. Inf Bergt. James Barnes .Co. I. 1st Inf Bergi li'i i .1 Brtea .Co. K. 1st Inf </seg>
            <seg id="p101">AD.HTAXT GENERALS REPORT 101 Sergt. Edgar B. Bridges. . . Sergt. Edgar Detts Sergt. Harry Schmidt Sergt. Frank F. Willott. . Sergt. James E. Del-ancey Corp. Glenn A. Tucker. . . . Corp. Holland F. Daggy . . Corp. Fred W. Nye Co. L. 2ud. Inf Co. A. 2nd. Inf Co. A. 2nd. Inf Co M. 2nd. Inf (" M 2nd. Inf Co. A, 1st. Inf Co. A. 1st Inf Co. B, 1st. Inf Corp. Clarence C. Grimm Artif. Emil Storkan . . . . Co. E. 1st. Inf Co. E. 1st. Inf Cook Isaac Brook . Cook John Gibson. Mus. l.ouis Zander Co. K, 1st Inf Co. L, 2nd. Inf Co. B 1st Inf Mus Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Priv Earl .1. Meixell. Everett \V. Owen William Duffy. . . Co. H, 2nd. Inf Co. A. 1st. Inf Co. B, 1st. Inf .Co. D. 1st. Inf Co. D, 1st. Inf Co. D. 1st. Inf Delbert A. Ferguson. . Albertus C. Meisenbach Charles A. l.inton Co. E. 1st. Inf Co. E. 1st. Inf Co. E. 1st. Inf Fred C. Fraser Charles Broot Everett Dale. Limi Gammon. Co. F. 1st. Inf Co. I. 1st. Inf Co. I, 1st. Inf Co. I. 1st. Inf Cecil K Hashberger James E. B'own . . Charles H. Stewart Frank Allington. . . Co. K. 2nd Inf Co. H. 2nd. Inf Co. H. 2nd. Inf Co. I.. 2nd. Inf Vitii Cadv Co. L, 2nd. Inf Ernest C. Green 1. 2nd. Inf ■ minions. of the match irmish run Is. rapid fir* ards. slow fire 4. 500 yards, slow fire Is. slow fir b N in Skirmish fi Rapid tiir. shots HI shots ightlng shots and 10 »t fo 1 at iw fir eco each rang P itior undin yards, and prone with head •ward* target her range Daniel Switzer. . Walter F. Peters Winfred Woods. i w i n n are the </seg>
            <seg id="p102">AD-U'TANT QBNERAL'8 REPORT 102 IV. The fifteen receiving the highest markings will constitute tht? Team which will represent the State of Nebraska in the National Oom - jtetition at Camp Perry. Ohio, commencing August 2H. 1 90 7 . V. The following compensation, in addition to subsistence, has been fixed by the Military Hoard for this tour of duty: $:;.&lt;in per day for commissioned officers ll.i'ii per day for enlisted men VI. The commanding officer of Company F. 2nd Infantry, will detail eight caiefully selected men. and the commanding officer of the Signal Corps will detail four competent nien of the Corps, to report for duty to the camp commander on August ."■ t h . The detail from tht Sig - nal Corps will take such iquipment as is necessary to establish and maintain telephone coinmunicat ions as may be necessary. VII. The service uniform, with blue Manuel shirt, will be worn, and the officers and enlisted men reporting tinder this order must be equipped for duty in the field. ■■ no bedding or table ware will be l near Lincoln, on Monday. August 12. lHoT. remaining until August 17th: except that Company I. 1st. Inf.. will leave home station on Sun - day. August 11th, and return so as to arrive home Sunday. August ISth: and that the Signal Corps ami Hospitjil Corps will leave their home stations on Sunday. August 11th. Company commanders will be furnished with special written Instructions as to travel to and from &lt;-amp II. The commanding officers of Companies C. F. (i. I. K. M. 1st Inf.: Companies A. B. C K. K. L. M. and Hand. 2nd. Inf.. Hattery A and Signal Corps, will send a detail consisting of the quartermaster sergean and three enlisted men to camp on Saturday August loth: and the commanding officers of Canipany A, H. I). E. H.'L and Band 1st Inf. Companies I). F. (',. H. 1. 2nd Inf.. Hospital Corps and Hastiags Rifles will send same detail to camp on Sunday. August 1 lth. with *JI uecessan oan'p equipment of their respective commands, which detail will make ramp and have same in readiness for the arrival of the company. III. The 1st Regiment Infantry, and Battery A. will camp near Capital Beach, one aHd one half miles w»st of Lincoln, the camp to be provl provided at the range led By in diT i f i In 1 OoTtmor. C. F. SCHWAKZ. Adjutant General. HEADQIARTKRS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GIARD) Adjutant General's Office f l.iinoln. Ausnst B.1M7. General Orders i No. l&lt; I. Pursuant to, and aint-ndiiij; (icncral Orders No. If, A. G O. r. t.. the Nebraska Natiimal Guard will k&lt;&gt; into canip of instruction </seg>
            <seg id="p103">ADJITANT GENERAL'S REPORT 103 IV. The -'nil Regiment Infantry, and the Hastings Rifles, will camp in Kpworth Paik. two and CMM half miles south west of Lincoln, lh« camp tii be under the command of Colonel John C. Hartigan. 2nd luf V. The Signal Corps and Hospital Corps will camp on West "A" street. ;i[ ;i point midway between Capital Beach and Epworth Park, and the commanding officers will make such details from their com- mands for duty at the camps named in Par. Ill and IV, as in their judgment will be for tlit best interests of the service, or as may be ordered by this office VI. The following officers of the Adjutant Generals Office, and General Staff, will go into camp on W est "A" street, for the purpose of administration. Held and ramp service, Brig. '■'•*'"■ C. K. Schwarz. Art jut o include the dates named ant General, August 11th. to 18. Col. George E. Jenkins, y. M and Corny General. AM. T.th to lMh Major E. H. Phelps. Asst. Adj. C n'l. August 11th to lMh Aug. 11th to 18th. Ca,pt. Brad P. Cook. Asst. Q. M VIII. The following officers, m mbers of the organizations named in Par. III. IV. and V. will so pi d to camp, and return to their home stations, as to be on duty on the following dates, inrlusi Col. Joseph A. Btorch, 1st. Inf. Aug. 9th to Aug. 19th. Capt George H. Holdemau. Adj. 1st. Inf. Aug. 11th to Aug. 17th. (apt. Arundlo M. Hull. Q. M . 1st. Inf.. Aug. 10th to Aug. 18th. Capt. Otis B. Davis. Corny. 1st Inf.. Aug. Ill to Aug. 18th. The Q. at., and Corny Sergts.. 1st Inf.. Aug. 10th to Aug. 1 «th. Col. John C. Hart lean, 2nd Inf.. August loth to ABK. lMh. Tthe Q. M. and Com \ Serg'ts. 2nd Inf., Aug. -Oth to An VIII. 1'nder the provisions of Section 7241. Cobbey&gt; IMS Sup plemtnts to Nebraska Statutes, no member of the Nebraska National Guard will be excused from attendance nt ramp, except nimn suraeon certificate of disability, or of serious illness in the immediate family. IX. The commanding officers of the 1st. and 2nd. Regiments of Infantry will make requisitions direct to the office for transportation «&gt;f the commissioned and Don-commissioned officers of their respective headquarters: the company (•iiminatidfs. for their commands; and mounted officers, for their horses X. The Quartermaster and Commissary General will furnish XI. Company commanders will forward field returns in duplicate for August 12th, to regimental headquarters; and the Signal Corps and Hospital Corps, to this office immediately on ar-ival in camp, and • hereafter consolidated returns for each camp will be forwarded to this office daily XII. Morning xhk reports and daily sanitary report for each camp will be forwarded to this office dally under command of Colonel Joseph A. Btorch, 1st Inf rubsistfiiie. fuel, forage, mid tiinsportatiori </seg>
            <seg id="p104">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 104 XIII. One ambulance will be sent from the field hospital to each camp every morning at sick call. XIV. Commutation of rations at twenty cents per capita will b« allowed for the days en route, and paid on the state pay rolls. XV. Five copies of pay rolls will be prepared and forwarded to headquarters of each camp by 1:00 p. m., Wednesday, August 14th. XVI. The service of khaki uniform, with blue flannel shirt, will be worn, and each company will 'eport at ramp equipped for duty in the field. Equipage must be limited to U. S. Army Regulations, and un&gt; - thing not necessary for this tour of duty, must be left at home station The tin cup will be carried in the haversack XVIII. No ammunition or unauthorized fire arms will be curried or brought to camp; companies will be carefully inspected by a commis - sioned officer on entraining and detraining to see that there is m&gt; vio - lation of this. XIX. Officers will be held to strict accountabililv for the care and use of government property, also for the conduct of the men: and all irregularities, or damage to public or private property, including that belonging to the railroad company, must be promptly reported to this office through milita:y channels. By order cf the Governor Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) Adjutant Generals Office ilncoln, August '',. l General Orders ) I: The annual In8| r the Nebraska National Guard as Of Congress approved January 21, required by EfecUoa In of i! IMS, * ill he made while in camr No. HI. A. O. O.. c I near Lincoln, under General Order Inf.. will detail the inspecting officer ion of the 1st Regiment of Infan- try, and Battery A: Colonel John ( the Inspecting oflcc i the Regiment of Infantry, Bignal '.. Hattigan. 2nd Infantry, will detail for tht inspection of the 2nd III. The inspection will be n sufflcienll informed, end itde to ascertain if the companies art -qaipped for active duty in the field: wheth 1 (1 properly kept: also as to the effici - nd non-commissioned officers, and of the lie v c ni|&gt; e; full repot ts of which will be made by the in- ;1 promptly forwarded to this office through n. Ian rl No. 17. II. Col. Joseph A. Btorcb, Isl and fix tN- hours for the i ml II spit :i 1 Corp: </seg>
            <seg id="p105">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 105 i IV. Company commanders will furnish the inspector ■ list, made mt on a quarterly property report blank, of the equipment left at home • •atiun. also that in camp. By order of the Governor C. F. SCHWARZ Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant General's Office Lincoln. August 10. 190 General Orders f No. is. i I. The state contest in rifle shooting, provided for by General or - ders No. It, A. G. O.. c. s.. will close August 11. 1M7. when all mem hers of the National Guard on duty in the said contest, will report to their respective organizations in camp near Lincoln, under General -Orders No. 1C. A. G. O.. c. s. II. The composition &lt;f the Nebraska National Guard Rifle Team, to participate In the Naticnal Competition as prescribed in General ■Orders No. 47. W. D.. dated March s. 19"7. will be as follows: f the tour of duty, the inenibe s will return tj tlieh n - itions IV Thr Adjutant Central will arrange transportation and sub - sistence, the allowance for enlisted men for subsistence being &lt;&lt;&gt;tniii ut- Captain Edmund H. Mullowney, 2nd Inf Captain. Majo- Fred J. Mack. 2nd Inf Coach. Major Ernest H. Phelps. Asst. Adjt. Gen! Spotter. Captain August Wagner. 1st Inf. Captain Charles E. Fraser. 1st Inf. Captain William E Osboine, 1st Inf. 2nd Lieut. Harry li. Hobhs. 1st Inf. 1st Serpt. Prmnh F. Willott Co. M. 2nd Inf. S«tkI. Edsar B. Bridges Co. L, 2nd Inf Serst. Waller D. Jenson Co. D, 1st Inf Sertrt. .lames K. Del.ancey Co. M. 2nd Inf Co:p. Waller F Peten '■&gt;. I), 1st Inf Corp. Daniel Switzet Co. I). 1st Inf. Mils Earl .1 Meixell Co. H. 2nd Inf. Priv. Charles A. Union Co. K. 1st Inf. Priv Frank Alliniiton Co. I,. 2nd Inf Priv. William P. Dii.Ty Co. B, 1st Inf Priv. Charles M. BttWMi Co. H. 2nd Inf. Ill The Team will k&lt;&gt; into camp on the state raiiKe on the lMn instant, for practice, and on the 22n&lt;l install! it will proceed to Camp IVrry. Ohio, »rd take part in the National Matches, and on completion </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 ADJITANT GENERALS REPORT &lt; i ed in advance at iht rate of tl.SO for each day during the time occupied in I ravel under this order, and for the number of days spent in camp Kerry. Ohio, during the progrwa of the shooting tournament. By order of the Governor C. P. SCHWAKZ. Adjutant Genera HEADQIAKTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL (JIARD / Adjutant Generals Offu \ Lincoln. Align t General Orders j No. 19. I. The following apimlntueBtii c.f Aides-de-Camp oa the staff of Jovernor George L. Sheldon, to rank from January :;. jyn; are an- nounced Colonel Charles B. Anderson Creu Omaha Oniahii Tekamah Colonel Charles H. Cornell Valentine Colouel George L. Da Superior Coonel .Irhn M. BllinxHwortb Lincoln Colonel Charles Grot I Omaha Colonel George Lyon. .It Nelson K lirbur Omaha Newport Colonel Fred NeiUon Bancroft Colonel Hen y J. Pen fold Omaha Colonel Albert A. Reed Colonel Landreth P. Kim Lincoln Colonel Herbert p. Shumwuv Wakefield Lincoln Omaha Nchawkn Colonel Kredevlc I.. Tempi) T.oxinsrto Colonel John G. Worklai Lincoli &lt;;eneral O dera No. i, A (I O . series of 1««5.) a Board of Officers &lt; oasisting of. Col. John D. Workizer. Aid-de-Canip. Major John M. Hirkner. Hospital Corp Capt. Allan I). Kalconer. 2nd Inlantrv. s ap|&gt;ointed to examine officers elect as to llieir fitness for commission* nd will meet in the t ffhe of she Adiiit»rt Qeneral on the Irst Tw^-«ay of Colontl Emil Braadies. . . . Colonel Tkomu C. Htym Colonel .lohii I'. Cameron Colonel John \\\ McDonnell Colonel The dore W. McCvllonch C clone I Ernes! I.. Myers Colonel William K. Btraub Colonel Arthur &lt;\ Smith Colonel Andrew V. Sinmi Colonel Millard K. Perry Lincoln. II. l 7 nder the in- visions of I be unitary Codr, (Section i:&gt; of a&lt;h month, hi I l a. ni.. &lt;oinnieni iiijr Tuesday. November SC. lW'iT </seg>
            <seg id="p107">An.lfTA.VT GENERAL'S REPORT 107 III. I'nder the provisions of So Nehiaska. Patrick H. Barry, at his retired list, with the rank of Brigadi [■tion 7245. Chapter ?&gt;?,. Statutes of own request, is phu-ed upon the tr General. General Barry enlisted Seplemli Third New York Volunteer Infantry. February 17. met, when he was dis&lt; •eived a t the liattle of Antietam. i-r 2. 1SC1. in Company E. Sixty - and served in that regiment until harmed on account of a wound re- Immediately upon his recovery July 17. IS63, he in Company A. 12th Massachusetts Volunteer Infantry, and was transfer - red to Company I), ::&lt;ith Massachusetts Volunteer Infantry. In Igatias; before Petersburg, mounds which necessitated the amp rlbow. H&lt;' was discharged October : Va.. &lt;n July 7. IM4, he received nation of his rijihi arm above the fl t A|ipoiutfd Adjutant (Jenert r the State of Nebraska. April 13. I8t". and January C. lxstft Re- 18»5. Ke-appointed January 2 1 signed January l. itoi; lesienatl pointed Brigadier General. Nebra Discharged March 2, I»u4. The Military record of Geners might well feel proud. Enlisting seventeen, he took part in many Civil War: among them being Siege Gaines Mill. Bottoms Ridge. Savagt Second Bull Kun. Antietam. Mine al Hairy is one of which any soldier in the fnion Army at the age of of the hardest engagements of the e of Yorktown. Battles of Fair Oaks, B Station. Cold Harbor. Malvern Hill. Run. The Wilderness. Laura! Hill, Spottsylvania Court House. Bowling Green. North and South Anna Rivers. Bethesda Church. Cold Harbor I second battle) and Petersburg on June 16, 17 and 1 8, 1 mm As Adjutant General of the Stat organization and discipline, gave an which placed the state troops among abled Nebraska to furnish the nation teers for the Spanish-Anie' ican war. ■ General Barry, through system, impetus to the National Guard, the best in the country, and en - with its quota of efficient volun- During the war with Spain. General Barry, as hei.d of the military ■n department of the slate, by his ex &lt;u ive ability, carried on the onerous duties of his office with marked Sill wringing credit to the state. and earning the gratitude of her volunteer soldier Because of his deep interest Its impDitance. he was one of th about a closer union between th in the National Guard, and realizing • foremost in the movement to bring 1 State troops and the fnited States Army, which resulted in the enactment of the 'nick Bill" by congress January 21. IMS, which secured t to which it is entitled, and placed i the National Guard the advantages in a more responsible position. By order of th Governor Adjutant General ignation arrepted February &gt;t, 1901. Ap- Nebraska National Ouard. March 1, 1901 V. F. SCHWA HZ. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 ADJUTANT UEXERAL'S KKI'ORT HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln, October 20. 190 General Orders / I. Paragraph III of General Ordes No. 6. A. G. O.. C. s.. is here - by revoked. II. Commencing October 1, 1907. the following will be the rate of pay to companies, for each drill of two hours, provided, however, that This payment be made for not more than one drill per week: Major. Commanding Hospital Captains Corp $ SO 1st Lieutenants. 2nd Lieutenants Sergeants 4.", 4&lt; Corporals. Artificers. Farriers Musicians and privates Blacksmiths and Saddlers 30 III. Thrie copies of pay roll, sworn to before a notary public. will be forwarded quarterly, so as to reach this office not later than the complete during the entire drill. In the marking of the present and absent, company command*;"* will use the greatest care in order to prevent the misappropriation of State moii. Roll will be called ;it the beginning and at the dose, of the two Lours drill, and no one marked present who has not been in ran'.cs hi complete uniform duringthe entire drill. IV. Company cemmandes will make a thorough inspection of the anl property of their commands at t):e last regular drill in each quarter, and if it is found that any article of | ublic property has been lost or damaged by the neglect or fault of any officer or soldier, notation thereof will be nii'de on the pay r. 11. and pay will be stopped for the amount of the same: provided, however, such person will bv tion, bonds, warrants, and other regular paper work, must be made on blanks furnished by this office. No. 2n. \ in formed ;it the time of elgBing the pay r 11 that his signature will !.»■ regarded ■■ ::n ackiKiwlcdpnuni of the justice of the charge, and an drier for the deduction Of the same from the amount of any pay due him; and provided further, that no rtoppage will t&gt;&lt;- finally deducted without a survey, if demanded. Paragraph i\\ of Den era I Orders No. C, A. (;. O.. &lt; a., is hereby amended provide that cervice pay, as p.ovided for uadei tion 40 of General Orders No. :,. A. O. O. aeriea 19u.",. will be paid on the MUne rolls as that for weekly drills. BOting in column of remarks for what months the pa) is due. VI. All lequisitions. receipts, invoices, returns, reports, rolls. vouch, is. enlistments, discharges, oaths of cffice. certificMtes of elec- </seg>
            <seg id="p109">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT 109 VII. Regular coi respondence paper will be furnished by this office upon requisition, and when other paper is used, it must be letter head size. I 1-2 by ll in^es, and contain only the designation of the brigade, regiment or conn any. post office address, blank date line, and in the upper left hand corner, a brief request for reference to a file num - ber in making reply; names of officers or other persons, or telephone numbers, will pot be print"- 1 "n letter heads.. VIII. No purchase of supplies, transportation or labor, will be approved except upon the written requisition of this office, and the written receipt for the mwiH— . transportation or labor, by a commis - sioned officer, accompanies me claim. IX. The attention of all concerned is called to sections 35 and 39 of General Orders No. .".. A. G. O.. series 19n.~&gt;. which will be strictly en - forced. X. Resignations of officers who are responsible for public pro - perty, will not be accepted unless accompanied by the receipt of the officer next in rank, for all public property for which the office' so re - signing, is responsible. XI. No certificate of election will be approved unless accompa - nied by the oath of office, bond when required, and a statement of pre - vious military experience of the officer-elect. XII. State vouchers for armory rent, or other claims, must be signed at the bottom as "claimant", in order that the warrant may pass through this office for record. XIII. No discharge will be granted for "Non-Residence", or "On Application", except upon the written statement of application of the oldler, forwuided to this office through military channel By order of the Governor C. F. SCHWARZ. Adjutant General HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) General Orders | No. II. i I Colonel Joseph A. Storch. 1st Infantry, and Major John M Birkner. Hospital Corps, ate appointed Surveying Officer*, under the provisions of the War Department Circular dated June L'V 1906, and will report by letter to the Adjutant General for duty. II. Accountable office! s will apply to this office for a survey of public property which has been lost, damaged, become uuserviceabl from use in service, or is unsuitable III. Officers responsible for public property will be chary iiy damn to. o~ loss or destruction of the same, and the money valu^ will be deducted from iheir pay. unless they show, io the satisfuclii rttary of War. hv their own affidavits, or by their cert I Beaten Adjutant General's Office (| Lincoln. October It, 1907. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 AD.) I'TANT GENERAL'S RKI'OUT ■&gt; supported liy onr i»r More affidavits, in triplicate, that the damay. «&gt;r destruction w«a o&lt; &lt; asiom-d by unavoidable (ansos and without fault or Mgleci on their pal The report of a surveying utti will then be submitted to tin- app approval Separate reporta will b&lt; rented. rr will l&gt;e prepared in triplicate, uud intiiiK atitlu-rity for approval or dio - madf for eai h staff department con- IV. Colonel Joseph A. Etorrk. 1st Infantry, and Major John M. Blrkner, Hospital Corps, are appointed Inspecting officers tinder the provisions of Section is of the Art of Congress approved January II, 1 »&lt;i :: . entitled. An ;■( t to promote the efficiency of the militia and for other purposes. " and will report l&gt;y letter to the Adjutant General for duty. V. Major John M. Blrkner, Hospital Corps, is detailed H Ius|&gt;ec - tor of Small Anns Prsrtlre. and will repcrt to the Adjutant General for duty. liy order &lt; I the ( verm C F. SCHWAKZ Adjutant General HKADQIAKTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL Gl'ARP) Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln. November 1C. 19 I. Section 7^:!ii Cobbevs Annotated Statut.-s of Nebraska. Sup - plement of liMi.V (Btaction and Appointment of Officers), published a» Section II. G. O No. .'.. A. Q. O.. 1 9 o r&gt; . requiring an examination of all officers appointed, elected or promoted, the following regulations for K»id examination are prescribed: II. The examination of officers will be conducted by boards select - ed by the Adjutant General. Each board will consist of three members senior in rank to the officer to be examined, one of whom shall be a medical efflce'. shall act as recorder. III. Officers detailed as members of examining boards will be selected with special reference to their fitness for the duties to be per - formed and will ordinarily be continued on such duty for a period of not ilian two years, except in cases of necessity. They will not be de - tailed upon duties which will interfere with the proper functioi. members of the examining boards. Or-&gt;nniieatioii and I»r»c*-duro. IV. The organization of examning board shall conform to that of retiring boards, the recorder swearing the several members, faithfully and impartially to examine and report upon the offlecer about to be ex - amined, and the president of the board then swearing the recorder to the faithful performance of his duty as member and recorder. Pro ceedings shall be made separately in each case. ;il Orders | No. ■:■. , </seg>
            <seg id="p111">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S RKF'ORT 111 It anything should arise dnrin troduction of evidence, the Inquiry shall proceed upon wrhten interro - iird determining to whom questions onducted according to procedure of &gt;n of the board, it Incomes essential calories as far a.s possible, the b( shall be forwarded, and shall be i ourts-martial. When in the opir i to take oral testimony, the fact hall be repotted to the Adjutant Oeneral for the necessary order* t witnesses summoned from a clis ill be sworn by the recorder. nee. Witnesses ixamined orally gh All public proceedings shall )&gt;, It the presence of the officer under ■xa.mnation: the conclusions reached and the recommendations tered in each case shall be regarded as confidential. xaminatior en- V. The board having been a xamined baring appeared before onvenins the board and the order t. the recorder shall re;&gt;d the order for the officer to report to it for ex - challenged for cause stated to the t which shall be determined by the of courts-martial. The record must xmination. Members may then be board, the relevancy and validity o full board, according to procedure ' show that the right to challenge wa nccorded. If the number of nirm- l.ers is reduced by challenge or otherwise, the board shall ndjoim." and the president of the board shall report the facts to The Adjutan. Oeneral for action. The proper complement being present, the member* f the board shall then be sworn VI. The examination of an offl ( d in the following order: (1) As er for promotion shall be co.idui t - to physical conditions: &lt; -' &gt; ».&lt; to efficiency: m as to professional :n of the board as to the fitn. shall show under whiili of these moral character: i to general litness. The record of the final opini n.;fitness of an officer for promotion head* the officers qualifications are COM vljich. if any. they are unsatisfactory. 7 Physical Hlne»s f,,r promotion _ Th » nledical offl( . er pr .,,, nm ,. (( thorough physical examination of all officers, and shall report their ..pinion, in writing, to the board. All questions relating to the physical fitness of an officer shall be determined by the full board. Defects of vision that may be entirely corrected by glasses, do not lisqualify. unless they are due to •ase. or are accompanied by, organic dis- VIII. When the board finds m officer physically incapaciated for .service. It shall conclude the examination by finding and reporting in full the cause which, in its judgment, has produced his disability and whether or not such disability was contracted in the line of duty The finding of the board shall be stated as follows: 'The board is of the? ■ pinion that physically incapaciated for service *nd was contracted ir is His disability is due to contracted in line of duty," and shall be- signed medical officers. If any member dis by all the members including the ients tram the opinion of the b-ard. shall be so stated Hie examination rcqul.lnc ihe in- lembled and the officer about to be idered satisfactory, and under </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 ADJUTANT GENERAL S REPORT IX. Moral fitness for promotion. Examining t&gt;oar&lt;ls art- expert "il to fully satisfy themselves with reference to the moral fitness of officer who come before them, making careful inquiry in all cases of doub To this end company commanders shall report in writing to niniinam ing officers any facts relating to lieutenants, which, in their opinion indicates moral unfitness to perform the duties of an officer. Whe any officer of their command is ordered for examination for promotioi commanding officers shall report at once in writing, to the president &lt; the examining board any facts in their knowledge relating to such offi cers, moral disqualifications, at the same time furnishing a &lt; opy of sal report to the officers concerned. These report! shall be thorough 1 inquired into and given due weight by examining boards in determinin an officer's fitness for promotion, provided that all proceedings d^'iin the examination of an officer as to moral qualifications shall be in tb presence of himself and counsel (if he desire counsel I : that he 1m? fur; iphed full information as to any allegations as to his moral c&lt;&gt;n in na.nes of accusers and witnesses, and documentary evidence •JCftini hat he be allowed to examine such witnesses and LTl4fnu testify and introduce evidence in his own behall. In the absence oi detrimental reports from commanding officers, from the records of the Adjutant General's Office, or other reputable and authentic .- officers shall be presumed to be of good character ;.nd no tfvliniimli «r I -tiers to that effect shall be required, submitted, or attache*! to I Hil's o« examining boards I-.. Kitni-ss hs regard- general efficiency : Tin- use nil .ifriot -r hw ir.i-d.' of hi- opportunities in the past, his ability to apply pr.ic: ih'c al his iHtpfessioi.al knowledge, and his general trustworthiness an 1 iMlti in the performance of his duties, shall be taken under consideration. T this end. whenever an officer is ordered fur examination for promotion The Adjutant General shalj forward to the president of the board a papeis on file in his office pertaining to. or affecting the efficiency of th officer; the commanding officer under whom he is .serving and the con manding officer of the regiment, without further instructions, shall fu nish to the examining board. In writing, a concise statement of th, the officer has made of his oppc: tunities for perfecting himself in h professional duties, of his appreciation of his responsibilities as a officer, and in the case of line officers, of his efficiency in control &lt; troops and his power of commanding men In case the statement con tains facts showing any disqualifications or failure on ihe part of a officer in these lespects. a copy of the statement shall be furnished t the officer concerned at the time it is made In the absence of evidenc to the contrary from authoritative sources . an officers fitness as to ge eral efficiency shall be assumed. XI. l'roressionul fitiio* for promotion. Kxaminations in all p c :ial subjects shall be oral and practical, with the exceptions her. inafter mentioned. During the oral and practical examinations of off cers. all the members, excepting the medical &lt; fficer. shall be p 111 II I </seg>
            <seg id="p113">ADJUTANT GENERAL'S RKPORT 113 I XII. The examination shall be uch as will fully test an officer s Knowledge of the general profession of arms, of all the details, theo- retical and practical of the part or parts of his profession in which by «uom of his opportunities, he should have |&gt;erfected himself, and of the general principles of all the duties pertaining to the particular orps. department, or arm of the service that may devolve upon him by n of his ■motion 10 the next higher grade. In all examinations the board w I m their opinion of an officers professional qualifica- tions by comparison of his knowledge with his age. service, and oppor- tunities for acquiring such knowledi LXIII. A bjert from Brer holding a certificate of proficiency in a required of th I'nited Slates Army will be ex- empt from the date of Mlbjt t for a period of five years from 1 XIV. The board shall prepare and prescribe for each examination pare and |&gt;: escribe for each examination mill number (if questions Ml each subject as it may deem necessary to nidi niiinl ach ubject as it may deem necessary to test thoroughly I he theoretical knowledge of the officer beins examined: test thoroughly Ihe theoretical knowledge of the officer being examined it shall also leqtlire sm h practical exercises, including problems, appro- priate to the subjects of the examination, as it may deem necessary to demonstrate his capacity to perform property the duties of the office rfoi roperly the duties of the office 11 for which he is examined. XV. Questions on each subject, as well as all practical exi XV. Questions cm each subject, as well as all practical exen required for the oral and practical examination, shall be prepared in required for the oral and practical examination, shall be prepared in writing and in quadruplicate, one copy for each member of the board writing and in quadruplicate, one copy for each member of the board and one for the officer beta I examined: for the written examination and one for the officer being examined: for the written examination 1 lint one copy need be made. For convenience in calculating percentage, but one copy need be made. For convenience in calculating percentage. n the board shall assign to each question asked, or exercise required in the board shall assign to each question asked, or exercise required in any subject, a value which shall Ik- entered cm the margin of the paper. any subject, a value which shall be entered on the margin of the paper. These values must aggregate !•• or some multiple thereof in each These- values must aggregate Imi or some multiple thereof in each subject of the oral, pi actual, or written examination. XVI. Where both oral tor written! and practical examinations subject of the oral, practical, or written examination XVI. Wh th oral lor written I and practical examinations are required in the same subject, the board shall re poll the peioentages are required he same subject, the board shall re poll the peicentages attained in each examination, in each subject, whether oral, written or attained in each examination, in each subject, whether oral, written or practical. No officer shall be passed who fails to attain 7.". per cent in practical. No officer shall be passed who fails to attain 7.". per cent in each oral or written, and in each practical examination in each sub- each itten. and in each practical examination in each sub \v ject. XVII. In c onduc lini; examinations the officer being examined j#.-t XVII. In conducting examinations the officer being examined shall be furnished with only such number of ouestions. or be iemiire.1 heel with only such number of qaeattoas, or be required to conduct su leal exercises as he may be able to answer or com- plete before a recess or adjournment is taken. As each question is an - swered or each exercise is completed, each member of the board snalt note his estimate of the value of ducted and the Mean of all thise the answer given or the exercise cou- th i sc- estimates of any question or exercise Khali be the marl' board on that question or exercise. From the mark thus determined by th hoard for the questions or exercises in any subject, tl ntage made in that subject shall be- calculated </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 AOIITANT GENERAL'S RKHORT XVIII Wiin.-,, examination,.. Written examinations .sliiill be N f. f.nently comprehensive in scope ,„ ,,. s , pl , )|)erlv ,„„ „„,.„,,, kll&lt; , wlw| m the Whole subject. They may ,„. conducted in the presence ,,f on.- member of the board, for which purpose the hoard mav be divided into committee, before whom the examinations shall he continued from da» to day until completed, after whirl, the hoard shall reassemble to deter - mine its findings Ineted hist bj a mc-dical officer ,.s| illy desiunated for the purpoae f h h '•■' -'«« '^^,. i ,,,,,:;::; l ';;;::::: 1 ;: den. o, the hoard, who shall communicate lh e,n to the Adjutant C, ,. nl , There shall he attached to and hied with th The- hoard is of the opinion that has the tjoneral efficiency and the physical, moral and K'vorrt ' ■■"■" &gt;»■« '&lt;&gt; mm nied wit i Hi,, record in h-..-i, sn JtEsrisr 1&gt;oard shan be stated a&lt;&lt;ordins - XIX. written examinations aliall.be held: let. In any nhjed in which the oral examination of a» ,,fli (^ r ■ s liBaattafactOry. I. „,„.„ eaae the written ,.x ;1I ,iin; t ,ion will be ,„,.'- • ..■&lt;l.-d with ■( once ' -'ml \\h..,,,.v^r. ..wi, ls to the exlgearie. of the icrrice it is in. |.ractj«ble for .n ntfi,,., ,„ „„„,„. U( . fl ,, t . , u „.„,,„„„ 1(()il] . (i ; Mcfc b -as,. h,s i.n.r.-ssi.mMl .-xannnati,,,, shall be nwducted entirely in wrii- &gt;&gt;. In the ,„■,,.,„, of an , ffi,,,- .le.si.Mu.ted l,v the convening anthori- '";■ '^""■"»~ &gt;»o.rd shall prepa,f , «tio M and problem* and rorward -h,n, to the ,l,.si,na,e,l offi,,,-. wilh ln . trilcUo J , o ™ \ "~ ...e..io 0 . ausw,,,,, in ,„„,, The .ne.li,,,, examination ,hal ,„„ </seg>
            <seg id="p115">An.jrTA.NT GENERAL'S RKJ'ORT 115 XXIII. Hill one ropy of the lamination will be required. proceedings ;md record of boards mt r XXIV. To assist the boards and in the nterest of uniformity la he examinations, boards will 1 furnished by the Adjutant General with lists of questions on eertali subjects of examination with values d. Boards w I. Hoards will not Ik- expected, however, to use or to confine v.s exclusively to Ike questions contained in these lists, but are Iv. to the iiiiestions contained in these lists, but ar« d iisk ;my questions with suitable values attached led to frame and ask an; questions with suitable values attached from the publication! recommended for study, or to use black- k ' u "' '■'■ ""»*■'■ illustrations which will facilitate its work and which or other Illustrations which will facilitate its work and which leem nereraary duriim the progress of the oral, wiitten or prac- It Dli deem necessary (luring the I 'Kress of the oral, wiitten or prajr- t iniinalions. ■ proceedings of examining boards shall be made up according xaniinlnj; boards shall be made up according; i furnished by this office and shall be forwarded to The Adjutant for final action. PinAiiiiluaai Kviuniimtion Hahjprta of ** — n'nllsn See and shall be forwarded to The Adjutant &lt; Prmft isilnsml K\ii in iimtioii XXV. Kor .Medical Oflferr*. Subject- of F.Miiiiiiiafion V. Kor Mc.li, al (Mil Mb. six months from date of a intment X months from date of appointment Lieutenant, and enant. and on promotion from Lieutenant to Captain. Medical department administration, covering: (■) Army Regulations, BO tar as they relate to the Medical Department or to the medical office a* an ogfcer of the National Cuanl. (b) Manual for Ike Medical Depart meat. (c) Drill Regulations, Hospital Corps. id» Field service Regulations: Organisation of the Medi - cal Department: shelter: medical and sanitary service. Hygiene, general military. Furnish certificate that he is entitled to nra iriiia Medical department admin Army Regulation f r as they relate to the Medical 11 Heal officer as an officer of the X Manual for the Medl al Department 'spital Corpa. Drill Regulations, H utions: Organization of the Medi •Iter: medical and sanitary service Department: slit Hygiene, general military. Furnish certificate that he ntitled to prartfc and surgeon under the laws of Nebraska. and surgeon under the law f XebiasU F lotion to Major. promotion to .Major Medical department administration. (a i Same as for Lieutenant to Captain. Same as for Lieutenant to Captain. Manual for the Medical Department. Field Service Regulations same as for Lieutenant to Captain, and in.structicns for sovernment of arms of the (bl Manual for the Medical Department. 111 h " it " l(1 S»''vice Regulations same as for Lieutenant to Captain, and in.structicns for government of arms of the I'nited States in time of war war Hygiene, gcaernj and military. Law (•) Military law: K enen,| courts-martial: inferin: martial: G. O. No. .",. A. G. O.. 1 !• jur martial: G. O. Xo. 5, A. G. O.. 1 105 (1.1 International: Geneva Convention: Hai;ne Conference International: Gent XXVI. For Officers of the Signal I Kor Officers of the Signal CWns. Administration Army Kesulation b i .Signal Corps Regulation </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 AD.MTANT GENKRA1 RKI'ORT Field Service Regulations (a) Organization (l)i Service Information. lc) Instructions for ihe overnment of the Arnica (if Inited States in time Visual signaling. of wa Military law F&lt; )inotion to First Lieutenant me as for p: oinotion to .Second Lieutenant and Ilie employment of Military force (Article XXXVI. Regnla tions of the Nebraska National Guard, IK»6.) F. promotion to Ciiptain me as for First Lieutenan and Telegraphy and telephonv • • • 4 Courts-martial XXVII. Chaplain*, six months after appointment I. Administration. Army Regulation*, so far as they relate to the duties of ch lains as officers of the National (iuard. An essay of not less than four thousand words upon the work of a chaplain in the military service, and the methods hy which it may liest lie accomplished. XXVIII. Par Ml Tin of Infantry. For promotion to Second Lieu - tenant. 1 Administration Army Regulations at the discretion of the Hoard. To be suf - ficiently extended to determine whether the candidate Is •«- Diiliar with the subject generally, as well as with his duties un - der the regulations, the conduct of military correspondence, and the preparation of con pan; papers. Drill Regulations To Include the general p ■quad, manual of sabre 1 1 Manual of Guard Duty. inciples. schools of the soldier and iractical I . and honors;. ror Promotion to Fiist Lieutenant 1. Administration. Same as promotion to Second Lieutenant Drill Regulation*. Same as for promotion to Second Lieutenant and School of th« Company, the Company in Battalion, and Ceremonies. la I &lt;: O. No. .",. A. &lt;;. ().. 1!" </seg>
            <seg id="p117">AD.HTANT GENERAL'8 RKPORT 117 Fii'lil Service Regulations I)- sufficiently extended to determine whether the ofllc 1 111; examined is familiar with the subject generally, as wo wilh his duties under the regulations mall Arms Firing regulation be sufficiently extended to determine whether the officer ng examined is familiar with the subject generally, m with hi., duties arising under the regulations, and to inrlud x w men I of Military force (Article XXXVI, Regulation* Nebraska National Guard. 18»6&gt;; 0. O No \. A G O Guard Man r Adm Army Regulation* at the discretion of the Hoard To be sufllci ■li t ly extended to determine whether the officer being examin iniliar with the subject generally as well as with his rising under the regulations and to include exercise* at ion of company papers and accounts, and mlit- 1 A demonstration of the ability i:f the officer being examined iiiiind troops in the exercises and maneuvers include command of a company in on drill and of his knowledge of the chapters on the sabre I practical I . marches, camping (1 In in Field Service Regualtlon fficiently extended lo determine whether the officer mined is familiar with tile subject generally as well ties under the regulations, and to include ex - ireparation of orders. w\ Small Anns firing Regulation .Same as for pi immt ion to First Lieutenant uard Mai Enti Ml w notion to First Lieutenant, and Courts-Martial II For promi M; 1. Administratioi Same as promotion to Captain preparation of records and report </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 AHM'TAN T GENERAL'S KKI'ORT A demonstration of the ability A demonstration of the ability of the officer being examined to if the oflcer being rxamined to instruct and command troop* instruct and connuid troopa in the exenises and maneuvers in the ezeiciaea and maneuvers of the drill regulation! &gt;pp of the drill regulation! app opiiate to ■ battalion and a regiment. Field Service Regulation*. Field Service Regulation At the discretion of the Board. At the discretion of the Hoard To include writing of orders and To Include writing of orders and exercises in indicating on maps the dispositions to be made of forces of strength ■&lt; t less than a tesjiment u advance jtiiarU rear piard, outpost. and when on the march. 4&lt;i Military Law Same as foqr onirtion to Captain Minor Tactu One or more tactk al piohlen to be given by the Board. The officer being examined to pi re the orde s for the troops and to indicate on the map fiirnisl d htm for the purpose, the posi- li; us of the iroops for such tion as would lie demanded un- der the conditions ot the p-.ol 111 deterniloe whether- the officrr w 'lie general principles of the subject Equation Practical. ronioti.n to Lieutenant Colonel Same as fur promotion t:i M Hid Colon ijor. omit in it i in and 4. and * me as for promotion to Ma jor. substituting "iirigade" for reRimeii &gt; of not |ecH i hau tin Hi iis.md words upon a subject in« cm the efficiency ( ,t i \ XXIX All c rclc-is or pans of end liionsisteut with the provis- this older are hereby revoked B} order of the ( ASKA NATIONAL GLARD/ E-nerul'i O9c« \ i' : In. December General Orders j \ I ■ •" ."mp.iance w,,h Q. O. N,,. 22 2. War ll,,,a,tn:e.,t. c. S .. nnd "" ll1 ""' 1 wiI " ""• "Military code of the State of NVhr».k, L. C Military Hyirien To be sufficiently extended being Pin mined is hmiilh.r vrnior. f F. 8CHWAR2, Adjutant General HBADqrARTERS NHI Adjutant -■:.. In xinipliaiK c with (i o. \ ( E-rcora.-™ »"„ ,„, military ,,,,1, of the 8Ute of Xebra.ka . medical •!»""«« "f -h,. Krtnuk. SCttaul G.,«rd is hereby ,,,-^nized, to </seg>
            <seg id="p119">AD.MTANT (1KNKRA KKI'ORT 119 I surgeon Ken with rank of / • hi \v Ml- f I Jfu tenant-Colonel 4 KiiiKrons. wi s assistant sm N assistant sut II. In fnrthe of Mali Hi. I into lia 1st. H li 1 ( ( mil in I. Kushvillf ( 1111 I tin I.. Omaha 2nd Batallion. ('onipanv A, York niton F. Madison. K. ('(iliimbu &lt; mil mil M, Broken Bow n i mil ini| M, Albion mi mi ( Mill .1 H I). Hastini H. Anrora 111] n\ *s !ilmni il \l ianalioii. \. j.; Infty. 1st Hattalion. Major Fred .1. Mack, \ iid Battalion, Major Heibert J t I'aul. St Pai (I H Itallon, Major Waller F. Sam- K'iirn«'\ . &gt;ns. with rank of Captain. )tis. with i an k of 1st Lieutenant. umpliaacw with Q. o. No. 2SS, Wmt I&gt;e|&gt;artm«r.t, the Nebraaka Natiunal Guard are hereby organ- iftv. lsl Hiitt 'ompaaj ii. Wi^'pitiK Water 'ompany H. Nelson. Company E, Wilber C 'llll|i;in\ (!. C. ny K. Si hu: ny L, Alma »&gt; ('. XHinisk:i City B, Tekamah. &lt;:. Omaha I, Ofetiaha. A. K.m </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 ADJITANT GENERALS RAI'ORT IV On receipt of this order, each major will, in accordance with law, recommend to this office, through the colonel of his regiment, his battalion staff, consisting of: 1 Hattalion Adjutant. 1st Lieutenant. 1 HattHlion Quartermaster. 2nd Lieutenant The colonel of each regiment, on recommendation of the respec - tive majors, will appoint a sergeant major for each battalion of his :»-Kimeiit. V. In further compliance with G. O. No. 222. War Department, the following medical officers are hereby relieved from duty with their respective organizations, are transferred to the medical depart niijit. and will report to this office by letter, for assignment to duty: Col Prank S. Nicholson. Surgeon General Maj. .Icbn M. Birkner. Ambulance Company. Maj. ClilToKl W. Walden. Surgeon. 2nd Infantry Maj. .lames B. Hungate, Surgeon, 2nd Infantry. Capt. George A. Heath. Assistant Surgeon. 2nd Infantry Capt. Km i 1 ('. I'tiderberK. Assistant Surgeon. 1st Infantry ('apt. Samiu-I .1. Stewart. Ambulance Company. 1st Lieut. Char lea K. Gibbons. Assistant Surgeon. 2nd Infantry George K. Spear. Hospital Steward. 2nd Infantry VI '111.' Ambuiince oCmpany will hereafter be designated as Fi'-ld Hospital No. 1. ;ind organized as fellows: ."&gt; sergeants, first da rgeaats. B8 privates, first class and private 7i; Total enlisted I minimum.) VII. The standard of physical examination for recruits for the I" s Army is adopted for the Nebraska Natonal Guard, ami the exami - nations will be conducted in accordance with V. S. A. Regulations By order of the Governor C F. SCHWAKZ Adjutant General 1st Lieut. John F. Spealman, Ambulance Company </seg>
            <seg id="p121">&gt; 2 a: 7 IT n ■ &gt;2 r;?» - *T.~.V. y sim^im ? 2 • ? ■ S 5 ? I ' * *t '""* -* 5 1 3 ~j- &gt; '*'*'- -7? 2'= ; _r? m 7l.-'- = j; — r - - x -! — -. x _ — -s - 8 3 1 mnnm \ \\ - ' 3 " ? -CDrJ?- ICO 5 5 - r?s.7;-'_---- = -- if a ? 5 - a S. =, — ?s ?£^ r- — - .~ ; 3 = 3 — - — = s =- : : : I : -f ? ; § | ~= iz = : = : ; ::.-::: aw yar.it, , - T -HH) vanls - r -' - ;i _; -^i w sa^a*.* it * 3M yard-. ; '.■ ■ • i" &gt;: r £ £ ............ :,ii(i yards 3 "S | o" „ _ - _=_^ - - ■, m „ = ~ '■"O yards 3 ["S _■ — i; u -■ _ — i- ic - s IS 2 a ~ - ■ ' ~ P3 -- - - - — - - - - - - - - Total * S-'S &gt; "•"S &gt; =jj ~ Z £ Z -.' - - a ;~ j. i- - ■ &lt;? 3 S! its r = = r r- r = 3 n n ri r (1 «o y«"t« = a S , ;^.-___ r .. r _ ",.fo vards Tim, I | I. | g ■n't • &gt;00 yanls r V^l If 3 200 yards J . F ire = f « i'~ x -J £• g .-_■ § * :J j» J - |j rj •» B««t run j/- 2 1^ !l n 7 ? OB 7 .-08 ~- --ZZZZ-ZVZ*^ Tutal ? J Total &gt; " X ■&lt;5 »w S '£ -retrate 8 Apt; rebate ■J_^i I ►§ „ &lt;.M, yards S- ?_S&gt; &gt; MB yards 2 I . ? _ £; &gt; - -• r-. i' c — . -■ — . &lt;i i ; -*-■&gt;; 2 ~iS ■&gt;■ * ;!etC tKaj . u ».»tt»i KWOyanls ; §- &gt; « *■ 6&gt;ce-i3icosae — 5 2 -~ —• r* 77~ xxx-.-.xxxxx Total J jf * g * n MM,,, Total ifoS - O -.-!.--*- K =r. -4 w** r; « ' " jr ~r 20 &gt; so =n c x !~ — „ y yyu--i;i;^^uy^ A ifi? rebate 3 5 zr ~ ■» -i </seg>
            <seg id="p122">AJj.ll TANT GKNKRALS REPORT Marksman * Courgp Slow Fire MARKSMKN IHIIiert A Ferguson. Private. Co. E, 1st Infantry .lolin I.. Cilison. Sergeant, Co. L, L'nd Infantry . . .lames It. Hungate, Major. 1st Infantry 4 s 4.". 4 2 13 4 2 II 4 C 1 i 4 7 38 38 1J ■&lt; .lames Barnes, Sergeant, Company I 1st Infantry 4043 40)1 il Aubert, Captain, Company A 1st Infantry 4n ::s 1 2 12&lt;&gt; 1*1 Infantry :;:i :;\i 42 1 Howard B. Heath. 1st Lieutenant. ( mpany K. 1st Infantry 4 4 ::t ::'.i 120 Fred I!. Fraeer, Sergeant. ( oni|iany K. 1st Infantry :::i :;s 1:: 1 1 Holland P. Daisy. Corporal. Company ,\. 1st Infantry .... 12 :!'.i :'.'.&gt; 120 Albertus C. Meisenhaeh. Private. Company E, 1st Infantry 4" 41 :;'.&lt; 1 fcverett K. Dale. Private. Company I. 1st Infantry 40 41 38 11 Uamnion, Private. Comiiany I, 1st Infantry :;s 411 411 11 42 11 H. K. Miller. Corporal, Coni|iany I. 1st Infantry 41 |n :;,; n in ::n t 4 I :: s :: 4 1 1 George S. Dale. Private. Company st Infantry :;s |i&gt; :;i; 1 1 4 Krnest ( . Creene. Private. Compan M. 2ii I Infantry 38 36 :'.'.) 1 1 Rollin P. Smith. Sergeant, Compan A. 1st Infantry .... ::s :::i :::&gt; 1 y A. 1st Infantry ... :: 7 36 39 1 1 .' t« 111 K. 1st Infantry :t;i :::, :;7 n 2nd Infantry :|s ::s :::, in ny M, 2nd Infantry. . II ::-- ::s 11 1 K. A. Miller. Sergeant. Company ml Infantry .... ::.". :i'.i :;:, in Infantry Martin C. Shallenberger, Ca|&gt;taln ( o. L. I'nd liifiumy u :;,s |o 12" Ivi-r s. .Johnson. (';i|itain Company ni|iiiiy M 2nd Infantry Aitlnir ('. Hoonc. 2nd Lieutenant. &lt; II ::n US 4:: 41 n :. 4" 4H Us I \V Owen, Coriforal, Coni|iauy A. 1st Infantr Chris L. Anderson, Sfrs^mt. ( om i &gt;;&lt; ny H, i si Infantry En-en:-. ■ i;. Grimm, Csrporal, c.oiii|i:iny E. 1st Infantry. ill's I". HuslihcrutT, 1st Lieutenant. Co. K. L'n 1 Infant nest H. Byeis. Private. Company L, I'm! Infantry • Ili'iin A. Tucker, Coriiora!, Conniai r H. I'.i.'lps. Major, A. A. ( El.inton. Private, Compan Miissli'iiiiin. Private. Co!ii|iany )ii H. Da\is, 2nd Lieutenant, Co;i Itcrt .1. Brian, Sergeant, Company I- </seg>
            <seg id="p123">Maiksmai Conn Slow Fir x . so ;&lt;'.; ID I » 4 33 1»4 ) i i t \ &gt; • I t ADJCTANT GENEF rlAL'S RKI'OKT MARK3MK.V BUI (1 Cecil K. H:s In rger, l'riv I^ouis E. 7.un ' r. M Ausiistis X. Unlsf. A Ern.st R. Ha Ivan McK ( Chas. \V Outran William E. (liiftin. Private. Coiini:iin F. 1st Inf Jo'.in Horn. P Hans M. AniUrson. Private. Coni|tany B, 1st I nf.it Will. Do 2nd Infai Philip F Jandebuer. M Fre.l Fayrtn- C.t re De (Iroot. Private, Company F. 1st Ugar Diets. Sergeant, Company A, I'm! Inf Harry Schmidt, Sergeant. Company A Robert E. hpratt. Corporal, Company F. la) Infa Winfred We I.ouis \v. Skala, Bergrint. rompaa.v K. 1st infantry :,- 3(3« pi:» Osbornp l&gt;. Latta. Jnd Lieuli nant. Company I). 1st Infantry . In 38 36 lm Ed\v:ii(l A 7. Compamy K. 1st Infaatry :: ) ( oHipiinv K, L'nd Inf.intry. . . . :;:. Fn\l .1. Mirk, Malar, 2nd Infantry I si Infantry 2nd Infantry ul Infantry . Captain ('. H&lt; niuny L, 2nd infanti y John H. Hiork. 1st Utiituiant. Coiii|i;inv K. 1st Infantry E:ic I'rock. ( ook. Company K, 1st Infantry pci W. Xye. Corporal. Company B, l«&lt; Infantry lil stcikiin. Art. Company B. 1st Infantry.. (has. \\ . Ostranrier. Private. foiii|&gt;:iny I, 1st Vein C. Cady. Private. Company I.. 2nd lufar Charles Brooka. Private. I'omnan* I. 1st Infa Rob.it F. Billir ('. K. SPHWARZ. A </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 AD.HTANT GENERAL'S REPORT i HEADQIARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) Adjutant Generals Offi&lt; \ Lincoln. Match 2. 1 Mi&gt; I The use of "Winder'* Improved Armor) Targets" is eontinu pd in the Nebraska National Guard II: Hereafter, gallery qualification* will be made on these targeti required in "Coarse C," and will be reported on regular blanks marked "gallery" classification, and figure of merit will be determine* n the same manner as for outdoor range practice with the service ri fit III. A soldier must qualify as marksman in nailery practice befor he will be permitted to fire on the ratine with service rifle. Company • omnianders will take the necessary action for compliance with this ■ ■ider IV. All Gallery qualifications will be made previous 10 May 1. ii ich year, except recruits, and others for approved reasons. Recruits a ill be Riven sixty days in which to qualify after en list men I V. Company commanders will not expend more than muds Rallery ammunition per man for those qualified to practice in the u'al- ry VI.. Company mm wanders will not forward monthly reports ol llery practice; bat, immediately on completion of gallery practice wili I' iward reports without delay to the- Inspector of Small-arms Practice. VII. The following appointment of aides-de-camp on the staff ol Governor George L. Sheldon, are announced Colonel William Bischof, Jr., Nebraska ( Colonel Oihniel G. Horn. Sviacuse us VII. Paragraph II of General Orders No. 19, dated August is amended so as to provide thai commencing Tuesday Apiil 2 1. the Hoard of officers to examine candidates for commissions will ne third Tuesday h month, instead of the last Tuesday consecrated to the brave who di,-.l the preat cause for which they of. it is earnestly desired that all or- not for themselves, but on behalf of fered themselves a willing sacrifice. ganizations of the Nebraska National Guard, lend such assistance as &gt; S within their power, to any patriotic- organisation* arranging appropri - ate observances of the day. thus honoring both the living and the dead No. I. By order of the Governor. C. F 3CHWARZ. Adjutant General HKADQI-.ARTER.S NKBRASKA NATIONAL OUARO) Adjiitam General'! Office Lincoln, May 9. IHuv ifneral Orders / No. ::. j In recognition of Memorial Day. coneecrated In the h»m .1,,, ,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">ADJTTAXT GENERALS RKI'OKT 125 b. l.t. Col. .1 SI. Hirkner. Mediial Department. Insp. Small Arras Practice, will report to the Adjutant C.eenral at Ashland. Xebr., Satur- day. July -v inns, for duty with troops engaging in target practice on the State Rifle Range. Major George A Bberly, Isi Infantry, with his staff (1 Battalion Adjutant, l Battalion Quartermaster and Commissary and For this purpose the above organisation! of the State of Nebrai (I hereby graated permission to parade folly aimed and equipi&gt;ed Satnr rl:i \ . May 30. 1 9» V In accordance with Paragraph 444. 1'nlted States Army Regnhi lijnis. the national Ha*; will lie displayed at half-staff on all ;,rmoi public buildings fioni sunrise till midday. At noon the flat will b&gt; hoisted to the top of the staff and remain there till sunset By order of the Governor. C F. 8CHWARZ. Adjutant &gt;;eneral. HKADQIARTKKS NEHKASKA NATIONAL GUARD j Adjutant ('lenerals Offi&lt; e \ l.incnln. .Inl&gt; in, | lelieral Orders j No. 4 \ I. a. Brig. Cen 1 C. K Bckwan, Adjutant Ceneral. Major K. H. 1'helps. Asst. Adj. (len'l. Capt. Brad P. Cook. Asst. Q. M. with the nee- •ssary office force will proceed to the State Rifle RanRe. near Ashland. Vebr.. Saturday. July 1 v 1!tos. to prepare for and have general direction if the troops of the State, engaging in tarsiet practice at thai point. 1 Battalfoa Bergeaat Major), will report to the Adjutant General at Ashland. Nebr.. Sunday. .July IS. I «+&lt;ts . f&lt;i r duty with troops eBftadM in iar«et practice OB tin- State Rifle Ranye for ten days BCKlnning .lul&gt; I'll, 1 H &lt; i s . b. The following organizations with the number of office's and •nlisted men indicated will report to Major A Eberly. 1st Infantr Ashland. Near., on July :.'(&gt;. lwns. for ten days target practice on th* State Rifle Range: Company R. Igtantoa), 1st Rei;.. ] Officers and 3« enlisted men. (dinpanv I). | Weeping Water). 1st Re^t . -1 officers and :;n enlist- ■d men Company K, (Wilbur), 1st Rest. :', offiiers and :',n enlisted men. Company V, (Madison I. 1st Re S t.. :! Officers and 38 enlisted men Company I.. [Omaha), 1st. Keu;t.. :! Officers and :lti "nlisted men. Company K.( Tekamah I . L'nd Rent.. :: Officers and J« enlisted men Company Q, ( Omaha I. Retit.. :: Officers and :'." enlisted men Company I. (Omaha I. !M Ret't.. :: Offiiers and :'.» enlisted men Caaip«B]r K. (SclMivleri. L'nr| Fte-t.. :: Officers and 311 e- listi d men C mpany M, (Albion), 2nd Rest.. ?. Officers «nd :!" eni Signal Coips. i Kremoni I. 1 Officer and It; enlisted me., </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 ADJITANT GENERALS RK1OKT ! :oli 19 4 t i 1 1 1 I* 1 1 t in r t ml li HEADQ1/ARTER8 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD) Adjilt nut General's Office Lincoln, January u 1 . l !• No. 1 . \ I. The annual Inspection greas approved January 21, IMS \ . Retired, on the datas n 11 Illli vttoa 14 of tilt- Ail of Ci made by Major !.. I". Darts will I), null In i i\V ( o. A, o. M "o. I, ( ( ( ( ( 1st lnf Saturday Feb. , 2nd lnf Monday. 1st lnf Tins lay. Feb. 2 1st lnf Wednesday, Feb b;. Corps Thursday. Feb. 2nd lnf Friday. Feb. 28 ) M F o. It, 'o. Si •o. K ( t Saturday, h ( ( o. I 2nd lnf Monday. Mch 2nd luf Tut sday. Men. nil lnf \Vi-ilnesd:iy. Mi 1st lnf Friday. Mch. 8 o. E o. 1 o L ( I Saturday. Mch I o. H land 9, A . 2nd lnf Monday, Mch. '.&gt; &amp; Co.B, 2nd Tuesday, Mch. 2nd lnf Wednesday, Mch 2nd lnf Thursday, Mch. 2nd lnf Friday. Mch. 1 :: I ( ( o. 1) o. L. ( Saturday. Mch. 1 &lt; o. K 1st lnf Monday. Mch. 1« 1st inr Tuesday. Mc!i. l 1st, lnf Wednesday, Mch. 1st lnf Thursday, Mch 1st lnf Friday. Mch. 13 ( ( l K o. (' o. H o. li ( Saturday, Mch Lincoln ( Lincoln Weeping Water ( Weeping Water Lincoln Wednesday. Mch Company commanders will t 7::;n p. in., on the dates mini nilile their commands under a I'niforms, dress (blue). d II. The inspection is mndt with the view of ascertaining what lEanlsations are suffiicentlv e^nlpped for duty in the field. All prope must be arraaced for conTenlenl inspection, and articles of uniforni a equipment, which have been issued to members of the company, il played in their respective" lockers. irder of th Governor C. F SCHWAR7. Adjutant General General Ordem / 1st lnf WkIiii s&lt;l;i\ . K 1st lnf Thursday, F« Hand. 1st Inf Hosp. ('i)rps *i Monday, Moh. ' Co. F. Und Inf J Co. I). 1st Inf Tuesday. Mch LEAVE AHKIVK Lincoln York Uroken How Rushville Albion Madison Stanton Fremont Schnyler Lincoln Omaha 'I ekamah Omaha Nebraska City Lincoln Aurora ml. Kearney Hastings Alma Lincoln Wither ■\Vymorf Heat rice Nelson Cn-ne\ a York Browea How Hns.ivill,- Albion .Madison Stanton Fremont Scbuyler Lincoln Omaha Tekamah Omaha Omaha Nebraska Cit&gt; Lincoln Aurora St Paul Kearney Haatlasi Alma Lincoln Wilber Wymore Heat rice Nelson I leneva Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p127">ADJl'TAXT OKNKRAI RKPORT 127 III. a. Major Fred .1 Mark 2nd Infty.. with his staff. I I Battal- ion Adjutant iilion Quartt talion Sergeant Major), will report t lie Adjutant General ;if Ashlan 1 Nebr. Wednesday, July 29. i«ii&gt; Inly with troops engaging in target on tr Kit). Ra age for ten days beginning July ::u winn oruanizali n with the number ol officers and Major Fred .1. Mack. 2nd Infi Ashland. Nebr., on Julv 30, l»0S »n days target practice on th State Rille Rai Company A. I York 1 . 1st l{ Officers and 20 enlisted men Dinpany c. ( Beatrice i . 1st h Officers and 60 ( nlisted men Company G, (Geneva), 1st Re 1 Officer and 20 enlisted men I Officer and 20 enlisted men Companw H. (Nelscnl, 1st I Officers and :',n enlisted men Campany C, (Nebraska Clt 2nd Kt in. impaoy F. i Lincoln i . Ind F '.. ■ ', Officers and l&gt;0 enlisted men d Separate Co., (Crete). 2 Offl rs and :',0 enlisted met rps ( Fremont I. 1 Offi&lt; "r and 1 0 enlisted men Field Hospital. I Lincoln I. 1 Offl r and 1 6 enlisted men IV. a. Major H. .1. Paul, 2nd Infantry, with staff. I 1 Battalion Adjutant. 1 Battalion Quartermaster and oCmmissarjr, and l Battalion Sergeant Major), will report to the Adjutant (leneral at Ashland. Nebt Sunday. August 9, 1*08. for duty with trams miulu in i&gt;,r,r..t ,&gt;,:»■ ri, for duty with troops engaging in target practice the State Rifle Range for ten d; li. The following organization with the number of officers and en- listed men indicated will report to Major H. .1. Paul. 2nd Infantry, at Ashland. Nebr.. on August 1». I Hips for ten days' target practice on the State Rifle Ran Campany M, ( Broken Bow), l t Infty . 2 Officers and :lit enlisted men Company A. I Kearney p. 2nd Infty., J Officers and 30 enlisted men Company B.I St. Paul). 2nd Infty., :; Officers and 60 enlisted men Company I). (Hastings!. 2nd Infty., :: Officers and SO enlisted men Company H. (Auroral, 2nd Infty.. :; Officers and 60 enlisted nun Alma. 2nd Infty.. 1 Officer and Alma, 2nd Infty.. 1 Officer and ::ii enlisted men. nlisted men 1st Separate CoaipaBjr, I Kenes; iepaiate Company. I Kenes »W&gt;, 1 Officer and 3t ( -nli.-,i.-&lt;l men I Officer and 36 enlisted men. wi. 1 Officer and 30 ea listed men 'gel, 1 Officer and iiu enlisted men 2nd Separate Company, I Holdr d Separate Company. ( Holdr Signal Corps. I Fremont 1 . 1 Offl ignal Corps. I Fremont I. 1 Offi cer and 1C enlisted men er and 1G enlisted men Field Hospital. (Lincoln), 1 Offic V. a. Company Commanders Field Hospital. ( Lincoln 1 , 1 OfB V. a. Company Commander! er and It; enlisted men. and Commanding; officer of the er and It; enlisted men and Commanding officer of the Band, Signal Corps and Field Hos|: show preference to those who have Band, Signal Corps and Field Hos &gt;ital in their selection of men will been faithful in attendance at and show preference to those who hav been faithful in attendance at and t-fficient in their weekly drills throng efficient in their weekly drills throu ■• hcuit the year They will also report hoiit the year They will also report Field Hospital. (Lincoln). Hand. (St. Paul p. 2nd inf.. I Ofllrt Jind 2~&lt; enlisted mun. master and Commissary and 1 Bi nlisted men Indicated will rei Dipanv K. i w Officers and t;&gt;i enlisted beginning August 10, l </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 ADJl'TAXT GENERAL'S RKl'ORT &lt; to the Adjutant General before .Inly |5, litns. whether they will be able to luiiiK the designated number &lt;if offlcera and mt-n to Hie target rang at the time specified 1). Organizations will report in serrlre nniforn fully armed and equipi&gt;ed for field service. All lentage and .ill ramp equi.iaiie will I will bf All rifles and bayonets, aad ammunition on hand in each organisa tion will he brought t.i Ashlaad where new rittes and hi lit km will !&gt;•&gt; issued io the organizations whose old rifles and b will report to the Adjutant Genera I at Ashland. Sebr.. Saturday. .In IS. I Mo s . for dni\ with troops paa Rifle Rani King in tar It Major .1 B. Huogate. Medic Adjulant Ceneral at Ashland. Neln . with troops engaging in target prartii ■ Kinaing .Inly 20. 1 90S. il Depart meat, will re| Sunday, .Inly It, mns. for dutj ■ on the State Rifle Halite for ten Major c w Walden. Medfa I Department, arl t to thi Vdnnant General at Ashland. Xelir dni&gt; with troapa engaging in target pi ten da&gt;s beginning .Inly 30. l»08. Wednesdav . lnl\ Jf, litns. for ;i&lt; ti&lt;c (■!! the State Rifle Range for Medical Department, will re- port to the Adjutant General al Ashland. Nehr.. Sunday. Atiii'ist :&gt; !••». for duty with troop* engaging in target practice on the Stat&lt; Hitle Range for ten days beginning VII. All officers and enlisted August |0, l&lt;(ns men of the N. X. G. not included above and who desire to take the prescribed In days' course in rifle tit ing, will report by letter to the Adjutant General before .Inly IS tons jntant General before Ju I. r 1.",. inns in* any preference they may have for time of praotk-e. All offi -hould brim their own bed rolls, etc. Meaning arrangement, will inged for at reasonable rates. VIII The Slate Rifle Team will || f . selected during this target leaaoa and will be ordered to Ca.np Perry, Ohio, for the National Team I Match. August -l I, inns By order of ih ( &lt; vernor C K 8CHWARZ Adjutant Gen&lt; l.muiilu by encfa &lt;&gt;rs;inizitii(in. No rooking outfits ami no t brought except ;ts nun be d heeled in sjieciitl orders. v (leaned \ I a. (Nil. F. S. N'lcholaon. Medical Depiu inieni Snr^eim c.n 1 1st Ueutemam Cb«». K. Oibl </seg>
            <seg id="p129">f ADJUTANT GK.VRRAL'S RKPORT HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARDJ Adjutant General's Office \ Lincoln, August 18, 1908 General Orders I No I. The composition of the Nebraska National Guard Rifle Tram to participate in the National Competitions, as prescribed in Genera Orders No. 2t;, W. U.. Febuary 29. 19ms. is announi &lt;■&lt;! u follows: III. The Adjuant General will arrange for transportation and subsistence, the allowance for subsistence being commuted in ad% at the rate of |1.S( per day for enlisted men durinii the time occupied In travel under this order, and for the number of days spoilt in cami at Camp Perry. Ohio, during the progress of the shooting tournament IV. Lieut. Col. O. G. Osborn. in addition to his other duties. *l Team Quartermaster, Ordinance Officer and Paymaster. V The following appointment of aides-de-camp on the staff ••! Governor George U Sheldon, is announced to take rifori March 2 1 lltus Colonel George H. Rogers. Lincoln. Colcnel Win. C. Shinn Lincoln. By order of th Govern C F. SCHWA HZ Adjutant General 1 Lieut. Col. O. G. Osporue . . . Jnd Infty Captain. 2 Col. .1. M. Birkner Med. Dept Coach. ;i O. M. Newman 2nd Infty.. Ram*e offi.f 4 Capt.I. S. Johnson 1st InftJ Bpotter 5 Capt. J. ('. Ferguson 1st |nft&gt;. 6 1st Lt. J. A. Balderson 1st Inftv. 7. 2nd Lt. C. L. Anderson .1st Inft. S 2nd Lt. H. B. Hobbs 1st Infty. 9 Res?. Srg. Maj. D. F. McDonald 1st Infty. 10 1st Serg D. C. Gill Co. K. 2nd I; H Serg. F. W. Mohr Co. K. .'nd Inftv. 11' IMS. F. M. Brian Ca M. l'ih! Intty. 11 Corp. F. W. Xyo. . . ('&lt;&gt;. B. 1st Infty. \i Mils. K. .1. Meixei. . .*'&lt;&gt;- II L'nd l.ittv I.'. Art. C. C. Blod^'iti .Co. C, 1st Infty. |« Ptiv. L. H. Rons.- .Co. K. 2nd Infty IT I'riv .1 I. Cibson. . ( ". I.. 2nd Infty is Priv. F. B. llRonfritz ...Co. A. 1st Infty. 19 Priv. A. E. Renkin -id S«'l&gt; lnf&gt; &lt;''&gt; II. The team will leave the State Rifle RUft, memi Ashland. Nebr. August 19. 190S. and proceed to Camp Perry. Ohio, to take part in the National matches, and cm completion of their mnr of dutv. th.- members will return to their respective stations. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">AD.11TANT GKNKRALS RKPORT HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD/ Adjutant Oeoerml'i Offict \ Lincoln, October. 2:t. 1H"^ leneral Order j No I i No 1 . dated State Rifle Range. is. ih«' following cash prizes are Pursuant to Far. V b. Field Ordt near Ashland, Nebraska, .Inly 211. 1H lit-ri-li&gt; dint ri Uu ted . FIRST PRIZr To Co. K. 2nd Infantry. Sc-huyler. Nebraska One Hundred ($1M.»O) Dollars, contributed by Brigadier General c T. Brhwara. Adjutant General. SECOND PRIZK To Co. F. 1st Infantry, Madison. Nebraska Fifty I $.".(!. no ) Dollars, contributed by Major U P. Davison. V \ Retired, mi duty with the organized militia of Nebraska. THIRD FRIZK To en ('. 1st Infantry, Beatrice. Nebraska Thirty | $34.00) Dollars contributed by Colonel F. S. Nicholson, Burgeon (ieneial. l.ientenant Colonel .1 M Birkner. Medical Corps; Major K H. Phelps. Assistant Adjutant Cieneral. FOl'RTH PRIZK To Co. K. L'nd Infantry, Tekamah. Nebraska Tv»ent\ (I20.M) IKillars. contributed by Captain C. M. Bundel :iikI Lieutenant L. R. James, of Company I</seg>
            <seg id="p131"/>
            <seg id="p132"/>
            <seg id="p133"/>
            <seg id="p134"/>
            <seg id="p135"/>
            <seg id="p136"/>
            <seg id="p137"/>
            <seg id="p138"/>
            <seg id="p139"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>