<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL STATION OF NEBRASKA.  FATTENING PIGS ON CORN AND TANKAGE.</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The LJnivi Nebraska. BLLLKT1N of Tin: AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION FATTENING PIGS ON CORN AND TANKAGE. a 190U. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATION AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD ' THE STATION OFFICERS THE WDRKING STAFF </seg>
            <seg id="p003">FATTENING PIGS ON CORN AND TANKAGE. T, D1KKCTOR. IN rUOIttC'TION. _ importance of the by-products of the p. ipplciueutarv I' 1 iu connection wit 1 1 corn, it»u to undertake several experiment to deter - whether i In- farmer could increase the profit of his '|Mi-at ions l&gt;\ the use of tankage. In one experiment so endeavored to determine what effei-1 upon tli«' of bone in the growing pig n-sults from feeding _ house by-products. Experiment** I, II. ami III were t the effeci of tankage on the rate ami tin Experiment IV was made to show the HIV strengi h of bone. I is (li'sri-ilic.l by Swift &amp; Company as "a n I protein meal made from fresh wholesome pie. trimmed from lc-rf carcasses. It looks much like dark •il wheat shorts, j s shipped in 10(1 pound Hacks ami will imleiinitel v nmler average conditions of dry stora EXPERIMENT I. ■y IS, I'.ni.".. three lots of prude Poland pi'_'s iin^ e\|ierimcnt to test the value of tankage, 1 was fed soaked corn. lid \C&gt; per eeiit soaked eorn and ."&gt; jn-r cent tank- K^ fed '.in per rent soaked eorn and IK per pent B'v were ] laocd in dry lots, hut were fed a small amount ■in sorghum each day. i I.. MX </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 I had In four months. Inn wen- not iinisln-&lt;|. Tl of two w&lt; i iinsi'ciii i\c uing ;iinl i riiucut. Thev I V ■ ■l|-;i\\ n I rum ■&gt;tl l.ol follow ii </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 : lint Lot -, ted up" &gt;f tankage, made the gres •II this lot I »&lt; ■ i iiii but -•!.7&lt;i per hundred to produce uudml to produ 'id ltt per cent lank is much tankage as th&lt; fed, in the trough. »old September 1 lit li at $4.90 per bun - fur figuring the price received for I EXPERIMENT II EM. liMMi. ihii-iv hogs which bad been following in tin- feed lot wen* separated into three lois of t«'ii ih ami placed «&gt;n alfalfa posture. Tiny were fed as K.iki-il i orn "ir. per cent, tankage •"&gt; p&lt;T cent kcil .urn !"ii |Mi- cent, tankage 10 per rent li lot was fed practically all it would i-at. In thi - okage was atlilcd to the soaked corn ju« while in the previous experiments the tan the corn an I lioth had l»een soaked to - : -lit that the soaking of the tankag have affected its - u]H&gt;n 10 !&gt;■ tankage did not ration so well as those fed upon corn with •"&gt; added. hmed for the eight ipon exjM»rin ■ iidiiion. no r being off Teed, and for the food consumed. Tb« ■M,| on .Monday. Juh 8, 1906. flhed tin ' lie beginning of th&lt; ikril corn. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 l.ll 7! i:.\i'i:i:i.\ii:nt in En An . 1!MI."». i line lots of ]iii:s nnv , iii-ni after a [irt'liiiiiusirv fe^linj; for &lt; • i _; 1 1 1 wicls the ex|MTi:iu'ii1 i. TIh'h- were ciulu pip&lt; in &lt;*acb lot. All li:nl u »&gt; 1 ;il iii-i-. Tliix i-cii'iM-d (he following i I |HT rent, short « "_'&lt;! |KT I J |H T Clli are thfl averages &lt;&gt;f those ilim- weights. Tin- average w of Ul&lt;- ]»iiis in &lt;;nll lul \v;.is ;is follow injs ." |n c corn i;iiiii. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 r.t; 1.03 anv of i : imi'iiis. Inn assuming thai the pasture was equal iu v.- i In- following coin jKirisons mi^lit !»• in lade : _.iins of I. hi | rust !'."&gt; per rent oiore than thos * * 'ii t nit &gt;r* * i 1 1 ; 1 1 1 thos The pains of l.ni l cost H per ct«nl more than those &lt;&gt;f BMTiinciiis III and I V terminated before the lmixs were for market, which would affect the amount of grain eh 100 pounds of increase in weight. I experiments the cost of producing ]»&gt;i-k Ii neil hv the addition of ."&gt; per cen&lt; lankaire ti&gt; -lulled corn, and in l]x|iei-inient III the c was lesselieil 68 eelits [ler ll II 111 I I'd I liv llsillLJ corn \\illl 5 over usiiii; four-fifths corn ami one-fifth l&gt;eriiiieiits witli i-elaii\elv mature animals have all ii that the addition of ."• per cent tankage to the ration I i-1ic;i |m r gains than when 1&lt;^ per cent tankage waa With young iiijrs the gains wire made on smaller amounts «&gt;f fi»&gt;d when the larger amovnl &lt;&gt;f tankage was adih-d to the ration, but the high cosri of the tankage has the smaller amount of tankage more profitable. All -i uf alfalfa p;tsnirc is not figured in Con </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Pall quantities and the payment of local t ng the &lt;ust iif&gt; to thai figure. Where the i r-load luis. tl given in ih&lt;- ■notable, advantage in 1 1, rapid gain* made by the h cuing df the feeding I bone upon ili&lt;- *tn i irried on « ith fo Bie pig r&lt;-. The experiim i' iirt'liminary feed l,&lt;ii 1 1 I M -f (111 B3 received 90 per ceni - d bone. Tli - had recently been weaneil I nineteen wen 1 Duroc J four KPUUCCUl uii-i-&lt;l to |&gt;i suit &lt;;■ I all lli' jisilv put uncd I csi made Itlv to In i i: i m i - i'im rivtil 7.~i nor ««n! su;ik&lt;*&lt;] </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 •. whirl) fa .m&lt;l tiv The following l;tl&gt;lt&gt; f the lirst experii ivember \'.K i .(•ins per liniiiiiccl [&gt;ouu&lt;ls; tan :uivil ni si'.imi per hundred. Kiid shorts rec]uired for I two pigs in I. "i 1 nut «] n. with normal pigs upon corn urn dial required !•&gt; Lot I ivemlier !'••. 1904, and for four iv all feel 10 per trill cm al until November 19th being i 1 1 : i \ 1 it |mt rent. _'• Hi | &gt;&lt; -i- pent, alfalfa ha in per rent, alfalfa ,; ha\ K' "TJmi'iit and tin Tin- ;mi&lt;&gt;!int of ! </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Erd of wciulii - ins wan I- pi o v did not relish the alfalfa hay as fed and \\&lt; .11 DO |i-i nlil oi 11. I January &lt;. 1905, ill • iu ] &gt;!;»&lt; &lt;-&lt; 1 &lt;&gt;n th t the In «»f tin- cxiMTiiiH'iit. the \i\n- Inning Iiimh thrown out, Iim in carli In- fi January 7t h their i lows: Tin- larjj Ki\]»iiiiiiiii \\;i&gt;i i mil i ii in, 1 for another (&gt; hiili win- i niisiiin ,1 corn i&gt;r mil kIioHm in. I. ut only the &lt;&gt;ii r&lt;4&gt;ruary 10, &lt;-;i&lt; li |ut ;iinl - </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 KnI' bon iowd by the t&lt; Irength of iIm 1 leu; bones, each l»&gt;i! chine ;m&lt;l broken. (This work on nl tin- department of Mechanical En - uivereity.) The machine in each ca il ilii t ri|iiirc«l to Weak the hone. Iiml bone to young growing pigs produces ;i rery ed effect on the strength of bone when compared with a ration and thai its influence is still marked when I with rdi-ii and shorts on alfalfa pasture. will i&gt;&lt;- noted that there- is ■ marked difference in the »ht of these hogs at killing time, an&lt;l it will doubtlea by iiian\ that tin- breaking strength per hum Short ,, 213 mil &amp; t MS nt from tli' ■suits tliiit the fecdin of tank- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 principle would seem i" be i i-iiiK'iii were aoi - the li&lt;-a\ ier 01 ml bone and tan thai th&lt; •a to li\ conipara Eat k\\\\, of the ill &lt;&gt;f I' i that i fed on i lu- ll gi\ in tt ur. While it </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>