<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00054.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00054.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Inaugural Message of Governor Adam McMullen to the Legislature of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1925-01-08">1925-01-08</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Inaugural Message of Governor Adam McMullen To the Legislature of Nebraska January 8, 1925 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">C.OYKRXOK McMULLEN'S INAUGURAL MESSAGE run Mkmbekk or the Forty-third Session ok tmk LKHLATtXBI ok Nebraska: Ladirh and (Jkxtlbmex You have been chosen by your fellow-citi - zens as their representatives in the law making body of the government of the state, a position that not only confers high honor but also • airies with it responsibilities both serious and sacred. They are serious l&gt;ecause for the time bring, you have been entrusted with the power to define, regulate and control the legal rights nt the citizens of a great commonwealth; they are sacred because your official acts will have much to do with advancing or retarding the moral and material progress of more than a million people. On the other hand, you have been favored with an unusual opportunity to render un - selfish service to society. You are in a posi - tion now to help do the things you believe will he of benefit to the state. Your task will not be easy; your road will not always be smooth. You will find divergence of opinion where you expected reasonable uniformity, and you will be confronted with conflicting interests where you had a right to believe there would be mutual sympathy and common concern. The executive department, let me assure you, will be anxious and desirous to work with vou •&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 iu every possible way. While the duties of the legislative and executive branches are en tirely different, still, their aims and purpose - are identical. Each should strive, within the channels prescribed by the Constitution, to carry out the will of the people. Each should co-operate with the other to the end that the details of a sound and efficient program shall I.e carried out. In this spirit of co-operation for the common good, and as required by the Constitution of our state, 1 have the honor to submit the fol lowing suggestions for your consideration : Platform Pudges The political party whose inenik-is const i tute a majority vote in both the senate an&lt; the house pledged certain specific lcgislatioi in its platform. All such pledges should b redeemed and all promises covering dtfinit legislation should be held inviolate Agriculture In Nebraska, agriculture is the basic indus try. If agriculture prospers all other indus tries will prosper. Trade and commerce will fnnetion upon a profitable basis; labor will be given ready employment under favorable con ditions, and all other lines of endeavor will b. - made comfortable and remunerative. No mm* state can be expected to solve all the forming problems because some of those problems, if not most of them, are beyond the reach of legisla tive solution, and some are inter-sectional and international. Yet. each agricultural state </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 should do all thai is possible to be done by legislation to improve farming conditions, and Nebraska should lead in this direction as it always has in the past. In the main, the future of agriculture de - pends, and will depend, upon the energy, skill and thrift of the farmer himself. Legislation cannot create wealth. It can, at most, direct the conditions under which it it created. But legislation can and should have much to do with the distribution of wealth once it is ere - ■ted. Within these limitations every effort, should be bent, in my opinion, to the assistance of agriculture. Such obstacles as may exist in our laws, to the organization of sound agricul tural enterprise, should l&gt;e removed. Such im - provements as experience has shown to l&gt;e needed in the laws, under which these enter prises organize and operate, should be made. Such measures as seem wisely calculated to adjust production of farm products to their piobable consumption and that tend to promote orderly and efficient marketing and distribu - tion, should have your hearty support. A prevailing agricultural problem is the ade - quate dealing with bovine tuberculosis. It is well known to be a source of great loss to the breeders and the farmers of the state. It is a grave and constant menace to human health. It can be eradicated by mrnfrtic state-wide ac - tion. Means to make such action possible should be provided by you. Roads Roads are becoming daily of more importance to the people of the state. The growth of traf- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 f if. the increased use of the highways for the marketing of farm products, make it needful that continuous improvement should occur. In the past, much needed work has t&gt;een Mgleeted or postponed with resulting losses of large ex - tent. If Netrrasku is to keep abreast of the needs of her growing industries and her agri - culture, she must adopt and adhere to a con stant policy of extension and improvement of the roads of the state. I am opposed to build ing roads from the proceeds of bond issues. I advocate their construction, in sane compliance with the needs of the state, from current funds I shall constantly urge the most economic:!: and thrifty use of snch funds upon roads s &gt; built and so located as will most speedily bring the products of farm and factory nearer to The consumer. Gasoline Tax Among the many sources of revenue for road (•(instruction and improvement, a t;i\ upon gaso - line used in motor vehicles, has met with urns: general favor and is now a method of raisini: revenue in a large Majority of the American states. Its fairness seems obvious. It tends t&lt;&gt; place the burden of the cost of the road pro gram upon the user of the roads in proportion to his use of them. The heavy vehicle which naturally wears hardest upon the highways, with its relatively greater consumption of g:is. will pay its clue share. The pleasure vehicle. without apparent economic importance, also pays its due proportion. Such a tax is easy and certain of collection, and I recommend the pas sage of legislation necessary for its adoption in this state. I also recommend, however, thai </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 with the imposition of a tax upon gasoline, there ga eoarairtatlj a reduction in the license ikiw charged for motor vehicles. In my belief there should lx- no increase in the amount of taxation. Imt only a change to a more equitable inrans of procuring the necessary revenue for ;n! Safety in Highway Traffic I invite your attention and ask your action upon legislation greatly needed to increase the .-.ilViv of the users of our public roads. The toll of death and injury upon the highways is appalling. Some adequate provision should be made whereby the criminally careless or in - comperent driver be effectively penalized for his misuse of the roads of this state. A prou*r system of traffic regulations and provisions for Nummary punishment of offenders calculated to prevent a repetition of the offense, should have vour careful consideration. L.WV ENFORCEMENT The basis of sound government lies upon re - spect for the law. I'nless the laws are ade - quately enforced this basis is impaired. The governor of this state makes no laws. It is his duty to enforce such laws as the statutes direct liim to enforce. 1 invite your thoughtful con - sideration of such amendments to our civil and criminal codes as may increase the certainty of punishment and may tend to lessen the num - ber of shocking crimes of violence against the persons and property of our citizens. As gov - ernor of Nebraska, I promise you every effort will be made, within my constitutional and statutory powers, to enforce them. Violations </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 of the prohibitory laws lead in many instances to other violations of other laws ami the com - mission of other crimes. It will be my purpose to aid and assist in the suppression of this il legal and criminal traffic. IllKKiATION The importance &lt;if the large and glowing sugar beet industry, of our western counties, to the general prosperity of Nebraska, must In - apparent to all. Those sections of the ■tat*' devoted to this branch of agricultural produc - tion are Mtod for their thrift and energy and are capable, iimlei- proper encouragement, of greater development to the general benefit of all the people of the stale. Their industry de pendx upon an ample and steady source of water for irrigation, and any action that will tend to prevent encroachment upon the souree* of water now available for tins one, should hare your earnest rapport. La bo i Without labor all industry fails. Whatever improves the standard of later improves society as a whole. Labor thus far has program I through intelligent application of principle* producing permanent benefit. The eight hou ■■ day is now recognized as a just and equitable psfiad for service. The right to collective bar - gaining by labor's delegates is universally un - questioned. The compensation law as written into the statutes of our state is of common bene fit. to lx)th employer and employee. Its success like the success of any other law, rests upon th.* </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 wanner of its administration. Any legislation ending jo facilitate or improve such adminis - ration, will receive my approval. Economy There is alwaji an urgent need of economy in connection with public expenditures. I urge upon you i he most mature consideration of thrift and efficiency in the use of appropriated funds. The burden of the tax-payer is heavy. When* possible it should be lightened. While it is true that by far the greater portion of the taxes in Nebraska are levied by agencies other than the legislature, still, you should have constantly in mind the purpose of making taxes still lower, provided, it can be done without. impairing any of the necessary activities of the state. 1 promise you that so far as the executive branch of the government is con - cerned, diligent and constant effort will be exercised to direct the expenditure of the funds appropriated by you so that the people shall receive full vaiue for their money. However. wise discrimination upon all points of econ- omy should always lie maintained. It is fre - quently the case that prudent expenditure is the truest thrift. The various institutions of the state, for example, should not be made to suffer through a mis-application of so-called economy, nor should any department of the state government be hampered in efficiency through lack of necessary funds. Intax(siblb Tax A law was enacted at a recent session of the Nebraska legislature to define, classify and tax so called "intangible" property so as to pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">i 10 duce. what advocates of that law hoped, would be a larger and steadier stream of revenue to the state. In its operation that law has proved a disappointment to many people. An amend nient either of classification or in the rate •! the tax, or both, would seem in the Hght &lt;&gt;' experience to be required, and to such amend - ment I herewith call your attention. Nebraska deservedly ranks high in the stand iii}I &lt;&gt;f its educational institutions. They an- MM| our greatest assets ami attract to on: - state each year many new citizens and resul'. indirectly, in the investment of much capital. In mr ways than one the\ pay luge divi - dends to the people of the state. The economic conditions of the past few years have required appropriations for these institutions to 1/ • lessened, while at the same time the attendant •■• has greatly increased in all or in most o r them. Crowding of students and lack of suf ficient facilities for instruction and napervi sion have progressed to the pout where furthe continuation of these conditions means a per manent lowering of educational standards. therefore urge upon you a areful study of these problems to the end that all necess;ii\ action be taken adequately to maintain and promote the cause of education. Statk Cafmtoi. The new capitol building has progressed far enough to make it clear that if completed ac - cording to the plans of iis gifted designer r will be a monument feu- many long years tr the civic dignity of a great state. The manage Editation </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 ment of its erection seems to have been ably conducted by the commission in charge. I MB informed that to complete the structure will require a continuation of the present levy for a period of practically three years. I recom - mend tlic passage of the appropriate legislation o produce the necessary funds. In the foTCgatag paragraphs I have called your attention to several matters which I think require your consideration and action. It may be that as the session progresses other vital and important subjects, pressing for legislative rec - ognition, will come to my notice. Should such be the case. I shall consider it my duty under the constitution to submit them to you. Finally, in view of the responsibilities placfd u|K)ii us. let it Im' our mutual privilege to perform our respective duties in a manner that will not only reflect upon our efforts but also will re - sult in promoting the general welfare of the state. ADAM McMULLEX &lt;'ONCLUSI0N </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>