<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00032.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00032.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF THE Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission TO THE Governor OF THE State of Nebraska FOR THE PERIOD FROM April 14, 1913 TO November 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">REPORT OF THE Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission -TO THE - Governor OF THE- State of Nebraska -FOR THE PERIOD FROM - April 14, 1913 TO November 30, 1914 BY CLARENCE E. HARMAN. Deputy Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 John II. Morehead, Governor Commissioner Clarence E. Hannan Deputy (Commissioner K. L Kedfern State ( Ihemist Miss Marion K. llelinann Secretary Miss Til lie ('. Kppens ..Stenographer Miss Grace A. Trott Clerk INSPECTORS. Food, Dairy and Oil. Eil Ay res. S. Austin. S. Stahl. V". Moore. Murphy. Anton Tnsa. Frank Maloney. P. J. Biglin. I). W. Hecox. J. (J. P. ITildebrand James Graham (dairy only) George S. Mayo. Food and Cold Storage. Weights and Measures. F. W. Schaupp. D. A. (Jeil. (resigned). i. II. Held Feeding Stuff and Linseed Oil. W. P&gt;. Alexander. (Part time only.) Seed Analyst. E. ('. Kemble. I Drugs, (i. Hoffmeister. (Part time only.) Louise M. Allen. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 * ■■• - 1 'lllillliAll' I Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir:— I have the honor to submit herewith a report of tlie Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission, for the period beginning April 14, 1913, and endin-.- November 30, 1914. Said period being for the time since the consolida - tion of the Food, Drag and Dairy Commission with thu office of State Inspector of Oils. CLARENCE H. HARMAN Deputy Commissioner. ]&gt;ated at Lincoln. Neb., Dec. 1, 1014 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I 'he Food, Drag, Dairy and Oil Commission is ;i &lt;-i&gt;n - dation of the former Food, Drug and Dairy Commission h the office of State Inspector of Oils. Their eon - dation was brought about by Governor Morehead &gt;ointing the present Deputy Commissioner as the head the Food. Drug and Dairy Commission and also as te Inspector of Oils. He then asked the Legislature consolidate the two departments so that greater ciency and economy would be established, and in order t those employed might be working under the same s and to the best advantage at all times. Ileretofore the Food, Drug and Dairy Commission was upered in its work by lack of funds and for this reason I unable to give a full enforcement of the laws in all ts of the state, on account of infrequent visits of pectois. Many towns in the state had never been ited by an inspector and some not more than once. w each town is visited from one to three times or more h year, which gives a full operation of the laws ami gta with the genuine approval of those engaged in busi - s, as well as with the approval of the public, and a iceable difference in the manner food is handled in found every hand. I formerly the State Inspector of Oils had an abundance funds and employees and a shortage of work, bat now 'h inspector has been given a separate district, and en not engaged in one kind of inspection is profitably ?aged in another. IPhat the plan of consolidating these two departments successful is easily proven by the figures shown in the incial statements in this report, which show that more in $80,000 has been collected in fees above the cost of ■ operation of the department since April 14, 1918 to vember ."50 of this year. Further evidence is shown the report covering the inspections made by the inspeo - s, which when taken into comparison with the inspe** - ns made during the previous biennium show more than ice as many inspections made this biennium as were de daring the previous one. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">i*he cost of operating the deimrtment under consoli - ioo is materially less, and the results obtained have 11 greater. In addition to the duties of the two depart - its &lt;is formerly constituted, the last Legislature added liis department the Standards of Weigh™ and Measures I Cold Storage laws, which have been given the same 'iitM-n n:-i the Pood, Drug, Dairy* and Oil laws have. (Ih- records of the ( 'oniinission show that the amount )!iile:i:ie used in field work by inspectors in the 1 wo laituient- formerly amounted to about 240,000 mile-; railway transportation each year. During the past r inspectors of this depai troent in the enforcement of the if laws, used 160,000 miles of mileage, which shows a net action in this item of 80,000 miles. It is impossible in a report of this kind ti&gt; treat all nutters in detail and in order to condense the report as much as possible the different subjects will only be touched in a general way. so as to Ihose interested a good gttueral idea of t lie enforcement of laws, fees &lt;•&lt;&gt;! - le't-'d. and results accomplished. tn submitting this report 1 desire to add that in addi - i to the wise step taken by Governor Nforeltead in consolidation of the departments, that his good judjr - nt and counsel as to the changes in some of the laws ler the jurisdiction of the department has saved the 'chasing public in this state hundreds of thousands of lars during the past bienniuin and will continue to do tin the years to come. I desire also to say that tho* • t were appointed to assist in carrying into effect the visions of the law and the work of the department have n efficient in every way, and to them belongs the ilit for the lesults obtained. CLARENCE K. II ARM AX. Deputy Commissioner. V When food laws were first proposed in this state, as well as in other states, there was a feeling of appre - hension on the part of those engaged in the manufacture, distribution and sale of food products, that such legisla - tion w;u drastic in the extreme, but now those engaged </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 »ihis business welcome the enforcement of food laws I it is not an infrequent occurrence that legislation erning 1 he manufacture and s-.ve of foods is propose 1 them. While the food laws of Nebraska are tot perfect in nil respects, it is a well-known fact that this state is in advance of many other states in the protection of the con - suming public and it is a common occurrence in the passage of food legislation for other states to model their food laws from the Nebraska laws This state was one of the first to place a "net weight" food law on its statute books. The adulteration of foods has practically become a thing of the past on account of the activity of tin- National government and state departments. Fraud and deception have been eliminated to a great extent and the matter that now confronts the food officials of both state and nation is the protection of the public health by forc - ing the proper sanitary protection of food products in the course of their manufacture, distribution and sale. Ifhat the public is in favor of, and greatly interested the proper handling of food products is evidenced by tact that places of business, where food is not properly idled, are not well patronized, and places where food properly handled are always well patronized. The Uiaska Sanitary Food law covers the sanitary handling foods in a comprehensive manner and requires that all ds shall be securely protected from flies, dust, dirt or ier contamination at all times, and information conies this department through the inspectors in the field, as II as from interested people in all parts of the State, it this law and its enforcement has accomplished much rard the handling of food products in a dean! and whole - ne manner. Wholesale and Retail Food Establishments The inspection of these places of busriness reveals ii;e fact that the foot! commission is receiving the hearty co-eperation of those engaged in business, and are usually found to be willing and ready to do everything in llioir power to eo"ipiv with tl'e laws of the slate as construed by and enforced by the department. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Drugs. The co-operation &lt;&gt;t' the druggists of Nebraska with thi&lt; departmeni and their entire willingness to comply with tli • laws which come under the jurisdiction of this covi- i&lt;ion. is in evidence on every- i nud The inspect:. • &gt;•. - t have heen made of dru^ stocks in different parts of state go to show that the druggists are giving their : efforts to keep their stocks strictly within the pro on&gt; of the law. The Dairy Industry The magnitude of this industry or the importance of tlii — part of the work in the department can not lie fully understood without coming directly in contact with the work itself. Nebraska has sixty-two creameries in opera - tion at this time whose total annual output is forty-five million pounds of Initter, which brings to the state au income of approximately fifteen million dollars a year. While to some it Blight appear that this income could not tic increased the facts are that it can and should be. The industry itself is the development of a resource which h:.&gt; grown by leaps and hounds, and is the result of the constant collective and personal effort put forth by those r-ngaged in the business with the assistance of proper legislation and encouragement on the part of the stale government. In the years gone by the effort put forth lias been to increase the quantity of cream produced and little attention has been paid to the quality. Now it appears that the time has come for this state to put forth an effort to better the quality of the raw material in y}vd^r that the manufactured product will sell on the market on the same basis that the butter of other states sells for. This can only be accomplished by proper legislation, governing the baying and selling of cream and the handling of the same from the time it is produced. Nebraska cream producers would get a material benefit in the way of an increased price for their raw material ami the industry itself would continue to grow to the fullest extent. Several other states are taking the matter up with this end in view. Bulletins have been issued by this department from time to time pertaining to the handling, testing, sampling </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 II weighing of cream, and the net result of t lie woi i&lt; the commission the past biennhun is that thi&gt; depart - nt is receiving the co-operation of tliose engaged in Daily Industry in every part of the state. Petroleum Products I 'he fees collected by this department, for tin- past nniuin. for the inspection of kerosene and gasoline \v a large increase over the previous hieniiiuin. and the largest in the history of the state by many usands of dollars. As a matter of comparison, in 11*11 fees collected amounted to $.j"),UOO; in 1912 to king a total of $li:UXH) for the hiennium. For the ir 1913 the fees amounted to $&lt;;7,l&gt;&lt;&gt;0 and in 1914 to 1,000, making a total of $143,000, which show.- a net lease of $.')(),(M)0 the past bieimiuin. In addition to a large increase in the fees. Governor rehead recommended to the legislature that the dis - nination in the oil laws he repealed and that all &gt;tate&gt; allowed to sell kerosene in Xeltiask;i on the saioe ;is. Formerly Kansas, Colorado and Oklahoma COU - lled the Nebraska market on kerosene for the reason t all states but these three were prohibited from Belling osene below a 4(5 degree Beaunie gravity test, while se three states were only required to deliver a 42 test. w Wyoming can come into Nebraska with her products the same basis as other states and this alone mean* saving in transportation charges of a considerable mint, and at the same time has done much to reduce ■ price of kerosene to the purchaser in every part ot the Gasoline. {Die consumption of gasoline in Nebraska, as elsewhere, rapidly increasing on account of its coining into bo leral use for power purposes. Formerly our law uired a (iS degree Beaunie test on gasoline, but as the Band increased the test was lowered until the legis - ui e of 1913 took the test off altogether and Hxed the luircineiits under the law that the product be branded to its gravity test, and that it should not be adult-rated. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 The reason for. tliis was that for power purpo-es a lower grade gasoline could be used to just as good advantage Kl at much less expense than a high grade. Anothe sou for the change in the law was that the demand t'&lt; the product was so heavy that the price was iucrcasin I the extent that it was becoming prohibitive for tli rage power purpose. Under the proeiit law tli ility of the product meets with the approval of tli ■rhmer, as he can usually buy the grade lie desin ! en immense sum is thereby saved to user.- of this pr&lt; ■i on iccc -nit of the greal reduction in the price. V* t.uici . ,-it the time of the passage of the new law th ue in price of gasoline at Lincoln, Nebraska was I'roi w 2~&gt; o«.ntf Today the range is from II 1 - to 1.") ecu: s estimated that the net saving each year i- not leu n 1500.000 per year. Linseed Oil. I ■'or several years a strong effort has been made to force i.M- engaged in selling linseed oil to sell a pure linseed or brand the product that was adulterated with the ne and percentage of each ingredient contained therein, iiif? to a defect in the penalty clause of the linseed oil j it had been impossible to secure a proper operation the law. At the request of Governor Mprehead the las! irislature collected this defect and now instead of Ne - iska being Hooded with an adulterated linseed oil, which itained from 20 to ."&gt;0 per cent petroleum oil. practically linseed oil sold in Nebraska is the pure product. It was found that our law only reached those engaged in the linseed oil business within the bounds of the state and did not operate against those outside the state. By prompt action and at the request of the Governor the United State- Postal authorities issued a fraud order which prohibited the u&gt;e of tlie mails for the purpose of the celling of adul - terated linseed oil. unless all mailing matter contained full information as to the ingredients contained in the adulterated product. This action, together with the en - forcement of our state law. has effectively stopped the sale of adulterated linseed oil in the state, because purchasers of linseed oil never buy the adulterated product knowingly. Figures compiled recently show that this law and it&lt; enforcement has saved Xebraskans $100,000 a vear. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Cold Storage Food. I This is a new feature of the Nebraska food law and an »rtant one and covers all food in cold storage, not only ;he time in storage but the distribution and sale after n out of storage. Cold storage means much, not only le producer but to the consumer, as in reality it is a * regulator for the reason that in times of plenty the -supply goes into cold storage and in seasons of scar - when there is very little production, the consumer s the benefit. I is a hard matter to overcome the prejudice that exists rally against cold storage food. This prejudice has beei ght about on account of the fact that consumers ha\( been fully acquainted with articles of food that have in cold storage. Under the present law all dealers mus fy purchaser! when a sale of cold storage food is made 1. In this way much of the stigma that has been placec his class of product is removed, as the purchaser wil W absolutely what he is buying and a poor article can be charged up to being cold storage food when it is and fresh food and cold storage food will go to the inner on its quality. I his commission inspects every three months eaeh am •y cold storage warehouse in Nebraska and no food is wed to remain in storage at any time which i&gt; not ti food. There are L'l licensed cold storage or rcfrigera warehouses in the state in which food is stored. The icity of these warehouses in sum total is more than million cubic feet! At the end of each three month i cold storage concern makes a sworn statement as to amount and kind of food products in cold storage in r respective wai eiu.uscs. To give some idea of the tense amount of foods in storage as reported to thi artment at the end of one quarterly period a fompila i has been nude in the department, which Bhowa a r.ws: KiO.000 dressed beef carcasses 30,000,000 lbs. of beef and pork products. 375,000 lbs. egg pulp. 50,000 lbs. frozen fish. 410.000 lbs. of batter. 150,000 c;iscs of eggs. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 9,000 bus. of apples. ."&gt;,()( )0 boxes of other fresh fruit More than l'.IM )(),(&gt;()() lbs. of other items, including cheese, candy, dried fruit, oysters! poultry, etc. I old storage law provides that do food products can be i in cold storage longer than one year, unless applica i is made to this department for an extension of time before an extension is granted the food product mot inspected by an inspector of this Department. Six •Mentions have been filed and five extensions of tim nted and in one instance the extension was not grante&lt; I the food ordered out of storage. Standards of Weights and Measures. The enforcement of the weights and measures law was added to this department by the last Legislature and be - came effective on July 17, 1913. This law fixes the stand - ards of weights and measures and provides for the inspec - tion of scales, weights and measure* used in trade. i)n account of the time nece.-sary to secure proper equip - iit and have the same verified by the National Bureau Standards, no inspectors were placed in the Held until toher. 1913. At that time two inspectors were appointed, ' of which to make the inspections north of the Platte er and the other south of the river. The work was taken in a systematic manner and every town in each county s completed before the work in the next county was iiiueiiced. Il'lie enforcement of this law has been of great benefit those engaged in the buying and selling of commodities. r instance, an inspector engaged in inspecting the scales a large mill discovered that a set screw on the sliding se of the beam had been lost out and another one put in place. In replacing the screw one much heavier than the ginal one had been used, which caused the miller to it 8 OX. more flour in each sack" than the sack should itain. As the mill turned out 600 &gt;a&lt;-ks of flour pel &gt; los&gt; to the miller amounted to approximately si'.liou • year. Xo one around the mill knew how long before « dinner? had been made. At another time an inspector found a load of hogs heini? sold over a scale and a scale weighi was being used which </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Is marked 2,000 lbs., but on a tost revealed the fad that ook 2500 ll&gt;s of bogs to balance it and thereby eausinr ;; i to the farmer of 500 lbs. at $8J50 a hundred or $42.50 money. The error was discovered in time to save the nev for the fanner as the weight was condemned and ifiscated by the inspector. &gt; Ifany such cases as above cited have been found by the u ctors hut space forbids enumerating them and the purpose in citing these two cases is to show conelll - ly that the inspection of scales and weights is not only f*!*ary but operates to the advantage of all concerned. The Chemical Laboratory Earing the past bienninm the number of analyses made h.- laboratory by the state chemist lias been more than bled over any previous bienniuin. ihas been the policy during the past two years to firry the laboratory work to the fullest extent and ai the e time to serve the public in every way possible, as I as to make analyses called upon to make by other aitinents under state government. A large number of ly-es have been made for the Board of Control to give n the necessary information as to the quality of food iucts and other commodities being purchased by them. ')•&gt;■ vestige of red tape has been eliminated and no fees e been charged for analysing food products or other ii&gt;, which were not fixed in the law. On Nov. 20th, Mr. E. L Redfera, who has held the posi - tion of state chemist for the past ten years filed his resigna - tion to take effect January 1st, as he had received the appointment as state chemist for the Iowa Dairy and Food Commission. Mr. Bedf era's service in this department has been faithfully rendered and to him belongs a great deal of the credit for the high standard of the food la w&gt; now on the statute books in this state. It is a regretable fact that the salary fixed in our law for state chemist was not sufficient to retain his services. Prosecutions. Elelieving that the best way to secure the enforcement awa under the jurisdiction of the department was To I -ecure as far as possible the co-operation of those aged in business and when this failed, to prosecute the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 offenders to the full extent of the law. The Deputy Com - missioner and tiu» inspectors during the past biennium have filed Ki."i prosecutions and secured verdicts in favor of the state in all hut one rase, and two cases are still pending. I The most notable prosecution was one wherein a con lint was filed at St. Paul, Nebraska, against a butche r the sale of meat from hogs that had been butcher© tor the hogs had died from the disease known as ho olera. Additional counsel was secured from the Attoi ney General's office by this department to assist the count attorney of Howard county in prosecuting the defendan When the case came to trial the defendant did not tigh the case, hut plead guilty to the information and was fine* $.")(!() and costs, which was the limit under the law. Th law should he remedied in this respect to the extent tha a penitentiary sentence would he the penalty for this kin* of violation, as it is without question one of the worst foot law violations ever committed tigainst an unsuspectin public in the history of the state. Food and Dairy Show at the State Fair |\t the State Fair during the present year this Commis - n had charge of the Food and Daily Show which was d in the old Agricultural Hall. This building contains 000 square feet of space and was filled by exhibits of &gt;d and daily products and an extensive exhibit from s department. A large number of manufacturers light space iii the building and the net receipts for the ice sold was more than $2,100. &lt; &gt;f this amount about &gt;0 was spent in decorating the building, $15() was given the Dairy and Creamery Improvement Association to ;ist in paying the expense of installing and maintaining • dairy exhibit, and the balance of $1,S0() turned over t&lt;i ■ State Fail- management. ifhe Butter exhibit consisted of a large glass ice box in ich was placed a man driving a team of horses hitched a plow, sculptured out of butter. This was one of the ef attractions on the fair grounds and was much apple ted by all who saw it. A model milk house with modem lipment and a model dairy barn were also installed as a t of the dairy exhibit, and were an added attraction II worth the effort put forth in installing the same. Sev- I cows from the Fniversitv Farm, including the cele- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 luated "LaMay" were placed in the Dairy barn and a • i ■ -"•■** practical demonstration was made twice cadi day showing the use of the milking machine. The Dairy exhibit was in charge of Mr. W. C. Andreas, who was ably assisted by Prof. J. II. Frandsen of the State Farm and Mr. A. F. Wilkenson of the Dairy and ( Yeamerv- — — --' ■* — — — ■- * — . ~— j men's Improvement Association. Much credit is due these gentlemen for their untiring effort and the successful show- ing made for Nebraska's dairy industry. FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION. Financial Report. From April 14, 1913 to November 30, 191::. RECEIPTS. I'ndt-r this heading appear the receipts from all sources for each month. APRIL— 14th to 30th inclusive. Testers and samplers permits issued $ 69.00 Wholesale ice cream 6. 20 — $ 2,075.95 $ 700.74 Wholesale ice cream 5.00 Commission .merchants 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 68.75 Imitation butter 4.20 Commission merchants 20.00 Oil inspection fees received 1,976.5(1 MAY Testers and samplers permits issued $ 136.00 Imitation butter 6.67 Creamery 1.25 Retail ice cream ,.. 4.00 Wholesale ice cream 2.50 Bottlers 10.84 Commission merchants 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 198.75 teed analyses fees received 5.50 ondimental licenses issued 58.33 Oil inspection fees received 266.90 * «•*£. Testers and samplers permits issued $ 21.00 Imitation butter .84 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Seed analyses lees received Oil Inspection lees received 6,987.70 JULY Testers and samplers permits issued $l,v Imitation butter permits issued 1,897.5] Creamery 561.00 Wholesale ice cream 3.",.",. on Retail Ice cream 103.00 Bottlers 290.0o Commission merchants 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold Condimental licenses issued 1,400.00 Oil inspection fees received 6,24."i.48 Cold Storage license and inspection fees 7 7 $13,266 4 AUGUST Testers it ii ti samplers permits issued 170.00 Imitation butter 81.67 Creamery 7 4. mi Wholesale ice cream 55.00 Retail ice cream 19.00 Feeding- stuffs tax taps sold Seed analyses fees received 4.50 Condimental licenses issued 100.00 Feeding stuff tax and no tags furnished 188.20 Oil inspection fees received 5,858.43 SEPTEMBER. Testers and samplers permits issued 221.00 Imitation butter 83"&gt;.80 Creamery . 5.00 Wholesale ice cream &gt;, 10.00 Bottlers 20.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 31S..",i&gt; Condimental licenses issued 500.00 Seed analyses fees received .SO Feed analyses fees received 1.00 Oil inspection fees received 6,6*7.1:; Cold storage license and inspection fees 15.00 S S.fil OCTOBER. Testers and Samplers permits issued 105.00 Imitation butter 1,290.65 Creamery 5.00 Wholesale ice cream 5.00 Retail ice cream L 3.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 280.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Condiniental licenses issued 200.00 Seed analyses fees received 1.00 Oil inspection fees received 7,9S3.6t Weights and measures fees 74.70 ■ $ 9,047.94 NOVEMBER. Testers and samplers permits issued 78.00 Imitation butter permits issued 348.04 Creamery -1.00 Wholesale ice cream 15.00 Retail ice cream 3.00 Bottlers 5.00 Feeding stuff tax tags sold 382.50 Feeding stuffs tax and no tags furnished 8.30 Condimental licenses issued 300.00 Feed analyses fees received 2.00 Weights and measures fees received 36:5.90 Oil inspection fees received I,* 11. SB - $ 9.122.59 MIS&lt; KIXAXKOIS rOI.LK.CTlOXS. Sale of one hydrometer 3.50 Mileage redeemed M.St Making copies of oil inspections 30.00 $ 132.76 Grand Total $55,763.49 IMSHl HSKMK.XTS. From April 14, 191S to NOv.iiiImi :{(». IMS. Vnder this heading appears a statement of fees paid into the State Treasurer's office showing the date on which the payment was made, number of the Treasurer's receipt and the amount. K13, State Treasurer's receipt No. 84,543 $1,476. .10 IS, State Treasurers receipt No. 84,. 144 99.45 17, State Treasurer's receipt No. S.I, 574.... 488.39 June 27, State Treasurer's receipt No. 8r&gt;,57.V 2 1 2 June 27, State Treasurer's receipt No. 85,57*1 -~.o00.00 July 18, State Treasurers receipt No. 86.139 1,099.79 August 1, State Treasurer's receipt No. 86,366.. 5,000.00 August 7, State Treasurers receipt No. 86,48;!.. 8.271.49 Sept. 23, State Treasurer's receipt No. 87.105.... 6,721.62 Oct. 24, State Treasurer's receipt No. 87,877 8,618.93 Nov. 24. State Treasurer's receipt N'o. 88,411.... 9,064.68 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 VOt'CHKHB OKA.WX KOK KXI'KNSKS. FimkI, Drug, Dairy ami Oil Commission. Expense of five summer dairy inspectors H'.'T Office expense including postage, laboratory supplies, office equipment and extra help and express and drayage 1,125.58 Telephone and telegraph 182.55 Mileage tor inspectors. Chemist and Deputy Commissioner 2,200.00 $21,560.1 Total Standard of Weights and Measures Depaiinpiu Salaries of two weight and measures inspectors ] 93.95 Expense of two weight and measures inspectors 15.77 Mileage lor two weights and measures inspectors 80.00 Kquipment for standards of weights and mea- sures I'Tii. on Drayage, express, printing and incidentals 75. !tn Total $ 705.1 &gt;,KM'itti«in of Cold Storage Food l.au Salary of inspector... Expeue of inspector Mileage for inspector Printing and supplies 2lU.no 111.07 40. 01) 8 $ 473.4 Total For O|&gt;eration of Seed iiml Feeding Stuffs I&lt;an Salary of seed analyst.. Salary of extra help... 2t;.4d 42. 3o From April 14, 1913 to November 30, 1813. Salary of Deputy Coiinnis.sioner I.ISf.66 K\|i.-nse of Deputy Commissioner 164.71 Salary of State Chemist L,tS6.90 »BM of State Chemist 4".4s y of Secretary 565. 9n Salary of Stenographer :'.T9.Ki Salary of Clerk 149.53 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil inspectors... 8,380.05 F.xpenses of Food. Drup, Dairy and Oil In- spectors S.kSO.OO Salary of five summer dairy inspectors 1,280.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Equipment and supplies 211.86 Tags, express, printing, etc 240.21 Total $ 720.77 Grand Total $23,459.96 Recapitulation Balance on hand with State Treasurer May 1, 1913 .....$ 3,477.14 Paid to State Treasurer 46,053.20 Total $49,530.34 Total amount of vouchers drawn for expenses 23,459.96 Balance on hand with State Treasurer November 30, 1913 ...$26,070.38 Total amount of fees collected $55,763.49 Total amount paid State Treasurer 46,053.20 Cash on hand forward $ 9,710.29 FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION. Financial Report. From December 1, 1913, to November :50, 1914. RECEIPTS. Under this heading appear the receipts from all sources for eacli month. DECEMBER. Testers and samplers permits issued ."18.OO Imitation butter permits issued 65.02 Creamery permits issued 10.00 Wholesale ice cream permits issued S.M Bottlers Permits issued '. 5.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold Hi'::. 44 Condimental licenses issued 100.00 Seed analyses fees received .50 Oil inspection fees received 6,371.90 Weights and measures fees 225.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">1 Testers and samplers permits issued Illl. Illl 43.34 41U. (Ml I«#.94 Imitation butter permits issued Commission merchants Feeding stuffs tax tags sold Seed analyses fees received 'ondimental licenses issued Oil inspection fees received 'old storage license fees Veights and measures fees 4.50 66.67 2T.8.93 100.00 :.' 4 :..:;:&gt; r,,4Tn FKBRUARY. Testers and samplers permits issued so. oo Imitation butter permits issued Creamery permits issued Commission merchants tending stuffs tax tags sold Bed analyses fees ('ondimental licenses issued Feed analyses fees Oil inspection fees received Weights and measures fees MARCH. 1154. (Mi 14.17 Testers and samplers permits issued Imitation butter permits issued Creamery permits issued Wholesale ice cream permits issued (Ml Retail ice cream permits issued Commission merchants permits issued Feeding stuffs tax tags sold :2n Seed analyses fees Condimental licenses issued Oil inspection fees received Weights and measures fees.. .2s t APRIL. Testers and sumplers permits issued Imitation butter permits issued Creamery permits issued Wholesale ice cream permits issued Retail ice cream permits issued Bottlers permits issued Commission merchants permits issued Feeding stuffs tax tags sold Ki.dc 136.6.'. Seed analyses fees received.. Condimental licenses issued 80.50 Illl </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Oil inspection fees 4,352.85 Weights and measures fees 170.00 — $ 4,893.09 Testers and samplers permits issued IS. 00 Imitation butter permits issued 1.67 Wholesale ice cream permits issued 1.(0 Re'ail ice cream permits issued 4.00 Bottlers permits issued 9.18 Commision merchants permits issued 20.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 63.18 Seed analyses fees received It. SO Oil inspection fees 5,215.84 Weights and measures fees received 203.15 $ 5,637.02 JUNE. Testers and samplers permits issued 2.00 Imitation butter .8.'&gt; Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 69.00 Seed analyses fees 3.50 Oil inspection fees received 6,312.69 Weight* and measures fees 178.83 $ 6,566.89 JULY. Testers and samplers permits issued 1,939.00 Imitation butter permits issued 1,365.00 Creamery permits issued 559.00 Wholesale ice (ream permits issued 345.00 Retail ice cream permits issued 97.00 Bottlers permits issued 255.00 Feeding stuffs tags sold 3.00 Seed analyses fees ~ 5.00 Condiniental licenses issued 1,200.00 Oil inspection fees received 7,044.87 Told storage inspection fees 610.00 Weights and measures fees 279.50 $13,702.37 AUGUST. Testers and samplers permits issued 161.00 Imitation butter permits issued 130.89 Creamery permits issued 103.00 Wholesale ice cream permits issued 50.00 Retail ice cream permits issued 10.00 Bottlers permits issued 30.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 130.00 Seed analyses fees 4.50 Condimental license issued 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Oil inspection fees received. td storage inspection fees, ights and measures fees ... 8, 22.".. 25 60.00 173.80 S 9,178.44 MtSCKM.INKOrS COIXKCTIONS. Sale of six hydrometers and jars Mileage redeemed Illl 27.90 |».00 Making copies of oil inspections 114.90 Grand Total $92,927.1? SEPTEMBER. Testers and samplers permits issued 98.00 Imitation butter permits issued ST4.16 Creamery permits issued Wholesale ice cream permits issued Ketail ice (ream permits issued 5.00 10. Hi) 7.00 Mottlers permits issued 2.".. oo Feeding stuffs tax tags sold :'. 10.00 Seed analyses fees 5.00 Oil inspection fees received 91856.62 Weights and measures fees 149.30 $1 1,140.01 OGTOMMt. Testers and samplers permits issued 53.00 Imitation butter permits issued 779.22 Creamery permits issued :,.no Retail tee cream permits issvied 1.00 Mottlers permits issued :..imi Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 247. oo Oil inspection fees received 7.O24.9T. Weights and measures fees 169.20 $ I.S84.S1 NOVEMBER. L Testers anil samplers permits issued Imitation butter permits issued 4 1.00 270.45 Creamery permits issued 5.00 Retail ice cream permits issued ... 1.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold. 110.50 Seed analyses fees 2.oo Oil inspection fees received 8J254.16 Weights and measures fees 179.8") $ 8.S63.9.' </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 IHSIHHSKMKNTS. From December 1, 1913 to November :U), 1914 Under this heading appears a statement of fees paid into the State Treasurer's office showing the date on which the payment was made, number of the Treasurer's receipts and the amount. 13, 13, State Treas. receipt No. 89,074 $8,771.69 Jan. 27. '14, State Treas. receipt No. 89,669 6,948.36 Feb. 17, 14, State Treas, receipt No. 90,333 6,239.38 Apr. I", '14, State Treas. receipt No. 91,442 ."),127.52 Apr. 29. 14, State Treas. receipt No. 91, 918 4,943.74 Apr. It, 14, Slate Treas. receipt No. 91,919 1,580.30 June 1. '14, State Treas. receipt No. 92,721 4,728.09 June 16, 14, State Treas. receipt No. 93,426 5,438.87 July SI, '14. State Treas. receipt No. 94,210 6,397.:.4 Aug. SI, 14, State Treas. receipt No. 94,675 13,432.37 Sept. 2S. '14, State Treas. receipt No. 95,119 9,009.64 B30, '14, State Treas. receipt No L's. '14, State Treas. receipt No 95,882 1 l,m.5« 9,6449 8,124.67 $91,944.73 YOICHKHS DRAWN r'OK EXPENSES. I oixl. Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission. From December 1, 1913 to November 30, 1914 Salary ot Deputy Commissioner $2,250.00 Kxpense of Deputy Commissioner 110.74 Salary of State Chemist 1,800.00 uses of State Chemist 188.85 Salary of Secretary 1,080.00 Salary of Stenographer 840.00 Salary of Clerk 819.00 Salary of Regular Inspectors 14,298.00 use of Regular Inspectors 6,380.46 Salary of four summer dairy inspectors 1,292.00 Kxpenses of four summer dairy inspectors 902.12 Laboratory supplies and equipment 278.89 TeK-phone and telegraph 247.17 Mileage for inspector*, State chemist, Dep. Com. 3,440.00 Printing 890.05 Kxtra help .322.80 Kxpress and drayage 97.64 Office expense, including furniture and fix tures, repairing, books, hydrometers, supplies, etc 949.55 I 'outage 1,005.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">1 l l ,' Standard of Weights ami Measures Demrtmenl Salary of two weights and measures inspectors .. 2.632.88 Kense of two weights and mea age for two weiglits and mea ipment and supplies for ures inspectors 1,185.8:! iures inspectors 119.00 Standards of weights and measures ting and incidentals l.ii?.-). 4ti Kin. 70 $ 5,854.8 toleration of ( i&gt;M Storaj&gt;«' K&lt;km1 Ipw. Ey of Inspector... ase of inspector ige for inspector tor 616.00 lector 249.16 lector 120.00 % »85.1( For O|&gt;eratioii of Seed and Feeding Stuffs Law Salary of stock food inspector 668.00 Expense of stock food inspector 383.0."&gt; Mileage for stock food inspector 120. (in Salary of seed analyst 422.00 Expense of seed analyst 69.38 Mileage of seed analyst 20.00 Salary of assistant seed analyst , 251.20 Expense of assistant seed analyists 17. .Ml Tags, printing and incidental expenses 387. 3o Equipment and supplies 1 » r&gt; . 9 8 $ 2.534.4 Grand Total $46,066 ltccapitulation. K December 1, IMS to November 90, H)l«. on hand with State Treasurer December 1. 1 9 1 :\ urer December li 1913. $ 26,07 Paid to State Treasurer H.944.7 Total $1 18.016.1 Total amount of vouchers drawn for expenses -ir,.m;i; Balance on hand with State Treasurer November :;u, 1914 ...$ 7l.H4s.4i Total amount of fees collected $ 92.917.11 $ !»2.927 1 Cash on hand November 30. 1913 1" Total $1O2,*37.4 $ 91,944.7 Total amount paid State Treasurer $ 10,692 Cash on hand forward </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Note: — The foregoing figures, showing receipts, disbursements and vouchers for the period from April 14. 1913 to November 30, 1914, have been verified by a representative of the State Auditor's office and a report filed with the State Auditor. INSPECTIONS 1913. Groreriei 2,618 Meat markets and slaughter houses 1,787 Drup stores 4 4 1» Bakeries 44 3 Confectioneries 92 2 Hotels and restaurants 1,470 Mills, flour and feed 83 Cream stations 2,700 Saloons 91 Bottlers 40 Paints and oils Com mission merchants 84 Dairies 350 Cr. ameries Miscellaneous 310 Total 11,486 Sanitary orders issued 1,99 1 1'rosHi utions "° Chemical analyses 1,367 Complaints received 1914. Croceries 3,841 Meat markets and slaughter houses 1,984 Bakeries 578 Drug stores 395 Confectioneries 777 Hotels and restaurants 1.930 Bottlers 2 4 Saloons 30 Cream stations 2,096 Creameries 110 Dairies 83 Factories 18 Mills, flour and feed - s " Paints and oils 377 Cold storage 292 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Produce Commission merchants Wholesale groceries ... ■Miscellaneous Total Sanitary orders issued Prosecutions 95 Chemical analyses 1,056 Seed analyses 6 Complaints 199 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BLANK USED IN FOOD INSPECTIONS. lNSTFU'CTIONS TO INSPECTORS: A copy of this inspection must be given to t he person in charge of the business inspected. Notation must be made on the reverse side of this blank covering all verbal orders J. A separate inspection sheet must be made out in detail for each kind of business inspected. Write all additional information on the reverse side of this blank. FOOD, DBUG, DA1KV AM) Oil. COMMISSION Inspection Report No. Hate Business Street City Owner Permit No Kind Ceiling j I'tensils I Walls ! Sinks Floors Troughs Shelving and Counters Bread Boxes Cellar Proof Boxes Hack Room Ovens Evidence of Stock room Rats or Mice Plumbing .. . Employees Toilets ) ' Clothing Ventilates Cheese I Light Butter I Employees Meats Personnel. | Foods in Bulk I Dining Room Candy Display Kitchen . I i Soda Fountain .1 Ice Cream Cup'. card- Containers ' Lavatory Water Supply Pools I'tensils Washed .. Waste Disposal Cuspidors Back Yard ! ( Garbage cans Outside Toilet (When Emptied Feet from Food Display Building I Sidewalk Display Condition Proper Protection Klies ' j Slaughter House.. Sanitary Screens I Condition ' Refrigerator i Offal ' Meat Blocks Hog Pens Sausage .Machine .. ( (distance) Meat Choppers h Hides Other Machines I I Yard I General sanitary condition — Excellent Good Fair. Bad Samples purchased Kind Reason Ordered off sale Pkgs Kind Reason Sanitary order written Reason I nspector </seg>
         
            <seg id="p027">YORK BLANK. HOOK CO., Toil; A'ei. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>