<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  THE SELECTION AND CARE OF SEED CORN</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">IHti IM\ERSITY OF NEBRASKA Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, V. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN NO. 38 THE SELECTION AND CARE OF SEED CORN BY KRWIN HOl'T Mill IOKN Mtlf NKM VEAK'S (KOI' MIST BE Kllshi* THIS VEAK. nt seed corn situation is one which requires careful consideration • - - well known, was exceedingly poor see&lt;l corn at l&gt;est. Nearly 4 thr 1 v 1 ' 1 cifi were utilized last year a* seed. The scarcity ami war has left hut l'ttle old corn of any kind in the state ■ inducted by the Nebiaska Kxperiment Station have repeatedly •I com not home i^rown is apt to tit very disappointing. Seed must this fall for next year's crop. IHF PREMEKT (»rT14N&gt;K FOK SKEK (0K\. ,K~&gt;r -rrd. cold soil, and cutworms, the corn over the state as a ..or stand, somt 79% of normal. In many cases replanting Since early in the season corn has lieen from one to three ■ coo! weather souir 2° per d.iy tx?low normal for the lowing July ao) tend toward still later maturity. I nless we are al: 1.111. an early frost niay &gt;;ive us a seed corn problem even more st ■ ! 191 1 . It has l&gt;eet] the general haliit in this statt to select seed Corn either from the . i-tilv from the field while "shucking corn. " There is no ilen\ inj» the ttt-iuiun-- thi- practice gives seed corn that (;ro»s prettv satisfactorily ion, however, both methods, and especially the first, is decid - it tier is disastrous Last year they certainly were, and r they may be. The weaknesses of crib selection are evident as soon as attention is caller] to ler than good seed ears are chosen. In the crib one can KXTBN&amp;ION Bl l.I.ETIN NO. 91 1 Distributed September 7, /y/j. ) WEAKXKHHEN &lt;&gt;K I SI VI. MK1HODS OK SELECTION. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">■ »rar ui: N ■ ■ - M'HIII. EAKL1 sH.KMhtN Ol stHIUHIV . </seg>
            <seg id="p003">„ bruin* rather •» ptrmlpt-r 24th. I'll is a In . In any B, however, tht- is the - &gt; KETHOIM OF I'M KIM. SEED ( OK&gt;. ir\ xnl while pkkiny it is ■ i-h\ of con in whatever part of ; hiir&gt;e. n IB he ! 1- me Icl. Si -I milling for ri ■ : ; v he in. 1 iuui : 1 two men ran. ■ Itl II. HIM. N IN MUM II IO Nlitllt HEKW. Bbc l.uii.liiiy in wlm •'. a fn 'in r will furnish. Tl reqnirrmnrt H ■■ fui nidwd oalv full of moisturr. the \f 1 bkibM i&gt;iiill\ . mil. — &gt;- a vt-M and that ion-, which hail been ■ ■i to.l shell. Likewise fc ■ . 1 :am which is swealniK «« in a If then ■ r »l&gt;o\e the building are north 1 \i:l&gt; I'll kH) K \lfs Ml M liK IIKIKII \ r OM K. ,'/i at the rar/it^t possikie mo- lt h tf mould is iritmy ear- from esch other. :n picked at the regular HoM of husk ieep. On the other hanii e\ en if but .jtie ear deep 1 ear and lioard. THE "(OK&gt; TKEE." nin mice and rat* are a pr&lt;'hlem, i~'» - post" or a "corn trre." kflj explain the loiistruction of this sini].: </seg>
            <seg id="p004">:" . ■• ; .hi. i THE -hEE-HHH IETHWII of til aimn II v ft Ji anil ' rated tin- i piece just al.« the rwii i- I nee. le. 1 Til with tl; ' off * W or three l&gt;u~i uiwl tbn »v ol is..!aun&gt;; ilryn ,1 The m..-t papulai &gt;| &gt;l&gt;l \K\ 4 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>