<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00025</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A.  LOSSES FROM CORNSTALK DISEASE IN CUSTER COUNTY, NEBRASKA, DURING THE WINTER OF 1906-1907.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Agricultural Experiment Station LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A. PRESS BULLETIN No. 27. Distributed January 23, 1908. rSSES FROM CORNSTALK DISEASE IN CUSTER COUNTY, NEBRASKA, DURiNG THE WINTER OF 1906-1907. P. J. ALWAY AND A. T. PETERS. ase" 's the name given to the cause or causes of death of run in fields of standing cornstalks from which the ears d. It is probable that "many different maladies have been In Nebraska, however, there is such a similarity r by the farmers that it seems probable that the ; attributed to cornstalk disease are really ilue to As to the exact nature of this cause nothing is known. rics have been advanced, and methods of prevention these theories have been described A ustalk disease is valuable in so far as it enables the n it to avoid losses or to make progress in the study of the cure of the malady. Judged from this standpoint, mil luse of cornstalk disease hitherto advanced are worth- ■ of them are even dangerous in that they induce farmers to talk fields in the belief that acting on a particular theory they upon meeting with no loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 central counties the greatest loss. The small loss in the western part of tt state may be due to its small acreage of corn For the past four year b low CD have been especially severe in one group of four counties, viz.. ( ter, Buffalo, Dawson and Howard. Custer has experienced the he loistn and has been selected as the field for a detailed investigation of t circumstances under which cattle die of the malady In the month of February, 1907, we spent some time in Custer County ir vestigating the losses from cornstalk disease. From the school tea the directors of school districts and some 450 cattle owners we obtained of the names of farmers in the county who were reported to have ex enced losses from the disease during the winter. From only 34 of t school districts did we fail to secure definite information. To the 8 dresses thus obtained, we sent letters enclosing blank forms on which supply detailed information in regard to the losses of the wint as well as such information in regard to the losses of previous win could be remembered. Replies were received from 462 persons of had lost cattle from cornstalk disease during the w That the losses were not confine iiieny to new some, is evident from the fact that only 73 of the 404 had county for less than ten years The total loss of the 404 farmers fror 1,531 animals. The heaviest losses w a old. One hundred and eighty-two w tween one and two, 402 were between tw three. The ages of 173 of the cattle lost wire not rej The losses by months were: October 393; January, 422; February, 142; M ■ December and January are to be att the fields chiefly in these three mon The first loss of each farmer usually occ the cattle were turned into the fields, it being durin case of 336 farmers, during the second in tha fourth in that of 11. In the first month in first two weeks, being 132 in the first week, 4 and 61 in the fourth. During the first seven days the lot- 12, 11, 20 and 33 respectively The length of time that the cattle had been on the stal t was very similar to that before the first loss. Of the 1,503 in regard to wh we have data, 428 died during the first week. 377 during the in Ing the third and 187 during the fourth. The total loss during the first montt was 1,162, during the second 238 and during the third 103 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 No. of cattle w f Lj - No. of No. of cattle lost addition to ?£,£ f j^tjf catUe acres lost per istnie. f »™ " hSl. pas- pas- per 10C0 ers - lost - tEred. t5ed. $00 icres cattle, pas- acres. Where they had some other feed in loss was 61 per 1,000 cattle and 46 per I a was less where they were fed, but It should be animal of the first class there were two acres of 4 acres for each of the second class. xperiment stations and accepted by the majority lability of loss is greatly reduced when the cattle ain on the stalks only a short time at first. Our data do ew at all. Eighty-ono farmers, who allowed their cattle only one hour or less at first, lost 327 head; 139, fir ain from two to three hours, lost 574; 46. who lim- a w to six hours, lost 186. Those who allowed the cat- main in the fields all day and kept them out at night numbered 27 140. Lastly, 88 farmers, who allowed their cattle to remain on the ght and day from the first, lost 373. It will be seen that each of the a ist on the average from four to five head uf stock no matter to five classes he belonged. fa 113 464 33 115 79 333 a&gt; 87 23 97 hay 36 146 10 62 Feel S 11 alfalfa 14 52 green feed 13 38 green feed 6 33 y anil green feed 6 'SI 1 K reen feed 2 4 iv and alfalfa 5 24 ilfa and green feed 3 14 iy, alfalfa and green feed 5 16 MM 1484 7541 1402 1297 1993 2282 203 1343 578 331 185 57 192 131 193 11077 3171 5096 2560 1862 3154 1335 418 1640 1185 567 236 160 260 255 295 81 77 44 62 74 61 28 54 :«t 65 98 145 70 is 107 82 1 is used to signify that tbe cattle were all &gt;wed to p asture on rape, wheat oi ornstalks. ■attle had no other feed than rorni talks t tie loss averaged 81 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">»• ■ no salt 211 w iere w nfa N n &gt; I 4 of both. Out of 183 cattle that had salt but were nm we water 10 were lost; out of 3,970 having plenty of water hut : lost, while among the 18,687 having both salt and water t deaths. We have been unable to find any relation between the rai mer. or of the autumn, and the losses of the following wint temperature of the winter months nor the snowfall has In fluence the losses when the latter were considered in ten-da No part of the county was distinguished by its heavy f Neither was there any important difference between upls Rtween sandy and heavy s&lt; le replies indicate the ge ne that few animals attacked by the ma only 22 reported having ever had an ar In previous publications of this Station it h;. prevent or to mitigate the losses from corn not responsible for the disease and that what simply a natural condition of the third stomach Since the discovery in sorghum of a Klucosidt son, hydrocyanic acid, many frnltl ipts h similar chemical compound from cornstalk poisonous substance has been found in the stall cattle have died. 1. The farmers of the central couni lose the valuable forage of their alternative (a) Cutting the stalks when the com i (b) Pasturing the standing stalks with the km to lose as many as one-twentieth of their cattle 2. No precaution and no feed or combination ' </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>