<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Seventh Annual Report OF THE NEBRASKA STATE Horticultural Society Containing all the Proceedings of the Summer Meeting Held at York, July 19 and 20, 1905, and the Annual Meeting Held at Lincoln, January 16, 17, 18, 1906.</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">-Seventh Annual Report orticultural Society Proceedings of the Summer Meeting July 19 and 20, 1905, and the Meeting Held at Lincoln, January and 18, 1906. RUSSELL, Secretary BRASKA STATE </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">NSMITTAL ition, the annual m al Society for th M. R Society. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS ittal ( mmitt 1 n aw iimmer meeting I ngs Annual meeting Fruit d port </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">FICERS J. H. Hadkinson, Omaha H. S. Harrison, York C. H. Green. Fremont !.. M. Russell, Lincoln Peter Youngers, Geneva RECTORS .1 A Yager, Fremont A. J. Brown, Oi W. G. Swan, Tecumseh </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">SOCIETY. r XONYMS H. Barnard, Table Rock. i ENTOMOLOGY AND ORNITHOLOGY MMITTEE TO THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA XPKHIMENT STATION )LOG Harbour, Lincoln )RESTRY ABLE ( Lincoln. A. En NTAL GARDENING. H. Hadkinson, Omaha EGISLATION H. Barnard, Table Rock. </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">11 us Grand » UrooK Park XCTIVK I.IKE MKMIiKKS r, Oregon ..Pa\&gt; .Tabl, Lincoln Lincoln i &gt;fflce Unknown Geneva Florence Kearney Cedar Bluffs ( ( u Kingston, R. I ( Grand Junction. Colo Chapin, H. A Lincoln Cha n L. C Lincoln Chowin Cha Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Christy, Q Coppoc. J. L. wr &gt;ff } wa Cross. T B Krow. Chas. F. y, R. H . . . . WE :ia Davidson. J R Da vies, \' Davis, W li ■ Franc, reber, H V on, J. W Dole. E W . Dunkin, J. M Dugan. John. Dunlap. K Kmerson Erfllng. K P. Wm , B. F. , R. H . Paul B. C. Fredenburg. B Frey, C. H.... H. H •Furnas, R. W Cane, J. Hadkinson. J. H •Hale, C. A Harris. \V R Harris. W T D Galbraith. G. B. . •Godfrey, A. S. . . Green, Chai Grennell, E. N. . . Gurney, C. W </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Membership I .York Lincoln Omahn Farnam St., Omaha Omaha Omaha Pasadena, California Luce Raymond . Auburn Fairbury Purdum Arcadia Box 961. Lincoln Lincoln Seward iffic- 1'nknowa Millard ,ng Water Arlington Arlington Arlington Arlington . DuBois Syracuse Lincoln Boulevard Ave., Omaha Lincoln Alda Unadilla Unadilla Omaha Greeley Center Colorado City, Colo Kearney M Exeter M P. A Davey Humboldt I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Poll It Kh. H h. H Smith. I - - - Stran.! 8wan. W &lt;". Tanahill, Wm Taylor, Frederic k W Tiffany. M. D G. N Tracy, Ck Van Metre </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 rcniont Arlti. I'lace I ifllce Unknown . . Washington, D. C Fremont Falls City Tecumseh </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ARTP . ARTICI promotion t ARTICLE III M&lt; •ball pnsldi : board &lt; V f i for o .trd ev V. l&gt;uti&lt;* of I'n-i.l. -i:l :, treasurer iry; in conjun arrange all programs for the meetir board other d u t i • ARTICLE VI. l&gt;uti«-s of \i&lt;&lt;-l'r i.l.-nt ■hall superintend all exhibits of the office of president at any if ton, shall perform all the funetior rank </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 mor h r the leading papers. This to be done with memt rd Report* of Officer The | 1 report in writing at the pertaining to their r at that time. annn ma xiiirin ty shall hold two or nco-e hall be held in Lincoln on ante, and the other nd place as the annual ex- Meetings. Th&lt; provided llture </seg>
            <seg id="p018">. \ I \ I K I . I - Al » . I » * lar ni' ARTH Amendments a office i &gt;rs, ont din^; ry, V a majority of tl </seg>
            <seg id="p019">ROCEEDINGS Horti ing of July ]9 and </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">1 1ir M'KUDIM Nebraska State Horticultural Society House, York, on Wednesday, July 19, 1905, at hair. Following is a copy PROGRAM WEDNESDAY, JULY 19, 1905, 9:00 A. M i M. Sovereign nt Christy dent York Commercial Club Judging Course at the State Farm Val. Keyser, Lincoln P M. Harrison, York Horticultun Johnson M Morn Hon. E. Von Forell, Aurora Ladies' Quartette J. H. Hadkinson, Omaha V. M RSDAY, JULY O. A Marshall, Arlington ntal Planting of School Grounds. .Prof. P A. Emerson, Lincoln entral Nebraska A. J. Brown, Geneva 1:30 P. 30 P M. about the City of York. jt Prof. J. A. Parks, York. jf Prof. J. A. Parks, York. Music at this meeting in charge ?r meetiDg of the Nebraska State r meeting of the Nebraska State THE PRESIDENT: The Summ THE PRESIDENT: The Summ Horticultural Society will now come to order. I want to announce that tfMER MEETING rvlce in Nebrmak Chat*. A. Scott, Halsey C. H. Green, Fremont </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 « B&amp;llard. All Mr. Prenident, M&lt; esiin;: In order the line of lam well kept lawns 4inVr"nt d W \v ing here will be a t people of York, and we th&lt; work has tlevate humanity is good men, you know. They are men ble. Thank you. RESPONPI Bv President ( = Hon. Mayor and &lt;'itiz.&lt;'n&gt;. at York </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 at no act V ret our ngaged Nebraska, wife and carry on nd sinew. noble eciative done work si While it Is a York to view the beauties of the i educa- vines d tr lory is n.l act from 1: e you to i labor will :he last two ial welcome, we will pass on to CRKKTINC Mr. President, Ladtel and tientleiii.n: 1 think about the best n to what our mayor has said I busy, we are glad to have you I hope this will be a pleasant meet mmerrial Club, I want to welcome you to our just across the street, and yo.u HIIIllS time. The people of York are glad to have has said, we have done some horticultural illv not a very bad place. All the work Y d." The ruler in abur.dan </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 of 1). ily don ■ixl in b&lt; The . If you want m. It ta mouth wa &lt;R not take long him a basket of big, red apples or Now then, it happens to b In our agricultural schools know vc </seg>
            <seg id="p025">■ 25 a t A 1 farm in an of i in fruit are (id need ible to the man knows nothing ■ans. It is man who is a, j produce ;her of horticult - izing the student he writer. It nd at our s on the subject. value he had ro- D exhibitor he did not I- now a few fitting rom l he pointed out t h lid that for yea lit judgiiife. Now i with varieties off his s!iaie of an to put our - if we can trace ■nt for a while and se awakened in growing frui made the most It has been tlie d an introduction nerally what might be ralle ng fruits, that the t announce ng and d ascribing o&gt; apples. We need not argue in your class roll students want su ng such a course h work. There are. The com r se would •atly lessen the nuii - wouid be possible to i this wiuld gr hoiie'i it and the citrous fruits; also nearly all me of year. le to grow strawberries so as iool is in session. Preserved y premiums because lid not understand tl fruit .(tiain we all know he carrl is a good he work could t urriculum hould begin t </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 of idrnt •corin Tin- S Tl one i; and j&gt; •ce. "■■ TarUti He al w are di Y rthe rhoii portunitr of this kind. The . be used, ; !d no UrdV </seg>
            <seg id="p027">jw to grow &gt;S.v. It are al 00 boy» hool. A would also giva iid since nd lack of nr schools. of ex- ar.d coro very American 11 jl con- I baa seen We do not until we get a i course as Mr iltural fair. So I say ■ fair last d took nearly all of the had fine, clean Marshall and Yager took all will do them as much a l&gt;lan and en- good specimen of fruit ■d to do is to muk6 the d^u </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska State Horticultural Sot ie 28 on the fruit growers of the state; encourage them to push tn. The hog men and cattle men. etc.. have judging courses, and think the horticulturists ought to take a back s. MR. HADK1NSON: I say amen to all this THE I would like to add a word Louis, Nebraska exhibito more prerr ber of exhibitors, than any oi This fact » on of the f the tables. This work « ""S. Hadkii w two or tt fruit judging course would ceru Th Plum Curt crchai ■ the ii I Apparent! chanl I .pie whi!. d arged to the full crop se the same many orchards tall control the iture Iom. orchard enssion. it he l&gt;lmn i '"an might not b€ work of this pa involves so sli number of bush* - hird or even o In Nebraska omptly met w ravages of th 1 ■ v •he b&lt; apple »])! tore is slight and mi apples at this II h r»rged to the we full crop involv of I lese the same number the loss of one-third 01 In many orchards in Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p029">» o icientiflc friends have had k n No. 98, University of Illinois Agri - 'ilio and the Apple," by Prof .tgraphs from this work may nay encourage the planter to at once i during the next thirty days as far as po emerge as mature beetles m cnrcullo is as follows: At about the ftation resumes activity and buds begin ation resumes activity and buds begin libernated under rubbish on the ground. ibernated under rubbish on the ground nd in other secure hiding pla&lt; ■ a fruit plants upon which they feed and plants upon which they feed and os bloom, mating begins, and as m lion of eggs begins. Apples no loom, mating begins, and as I ear from one to three of the ch;n this ourculio. The deposition o 1 from one to three of the ch rapidly during the month of June, but continues through le month of June, but continues through adually growing less and less as the been rowing less and ho beetles die. this generation do not live beyond the survive until September, or In rare in - ason both males and females feed .■ deposited, making small, usually of the beetles of this generation do not live beyond the ew may survive until September, or in rare in ison both males and female- ieposited, making small, usuall ;s hatch in from four to six days and the hatch in from four to six days and the ions burrows through the fruit. The larvae lurrowi through the fruit. The larvae Inch in length and .078 inch in nch in length and .078 inch in ? larvai he fruit to fall wtihin a he fruit to fall wtihin a va is the larvae matun "ding, bore enter the ground where they complete nature, cease feeding, bore v he round where they com: iout twenty-eight days emerge as perfect usually remain quiet for a day or to harden; then t' ht days emerge as perfect wenty- nin quiet for a day or and la na; upon the fruit. Beetles of this new es of this new in ran pair, and no eg The fruit is freely punctured for feeding the season ad- e nev a the greatest injur &lt; iiug continues as long as fruit remains on th€ te in the fall the and hide away in ad of hibernation f the full development of a plum cur le in fruit remaining upon the trees. It seems to be i: he fruit fall. Sometimes the larvae of the fruit begins; more fre- n </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 J dilions ti </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 ml it has never been so Hov^innpil the. inter- his Third Mi R while the frui This May until 1 m curcullo. This is due to d to the more di w damage do 11 injurious woi jld !■ spring under ■ EANS OF REPRESSION be recommended M iod of from thi </seg>
            <seg id="p032">1 •s . Killy effective h rious ir. Spraving is an w than they are in d&gt;- fr fungus d: lire add little to the I - of Codlin nii&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p033">N ing the sp for destroying plum curculio nerally unfavorable to insects. end here. The physical condition I renedered available. Growth of d and the increased vigor insure d diseases. In view of f mmended for the detsruction liplication is not chargeable to jallv to attack all orchard pests vorable to the growth and pro- USIOXS ng with arsenical poisons. This method aims at .i;e of the insect onl of the insect. All fallen fruit must e larger fruits that fall in lai lII apples that fall in June and ignored, but is really more i:n - 3n curculio than the late fallen directed against the hod of attack i , larvae, pupa, and pupa. ded to destro lonstrated: verv delicate and extremely sunlight is fatal to both other predaceous insects, as well as birds. rflcial tillage for a period of thirty mmended as an effective means of llios is, in effect, to urge the ilio in three different way n fruit. This method of att .■pment is at its height early </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 H .. &amp; » maintainence of 1- ard conditions Me to the production of aim at th ial v \V br « ba\ di.ri! Large Montmc dlcatd by ■ fruit •pondingly in. of r. kh hi vtgor </seg>
            <seg id="p035">hard two i that they bear notict with Bordeaux thrifty vigorous his indicate! this fungus ful condition. At ■ with sulp again crop tin ached to th with B&lt;&gt; \vn experience in this is wise to in nursery row two or three the foliar -rowth. Should 3 in July or August they the following such vigorous growth ion of healthy foliage. Heavy ap- ndance as to be of r&gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 t ling w • and fung unknown in ran awa fall now n than lu E;ht and e to th&lt; y and ■ most favorab ing and w Wi tion t). 1 shou: diseases In (hi 1» «I HK R ; 1 c fat cherry and apple i and all of disea wind n our we h. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 ■en more destn. orchard be a good community who is ientific man, ho d of the plum curculio. It is uprising how many He has fine plums to show for - all right. I think in to do the busint nigh, but spraying chard good cultivation and a should be no decaying chard ding place untrv I have i I curculio thla r disgusted *vith us down there. Tl not raise guineas in Johnson county. iwb th with a friend of min- v d( trouble with A the i Maybe It v the 1 bv worms or bugs, but I) of an inch long liu\&gt;- eaten nearly worm is a lea! in get rid with this curculio, it don't eat and for i 'ti it is pretty tinea idea. Swan now good thing. The trouble with You should let them run, for n hem and let them go it alone uineas von want in Nemaha Y h 11 kinds of guineas, but only * A h. but I would like to say a 1IROWX x New Yorker, and with us ginal appk as shade </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Kt could be grown Some had d is a that underly K Kt down these things things come to r. Z- is the do me ROWS e kind, y&lt; during the summer by the bird nore, and toward solving this insect q MR. YA&lt;;ER: I u Kg at - tin k the birds ought to be n MR. SWAN: A couple of I went ba </seg>
            <seg id="p039">ulio noticed some bugs on the cucumber out thirty chickens apiece, and when among those vines, they cleaned every p. m </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 H ■d .1 SECOND SESS ON. 2:0( THK .EXT: 1 TH: for tl ■ flowf into il gan! Mv line is growir and for plantir. r which wt Now perh; of you « tell you to plant something different fror hing new, somethi: il odd in this line of work beautiful sorts of plants recommend your yard, that will only bring d -omething that will though we saw it in our grandmoth with a long, unpronounceable nann hri e, that will possibly produ w the glorious lithograph only, abo and that will burn and curl genially, that will look like should hare a cool w </seg>
            <seg id="p041">( 41 » ■ met inies do here in God's introduction of new varities or from it. There is room for great les and new and better sorts are coming out ng dropped continually mber of new sorts of different plants. hat ever happened and sure to a. while we get something that is good irop from sight and are never heard of again. pring is coming, that we begin to lonf jwing things and for the smell of the fresh turned soil iiuary home and an ordinary knowledge of how We had a couple of flower beds last summer but the &amp; not amount to much. This season we are going to • ■ going to have the nicest yard in this neighbo n why * idered is annuals. These may be pro »nts from most any florist or can be grown at home ■ nsidered. it is perhaps better to get the s be better and stronger than you can prodn. w and you will be amply repaid in the s., mnuals which you can raise from xes. transplanting into other 1 nally planting into your flower beds * In their vurio aid col :rs, than utting for a bouquet for (tie table will bloom until everything GymnocariM or Dusly Miller, i beautiful border. all know. In Nasturtiums, alwaj gh you don't want them to climb. For in a compact little bush which I s off after it is w ill growing sorts spread over the d in this manner it ■ the most interesting classes of flowers grown. Aiwa ing new in color and markings every time you ing you want them, in the fall, and w </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebr H a Sta Kect them with leaves or ott ag bloomers early in the spri Phlox Drummondii w will Portulaca. Ricinus or elegant trot Plant a U colon- you i ins. An Y flori.- A in upon to lot Or Pansy, is rich; ir ment For a A bed of do •hems </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 there d for things ven name so patiently to the printed and dig up the flower m during the in nature, if you do not take dings as bright and pleasant as thing wrong in your one next ion you w it. have plenty of moisture for them, they d be all right. All conditions must of the Fruit Grower Company, is hear a few words from him. mer, have a jmniend 1 11 ■ plants, like country home, or would you :ock cannot be obtained for the aver o licker and I ilts, though. It use and hardy plants. Most of the riding purposes will grow until they outdoor stock is of course all right, :ve longer in the season. 'ii a perpetual blooming rose that ia ardy perpetuals you will get a good ;, and then later on they don't make perpetual blooming roses, but they in the fall. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">doing well IRK: Mr. Prritdrnt, M.-nii . &lt;.. in I. mi n : if I WOUl </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 of bt gan or \v and w t 1. I) A \\ om- 1 bellev i late freeze and i berries have a dead ap - will be aaginst them as a nipt aaon, the d soft and the . August I.uther and of exceptionally fine </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Krods long, five rows Geehon, added es were eight I planted Ked almost i twice. Last winter the them: and we !■■ one-half of thi </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 5 our raspberries. and i (black caps) and the ardinal red raspberries icked sixty-four cases, rent; the three rows ked at this date (July 29 cases of raspberries old, of the same length ey only yielded one case Hi! were dam » A.CKBERRIE :ml din and yield of berries oduce a much nicer other var ir crops. We are testing X rs in hopes of getting the desired b&lt; ear excelled all the blackben were trellised about ,1 ivate them and they a cna picked June 23, and \v berries w They hav yielded six box jwn the dewberry m than this year. I but a few are fine »e have ever grown, the Logan on. We planted a few last year and win without injury. also put on wires. The blooming and ripening ivberry and the color of the finest n when they are red, but the he flavor is excellent and the a ring and only ripen a icking expensive. As they are ve promise of ripenin -, I ordered </seg>
            <seg id="p048">N H another lot of plants from ( fine plants growing to make Eating, b ugh it c MR HARK MR. CHK MR. m MR BY nl MR. DAV I MR CHR C. S. HARRISON" MR. DAVIDSON dewberries. MR. CHRISTY berries for $ 1 QUESTION ro planted a few Burban, Is about thi rllfic in California, $1,4' its promoters I canno CHR KMK. BELTZKR MR. CHRISTY: Y Kern part of fthine out i </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 palate; it Is merely gooseberri erland about the best black rasp- Palmer is a little sweeter. The and it has done well in the northern part of the state. ng berries do you pick them pretty green? is on h far they are to go. We )W ;ire to go long distan ,uestion I would like to ask. I would fact that the Burbank plum is absolutely ate gen X ight. But if I were plant- w low I wou 1 )lant something the Persimmon is a good fruit for Ne \ are neglecting it ultur Burbank plum. I want ar were about the best Burbank plum .I ny of our peach trees have nis planted the same tiro fine shape. We have di fine shape. We have di.s - v, and I have alwa ly, and I have alwa I i st of li - he Burhank a u will find that the w f he \ou will find that they d not plant them in our juld not plant them in on we liage. w wh n buy pei where we can buy per- now i trial here. ial he persimmons started, the simmons started, get rid of them. I like unno ot get rid of them. I lik - on my pla row all right </seg>
            <seg id="p050">H N MR. DUNLAP: I years. The tree is a g&lt; w That th </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 juire argu 1 upon this nrriculuiu. All ound that it is a good, the subject. There is first, and that is that There is id that is that ong which the pupils' aid be wound up like he d« Then, too. of gr i then appeal alike to sv i change the d lieu would the nd he "Machine School." iniform, and unchan i apply. Happih ily, ho an automaton. He has var irying de Ji ions ars iias» I in mat i method pupil of seven are 1 ifference in &gt;ower. n wishes to find the unknown quant matics and God pa flower? d( ar acorn] litted to follow the nswer to thei Ped ;hat would deny or for ant It at fourteen? 1 nowled \n be taught only by of the pupil's the child mind? Are vines o bstra jns, or natural objects? he flow he horse, the toad, Dsition in geometry? </seg>
            <seg id="p052">V » It ■■ us duty to num. B man? Can that b room? It miel of w </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 ed with polished u who own 1&gt; mrishiuent ■nviron atmos- strong and n the moral !iil in the coun form of ani then th What is an ins dor UUili.il wl 1, how hink that wt hings ngs coiuii our i long this line, but ed with the inevitable "that's We therefore turn to tht American reason o the body «t, though life history o i nd shrul' proof. No one -ri!l his where special .'it- </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 ntion must b« Kthat was required were the sons and </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 Why? They knew 3. No one seemed exceed - Jung mind. We said by i the young men ani l&gt;t to teach agriculture common schools, h and honesty until the student in Moral I In the firsr ow to practi he order? In that we have jral lines. The littl Id of abstractions and kept g for natural objects have been s;; on how plants d by the system. condor, wh to manhood grown. ng of the bird, under foot the t, and surreptuously kills the inno- d with a thousand de- in order that )\V now to change the low more about 3 If will soon tan; wholesome and in- mple tastes he per- ious in viewing </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 jiromising well. W ( Pinr, i i will do a trial as soon as ence to nursery grown prortas i&lt; giving the Red K L Another ock for planting 0 Th that u '&gt;wn s( ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p057">ek. It would i dlings. a beginn Dakota and the sand id (ai! Ic at all times lr wor win 1!&lt;»4 could not id grow them A ainted with w dig v a f ng of iw .lack i from this - aw wh d we determined ded in getting of planting dug from n digging the ti- put in;-&gt; ad of beii IV lad h&gt; (i. O The moral of thi 'or the sand hills has n&lt; nd it for general plantin ,V md to my knowledg .tate last spring t (l Thedford. Two weeks ago I id asked for the n i['l&gt;ed in wild a ay of ou 1904 w. Thar ar. In our tu-x* live after tran </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 a </seg>
            <seg id="p059">1.1 59 year oil and the tr When planting in the &gt;w and each sui 1 the more it will cost to plant mil is a more tre 1 an is prefer in tr« ml his sfi lid be used, a ;ssful'v o\v on northern o8u« mi he en sho ind where the soil is fir rrows should be plowed torn of the furrow. in damp or f' ne trees in dry, wind/ Aing the seedlings has &gt;n. Time will not permit n now ' ganiz s in a bucket When plantln thousand planted, ttu (iisturban prevent undue exposu </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 IV I Y 11! t •\ith B for plan Anoth' srowt an inch or two o Bold it in check and w he future. In addition and Pi - downward tin In addition to growi n the </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 ome » neon :i rough a o not grow in. We grow them Tl Forest Service, e individuals and concerns, and rvice a not our pu -pend of doing for *' any othi ng ou ition and applies ta in is placed on file and means bu nt is I he pi it' deemed ad\ i h plans have A planting plan the tract under consideration. ve are t \v ntation. It reil. K&lt; rvif ind in tli pro- wo definite ol&gt;j. ir emphasized in every working of timber. The Fi nd perpetuation ization of the p bulletins publishei or hould be addressed Washington, D. C nstruction for planting trees or iroughly acquainted with work is to be done. To In Nebraska a party of </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 H a rank I part of i! It w&lt; north and south I For also E kind ' annually, and II irs old, on old land Neb., is selling $: plantation. Anotli. old, has paid these groves are on upland Osage Orange will ■ Honey Locust and llent trees for the 1 counties. ■' tlon a </seg>
            <seg id="p063">4 3. j t n wood at n IV v a given a thorough trial in Nebraska, Minnesota, the Dakotas, and Illinois. ree f»r eastern Nebraska. xcellent post tree, but it grows too ■om the average planter. hat are valuable for posts, Cottonwood iiite i v, and if methods are t the farmer can use, both will like'T ince they grow so raipdly. )le a timber to be used for posts, al - 3 that would pay well were the timber a Black Walnut ie prominent by this investigation It i protection of field crops. We have able and prominent men to show that st sides of a field will increase the crop mages oi 24.38 on planted timber ile riding along the road, ssed, noting the nd estimat - re recorded in this way While re accura is belieyed roha- mating, hence would </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 K estimate too low or tc would not I </seg>
            <seg id="p065"/>
            <seg id="p066"/>
            <seg id="p067"/>
            <seg id="p068"/>
            <seg id="p069">69 ARDENS Kooiii for School Grounds. an they are. i unded by a couple of - How many country sciools e old&lt; 3 of the state, farm land ol grounds must necessarily be ;niall. nd are commonly required for a Juno 1 ! i are the steers worth after u low (1 mpar; with ool children tlat are ded they must ise the sometiii' ground. There is no use to whiih farm hat will yield as good a ids properly cared for. Country two acres, and might te larger difficulties to be overcome in the mnds is the lack of room — room for I Grounds Should Contain. -iiable parts ied that shoulc not some 1 in Nebraska. It is not things at once. In- nt more things than can le properly i the main feature of for the house no grounts would be outbuildings and walks. importance. Of the plans that may deserve first consideraion. They ie, for protection, and for omame.t, and may </seg>
            <seg id="p070">H * ir tndiid whol«, a t* but th ■ 11 b&gt; omitted. It is 11 (1 ■ h.Tinon- think of i shrubs and flow </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 folio- planting nt ami nting shrub Is and many of a kind than to a school with t&gt; oward t! \v lit ay grounds, .(1 one for the sma"t -. and the boundarie: they are bare of plant. -, « ild be done nds. In i it would i'lared near the road for nientlv near the school dir as po~ traight ones and at the same ated and well nt orth and round for the school yard and In addition to these, a few ea of the place to furnish • &gt;nt yard. Tho larger shrubs he north and d in the curves of the on the buildings are climbing roses on house. The h l irregularly In ■ Ivantage when </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Is of with I wmtB. l. nd, w I As a hool grour requi me with ostern. but rn Nebrasl A considf in follow, though an or shoul art of the suggested except in the v Ki well to have several kind t the pupils may come to k plan ourse more kind </seg>
            <seg id="p073">h 1 her dry: Honey R ian Oliv y, at least while young, some of th whll€ ing an Mulber: . Cot - two are among the best for valley and . Cot- among the best for valley 'and y is good to attract the birds. raska. They grow as fast as most ablished, and some of the Pines the bird ow as fast as most ska. l blished, and some of the I sistant. The K are han: however, and grow much mo-e The E are harder *d however, and grow much mo-e e planted in masses at the rear, k Sootch Pi', robably the best for iven in the wi robably the best for lull Pine is especially adapted to w - to the sand hills. The Red Cedar ani Pi l The I r ani ood trees for school grounds. Of other ,'ruce, the Colorado Bl 1 grounds. Of Colorado Blue Concolor Fir ;i illy good iallv good i most attractive of ornamental trees, ornamental tree namental trees, none are better than Red Bui il trees, none are better than Red Bui Prairie Crab Apple and its relative, Crab Apple and its relative ab. it are native to th lie fnl- to the state, tl r l: Elderberry, Sumac, Snowberry and jmac, Snowberi ' falo Berry, Sand Berry, Wild Rose. Wild d Berry, Wild Rose, Wild rsdnia Creeper, and Wild Grape. These i the neglect and hard r 1. They can be had id nd digging them and similar planting n i i from ries. But then, some n\i that grow so commonly Y hi readers of this, they "&gt;' mon iome eastern nursery for ding off to mphoricarpos, Cornus Rhus e they will get the - j from the roadside the nd the like. Of cour or dig this paragraph. Fifty cents or a to pav for a botanical name (th'j </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 petent man of the neighborhc that would not leave any fun </seg>
            <seg id="p075">x »■ i .1 iav w :i 1 1 -&gt;m and older brother ime in the \ planted, since they a lough so that the trees will staid iod before being removed. In the drier part i and shrubs several inches deep? important to see that the earth 1 of the larger boys should pack the ; while the dirt is being thrown into the holes filled with moist soil, and inches of the surface of the ground. svith loose, dry dirt and leave it dry iter the trees at the time they are is just before the loose, dry dirt is necessary to water trees. If the ; too dry and windy, they wi!l they are to be watered, however, etter be left without water than to Two or three pails d-sued tree. A little water simply ground. In a day or so this driei most favorable conditions for rapid the surface of the ground. Newly ; cultivated. They rarely do well abundance of moisture. Keep tha ■&lt;&gt; wait until Arbor day be planted the first ft ■lanting the groups of shrubs •ous perennials the third year. It ■ me of the flowering plants d of larger shrubs and trees shoul 1 to properly locate the flow ? the planting on one side of the t another side the secnnil be planted about the front of tl»e i shrubs could be set in the c irtod at any time, and s uld be better to begin with a com- attempt too much at fir lants. see that the holes an </seg>
            <seg id="p076">w i will not i &gt;m winds np M&lt; « h prov nto the ground tild be spread ing the siiinn however, the It summer. If lawn gra should, of course be mowed in dry situations, not to mow the gras A dressing of fine barnyard n beneficial to almost any sod. I to attempt to grow the commor white clover, but to seed the grour. What School CJanl- School gardens may or may not be 1 &lt; ve for I V s down at all times, since they rob the pla ing tbe surface of the ground loose with a hoe of water by evaporation. The trees and shrubs flowers may be mulched to advai Ing st material which can be obtained in the neighbor! it- had, mow the large weeds and use th&lt; ought to be mowed anyway. A good time to i ■ school Is out for the summer. The ver - down and hold mi hile school is 1 the surface soil with a hoe or rake; then appl school is out and </seg>
            <seg id="p077">)wn at the school by the school ardens should be su- vi it these gardens are grown by f the teachers, there Is no reason why iens. To identify them still more of the products grown by the irdens might be arranged, to bo dual gardens have a distinct advantage 1 grounds. They would miner vacation at the homes of he things that can be successfully n comparison to what might well be What School C Jardens Are I «r. garden is to interest school children 1 sndary object school gardens may be A irv agriculture. A good school gar- ions in the proper management of i care of various garden crop arden might provide material of seeds, the habit of i; i \ ;irv for School Garden provided of course, it is well a the more kinds of plants can be grown d there is no reason to despair. A better than a half acre not be the case rown in winter, or ng, will serve v i should be chock-full of sug tions are the best In place of a box of soil, a dish af nv florist or nurserymen, is a very good during winter. Moss is an almost that it holds moisture so well lit in a glass dish </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 H a owth of What to Plant in School &lt; I Plant anything that is desired. Lei a ill take the more it v. Rrs, some things will not stand the n&gt; en will .luring nnuals w In the plan i i in t and » beiKis. I included in nitabl w Eg plui :tting re are hard to luipment and matei s, howerer, the mate room that it would be a plan - in connection witl of the general methods of propagation ar propa of the too off n ries and others ■ ir the might be (row readily withoii 1 ■ chile! . that some th KTherf &gt;ol gar' * of i ■ ed. In no twi Many other thi </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 .igated by I and replanted It will be interest- m the end of the root IV. i in planting. Of n by i lie Tamerisk is the is Willow and Cottonwood. eeially If planted early in the fall. difficult to lttings of these i packed in a box of moist win and moist but does not I nd and planted in the d, Black Walnut and Peach must ;ns mixed with over wir lght to be a good thing for these is are kept dry over winter and h is planted much as garden not boiled) to insu i ■ water and after cooling allow llings will afford practice in bud- following the planting of th&lt; lings I and rould be dug up in the fall and kept for dun To learn more about methods of 1 could be dug up in the fall and kept for Dg winter. To learn more about methods of Bailey ik, Goff's Princi- look. Goff's Princi- •epartment of ■ ■ partment of \ on 'The on 'The III. Pimm &lt;&gt;f the ScliiMil (.ardiii. den, it should be planned be- i be well to have distinct gardens, and one for tree seeds, cut- might care for the ible garden, and the The vegetables and the things that are The flowers may be planted ■ advantage grouped 1 i tainly han crooked rows. In gar- </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 ground so loose that il soil is heavy, fine me easily worked. If the Ell be needed all the more lding power of the soil. C it ther \fter s raked until the surface is fine ar the garden illv in Ne\ hoe or cultivator while I should be appliec litter for garden </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 will puddle and later bake nod garden soil. 1: d, that is, land which has mix this with the | eavy, add some sand. The •watered and from becom - d to the soil will also help 1 ui soil i o add low boxes fine man made by mixing equal The boxes should be ight, since they will not ■ ix or 3d d h of soil. Sift the soil jm of the box for drain - than any hide wn very early in th d. Some of them. In in th ing, from seeds sell which d be sown early in ~&gt;\ nip, Radish, and L&lt; nwi somewli Jo well when x though th&gt; anted very early, th hinted until midsummer planted before frosty weather 1 zing weath mall seeds too deeply. For f an inch I nough. Of the iiildren should ■• minating; they may be able to than Beans). Some of the finer I be covered very lightly, j It is important that the ground an absorb moisture better and in the t Sowing S.-f&lt;l&gt;. S.-ttiii« I'laiits, Etc. a be w . mid not be platned until the ground Beans, Cucumi ish, PumpUin. 't, Sweet Corn, Pop Corn, and Sweet inches deep, while 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">1 i uffieient </seg>
            <seg id="p083">.1 il 1 ns of York, on th \. VAGEI G SWAN. IIOWX </seg>
            <seg id="p084"/>
            <seg id="p085">1 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p086"/>
            <seg id="p087">87 N nua Folio ?OGRA \ M Morlan, McC&lt; ■us, C A. M nson, Omaha Harrison, York Dole. Beatrice P. M airman Plant Section, American Chas. W Association, presidic </seg>
            <seg id="p088">H iing C I M 1 H </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 on that subject. iraska » Failures in Growing Fruit in Ne- GROWING FRUIT IN NEBRASKA. ROWING FRUIT IN NEBRASKA 1, College \ \v annually by the people of Nebraska Nebraska I ement of their homes, and a homes, and a , because a very great per cent of anything of value, of use a v le country from one farm ho ntry fror ns to the story, that every man has 1 v and failures in trying to gro jnd failures in trying to grow an 1 hardly blame him for sometimes &gt;[&gt;end another dollar so many farmers ov&lt; n, can hardlv blame him for Bometimea ?nd anot any farmers over tr wing- an orchard, but according to es of failure. One is lack of for his stock, and the other is the commonly called. man or woman in Ne- ording to main i failure. One is lack of e for his stock, and the other is the mmonly call c; e man or woman in Xe- know about them, and it is mostly i it is mostly in not try to learn. Two years ago la : try to learn. Two years ago last f a number of farmers living of farmers living &gt;m to the Experiment Statiou and number of bulletins iment Statiou and ber of bulletins ni ral subjects. I called on those men called on those men I Dint to find out how they liked the find c how they liked the out one man in four had read the t one man in four had read the il had read the bulletins on all his agricultural paper has to he thinks he might al paper has to hf thinks he might b ing it, but because he does not see he does not see when it is two or three </seg>
            <seg id="p090">w Ese he generally ml tern. He has all kinds c of his proposition. One s at so much per i times their actual value, and who agrees to buy the grape: be made into wine by 1 1 according to the at tion with the ■ And h effect. Another will sell a peach 1 making his victim believe that 1 the actual value of the goods. T crop for the last payment on th Kif he dofs undt </seg>
            <seg id="p091">ugh Knox II ■ lorn raist irt ol' the in northeast Nebraska ipally Ben Davis, Xorth- upiiosed to be Ben Davis, ht of a man claiming to The trees n:;me, and last year off we apples, besides filling borne ;i f&lt; n Gr&lt; \v iat proved dollars worth of tivt from a plum .1 two hundred Pottawattomie. and the grape d this man why he ordered all ?d those varieties of grapes a partner in the nu ommending u and told him that the Experiment Station recom - iry. horticultural interests of the state, 1&gt; er parts of the country, where quite a don't know just how an orchard wl and if a few of the people are sold inferior ! to that locality they will become dis - wlth tin ,n apple tree is an apple id it don't give the results desired, tli. he country, where quite a how an orchard wll 1 if a few of the peopli id inferior x hey will become dis- m apple tree is an apple h • I, thev will have tried and failed, and that settles it with them. ind that settles it with them i will in time hurt the reputation of the nursery he putation of the nursery he rith, because he almost always tells the people that he Is • he almost always tells the people that he is : the nursery direct, and the nursery man has to take about the wrong that has been done. mean to say that every tree jobber is a rascal, for you will ind the nursery man has to take about the wrong that has been don i )bber is a rascal, for you will men in almost every business, but there are a great many men in almost every business, but there are a great many ng them. rchaser of nursery stock should buy his trees from the hould buy his trees from the able nursery, and if he buys through an agent he should ni he buys through an agent he should ing the nursery direct, and if he hat this agent i- 'ring the nursery direct, and if he </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 ■ tys from a jobber he sho rd. w Cin hi don avs edu Kl MR t», MR that a tree joi in order to do i I believe it would b« read it. It certainly has G. A. MARSHALL: I w patience. But it looks to me before the public that education of the public is one he farmers becom&gt; one be settled. Tt t attention w :iool of Agr partment, and as little • nan qu </seg>
            <seg id="p093">itional Amendmen 93 TEE ON CONSTITUTIONAL AMEND- MENTS n electing the board of directors, amend- n, so as to elect one director for one for three years, and afterward to ve for three year also in article four, so that the secretary Board instead of by election at the annual so in article eleven, empowering the ary a salary of $1,000 per year, if sideration of his keeping an open office and work, spending at least eight hours a be his duty each year to get out a creditable e monthlv bulletins to each member, preparing h for the leading papers, doing a: j be done with the nembers. This i &gt; Board HARRISON, f G A MARSHALL. J. BROWN, A Committee at th his committee be ieration i o'clock tomorrow to go about this matter w ider work this last summer and I are the members Harrison. Brown &gt; i into the work of the Iowa. Minnesota and M nun K heir offices, and this is I some of ve come to. This is a serious matter, and it &gt;re money; it is going to be a step in ork. We have inquired down at the a room there, and we have </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 In oli. •. and in I Ih-ii. • ] branrh&lt; turn n of plant I. notion ot and h rk. 1 of r&lt; •lly or ni. ly tha tint for </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 E . men had be as were fluU that each has h has look forward hopefully. B and hut until next ine oreh; forward hopefully. in and inn until next ! :ind for the fruit of the tret inii to know that li ill nor blight kill. of the tret know that 1 en, that neither cold can chill nor bligl Watch and Si ■ nd Spra: bile Iowa and 111 i— while Iowa and I Hi- &gt; ni and i . with the hope ' whlli . with the hope i, that i Inter-killing; blight is almot w her will permit n i r dis- r dis- isi meet and 1 illy. This illy. This -, true and fi ! from reading nchi Formed from readin &gt;m different In sume opulatlon and with tantly not been such as to keep :&gt;n and with the con- II would hare would have been eard ol boring m for a laboring man, or iry, to bay f: ; find named, and if pres- to buy fruit at iurlni onths, and yet we find will the fruK It* of 1 or entirely cut off the In . </seg>
            <seg id="p096">&lt;• 96 H Ker classes. more dol high than » J with for frui 'ore ai Few people, it of land to the north of </seg>
            <seg id="p097">nd oth a mar will from demands what yond d, in fact, fro 1 id enormoi them no dir ! . and new land of »nd nd for a time will be. directed to im- will be a own nd Canada d indn odiu Mothf had in of contending with adver that conditions are less jnorant or doubtful, if ition will get better returns and ne that there are brighter pros - ; apple growers, while the care - &gt; eliminated, leaving the entire know how. learn how, ha </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Cased the time mid attention of the plat omy of handling, best methods of protecting tt handling; methods of r« gage their attention :id m r • d, &amp;nd onl be profitabi- thought to utili he has no it is Th in frin •ire tit will b rapidly and con 1 1 red i i and well directed en&gt; their effo and wealtli stantly im changing condition i proach old-world conditions, and, wh no one well informed will den enemies and fui ethods tind thi 1 arig rather than i&gt;rodu&lt; investments, and points ( howi land&lt; ould </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 r I" of the world are &gt;a r hile here the jng men now are not, as a rule ing salaried positions and are of work and occupation as will not only willing but anxious to others, while they go into the ailed business, and in case o: e kind of labor, for pay, rather ther than to engage in som&gt; wher- .a secure — not the own exertions. In other v. ids of mediocre hat the few who do direct Kill be rewarded away abo\ - d downward, until in the no rom, so-called nobl - sed on wealth. When I ist or farmer will be regarded as led. This may no' iy. if but slo.v • not worse than we n horn- rell will it be for our of the pro mi ing, so. if we cannot wn. v them to make nd. by furnishing them with the best of and be the better satls- ission of the horticulturist, one by the apple grower, to make people by educating the 'o nature and to for aj?' of course, as in Eupore, baaed a of the futup </seg>
            <seg id="p100">A w ■ r ■ N xllinp r in th&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p101">band r i h Monta 1 in far i Uavis. \\ i. V( 1 Hyslop ( w w x x w </seg>
            <seg id="p102">X less fnm 11 Y </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 uch a floral w humble the home or Us furnished the for a window garden, for. while it is e from h manv window gardeners make, Is ! row in empera entv of Flowers to mlight w feet (1! njurious to plants. Their foliage wash i ir 1 w :i with many plan most plants admit «• and count. ■r, that the n a. plant, put on n w and the lower roots The frequency of on. During short days of winter, »-th and take a rest, should have hat are root bound and water than those freshly :he use of commercial fertilizers, do r ' our ion from a lumber of poorly but tli i n the looi! </seg>
            <seg id="p104">N v </seg>
            <seg id="p105">,1 i. They nqui little I ml x 1 1 ,v w \ Ffim I). </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 I grow. in on and has more in well dr » ■ I m int ths. union! Yi andard ho </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 d continuous flowering habit and '■&gt; not pot up Geraniums will not bloom until root bound. and rotting the roots when in Many new varieti- nd a few of them prove to be for filling hai i Martha Washr lien in full jrauiums. but their flowering I niiuer. The small flowering ■ &gt;me into bloom earlier, last i the large flou These id are, therefore, i ,1 all the water you can give »-indow suit them. Durir ff the old dirt etc., should be obtained &gt;rate with long may be planted ill, in If th&gt; e buds n White ir fr&gt; IK hardy and may Von rfion ion. The) will mill;; in, the time di-pending : on can call it. to </seg>
            <seg id="p108">N 1 w H h v </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 • U1N four ol ;ind we could find no ob - r what Hoard of all the i for, and by the people. It in. Why cannot our aw- ir all in this: it is simply a our Board of Di- of his main o omn to partake of a i» the duties of American Cl hold things down. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 rectors first, and n thinking this : eight men, with six momus :er man foj I MR. BARNARD LMR. BARNARD d wa and v . wants hir ■- BUM ■ a coir Uon. I ion . ■ - MR. HARRIS) MR. HARK and I and side who h rd for tli' ■ 'it. [ wi against it. 1 - . In the right direction, and we When put and eight against MR. HARRISON I h;r. mend also a chan^- Executive Board to pay th they d&gt; in consideration of r ing his whole time to the work, spending his office. It shall be his dut </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 the last two or three ard procure some suitable place nanimously, it was decided that a W. Furnae ired, and, with </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 » . tilled in \v owiiiL w sly prepared and &lt;ovi well worked in ann&gt;! The reason why with </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 I iirt, therefore making It a trowned to live. If you use porous, you cannot injure iour, — "continuous danip- soil will sweeten it. anted, they should ed high enough up on the stem of the Iriven down at equal distances finished. Or, a two-by-four or pole i alone by driving it into the ground nd leaving it about three or four method is a good one, for the with the tree row, if planted in rows, and ■ of the horse cultivator. Where tin I with the tr&lt; should be ial and the stake bound tightly 1. put some burlap ornamental «.: Oak, Ash, Elm, leu. Kt'dhud and Haws, the latter grow I will name a few of the less wing. in part of I Omaha ind the writer saw ng in Omaha, also some Thorn north and south, for at Table be found. Lincoln, a specimen of deciduous Cypr led growth. soil, you lessen ired, a little air-sl.. n in York, also Magnolia acurainata. ith, a specimen twent </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 H a Magnolia Soulangeana is growing Omaha. Hard Maple, Norwi nd i found in I n portion of th Maidon H eastern \ rl, thri le. i&gt; and id now being plan ttalnly a fine and nt for ornamental pur MR. HARRISON. I and out of that hundred there w ones. There have been thousar The hardy ones will n MR. BARNARD: We ha It has blooi handling the Tulip T MR. HARR C. HADK1 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">n ntion to thi oom until they get ag Birch for fine </seg>
            <seg id="p116">Enthiana, Cunningtu \. Vnlplaa Clinton, Taylor, Klvira, etc.; \. tmtmmtttaUt Dng, Thomas and other south- e fact that a wild plums, evolved from the wild Pi-unii* aiiu-ricaiiii species. Our Gooseberries wore 1 1 fron wi known American ipecies (KM iilmid. too. our Raspberries are the more or ! It. cynoslml llui. i American Raima itrifoaaa IX &lt; Ull'lltllll- short tii </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 1. but It is in ivated vari. w t a time that « I have cited wll d ieties have been d&lt; rocess. I hold M i an we now have from irich and enlarge our li vution still moi I i&gt;ted to ii i from a long list, that 1 ing. I may venture the hope that ■ I n iuation as well as the time and means for • of these wild Whea Rye, Barley and in my opinion are likely to n w he time and means for emenl w ( II opinion are likely to l.l) WHEAT. of the wheat proper (Triticuin i n of the closely allied I) Wt: wheat proper (Triticum ly allied lil Whi ast one B one - t for I :nent;U plant breed xperimental plant b k'heat Grass of the Great Plains | Plains i i&lt;l'-ni' ng a height ol tl, erei :ing a height a in a 1' I five to six inches loag I. The grain is long and is hairy at the apex, and grooved on the (1 five to six inches loii£ he grain is lor hairy at the apex, and grooved on the lid Wh already shows many -e , and the difft- ■ such as it '» the differences are such as it ! i &gt;ear under cultivation and selection, "a nder cultivation and selection, "a American Wild Wheat, with its strons. many-flowered spikelets, with the American Wild Wheat, with its strong I and few-ftoweri'd Argilops ovata of that the American plant is by far the id had but a fraction of the careful ii to the European hat it would have yielded a much more pro- han we have in our present varieties of wheat. an plant is a long-lived perennial, it is possibh nni i! cereal </seg>
            <seg id="p118">WILD Here we ha Horili'uni s of the genus to w lv allied | a nur ral o&gt; Trill the ■ I lyiii'ii' Kl in nun ' !l ]&gt; M ;is *i ■ This ( UmilHoiiii olijfoslachj B?ighi from ration it has 1m </seg>
            <seg id="p119">us Wild S 119 J also in some place tern, which bear* r portion. It and that it is • ( l^&gt;lll» Mill I ll ■— ll ( plants, la its wild mud iu t "intains, some Hivation of these mlgnt liiliiliiiiii) I to add Old World mmon use for i h ALO PI V he Buffalo (Astraga- of which ii-t iition upon the Great Plains assures nd to be palatable and he Plains or twice a day for i for dinner. While the cooking Y he result was a dish rte. Ever since that experi- d that in this common prairie I ir garden \tli«T»|M&gt;B&lt;&gt;n &lt;urtip«'ii&lt;lulu f the prain &gt;d quality of wild riment Si utablf hay. I have had . uy wild ile number of .iis family. These ow hi nnial which b'. irly in the I|IU&gt; I coll' nisiderable quantity </seg>
            <seg id="p120">\TO CHERRU For man Solatium trillorum used the fruits and ascending, much branched i .mmon Black Niglr -..laniini ni r has had a number of local nai: Khave used, n half an inch t nd 1 b w an old ad .' wr of .round Nut (ApfaM api.&gt; 1* and minosae). In the » an inch to an incl dia are very good iant, which belongs to an er which contains the P w ■aghly improbat tuber should v- a alon int May I ask you: appear to me to be waiting f orchards </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 E APPLE wild apples found in the rab apples." They are ic le doubt that had the common Mulu* malus) not grown well in New England mpts were first made to trans- hundred years ago, tht o cultivation. Had that i v ious native api iting 1 we ha. uting native grap«?. Iowa to turn to the (Main-, ioenals) as a promising species to be ini- ivatioii s ago I wrote in the Annual Report Nebraska N uris 1 wish here to urge upon g up this promising native species, and of . e from it a new ourse of time I have no doubt at &lt;&gt;ou will our li ike it HKKRY (I'rumis &lt;l«-nn- jmmonly a small tree, having ■ iible fruits wiih a thickish flesh, aud a: When unripe they are quite n them the unfortuna they are excellent eating in s I can vouch for their excel c ustered in rai • o which indeed this Dwarf Cherry i-&gt; ution to this as worthy g fruit, and I cannot refrain from ur,s sirability of taking HKKRY (I ■run ii- bes Sand Cherry (Prunus puniiliO and which for many years was suppose! d the attention of many growers - on the Sand Hills of C </seg>
            <seg id="p122">H .late clust ■ it I * in Of h. wi Xowada Cratacgu fear that 1 an </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 *■ on iously sweet fruita ■ verv good re;i The in nature (hen sly I think, as hands of tha fruits which ar- ish in the Sand Hilla </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 i 1' . I'lt -Mhllt. I.4MII''*- .tnil &lt;»• HIM a I •;:.- w mann. A labor nd i groun count i could rovide northwestern country, I ■* adopted as we om -nvironmen and never ir - is that known as ■ artificia I xp Mnnson of D« tne r. I&gt;1.\&lt; hardy varieties of grapes. Tw&lt; tatural fertilization of th« lohn Burr of </seg>
            <seg id="p125">a., and R a A ded 3 1 .1 ilization of &gt;lying to plant breeding, the fanci i was set with vines obtained o w to natural cross fertiliza - o£ Mr. John Burr. Having ooming season of a number of d for future use, I was enabled n conjunction with pistillate, or n of blooming. The intention M was to constitute the environ - late varieties would be necessarily hree-fourth well established 3 were produce* from Brighton, being pistillate This division w ?st and ni" i that the largest Herbert, flowered and the as purposely ■ •rfect berries « and planted. T'ie ds st ■ during their fir owth or diseasi ison's growth, •d foliage were re- first season growth they of the several angement of ■d for this way I ho; .m's coll. From the s John Burr system, forty-five o: ,f number of them has been ex- 3 proven remarkably good as a vine was produced in tl: ram and Delaware under ason as the above described lot. I attribute their \ the Burr • of fertilize vv rican. Fiv. being the season itnts ii: endrils, color of ransplaminK into particular. In from that and i ijority of vines origi i pistillate verietie fertilized and r&gt; However, there are t» </seg>
            <seg id="p126">n regula partly in i w H. -ation of other and abler met thave made with seadling vin arch, 190 2. During this moi Dem ignm&lt; renty-four varieties. His "At composed of the two species Ktion of forty-fi t one-half of Bnd and exhibited ve vleldt </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 eedling of Brighton in conjunc- 8, iy i seed bed, put in i bed. Last a At the close of the season there ik and diseased paints, twenty four have continuous tendrils. I con- ag vines ar is peculiarity , at my place i luring his r led them to ma the severe cold. end lop Doan Doaniana It w Upon An o umii, or (1 Purple." The?. Texas are not hardy U degrees below zero a d one dozen cuttings ne claimed to have endured 50 degrees below zero on, after being fully jwing se inted in the fall of area seed Dea, put in deep. A fence board ed row to prevent any anim:il3 'Ponroy." It Is a 1 pollen from j cold </seg>
            <seg id="p128">1 H exposed. These cuttings were r Tines produce clusters quite sinii BaccL larger than Bacchus. Tt have a cane of tht </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 low l.iidi.v and &lt;..-iill&lt;-nifn: When I was a young man l 1 northwestern part ot well in that climate. v man •dli anting them along - which would and sold them own in which he lived n of the Concord grai There wai a ( : lively interest in grape that Mr. Bull was originating trod action of a hybrid 1\ in some of the fine- 1! it interest in these planting and growing of ihousand nia. New York is the leading rapes. The most impo ti shore of Lake I w that In some t • ire Concord. ( ow I found a rei nd one of the nios ?ntly he took up like tl il of interest manifested f the country just then, he iir hortlcult- </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 , tin this in 1 is the Of IlllUlM and I On In v latic and scientific I rn something about the We ormation. Those who inot afford to nd not it. There is not much Ind </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 v he experim- he Geneva at this s ! some things of value hav apes has not been w to breed gi better one will ow rinciples 01 should take u ons throughout !h hem worn SSI ON" a al Coni il town, and I said: You graii ig; you cannot know roni you. I wa and old vine in. seating th i on tho rig he "kno'v- brou ivhicli d. With Mr. Patten, Pro- have il method- ; d to pollen varieti. nil tl ncord and yon rd. It is qui'' You look ;i you will fin: i • lood in them. In I would be very careful a In breeding | </seg>
            <seg id="p132">Th« ha F bu nefit \\ whict flow( he m 1 :ind t«- Home i he Omaha F hearty inv hold and i; R. </seg>
            <seg id="p133">w i nd my jrxest m. pollard on re- wanted to g( - -ot up the </seg>
            <seg id="p134">■ WHERE I'm OLVI The Comnr frn Fruit Gm by producing statements r amount of fruit grown in tl We also met tin- of! he A l&gt;anies, who were also willin fruit, and we have the pi been lowered, and ship]* rper crate on small fruit. We found the ei tion about the f From G </seg>
            <seg id="p135">them ably u- ■&gt;d proposition, as the pros - r. This committee could do he fruit I ind I me an appropriation of $100 added irk. It may also some few changes to be com: empowered to act »ill now hear from Professor X. E. Han- Nursery and Orchard." PETER YOUNGERS POl.LAKD, \. MARSHALL., C. B. PARKER. committee be ac- ■lilted to divide 1x up a list of recommended fruits ition. on the subject, "Siberian </seg>
            <seg id="p136">RIAN I Ki (1 i how ■ Pvru- inalu» 8] the I Pjrms Imxala. V\i t Cherry and Ytll&lt; hich is consid' I*ynifc iiiiilu^ aid PjmM b </seg>
            <seg id="p137">wing i bud them the following on the ti- il&gt; on d do irdy. Thi r.viii- im.iIun wint€ of the north- Fiirthermor ds fail to gernii- it would solve the world. This explains why the North Atlantic this kind? No, he on with the ordinary root- much as budded necessary, however, to find tin in I'.vru- li.i ielud&lt; ill thi 11 Hibernal </seg>
            <seg id="p138">ate Hortieultu Europe, with their eh that whole w but 1 di tibabl Wher Klow Sib How sh; man should ha raising seed. Or would be on the mark thinking on tht commercial m the tender roots. And cessfu! DIS( E HARRISON: I r ilings of Hybernal. ■ i at least. What is your hat xperi' t PROFESSOR HANSKN: It is a «m ore snowfall than we do. In Iowa. M low, apple grafts were killed The wl some way of doing the w»rk in wi log explains why American api larger gathep as root-killin north it would be indf tMeanwhil ich I mean a £t&gt;od m </seg>
            <seg id="p139">and Orchard 139 a famous young scientist said. w irticultural world if the art of vented." Some of these things mething in that. Whether we n you to recommend buying the ) we recommond to do is to d the Mahaleb stocks. The ultimate make the tree more dwarfy and They are also easier to spray. a not advise grafting on the roots and scion for this country? a SEX: Mr. i 'atten has tried piece-root grafting ?en a ■ Down here I would atering to the North Dakota trade, o have the root of this hardier than )R HAXSEX: Exactly. There is something about alter- e in the world will stand for instance then, would live would rish in the ground Y ion to this grafting proce: OR HANSEN: It is a matter of physical union. Some- on Mahaleb stocks, but you would MR. MARSHALL: A question of information, — Is the idea on he graft above ground o : HANSEN: Ye exactly MR. PATTEN: Do you find that the seedlings of the Yellow Crab re perfectly hardv up there with you PROFESSOR HAN </seg>
            <seg id="p140">Hor e Horticultural Socii MR. KEYSKR: I' tro.ii THK 1'KKS l,r. </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 I HYI JRIDIZ1NG FRl'ITs ins c A-- ixiution: I feel hon- [ the Aiiu-i-ii ;ui BfCfdOf h an eminent body of men from With so many noted men give a few facts from my ex- jcidate them. I'pon your program I am ■ ds and Results of Hybridizing. It is not dizinn jsarily the best i We made a great many id a few pears. From the little wild goose and the product polli- he Victor Sand-Cherry plum, one n dian -iderable larger than a silver 3 we pollinated the Miner \ dozen year tot a plum we juacken own it largely for . few years Quackenboas, and we have Red Glass Americana, is unusually thrifty, ex- hardy Wild Goose. w&lt; I from and Wolf Plum on Wild Prunt The fruit is a he little French Prune, to Jonathan and Martha Crab on Ben fruit size and quality of d taken by the wtih fruit buds and bark- -oon there was but one and that is photographed here in I the string running from apple to as easily as corn, and namen. have had a common i t </seg>
            <seg id="p142">V State Horticultural Neb: origin. We have fruited more than one thousand crab. Much of this work w ipon whirr w Some of with liiuli-ti. of the: dollar. We call tl fair and free from won .ing. It is as firm as I pear. Every family w n winter, and the tr ■ grow them by « The greatc Ider and ■ from befon our own mind to calling upon n; mian b useful ami e environ The indivii! through li: assistance of oil production ■ for what he r Vninu ion. To su understand their main all living things, but in tl mind is not often intelligent enou beautiful individuality of some of ou of it by allowing the n did not h: behind them h they know . . and that we are behind th cate a sense of justice, and thi of poisoi: irtue and where on&gt; 'ft and the other b&lt; across the line. Even plants commi rototype of the tenderloin woman ii. Aell known apples, and ot&gt;:. in human t </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 1 ind iuctiver 1 W I f »• i t n i\\ nn no return for i that even commit murder c Sundew, a Welsh plant, and the ntl on th of North rovin- riment, we aever n is an outrage upon nature's stimulating conditions thai will beauty and quality. wished for the Seckle pear and we from blight and productive. We ,t would reproduce aid grow them with a kind of in- em in the small white, and large type of red and yellow .pie hav&lt; them when the&gt; nil other hardy sons but the woody nrvelotisly beautiful bore such a ni &gt;w zero, in the winter, and 1 &gt;on it bore apricot: all the vigor we can get 1' The nursery should ven locality in large quai ng in a bud or by fting will blight and kill the be practiced. Now w. ing that is worth millions to hough it is only recently th. tine quality as by ■ ommunion by uits. tion, and we have reproduced ,md automobile .iiit of more than a hu which is large anil itiful. ifornia n&lt;i plenty of pollin to I did topgrafting, and .ethods of propagating mple perfection thai it </seg>
            <seg id="p144">i w grow icions w w 3 Soc tin this method we like scions three or four we wish to increase, getting them from the nevi terminal buds have formed. We slope these sc and run them beneath the bark of the tree we aid of two cuts less than an inch long. The fin with the growth of the tree, the second para fourth of an inch away, three-fourths Of an &gt;ss the top of the upper cut the knife is drawr nd which the scion is pushed between the two c grafted should of growth, with plenty of descending sap, which Healinp and growing beini ■I. If Oil' </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 BUSINESS d w (1 lo . ion li ,irv o i Mr. Gn U nd hon ny of you lly enjoyed thid 1 thank you for thirf 1 nil in this d tba made an bonoi &gt;f the -Mr. i up, havii,. of horticulture hat in order to test hi N line their adaptability to th&lt; inated Gentlemen of the N 1 to }w I am well i by : </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 Nebraska State Horticultural Societ REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON FINAL, RESOLUTIONS As we have been favored with the presence of our co-workers, Messrs. Van Houten, Patten, Greene, Hansen Beach, from our sister ■ so our local Burbank, Mr. Theod Williams of Benson. Be i Resolved, That w&lt; tlemen respectively. Be it fur Resolved, That «• an who have favoi i Repo: 1 and KT Of WHEl; Hon. R. W. Fui Craig, active mem I rber of our Resolved, That wt brothers to build up our stir the death if these at large, has sustained ai Resolved, Thai the faun Report of committee accepted and con Meeting adjourned. </seg>
            <seg id="p147"/>
            <seg id="p148"/>
            <seg id="p149">149 WILKINSON FURXAS England, date not known. Tl I -lors Kobt HT d at tl The neral At 1 apprenti- Hart, Troy, Ohio, serving fc». of printing with A hawk. I job printing house in Cincinnati, 1 periodicals . While a ind purer iv. \v i t h hed in N« June 1, 190j, was His Jenkins, were both born .nd mother in &gt;oin in Charleston, South John Furnas, was born at or Qu in infancy. Racba andfather Pumas, until 1 jin ai 1 to Rich. C. Lang- nston. Kentucky, where he y E. Mel .1 in clock. •o Tillage ion ot "ii &amp; Mil inlov of tli </seg>
            <seg id="p150">I 3 H icul ask &lt;-d to the council branch of the territorial leg four consecutive and printed the laws During his firs law for Nebraska; al ;. Was eli and journals of w o Board of Agriculture. During his term a.*. secured the passag never failing in eonspicuo A missioned torlal mil Paddc manding and ii Legs. The: was completed, was, by Governor Alvin S of same, and served under Genera dition against Sioux and other hostile I: •sessions. The Second Nebraska Cavalry of White Stone Hill" against the treble After the expiration of term of m Soon thereafter, and without his know 1. by President Lincoln agent for Omaha 1 serving near four years. During that tin confei • Eble in the Indian N </seg>
            <seg id="p151">Ro Wilkinson Furnas 151 During his term as Indian agent, from a y the government he elevated the Omahas oduction and sale of 40,000 bushels of surplus ugh his efforts the mission school was increased to one hundred and forty-five. jf Nebraska. After term of service where h has since, and to date, been ■owing antages were very limited; never attended i good practical education by efforts e, and over midnight lamp ary order of Loyal Legion of A. R. and milit has held numerous official positions them was also colonel of the First Regiment, ears President of the Nebraska State irs vice president of the American ee years postmaster at Omaha Agency; was nts of the Nebraska State University, and for two rd; one term president of Nebraska Soldiers' i States pension agen i line whig;" latter days, republioar ■: aska ui F. of NV i Grand Master Unit sd States Grand Lodge same ■V. I jrnas was initiated, passed Ohio, April, 1853. In No- Franklin Chapter No anklin Council No. Grand Lodge of Nebraska n 1, and again from 1869 to Jrand Master from 1866 to 1867. He received the order i ommandery No. 2, Washington, D. C, in o thirty-second degree In Washing- Omaha in 188 — . He was also pter O. E. S. and Grand Commander and I Commandery of Nebraska. Many minor 1&gt; ower bodies were also filled by him with honor and fidelity itv. His eminent fitness and efficient work led to his con- i i the debt of the order to him </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 l» A ation wei ■ Hon. r </seg>
            <seg id="p153">- \ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 Nebraska Hortic at h i A I'upulus UMMH caroliniana Beginning to show injuries, altt ?»aliv I rl viK-llina uurea Hal It A pretty, ornamental shrubb KAMI ! Querrus I hiiu- I linn- am&lt; 1 1 mil- &lt; i iii|m -1 1 1~ I luni 4 .III- ... • I.I. i FAMILY Muni- Mo i ii- alliii talarira ( L. ) 1 Good ; FAMILY PLAT I'latanu Plalanu- IX I Mi ■&lt;■!!■ One of the best ol FAMILY POM Main- H Main- i&lt;x n-i- i Wood i BrittOB. . A fine looking, round-'. rWtm MCMMIfl M wing thriftily, ru- n.liur and ij </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 u- &lt;l&lt; \il.uiiiiii~ aliin Ithus ulalira li il i I l.Y CAESALPINIACBAE &lt;■&gt; iiiiKH'liKliiK Lam. Kent inky Coffee Tree Ills (I lea GledlU Honev Locust ill h&lt; MARUBACEAE Ailiiiithus Desf. Tree of Heaven lulo-a ivation MILY ANACARDI EAE A( Uhus L Sumac on large ground h looks w ■1 FAMILY CELASTRACEAE Kuonymus L Kuonymus atropurpureus Jacq ahoo which does well smal </seg>
            <seg id="p156">I II It II M I -ill— I \ </seg>
            <seg id="p157">\ 1 .1 y </seg>
            <seg id="p158">« 15 | Nebraska State Horticultural Soci of any in the union. Just think, it has now 2,000, and the aim for next Th&lt; was this success achieved? Ion For years the socie was like Nebraska's, to .dically wr each year. This plan is secretary is one that pays the best salary, ana 01 i dates for it, and of □ who may not method we no &gt;l onstitutio was exactly what the Mi Bgent dir unt up i They &lt; judgr or calling. H Dt by setting the The Nebr board of directors and be a man of first class should have an office and keep o; rlslt different sections of the stati hundred annual members should be s their $1 a year and get the annual re rehash, warmed over and over and r fresh information, and be absohn It should be gotten out in good shape Into the world with a dozen glaring bh report which will be something more th s Strawberry Crop a Failure The first thing was several pap€ parts of the state the crop was a failur «ave good promise, but just as the fruit was sw </seg>
            <seg id="p159">hern Fruit Grower 159 ind wiped out the crop. We remember were at least a partial failure. ion over the cause. Some said the and winter, and so the plants were badly nfeebled that though they could w« in as the strain of fruit bearing came i so succumbed. South Dakota Agricultural College, one mil one of the most patient investigators, root of the tree and told the cause of you are raising have too weak constitutions, nt strawberries came from South America and 1 you will always have trouble with them. I do that I have to mulch. I throw away thousands w weakening. I want a plant that will stand out in where there is no snow on the ground and it is 40 You couldn't do anything with eastern or southern rouble with the pr&gt; of straw- The Keynote of Succry line of his experiments. He had r he could find them in the north - ng them with the hardiest tame ones, saving all ting all that were too tender. tying: "You must build up a horti - 1 develop what you havo and here is Hanson is doing wonders with the sand cherry. He is !i Manitoba and the Black Hills, raising iy. He rejects everything that kills w Jy the way, the professor will visit the Nebraska Horticultural he annual meeting in Lincoln and will also address the Thursday afternoon. He will tell us about forestry n Europe and America. The professor is doing a grand work for n the nor' </seg>
            <seg id="p160">\&lt;l&lt;lri'«MiiU tin- Agricultural Htudeul Th v M;i </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 K I. VENT STATION (1 ch&lt; • . quality. hold 15. We md the N. W I the Statf Horticulturiil S . </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 Nebraska State Horticul »■ fifty-five apple trees, inclduing ten variei made a fair growth. I was somewhat sun thans made the best growth of any kind on tria dozen each of the Concord and Worden grape, made a very good growth. I got a good stand a of blackberries, raspberries and dew berries. '. t grapes, have been sadly n waking up to the i. Irieties and by prop* these delicious frui eds and the soil loi !... w Er. and afte two or thr i froy- w manure The 1 w short time to mi Bearin tThis has been an It of the use of ash Ben Davis, Maiden iff fruit. Experiments in thinning fruit take off a part of that which forms where mains will be larger and be a better opportunity to dev Varieties The Ben D^ yielded th ■ing. The any kind we have in bea Maid which lh ion, orna i tre&lt; inga. Oi nted on too 1 i Cherry. The ; of the i Blush and R </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 nent Station o bearing, but last year they ase with all the bearing trees. with fine me apples as usual. The prettiest just coming into bearing at seven slower in coming into bearing to be of some age, it is a good tree. ( 'herrie ier in which they are named: Knglish Morello, Wragg and Osthelm. tations. The only sweet cherries 1 the Viln. ire a failur Plums. »n at the head of the list of plums. All n account of a late freeze; IVars at this station. We have some et come into bearing, being only well, making a good growth, and Experiment With Fertilizer Kith wood ashes, alone and in combi rnyard manure for several years. ing apple, cherry and plum trees. of this work, but briefly stated 5W ht, sandy soil, a mixture of ashes and half and half, or one part of sheep manure to two parts i good results. For plums on rich land (and this is the md suitable for this fruit) the same treatment given to will succeed quite well. For cherries, more ashes and less is required. In far- f wood ashes to the tree, well 'iat we are testing, the most the Amerieannas which do well here, ind J;r fin to be hardy lit bud. </seg>
            <seg id="p164"/>
            <seg id="p165"/>
            <seg id="p166">■^ i ■ A c ' ! I * '/ 1 ITT = «^p_Jj Hi rjj V^ (TflO \ 1 / * I V I / Wai 1Q ; ! J R*5 \ FTT7 ■ rji F f * J' 0 ;.- c I* •diamjHS j K &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p167">1 i\ hf I iitf Flora Belle, Famuse, and K and Plumb's Cider. Ben Davis, Gano, and Wine jwa Blush and Missouri Pippin , Jefferson, Saline, and Lan - he following varieties for i- Duchess, Coopers Early \ June. i Sw r White, Cole's Quince, E laiden's Blush, Fan r, and W. W ward, Butler, Polk, Yon following &lt; &lt;1W Pippin, Ben Davis. N. W. Greening, , M. B. Twig, Gano, Jonathan, Iowa Minkler, and Rome Beauty 1 For I (oniprisinp Colfax, Platte, Boone, Nance, and Merrick &lt;ounti« ommend the following for general planting Yellow Transparent and Duchf MrMahon's White v W. Greening, Salome i Hlush, Famuse, and I'tter's Red. Wine Sap, Jon Iden, Thayer, Nuekolls, Fillmore, and following varieties to: Jonathan, Grime's G Early II &gt; 'ooper's i, and Sweet June. lush, Utters Red, Patton's G </seg>
            <seg id="p168">N &gt; A 11 I Mill I } I \ V </seg>
            <seg id="p169">\\ n K 1 ul Jon lantin 1 Win </seg>
            <seg id="p170">LFor DiBt ■ rising and Grant counii' planting Summer — Duchess Autumn — Wealthy Mdge, low For I • nd the Autumn \i Wt »»d For I)i and Ki nt Summer — D Autumn — \V Win W. Green r apricots f' For Districts 6, reties of apri For District v I' iirdi** - For Di - and Palmetto For District No </seg>
            <seg id="p171">iricting the State. 171 RRIE n unsuccessful except in d d for trial, Stone's Hardy. or trial only Uichmond, Montmorenf Richmond, Dyehc heim ( imm»&gt;nd Early Richmond, Montmoren 3 Dyehouse, Baldwii Richmond. Montmo d Baldw 1 Ea Richmond, Montmorency we reconiraeud Early Richmond, house, and Ostheim *■ ii 1 Ea Richmond, Dyehouw immend Early Richmond and &gt;! end Early Richmond, Montmorency, 1 commend Early Richmond, English P der and Early Ha ami 14, we recomi ommond Early Richmond, Richmond, Montmorent Baldwin., i Earl 'tid, M Morello and Terry and T </seg>
            <seg id="p172">X H (RAH A For 1' »For D For 1 1 V K md V For I) </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 la, and Whii- White ia Dew- mend Dwarf J R It IKS Downing, Houghton, Ind i Downing. Houghton Downing. Houghton, and Ii ■ommend Houghton Downing. Hough &gt;,, Mo )drult i. Worden, Moon Diamond, and Wood :d, Worden. Moon 1 Moore's Diii! Worden. Moon </seg>
            <seg id="p174">174 tale Hortic For District No. 6, we recommemi Early, Elvira, Niagara, Wyoming Red, and Po For Di on, Bokara, and \\" For I • Early, Early Rive • 11, ( Cling, Wright, Smocl nd Hills ( For I 6 and 11 unrai triumiiti id Bokara. For D we r&gt; Bokara, Russell, and Wright, for tria For trial onlv in Districts S and I, Champion, Bokara, and Wrigh Eriumpl. ;ilway. tFor For I » lAkarn and Wrieht. f For District No Early, and Pocklington, for general plan For second choice in District 7, we For trial in District 1 Diar Foi Early, and Pocklington f For trial in For Di Early, Pot i and Moo: in winter to insure success. For Di- Early, EI\i ra, and v For Early. For Fo: I </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 lend Alexander, Triumph, R \Y nmend Alexander, Early Rivers, Hills Chili, Wright, and Crosby mruend Alexander, Early Rivers, anipion. Hills Chili, and Wright. ommend Alexander, Early Rivers, commend Alexander, Early Rivers, Rus- we recommend Alexander and PEAF &gt;mmend Kieffer, Bartlett, Sheldon, and &gt; . Sheldon. Ducho ■commend Kieffi De Jc y nd Duchess, Flemish Beauty, and id Flemish Beauty and Bartlett ckel, Duchess, and Lincoln we recommend Kieffer, Sheldon, Kieffi al onK, Flemish Beauty, Seckel, and 1, Sheldon, and Flaniish }. we recommend Flemish Beauty, Bartlett, and M ,Vild Goose, Wyant, Wolf, Forest Garden. ■ddard, Hawkeye. Cheney. \\ aver, Robinson, Pottawatto Ship Pride. Green Gage, Shrop, and Tag </seg>
            <seg id="p176">11 F and Forest Gardt For 1 1 Wic Wolf, W. </seg>
            <seg id="p177">Redistricting the State. 177 mmend Burbank, Wiekson, Wyant lrden, Stoddard, Cheney, Hawkeye 11 w mi mend Forest Garden, Burbank, n wommend Wyant, De Soto, Forest Gar- i Forest Garden, Hawkeye, Wolf, r i heney, De Soto, Forest Garden, iddard, Cheney, and Hammer oddard, Cheney, Hammer, Lombard, Garden, Wolf Pottawattomie, De Solo, KASPliKKRIKS mmuiid Cumberland, Kansas, Gregg, i Purple). immend Nemaha, Kansas, Palmer, and la, Kansas, Palmer, and Columbia and balance of district 3. Kansas, Palmer, Gregg, and Turner 1 K, we recommend Kansas, Palmer, and Nemaha. ;! 10, we recommend Cumberland, Kansas, Gregg, we recommend Nemaha, Kansas, and Palmer :easons or favored locations. choice for river counties and for trial in intend Nemaha, Kansas, Palmer, Cumber- jia istrict, Cardinal I) I, and 19, we recommend Cumberland RHUBARB. For Districts 6, 10, and 11, we recommend the following varieties ubarb: Linnaeus and Victoria. For District No. 15, Linnaeus </seg>
            <seg id="p178">1 178 STRAWBERRIB Aroma, August Senator Dunlai </seg>
            <seg id="p179">iicting the State. 17» Prairie Queen. Baltimore Belle. mbler lana-creeper. Jane Roses. Persian Yellow. Harrison's Yellow. Madam Plantier. </seg>
            <seg id="p180">N 1 Moss I ] Hybrid I'«-i-|m« ual 1 A ( 1 I V 1 y on I &lt; iMIIIIH'll II Oscty*' O </seg>
            <seg id="p181">-I Ti Kvi-PU MiSHA I </seg>
            <seg id="p182">X 182 ri ANTED a 1 a 000 acre the 99th V. pr ill anc planting and the plantations is th Bed grove in Nebraska that ha the enterprising farmer gives rity of the plantations have ha AREA P I Taking the average of the figi 3 and 1904, Nebraska has ncai his amount approximately 250 total is in the territory east of • uld \ •rinii: has I </seg>
            <seg id="p183">slightly ally accredited ad all of will show com ii ore, es- ire natural this o out of </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 Nebraska State Hortieultu ;i! So take on a tlif! me when hould be esp&gt; The farn primarily with a view to raising wood as a crop, and r and more profita 1 mid be used. The aim should b« lo make the tree crop a paying one. even when prott object of the plant: of shelter and ornament, and plantation •inniiii their ability of windbr of nurse nd Sal corn per acre. \V south A no: In preventing windf. •on. Nebraska, in hi as published in Bulletin No. 4- neighbor had a few trees of Ben D; land. They were fairly well loaded w per tree. After this storm he had actual count. My son had 550 Ben Dav larger, and may have had mor storm he had. by estimate, one and one-half bu?- orchard is protected by mine, adjoining, wr and has rows of maples on the sides and throug from east to west, and thirty-five rods in extent. Th am informed, no doubt that his apples were saved tectlon, mounted by this growth of trees However, with the orchardlst in Nebraska as with the grow ,r field crops, probably the chief benefit accruing from wind brea &gt;K PROTKCTK wind I com n </seg>
            <seg id="p185">185 southerly winds by checking i the effectiveness of xperien point has been demonstrated by ei- shown by experiments that there is a clt) and the rate of evaporation. The made investigations on this part, and that the rate of evaporation in- the velocity of the wind. Taking calm as unity, it was found that r hour, the n when the wind velocity per houi when the wind velocity was thirty miles herefore that will retard th idtion l&gt;&gt; ■' parent at this h ted- I'ard and ition. made quite an exli idy of which the ability of windbreaks to retard In one of their experiments. night of Aii- when there attire and a low humidtiy. with a high temi thr els north, and 3 3 pet !ian twenty rods south. The 31 and west I King of the Wis- ors humidity of the atmosphev r to the leeward of one affect. in "Irrigation, impact tn indin height of Icallj • the I'nited - ion to n re planning a nine the rela- LANTINC Held season of 1904, the I Ive intelligent advice as to the </seg>
            <seg id="p186">most promising trees to plant for comme the uses to which they are best adapted - W( N« •oils, cotionwood will prod cord onl crowdir I Hor hardy HI..1 used In hardy throughn No many heat uni Kromiii' r littl. Ithoug good soils. M&lt; . </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 The grove include limited to the i. but promlsii ir the wood hardy well knowi *ill hardly be plumed ou a he most available will ri Hut the and K </seg>
            <seg id="p188">r\ fint aniline iimiuus anini. broken by tht </seg>
            <seg id="p189">189 11 i *ter di ml 1 mor which w which tn- onlj will 1j. mltitud 1 wii! of » ii 1 n ;imii in » in jit ions growth when in the dispersal of seeds stances. Squirrels, rats, - of food, and or less commonly upon. ation while lanr li&gt; wth In tl nation of oeani </seg>
            <seg id="p190">190 rs and fruits, are effi other plan 1 excepting tho peds. The number of difft Included within third carry the sotnewh wholl mmiin bras), Its e full line I In th. bluffs" which swift flight enablt direction. tween 1 ■ill 111 conn f nrth </seg>
            <seg id="p191">191 F ced hills adjacent to the arly level valley of the a le Sand Hill country, the iinous ridges of the ex- 1 mour more sandy west- .ir west it becomes more more or less modified is in the marshy borders of some di The rainfall It is very unequally dis- in the spring. high, the days with sun- as those without. The as ma maximum minimum of winter, the for the northern. The ind winter. The average for ten ind for each season in eastern Ne- 6 in in summ viz.: Wings i) centimetre long and five d drops from the cone it is : ried a considerable distance from n the Rocky mountains from Mon- n Nebraska has pushed out upon niformity. Most of the irainless valleys of the nany ponds in regions southeastern part gradu- jmn, and 8 per cent lerally low, and is es- niier, and iped many devices, for to the physical factors just I'inus Scopulonun (Engelm) Lemmon). Each- i bend in the plane of the </seg>
            <seg id="p192">192 Nebraska Hf leu I ii r the foothills ( Pine ridge, and Wild Cat mour air the bluffs of the Xiobrara, and North F spread to scattered stations along th&lt; Hill region (Holt. countie: Linden i Tilia ani&lt;ri&lt; alia ■ ii and enlargement o: I of the ii and er | of tl at right angle- wing. wl. maturity the i .tnd wh. : -ind whirl: the Missouri 1 1 .ilong the 1 publican I In the central ; The Elm I I'tam i imii- margir Diareiti fall to the ground m to or i The I Ibmh MM The In, ii nit ward to tti. \ th ■ Eton i rimu&gt;. 11 1 ■&lt;!— Thoi i law I.M in ■ ibrara ri\ ■ ii'd from but two Red Klin I I Iiiiu&gt; fiil\ ;1 from which ■early or quite half »; station is reported in Fn The Ashes ( Kra\inu&gt; longed upward I </seg>
            <seg id="p193">Migration of Our Forest Tret 193 pedicel it drops with the heavier ing motion by the wing, and when metres before it reach* Kraxiiius aniericana Li is common in the Missouri xtended up along the eastern border of KraxiiiUN lanrrolata Bork.l is common in the Mis- n.luia Bork.i is common in the Mis- i has spread westward and northward tte to the western count spread westward and northward j the western counties Kravinus |M'iin»&gt;lvanica Marsh. I is found with the pre Ivanica Marsh. I is found with the pre - • minated with it. ' . The bean-like pods arc minated with it . 'iinuilfiiMis 1-. I. The bean-like pods at - .ipted to be carried in the wind a few ipted to be carried in the wind a few nimon in th»- Missouri forests and has extended north- issouri forests and has extended north- as Lancaster and Douglas com n(i Douglas counties pp.). The bicarpellary fruit develops two thin ["he bicarpellary fruit develops two thin one on the b;i jne on the back of • I win I split apart, and each falls slowl. ind each falls slowl -U o a greater or 1« *ind carrit id carries it to I li wind thi nty to iruni 'I'm ■!■(•&gt; i is abundant in the I. abundant in tli- Kcer Klahrum T« uthwaid. from which it ha- iriniim I., i occurs abundantly in the .ibundantlv In \. i i -.11 1 liiiriiiuin xtended ui i it hi river and westward fit ■us. ird fifty ti laple i Acer ih-kuikI" I- &gt; mows abund- Acer •eanmdo I. I crows abund rdin which it i ins from New M in western Nel (1 nici ili&gt;' OKtrra vincink-a (Miller) Wild.). The small nut is r that it si Mill into a </seg>
            <seg id="p194">fr&lt; liniana r r ( Minn Niobr K carried border of Nali\ two rows of in. Eir tuft of long s iscence of the m Betnla pan Rlack Hirch ( Itt-iu ntalis ;ird in LRln ' Mila m^i.i d. and h;i </seg>
            <seg id="p195">195 is and floated high winds, many in the Missouri &gt;;ili\ ■■jurtalnlrtfi And . i is found abundantly i, and has followed the river valleys acro&gt; S;ili\ liuitla Muehl.) occurs in U i for- \ Mum. it. undant in the Mi»- led up the river vail ifornia and Oregon. Siilix bebbiaaa nd in the Black Hills he northw nii»-iiiii-i' n~i» w d . moun- w miles I'opulus I ;iK;unifi'i., ended eastward into ntly across the onimoi ■ 'c &gt; I &gt;|1 1 II — 1 I 'IIHll&lt;ii(ll- l'ci|)iiliis .iiimi-iifolia .I,i dso a ickv in from which it has </seg>
            <seg id="p196">•I II II J|M'I U&gt; I II II 1 1" iMIIlillll Ililolll Illll ' In- .« ■&lt; nl. niiili^ has ei Mtinij. rut&gt;ra surrounded by the fl Rydl l*&lt;»pulu&gt; ;n uiuiii.it. i in the Ri I'»|&gt;iiIii- im &lt; iilinliili which le dis ihe plains </seg>
            <seg id="p197">i far awa ndantly in th. ward alom Mulii* k&gt;wen«is ' V .ibbits. lundant in rala&lt;*KUs Is wlii&lt; il:ni;ii- loiiKimi-.ii &lt; Mlaimi- niiilli- i- c iiIiiiikIo - count ( r.it:i.u»- occidental!* Bril (1 down III loyd and r in Thomas county .(lily eaten by birds :tnal uninjured and are curs in the :iey of II; \iii.laii&lt; hi« r (iiiiM&lt;l«-n«.i&gt; i!.. i Med.). The liulf </seg>
            <seg id="p198">198 H Cherries and Plums I I'ruiiu- 1 ovuled ovary I stone prot&lt; ed from when the f \v or quadrupeds, and i v passing through the are g by quadruped Chok. l'i iiini- s, from wt \\ I'ruiii br in the zz la ward Hoih I ilit-iii ti'iiu audio &lt; bent : thick pulp. Thf pods fall f and pan: doub' buffaloes the advent (if white men '! from Injury. Th. nu </seg>
            <seg id="p199">199 alley, and . up the Nemah e contains thin tlesh. When l.l.iiiimi- omiiion In KhaninnN lanc*ol»t« I{Iiuiiiiiii- ijmiliiiiana W which it hi Lepai n by bird I :ind (1 n the alini- uaha coun M d dn Kluio ropallina n by bird tried non MA 1'l.ir.inii- occidrntalla oblong n r roni th ,\ wind, c. rijirg their -ouri, from I The large, brown where they are qui' lesmlus ulalira \\ i </seg>
            <seg id="p200">BM Nebraska Slate Hortieutural Soci tieiitur Jl spicuous. Here they are picked up by large ni swallowed. They are too hard to be easily ma let be rejected after trial. In the meantime they h be rejected after trial. In the meantime they h some distance from the parent tree. Ti, some distance from the parent tree. Thi M souri forests, from which it has moved into N souri forests, from which it has moved in' ardson, Pawnee, and Nemaha count i- Walnuts &lt; .lujilan- drup ardson, Pawnee, and Nemar Walnuts iJuglans sp bony shell (the nut I enclo- t( the nut I enclo.sin the bitter flesh n ing tht' nut. *■ tuirrels and hidd. squirrels and nd carried aw or hidden for ful u or those hidden ai ■ or those hidden tributioi. Bu' &gt; [| tililll- run i tributioi nul i Juulitu- iiii'iT.i from whi&gt; from which as fa Walnut .Iii-I.iil- nigi.i Walnut iJuuliui- i in th&lt; in n moved ui valley to Harlan eo« The Hie The Hici flesh whi&lt; flesh which the hard rd, sni four-lobed, eri squirrels, and of ttr Shellbark Hickor] (Htroria &lt;&gt;\utit Hi. Hiroria vati ■rblch it eastern count i- Big Hickory Nut iHirotia hniiii..-., ■ N. Big Hickory Nm iHiroria laciiiin s. from which it I Missouri I i&gt;m which it Missouri river from Richard ker-Nul (Hiroria alba uri river from Ki&lt; lutidsf it i Hicuria alba (L.I I ests. from which i: HsavnM i Pip-Nut i Hie i lill i Brltl nni which it ■ ests. from which i: - iK«'iil Pip-Nut (Hicoria glabra i Mill I I mil which it ha ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p201">V nd Richardson to ( Black Oak from whic Nebraska to the e Migration of Our Forest Ti • Hi&lt; oria iiuiiiina I Marsh. ) Britt. ) is common in from which it has been carried ,1 of Nebraska from Richardson Querous spp. i. The fruits (known as 'acorns") are thin- containing a single, large, edible seed. and other rodents, as well as by swine. ieer and buffaloes. All of these no doubt ee to their dissemination, but the squirrels nts in this work, gathering and hiding .some distance from the parent tree. (JiK-rru* alba 1. &gt; is common in the Missouri forests 1 inlo .southeastern Nebraska as far north yuercus minor I Marsh* Sarg. ) is found in the Mis - mi which it is reported to have moved northward into Sargent which it has migrated along the river ■ aching Harlan county on the ntre and Cherry county on the north. It yiii-r.n- iicuniiuula i Michx I Sarg.), found in the Plane river in eastern Nebraska Willd ) of the Missouri for- (JuiTrus prinoi&lt;l«-! i ii Nebraska in Richardson county. yinT«u» rubra L). is common in the Missouri forests, i carried northward along the Missouri river to i westward fifty or sixty miles. iQuercu* coocinea Muench.) occurs in the Missouri entered the southeastern counties of Nebraska from ass (Quercus velntina Lam.) is found in the Missouri for - h it has moved northward along the eastern border of i Platte river. yucrcu* niMcnx hi |&gt;a Midis.i is abundant in tho Mis- uth Dakota, to which it was proba- ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p202">202 &lt; t) i- a \ Black Jack Oak (Quercus uiarilundira La, has moved into the southeastern cou to Pawnee and Neman and case of Mtao tlorad hundred ks, hicko Cuntain cles of v . i as i </seg>
            <seg id="p203">203 w w i win or fruits -fourth of the way hirds, and five to or beyond wo have barely en- he way across ntered ate; one. three- way a ler and beyond. Of the four w niri riv with H of 1 definii ind tal of th« with winged seeds with hairy seeds. with edible nuts, 16 per in thus express the in Nebraska is still go- cially in ttie southeastern ier which such movement occurs ;ation of prairie fires, (2) protec- &gt;rest border in a moist ralley. a onditions the forest border becomes margined with tall- growing weeds which kill the tenacious prairie grasses, at the same time affording a lodgment for seeds of shrubs and trees. These grow, and gradually the shrubs and trees retain possession of the belt of remarked, ward only a few </seg>
            <seg id="p204">t: </seg>
            <seg id="p205">] </seg>
            <seg id="p206">206 Nebraska t v ad done eh out th This school park was started incident of the planting of m were planted in tr were allow w to bearing ag course In the picking of the fruit from ginn:: and flut-i. This do tr ra In ganizfd an Interesting and and management c We tii&gt; rress by son: patn - program is ri by the young people. A Professor Miller of the f ttold us of the example of ;ribed. With this addre t organization next month to tal et tree planting. These organizations are being the name of Civic Improvement soc bProf. Miller told us of one of nposed entirely of women, but 1 y of park and tree planting thro strange </seg>
            <seg id="p207">1 I get I be willing to i tpi Id be glad to he right 1 who » r..°i o ng a their own ven ten i &amp; t into winter </seg>
            <seg id="p208">Earters, for I am sitting very comfortably in &gt;m without a fire, and have been at work a ese are exceptional days, however, for the Frosty nights are the rule for this season, and w it is the alternate freezing and thawing of the gi rihat works the injury to the plan If our » is such I rime forward until th n«-«»d for protecting With it time with . rt is 11 What snail w largel is usually th 1 were it w than « let it lie on it commercial grow I hav&gt; manuring nu. danger of \. have often had the plan for feeding. For my use this at 50 cents a load and have ry for spreading at the first As a general rule I do not is frozen enough to bear up a loaded w good freezing night I am ready to go to w straw now ready at hand. Barelv eno all that is needed beiiiM though it d&lt; r manure &gt;f manur. |y v\ </seg>
            <seg id="p209">209 . ATE HO R TIC L L. i Hor al Society, now building, al general hoi with work e different frui 1 of the ■ o all who are int 3SEL1 Lincoln, N't B I xhibition pure that bush and to king the to him, never tli , and the judge of the exhibit these bruises when com- ldge himself will I may i one has made mbership Is $1 ion, address the IIPPING FRUIT FOR BXHIB RPOSi md careful obst lit, t mt not so for we ar </seg>
            <seg id="p210">all ii in showing what N res, — not hard aru mended for to rii fruit is medium hard, new also, and when filling the 1 around tht r any which should alw; layf-r ior o </seg>
            <seg id="p211">211 in sh tore being exhibited, they i oiled paper, and i | fine excelsior between the of shipper, and nuni memorandum in the top of prepaid, to the E &amp; COLD STORAGE CO., Lincoln, N'eb Fi Be of the exhibitor should be on the Care of Hall, State Fair Grounds Lincoln, N« lowed, I can truthfully say thai pointed. We earnestly request you I his society. Fair." If fruit l M. RUSSELL, </seg>
            <seg id="p212">H i 212 a ii 8. Articles on exhibition removed during meeting except P tie is intended to prevent vat tides on exhibition. 9. All fruits obtaining premiums Society, to be sent elsewhere for exhibition Board of Directors may determine. 10. All fruits or other con premium must be arranged together in groups. T Cth t) Ing entitled to recognitii </seg>
            <seg id="p213">N 213 here must be five perfect specl- d no less. No duplicates of any hibitor competing for a premium. nd one premium, second, or first. n on exhibition until 4:30 p. m. of i iums are forfeited. I WITH MNTS. Genera] Kill, v d by the letter ana exhibitors have made their ei 'ion, and taste dig- being distinctly fruits, there should never be more than one 3ne group. Lists of names of varieti. ath group and must be attached to the entry number and designation — with or with- ule an not compete for different prizes. b ?st ten, five, or other numbers, and n varieties, but not the same plates t be duplicates, and in sweepstakes t ■s the number of each kind, usually )n exhibition, the exact number must be fruit by individuals, counties, or of of fruits are specified in the ecie i, o the collection may be passed by the ally in the display, or greatest and i the prima facie test of superiority. relative value, their perfect con- </seg>
            <seg id="p214">214 tural &gt; and value; third, cond 3th dliion and tasteful appearance will be considered i -i, number; second, quality or fourth, taste in displa scale of ten: No. 1 ma;. irgest coil- Quality; some inferior Condition i condition Form; perfect Sice; uneven Color; too pale Texture and flavor; insipid Total This scaling might be used in deciding b •Ingle plates of designated varieties competing Total . . ' Quality; supen Condition of fi anking. . Tiistc in th© urrniii. Total . . • ' ■ Total . . </seg>
            <seg id="p215">215 Uet premium with assortment of the schedi; &gt;|K&lt; i;il Klllts uidan] ol 11 in all rases. lit, which must : 1 1 shoult: in si/.&lt; kind art 1 and I "ints. . of the superintendent to appoint two as if a committee, shall n tion for exhibition at any time during the .riety of fruit in any individual or county display iid plums, etc., the Important elements are and condition Five points. i.ler and compare the form and size of the thei color, ripeness, flavor and con- the perfection and size of the nd condition. Three points. 11 have to look at the size, color, flavor and s. Four points. r as our guide the size and form, color. flavor, and </seg>
            <seg id="p216">aska e H ■A In Judging strawberries we flavor, firmness and condition, stem and calyx. hall cot IRaspber: a show shall have to judge of tb nts. w Blackcaps mu? Blackberries n i rf orni , In al. ligup Is condeniutoi\ of the possible award. L Seedlings er the rules of the Cl'earmc dwin, W . . \eet, F n Davis, \V . noni, B Back Twig, \V Bottle Greening. W one h State Fair d Stor F . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p217">217 : » : I i , ♦ 4 I 5 5 I F . . g 3 I 3 10 5 I 5 5 4 ( \V 3 W . 2 Romanite, W ... 5 Lowell, F Maiden Blush, F | Mann. W . . . . . . 4 Milam. W 5 Mlnkler, \ 9 Missouri Pippir. 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p218">McMahon Whi New Town Pippin, \V Northern B N. W. Greening, \V Ortl. Otoe, W Patten's Greening, W Peck Tit, K Penn. Perr&gt; Pewaukt - Plum- Port • Pound S«' l Red A Red Jur Romi- i Roniii: Roxbury I &gt;. Salon r - Sheriff. W Bops of Win Spitzenbii- Smith Stark, W Summer Hagloe Striped GillifUn* Summer Q Trent on Early, Tetofskv. 8 Talman S» ■ Utter. K Virginia Beauty. W ► Winesap. W </seg>
            <seg id="p219">i i w flower. W sparer ( I. ASS I. — Grt.n Fruits Lot 1. t and largest collection display of fruits by one indi - in quantities as provided by rules of the Society, not m 30 varieties *2S i best display 2&lt; * i display best display 10 For fifth best display K Lot 2. d largest collection and display of fruits by a county quantities as provided by the rules of the Society, to han 50 varieties and best display 25 ■d best display 2 * For the fourth best display J 5 For the fifth best display 1() Lot 3. (To be distinct from above lots.) 1st 2d 3d 4th Pre Pre Pre Pre ates summer and fall apples, any variety B Pi ieties. Display and condition to rule. .. ,»10 »7 $5 $3 va </seg>
            <seg id="p220">220 Nebraska State Hortlcultuial Society ■ plates summer and fall apples, any variety varieties, to be rated and judged by score card 1st 2d 3d 4 Pre Pre Pre P Best collect ion Nebraska grown summer apples varieties % i $3 %2 Collection autumn apples, 10 varieties Collection Nebraska grown autumn apples yai ... ■ lion Nebraska .mown winter apple varieti Collection rietif Collection ' Qui 6 specimens Earl) I 6 specimens Fallawatc 6 specimens Fall \V irinie 6 speciniins Hubbard's Non« 5 specinn-ns Iowa Blush S specimens Jonathan itumn 6 sp. ■ i: 6 8|« iilton </seg>
            <seg id="p221">221 air us Law 2 1 *■ 1 linens Little Romanite 2 1 Mann 2 1 .liden's Blush _' 1 Hlack Twig ish Red 2 1 \li Mahon White Minkler 2 1 Missouri Pippin. . . ■&gt;rthern Spy ] W. Greening | i Oldenburg | Ortl€ 1 Otoe Red Streak | i 2 \ Plum 2 1 1 1 1 1 Ho 1 1 iff 1 1 Gilliflow ■ I II 1 U 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 w VVii 1 Wolf Rivi ...11 W 1 IIS Yellow BellflOWl I 1 Vellow Transp. ... 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p222">222 Nebraska State Horticultural So( l«ot 4 — Pears. I I'. I ' 1 i ' Plate I Plate 5 specimens Triumph . Plate Pr« Prd ire f re "llection Nebraska grown \» $6 $3 * i as Flemish B&gt; I Plate us Bartlett Plate I Plate ; Plate .'. s[m Plate I </seg>
            <seg id="p223">3 I...I (i I'luni ich ula 1 3d Pre Pi J $3 $2 l.oi 7 — Aprirol i $:; 12 t f $25 ; LASS -J — (.i;i| Lot I i v $15 *10 $ 5 i l 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p224">224 A \\ \\ i I ISS ii in v 6 buii' ; wn in All exhibi L Monday, and arranged in ■ theni iiay. tlowt </seg>
            <seg id="p225">A 1 Krid xhibr iihhold pi liibiior will be e in Flu ment in Horticui try will immediately ipy and as near as possi- i application for space. Said &gt;&gt;us to first en' 1 unU complied i intender. visions as there art' exhibitors, and hall be al- Into and into the other the num- name from box of names and b number shall be the di ii shall occupy, and the&gt; il all d high in air before drawing. nent i be applied for and </seg>
            <seg id="p226">226 :n8tructed to send copy of al in tbe state thi prior to first day of Fa gnuii « </seg>
            <seg id="p227"/>
            <seg id="p228">Nebraska 14 ii al a Bouquet Best grown 5 bjx Grown collection of palms i I'UKMH M LIST I &lt;»l{ W1NTKK MKKTIM ( i. \«,«, | — (.i.-.n } i nii- l.ix 1 more v pi. I 6 si' - 5 »peciin.'us M Ii T»i - 6 specimens Minkler. S specimens Mo Pippin 5 specimens Nortkl S specimens N W. Oreemiag 5 sp' :oni&lt;- lle.i 6 si ioman K 6 specimens Salome. . Best &lt;&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p229">2 1 : ; i Class 2 — Cut Flowers. 1st 2d 3d Pre Pre Pre $8 $5 $3 8 5 3 •&gt; 4 3 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p230">h r :! "IK f n k wher N H TWO DISt (li This ing off" di - name. Both of the: both are causing me THE "DAM! The disease comn to young pines from tl four weeks old, there one or two months of Pine has proven to be I seedlings in Jack Pine Pine, only about 10 pf The disease mar plants. After examination it is fout fungus which stroying the fundamental tissue, and from the upper portion of the plant. rapid, an entire bed often bting d at Halsey 75 per cent of the seedlir destroyed in a single day. al fungi are know ion one is I'ylhiuni ililuiryaiiiiin living upon decaying organic matter i comes In contact with the tender comes a facultative parasite. The fui asexually. Most of the conidia gerrr formed, but sexual spores, and, even ng stage, and may lie in the soil nating. Most soils contain either the therefore seedlings are liable to attar ble for the growth of the fungus. </seg>
            <seg id="p231">231 Pin ) .i i i v ig the d ■ * i iry for the growth of the indance of water. Warm, sultry days, after a rain, are especially favorable, we have the greatest loss of seedlings Anything which tends to dry the surface soil ase; therefore frequent stirring of the tance of air and sunshine has a good itained by covering the surface of the nd or gravel. This prevents the soil from m at the place where it is most liable Bordeaux mixture has been tried at Halsey •d, there is no remedy; therefore the ase is by preventative means. In the ; bed should afford good drainage. mi: li. containing a great deal at amount of water should n m proved, however, b&gt; mixing to the and. After th dlings come up, the he depth of at one inch, unless Hit ultivation will he beds are raked f the summer. This ied, thev shouli velv l; .i ion ne- and two-year-old pines at is first ly part of in own toward the of th. the upper u deal of damage ■■Hings will H which l, have sent out strong lateral w ir whether the new shoots ised. in which such as is found at Halsey, since it A sami I niiihh is to be ivr orked when wi EAF" DISEASE </seg>
            <seg id="p232">232 No one lia Hiffli Dr. Heal^; ar, ar a to be present. He thin I. but has made no in&lt; Cladoeporium I'estalozzi nt. T f fur section of tt since no of the ah' identified beyond any d P. in the plate cul the disease, bu pine seedlii Peatalozzia, the onl Ing the troubl and make inoculations A number of normal on i-ured from t! at H under a shade frame. Several Bull P Ptatalozzia by placing th §to the seedlings with an atomizer tral seedlings were injured in orde other schillings were left in their n£ seedlings were covered with bell ditions for the germination of the spore made on June 2, or only five days ago. suffii to secure any results. Pure cultures of Cladosporiums have therefore no inoculations have yet been n i&lt;l&lt;»|xiriu sprin- &lt; 'hi&lt;li&gt;s|&gt;&lt;.riiiin Hum lyit close r.-somhl; Cladoaporiam termined to be dadoaporhui (olon ' .|..v|M.riurn fungi. In thi From nli&gt;-|H&gt;riuii </seg>
            <seg id="p233">233 1 ant in the vicinity. -&lt; ii-. tlcfornians i.iiniti.-s d are ntf om the only )nd uial mycelium by spraying. But ex- ment of Agriculture in California d by the Department In phate and five pounds of avily covered with Pruning off affected leaves are ject to the attacks of diseases which : 'Ulic •nt of m to have pretty ■uent from aying. The recom- March with strong Bor- </seg>
            <seg id="p234">234 Nebraska Sta Hor often defies inf. has to cease. 1 nl •■&lt; Hum in the the tissues, and |&gt;aired transport the fungus invade id the point of infection. The mos destruction of plum blossoms and the tree; the difficulty in k&lt; after picking is also largely du ously both&lt; :', OR BI I Ti&lt;li&gt;s|ii&gt;riiim i arpujtliiluiii </seg>
            <seg id="p235">celium OQ during the 1 bios lant, in- ar ommendation. previ ow down id bur and th is :com- ~&lt; ii — primi jddery plums without mediately after blos - e twigs, and spreads plum-pocket at ma- in n iestroj before the summer latlng fallen fruit ng is dif </seg>
            <seg id="p236">SHOT-HOLE FUNGUS (Cercospora cirriiinscissa) of This disease produces spots on the he Mir to a less extent of peach; it attacks especially tt attacks shot-hole even If tt </seg>
            <seg id="p237">237 the Farmer reminds he land ir with his new form of ;milar in its purpose that ory was a stranger fforts to gull the people was al grafter. His scheme was a nth which my home a \ lifetime in discovering a fruit-bearir ■ d in the roots of the large ims th&lt; promi- aoarding mean- his work until his without paying his rchant victims with a bill some of our people. n walnut trees the next &gt;d of thirty-five years, I ar anything but its natural friut. and the willow, have failed Neither do men gather grapes off GRAFTING ed by the frlut grower or nurseryman k or change old ones by the grafting •ees or shrubs unite their wood cells a new and perfect tree? W trees or different families been made make a lasting union. Many attempts we ffi </seg>
            <seg id="p238">Horticultural £ people we bear so married on find a remedy for IThe s of propagai Kthe me made marrif similar </seg>
            <seg id="p239">239 •ar or two. for this is that w i has not beconv. weather. It is found growing ■Ir S. W. Christy of •e too young ind growing d as without sue ■ d An to lap need and will id the mulching tender dug up and with I have wintered good ot seem atment. possible, nter was a Rambler, which instances. </seg>
            <seg id="p240">r </seg>
            <seg id="p241">241 r r "."ill &gt;r h hould pro in acre in The fl imated at of the Five or Mt Of -t per This will from the in </seg>
            <seg id="p242">142 N H ;isk come per acre, we have very close to $100 as th&lt; par acre for the cherry orchard during the ent years. If It can be made to live and bear ten ye known them to do. so much for the a\ figures will be fouii small orchard tracts near our growing towns growing of this 1 popular fi the writer plai r large we; proprietor at U connection with it demand for the frui for lmmeii looses on accou: hall storm twenty-acre orchard </seg>
            <seg id="p243">243 1'ulviiiaria iiinuiiK-rabilis Kathvon.) he following nil plaints ming isolated Nebraska our most ual abundance n ut the state, it is thought sion of its character and «1 «t native to the United States, familiar by reason of its habit e it was supposed to be entirely which it leaves the trees after *■! Dr. S. S. Rathvon, of placed costantly before the aper articles on account of a here conditions are e«- The most elaborate treatise* ion, having been found la in the Union. How - fortieth parallel on which attack it in that mt the state, but, in accordance Dme injurious only occasionally The region of the greatest Academy of Natural Science*, J. Duncan Putnam,* and more S. Dept. Agr. Div. Ent. pp. 7-11. \gr., Bureau of Ent. p. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p244">1 </seg>
            <seg id="p245">245 rokt'n with the which near 1 3 lift IK i ii &lt; 1 &lt; ■ be the mill, &lt;&gt; W1 white \w ni the s;iiul to two hutch during ing </seg>
            <seg id="p246">a i 4 bef i 1, d c P T es cr. les mig i H 1 t .1 ir bod - to form. This which, as stated before, r ftt K. By this time the scale has a the twig to which it is attaclx beneath the body. By the above general di It will be seen that thre is but on summarize briefly, occurs as follows In the early summer, the winged m the females and then die. The fema! </seg>
            <seg id="p247">M 247 er in this and produce Lheir EMIES AND REMEDIES i by a great mi h paracitic and predaceous, which commonly ; sufficiently to become harmful. Among the me harmful. Among the lion or the pest are the on of the pest are the The importance of this group in forestalling best shown by quoting what Dr. I oup in forestalling bown by quoting what Dr. L. O :&gt;logist, has to say in Coccopti ionging to th. 11 id tu Ooccopli h has been reared from ■ Bomber of cliff. ■ iliff g numbers. It was due to this par ible to &lt; It was due to this pai on in 1898; of the many man tied upon tht than one per cen i full gro August and September they wi on the tr in one per cent n August and September 'hlch laid Its eggs in their 1 in their bod k, the adult parasites issaii adult parasi Him leir bodies. The development ol rapid, octuping certmi»l] n The developmen id, oceuping certainly n id tli- iherefore in numbers in geometrical was therefore a numbers in geometrical progression, der close observation a branch of a I. in the Smithsonian grounds, which in J^ne was te egg-sacs of the Pulvinaria, whil? in July ics of the Pulvinaria, while i;i July spotted with newly settled young; in August i with newly settled young; in August ning trying to find a living scale insect, but ng to find a living scale insect, but hich were found had been killed by this im- h were found had been killed by this im little Oocoophagus even gained access to the Coccophagus even gained access to th i maple trees stocked with the scale insects were Ie trees stocked with the scale insects were d the scale was exterminated, although the xterminated, although the i been swarming with these scales, and although daily arming with these scales, and although ■' nff and crushed those which through a change which through a change :&gt;p. 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p248">ulliii-i. I \ Hi pcraspfa pi&lt;&gt;l&gt;;t : </seg>
            <seg id="p249">249 </seg>
            <seg id="p250">derived « tmining s f tht . i i i iind&lt; in f </seg>
            <seg id="p251">locate for the winter on the younger twigs, spraying to prune the trees back rather </seg>
            <seg id="p252">THE .••trarlirlu* iirnii|&gt;liur Hi iliononiii- quadrifcihliutt . I </seg>
            <seg id="p253">.TI.K' nk which I I % |&gt;|il«- ' nil ulii. I'liiin Ciirciilio. Prama aniin. **-' — Inrwrfi) ..n.i mtattPM), • bile the .ii&gt;i&gt;le curculk. With 0 : &gt;ii|i|ily. and in i ild for the cultivated vari. ■ find thi *hi&lt;l. wj |i O11 id cl ■ilio. how 1,,,-ii to (| la , | 1 '"' though until ihi: </seg>
            <seg id="p254">II 254 ■i bears a long, high, sharply edged, black hump 'I'M long, slender, almost forwardly d aa the body but in the male only one-half as long, broad ong elytra! base* towards the tips an. iytron b« eoaspiciious tubercles. These difl paring the accompanying cuts of the two - fully as much in life histor\ and methods It it best to consider I. IKK HI- M The insect passes the wl fallen leaves, loose bark after spring has dev begins to appear u| this appearan and the female yery young growing the end of her i&gt; about from th« ' not all ol die oR rapidly in J The ej,g of the iduii of an inch lout firing for their waj through irregular and ton case of cher 1b about one-third head, and with a doublt la the fruit altogtMl oecuring about the third » begins in latter Jui ronuii the fallen fruit the larva in usually to a depth of an inch enrrulio. b cavil </seg>
            <seg id="p255">255 in. In about four lately fly to the fruit. jpon the trees and are also made along with the ouncled by a ring pon the ! ■ he following his cu HE J r I . i o &gt;nks he spring at about the Matin . ind ovipo milar to that ■■ Hiiring about an hour s in fifteen or ng continues through June and it fifty to one hundred eggs one-twenty-flftn of </seg>
            <seg id="p256">t 256 I nod ii( 1 in « n d. ihe I ly the of the at underground </seg>
            <seg id="p257">ow i&gt; m thr whii il larvi than HI' ICO Wll' short tini. quit i 1 \ i </seg>
            <seg id="p258">Nebraska late Horticultura 258 .lairiu- When d ii il drop » dro urbed but nowev I'l ■ way in th. witht hardly va! of such applications in f Ip UK A moi' I in Mr. A. L. Q of th&lt; mcnt of Agri ferred with arsenatt- of lead consult B cultural Experiment Station </seg>
            <seg id="p259">259 n Sources of Infestation. If a well y infested one, or to extensive patches i haw, the former is liable to injury by nfested trees. The only way of avoiding 1 methods to the neglected orchard or mative trees, and It is conceivable that In ! alternatives would prove all but impossible. ;le instance of such difllculty has come under writer, and the indications are that this stat* ra &gt;ntcl v r^coni n i ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p260">» nd f I </seg>
            <seg id="p261">11 n mill)' .m.i one whoh hboi orthern Ml«hl valuable timber *hil (1.(1 llclW o niail&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p262">262 and fifty thou graph po mention the teteph 1 and mention the ti i and th the construction of new lines, makii the const run ion uf new lines, making a total at for poles and ties two hundred and I for poles and ties two hundred and thir match industr &lt;rl&gt; four li match iml'is't mond Match company I tly pu mond impany I tly purchas Oregon timber, the wh man Oregon timber, the whole to be manufactured into I thousand five him.! thousand five hund: ieeded in •hoe i»-n&gt; SI Acres mot mill &lt;on . acres mor&lt; n thousand tnto tootli, inufacturf Into toothpick fa. 11 pins • pins • n.'wsp»p. v from one hundred to one hundred and from one hundred i i nd flf to fifteen thou n ahing! rni imp]. - dollars worth annually farriages The lull cwrtei of four milll of four millioi * is greater thai all o is great. -i th of the minoi of the nm over 17 !'• not to mention not to m. terlals and Thus it will terlals and r Thus require ,i arts and Indus require ai ind iiuli; «leari' «learii prod n prod ii' &lt;lani:ic&lt; i! a But ways than in th over and trol Us distribution Inform- whether ihe | to do milh the aiuoiint on th &gt;ii. ih m. if at all, onl local sumniei Bui when I ■ diffe: in. There can b&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p263">I 1 low II.- nd policy, and n ion ii ky Mo bout six hundred wth if uii.l and h in. H ■ in of irru zona. for example, formerl inns rising in the [imbei d tran i all d development .iliorily tha ■r enough millio rninrnt s. r ;md flunn which n' of fc he problem of gi </seg>
            <seg id="p264">264 M is tl for ihr and now </seg>
            <seg id="p265">■ a tr but a I on thi nforced </seg>
            <seg id="p266">266 I \\i Klly or in i&gt;art covt merclal value of : t: no provision was taking care of the fi At length, however, due it Hoke Smith, a law ■ Interior pow-.-i 10 • into execution so far ;i Up to ii time mo been set aside as national fore the west and u d mail waters of streams. The United holdings in the west wh&lt; ■mt should acqulr </seg>
            <seg id="p267">267 rest lands are In large &gt;anles, and these lands </seg>
            <seg id="p268">affo: of lunibt I subm try al the proti . </seg>
            <seg id="p269">1 * of IS i hards rairit </seg>
            <seg id="p270">Horticul al Nebraska a locie My first effort consisted in pla Yellow Belleflow » I&gt; I : iU BUI of fc form size, and of all liai the apple in the N •4c* Dur deepening » -iberia future successfu Acting upon from know varieties and parentage, and thus elimi bo that, if anything o known on one side, and oft other. were taken from this work some surprising result seedling apples has me, small size has been the Uon of 50 varit- nearly or quite duplicate </seg>
            <seg id="p271">Y 271 K Poui ({.■d Siberian, and an undo ; locking with iind in ind mildly i this which 1 I" hen &gt;' Kiv m are of nt h eding a faniil in This fact is most Department of Agri' Pathology, entitled "Imi Herbert J Webber. Tl I with distinct colors of the male h it w I and no' lugo de V ' on "■* utional Conference on I" he theory of the color A. Beach's experiments at the n. in crossing a white grap&lt; :i \ large number of seedlings D jf these crossed grapes was ilinp on Color is one of </seg>
            <seg id="p272">i I V' II ■ f </seg>
            <seg id="p273">eeding Hardy Fruits. 273 iat suggests a grafted }f Black Annett ranches similar to the ?d, angular grower. typical three- ossed with in this cross Is i.i i « md the form, have » very seedling ee; the mother introduced by Prof. J. L. as upright in habit as a m of the mother parent, all are view, but several of them closely resemble ance sented will not seriously conflict ding, they may serve to awaken light onto this most intricate problem I Darwin to exclaim, "that the whole But in its unfolding as witnessed in the jphetic vision to see in it, and through ftine forces for the human race. nched, upright 1 with the Anjou. Not one </seg>
            <seg id="p274">a My 1c are r. time. In w wlndows awed m;m.u, as a ru As a w applicability of ise of dv :\ for pear, and The South Dj he first fruit-br periments have be&lt; could have been done ■ always Intends to be at the provide additional facilitie I liberality of the Regents of Ed .rs and other facilities, we are y Interesting and hybrid fruits, A-ht o various fr nough to Iulation. W 'ho I ould t </seg>
            <seg id="p275">275 Methods In Breeding Hardy Fruita. re hybrids of the South Dakota sand iiso being made nd raspberries. By far making of graft-hybrids i we await the fruiting of the lin work done i nd Si! \ ith choice d for nard . he results of ere' ardy frui 1 ening the fruiting awberries originated one have been raised up to much time In selecting varieties for propa- ation by our being able to roj field in illion fruit seedlings I find many anting themselves, but Just ion few varieties of the various ginate a of a permanent place on the present edling variations which present them- at Dr. Hugo De Vries in his theory of. head. It is certainly a very helpful :1c ific rank can originate as sports. it is, by leaps or steps, instead of svard slope. Memebers of the legfs- nds will certainly find more com at of Darwin. My experience i seedlings of native and cultivated 3ls me to believe that the evolution s effort intelligently directed Ik machinery in his workshop than anging panorama. Tn brief, plant- s, using material as furnished he work with modern scientific plums, a Chinese apricot (forded, thr imanent h and apricot and me have been raised up 10 nd fruited in pots under gla- </seg>
            <seg id="p276">Nebraska State Horticultural So methods, is very much shorter than that usually cons The modern plant-breeder rides in his automobile on evolution. And perhaps Mendel's law and De Vries 1 are two of the wheels. </seg>
            <seg id="p277">ii i ANT BREEDING Fiance of Laboratory Work. part of ant br idc ods and me more expert in into the underlying prim pplemented by regular ku the truth of tli&gt;- :al method instance would attempt to | n by lectures alone no matter how trated by charts and photograph work. It is largely on a iging is provided for in our agricultural hase of instruction, ho of plant breeding, too man work hi the lecture room and library ants themselves is just as import ng principles as to the one studying nstance, the student who has a chance to w plants and grow the hybrids for two or three gener- han he could possibly be w in reading about hybrids. His he has some experience m ul eported by others. to is line with the plants themselves is decidedly ng enthusiasm on the part of th lent will watch with more made. If the beginner is bud on his new hybrid in- </seg>
            <seg id="p278">of any w » i i&lt;al Work In H.vIukIi/ ollina course is given, and upon Some of the plants selected should perfect ones. Some plants should nated until the pistils mature and pollination. The plants chosen for the first that are easy to operate upon, while lat I Included. On the whole, c this work. If the studen s enough. When he comes crop he will adopt his own method anyway ..1 Work &gt;iiiii«I i«&gt; I.MlH.iiMni) IV. The p particular plant- as&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p279">LaJxm-.tory Study of Hybrids. 3 1 ars. E n be </seg>
            <seg id="p280">I 2S0 lorticultura ■ - ■ . • of f ll a, r sg &gt; II. im lo -.luc!) Hjrfc How i., s(ud\ II be suffic K- 8'. parents in son arn whether : ■ more tii: n a regular course of plant EenU in some n whether ce en more tim&lt; in a regula Ian as outlined above, but a more c ie student .should be imp - studying un He time as, for li wartiness airiness in popples and the like, enerations of the hybrid as well ot only observe the variation ii the various individual plants, bi heritance the number of Individ as outlined abov The student should V of studying unit chai a time as, for ii wartiness i hairiness in poppies an 1 the like, and generations of the hybrid as well as in tt not only observe the variation in In the various individua inheritance the nun number in which it Is wanting. In cas« should make accurate measureme </seg>
            <seg id="p281">281 In no other ariation that the particular ations under observation. another. He illy in color. The student hand just what lie might assume at the esent in a bean pod would tion will be corrected when he n a toush stringy - icdded one. He will at once wall fillers without Laboratory Work in Selection. a mini 1'rac- d I it ion ill diffl- lull no </seg>
            <seg id="p282">braska State Horticultural Soci by examining the best individuals produced in order to get an adequate ides on he must see numerous individuals -t made and all the indl ion or at least enough of them to Ir Individ pea as possible shoi : more n- ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p283">r the Northw. NORTHWEST C Brookings, S. D are needed is evident iard ;rowD under winter protection. nd covered with earth. This • fill to the busy prairie in \; der anil d ■ nera- d i n t wit h with the and ire not hardy ov« with- n to do </seg>
            <seg id="p284">.re Horticultur c The j Sorts it t?riment station b&lt;f w goo.: rom n Manitoba and and many tho tbred and h all ot w IIUIllI i wht ' r ■ o </seg>
            <seg id="p285">285 REPOF ka State Horticultural Society Friends of the Xobra nual meeting for the exchange ast year, and to arrange for the alized, much good work for the during the past year, through committee work :ommittee on redistrlcting the state where we only had nine before. For this aside, of which $44.35 was used. The committee xpress rates was allowed $300 for expenses, or as needed, and of this amount $76.52 was used. This important work nt and G. A. Marshall were delegated as representa- make a fruit show last September, before the Kansas City. They were allowed nd used $37.50 of this amount. At this shew society was awarded a bronze medal, but I have w Dffl( w Lincoln and Godfrey of Lincoln. naster at Fort Calhoun of the- California some time ago, and some are Tlw past year Professor J. L. Budd of Ames. \. Hale of Unt- </seg>
            <seg id="p286">Horticul 286 Nebni ,i Jury Iies W A. Ganaon nny P. I.i The following wa WARRANTS \ - 4 8 K J. I rid Hi: 13 D l.t 16 ■ Pollard &amp; H. .1 M. A A. M 4 Dr. T ib North &amp; ( L. M. Russell Crete Xur </seg>
            <seg id="p287">287 Experiment Station. 5.00 125.00 3.3 12.76 5.00 10.34 4.50 .... 12. 00 1 12.00 immer • • • 8.00 meeting . 1200 mer meeting 9-00 25.00 orting summer meeting . . . . nished York and Chambers ?,: salt ing winter meeting Fair 32.00 n 12. Of ionary premiums 12 2.00 3.00 5 37.00 V 22 "0 H </seg>
            <seg id="p288">Nebraska State Horticultural Soclet 288 6 9 Dora A. Hesseltlne, premiums 70 C. B. Hain, premiums 71 Lewis Anderson premiums 72 Ed Hayes, premiums 71 E. Hornung, premiums 74 Will Heitman, premiums 76 ("has. Jelinek, premiums RC. S. King, premiums C. Laub, premiums . . CWm. Lindsey, premiums John Logeman, premiums «C Richard «1 Thomas Lynct *: A. Martin, *3 John Martin, premiums M W. H. V mium S5 H. 1 S&gt;6 J. G. Neff, prem «7 C. P. Neal, | ** H. &lt;■ J-9 M. Rol SO Mr.- »1 G. 9 2 E. K S3 W. 94 J. L. Spees&gt; t 95 .hous, &amp; 1 96 «7 W. K8 J.I 9 - William 102 H S - 106 108 W 1 109 G. A. Ma ~ fruit. 110 J. H. Hadkii: </seg>
            <seg id="p289">Report 289 retar i. Barnard, labor and judging fruit at State Fair. . . . 18.00 l iadkinson, decorations for horticultural hall .... 20.00 rVilliams, premiums 2.00 loy Uhl, labor at State Fair 3.00 haw, labor at State Fair 9.00 Russell, Ass't. Sec. at State Fair 15.00 iV. Christy, fruit for State Fair 7.68 Lincoln Ice &amp; Cold Storage Co., storage on fruit 16.90 lapin Bros., cut flowers and vases for decorations .... 10.00 &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies for State Fair 20.07 North &amp; Co., supplies for State Air 19.25 iVestern Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass for flower case 2.85 i Colles, labor at State Fair 7.00 A Russell, labor at State Fair 13.50 lumann &amp; Co., floral decorations 26.33 &amp; Guenzel, supplies for State Fair 2.25 A. Wilson, repairing lagoon at Fair grounds 27.80 arborough, labor at State Fair 6.25 nvkins, labor at State Fair . 5.50 A. VanSickle &amp; Son, painting signs 7.50 during summer and fall at Fair 56.00 xpense making fruit show at American iety 21.20 making fruit show at American 16.25 &amp; Co., printing bulletins and entry cards. .232.90 &amp; Cold Storage Co., storage on fruit 1.75 &amp; Bag Co., supplies for State Fair. . . . 6.41 lumber for horticultural hall .... 18.75 mmittee work on frt. and ex. rates. . 23.25 svork on frt. and ex. rates . . . and ex. rates. . . . 30.52 3 . . 10.00 siiiuni' $1. 095. 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p290">290 Nebraska State Horticultural Socl TREASURER'S WARRANTS PAID Series 1904. ISO H. S. Harrison f Bartea 1905. Dole Floral Con L. Henderson . O. 8. Chris' E. M. Pollard . Peter Youngers C. L. Saunders C. H. Green 10. A. Marshall Frey * Frey . IC. H. Green J. B. Hunter David Hunter D. Longster . Marshall Bros P. A. Murphy 16 Isaac Pollard &amp; Sons 17 H. J. Rosenbaum 18 A. M. Schmale I Ed Schriver W. G. Swan I A. M. Freeman G. M. Whltford 2 3 Don Russell 24 Isaac Pollard &amp; Sons 25 Dr. A. T. Peters 2 6 Jacob North &amp; Co. 27 L. M. Russell </seg>
            <seg id="p291">291 asurer's Report. sv \ 125.00 wn nd 500 rshall on Bros 4.50 v Harrison 6.00 ar ssell ison 125.00 sll ip </seg>
            <seg id="p292">1&amp;2 Nebraska State Horticultural So e : Dora A. Hesseltlne C. B. Hain Lewis !!• 72 Ed 1 I E. Horning William I Charl^ King . . . C. Lamt • 7S Wm. 79 John 80 Richard Leah 81 Thomas Lyn 82 A. Martin 83 John Martin 84 W. H. Mills 85 H. L. Math* 86 J. G. Neff C. P. Neal H. O M. Robin Mrs.M. A. Schi ar 91 O. W. Shav E. E. Smith S2 93 W. B. Swislu 94 J. L. Speece 95 Stackhou&amp;e &amp; T F. Schumake 96 97 W. G. Swan 9S J. L. Stokes O. R. Trimme 99 G. N. Titus E. S. Williams 102 G. S. Christy 10S H. S. Harrison . 104 E. M. Pollard 105 Peter Youngers 106 Charles L. Saund&lt; 107 C. H. Green 108 W. G. Swan G. A. Marshall J. H. Hadkinson </seg>
            <seg id="p293">293 $2,935.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p294">Horticultural 294 Nebraska Slat In at K4, 1905, Cash 2, 1906. I Total r ' reports of th cultural SocU r! The Nebraska State H&lt;&gt;rii&lt; tilmral Sm §17, 1905, Balance on h 8, 1905, State Appropri 16, 1905, Cast </seg>
            <seg id="p295">I iNTDEX. </seg>
            <seg id="p296"/>
            <seg id="p297">297 I 94 294 W. Furnas 149 apes 129 153 ment by Utilizing Wild Species IK Forest Trees 188 124, 129 a State Horticultural Society 209 Breeding Grapes 124 Address of Welcome 21 44 168 herrv Orcharding 241 on and By-Laws If Amendments, Report of Committee 93 aving 207 Report of Chambers Experiment Station 161 Maple Scale 24S a awberries 207 nt by Utilizing Wild Species IK Directors 7 Diseases of Plum, Peach and Cherry 2SS Dole, E. W., House Plants 101 </seg>
            <seg id="p298">Nebraska Horticultural 298 Slate •,on. Prof. R. A er Garden ation Forest Planting as Forest Proble I Re Green, C. H Hanson, Pr O Br M&lt; Hardy Orn Harrison. ( Invocatior Schoo Letter of Transmi Marshall, C. G., Some Ca Nebraska Fruit Grow Meeting of Nor Membership Lis Kods and R' itlon of Our Fo: r, Prof. F- G — Forest Planting In Eastern Nebraska Some Forest Problems . . ■ Grounds and Gard 11, E. von, Hor </seg>
            <seg id="p299">299 Agricultural Schools .... 24 178 5 I a 121 :: and Treasurer's Reports. . . 294 adraent 93 Ex Hardy F a F, rvice In Nebraska T IT the Apple In Nursery and ry S., The Cottony Maple Scale 243 for Failures in Growing Fruit In Nebraska 89 M., Address of Welcome at Summer Meeting 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p300">Nebraska State Horticultural Socie 300 Ending Committees . . te Fair Premium List phens, E. F. — Apple Orcharding in Nebraska Commercial Cherry Orcharding The Curculio Emmer Meeting, Program . . . mmer Meeting, Address of W enk, Myron H., Plum and Ai The Tree Agent's G Treasurer's Report , Two Diseases of Pin Warrants Issued Williams, L. O., The *g tilllams, Theodore, Methods and R ork of Forest Service in Nebraska Youngers, Peter, Repor of Trea ran Houten, Geo. H., A an Metre, C. M., Repo </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>