<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 1920-1934</title>
               <date value="1934-06">1934-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 289 June, 1934 Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 1920-1934 E. E. BRACKETT AND E. B. LEWIS Department of Agricultural Engineering p" 1 ■*■ .» —g ggyass; jggl_; _bi__ ~ *~ __• ____P*i I .» (^ •• -^if^ti.m. yr mhiX V _—rt *___\j^~ —^ "~^ygjQi I" ""** UMM Zfc^fcl It ** LA-*? Jul ""T I" 1^, f*\Sj) I ., . &gt;nr .Ut,,, /I «— •pWrfl*^ ever ■■&amp; ' ' JTSTtV {___!______ _^^r-jj~ i _.=^HtfcrX i I — i p. j. p*&gt;_|^» p^erTOFtjhgl UlS.gg\., NU ?„ b^i ° f farms P^. s 1 ua re mile and location of lines from which farmers were getting electric service in 1929. Since about half of all farms are rented, the difficulty of obtaining the necessarv connections per mile of pole line is evident. necessary ■ '■■)■' .'"■■'.: TH 5«F? r iY ERSITY NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burb. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Introduction : 3 Methods of Supplying Electricity m Nebraska 4 Distribution of Usage m Amount and Time 9 Electrical Refrigeration m Rural Homes 14 Pumping Water Electrically 18 Electricity m the Laundry 23 Radio on the Farm 26 Cooking with Electricity 28 Electricity about the Dairy 30 Electrically Operated Irrigation Pumps 35 Processing Peed by Electric Power 36 Electrically Operated Poultry Equipment 36 The Electric Hay Hoist :. 40 Elevating Grain by Electric Power 41 Cold Storage Provided by Electricity 43 Heating Water Electrically 44 Heating Soil 44 Chore Motors 44 Animal Clippers 45 Miscellaneous Uses 45 Conditions that Influence the Use of Electricity on Farms 46 Appendix 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 1920-1934 E. E. BRACKETT AND E. B. LEWIS Various distributing agencies have wished to know Jvhat sets of conditions and what pieces of equipment have possi - bilities for satisfactory returns on investments required m supplying electrical service to farms. Many farmers have ™ ?T^? U K learn , in ? . what cos ts and benefits maj be expected if they use electrical equipment under the present conditions or under provisions to be met if service is later made available. This publication is a report of investigations made to obtain information required by the two groups 1 . •J he Agricultural Engineering Department of the Umver- SJ °f . Ne p r . as ka made some investigations m 1920 on] the ?qL e J e iQ r o£ lty b / the farmers having small plants, anil m 1924 and 1925 made a survey of most of the farms receiving electric service from central-station power lines. In none of these investigations could complete information be secured on conditions prior to 1919. , T Lights from sources other than the kerosene lamp were m use on 10,584 Nebraska farms m 1925. In 1930 electrtity for power as well as light was m use on 17,953 farms. 1 ] In 1919 very few farmers living near towns were using Elec - tricity supplied from the distribution systems supplying! the towns; a larger number of farmers had bought and were us - ing their own small light plants. Of the 17,953 farmers us - ing electricity m 1930, 5,278 were m the first group, together with those on lines built exclusively for rural consumers, and 12,675 were m the second group. During 1926 it was thought worth while to make a detailed study of the utilization of electric service m existence atlhat time m order to disclose causes of failure or success and to try to discover how to place future farm electric service 1 on a permanently economic basis. The first meeting of lany group for official action on studies to be carried out m rela - tion to the farmer and his use of electricity was held at the College of Agriculture, January 7, 1926. 2 mmwssmM </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 4 On March 12, 1926, the executive board of this group had its first official meeting. At this time the name, "Nebraska Committee on Rural Electric Service," was approved and E. E. Brackett was appointed as the project leader. Later a project was approved by the Experiment Station Council and started under the title, "The Use of Electric Power on Ne - braska Farms." METHODS OF SUPPLYING ELECTRICITY IN NEBRASKA The executive board felt that there was a demand for furth - er study after reviewing the report of the project leader, m which results were shown of contacts with the following six groups of farmers: Group I—Using1 — Using electricity from individual plants. Group 2 — Receiving service from transmission lines between towns — lines operated by a public utility company. Group 3 — Receiving service over a distribution system owned and maintained by the consumers as a community project. Group 4 — Receiving service from transmission lines built primarily for rural service. Group s— Receiving service over transmission lines between towns — lines operated by municipalities. Group 6 — Receiving service from a distribution system owned and operated by a bonded district. The next few pages contain a discussion of the information gained from the study of these groups. Group I.— Most of the general information related to Group 1 (those operating individual plants) has been sum - marized m Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 235, pub - lished m May, 1929. Some further data have been gathered and have been used further on m this publication. Groups 2 and 5. — Information concerning Groups 2 and 5, including all farmers receiving electric service from low - voltage lines connecting towns, showed that very little en - couragement had been given to this type of connection. Small revenue and the possibility that trouble on the farms might interrupt service to the towns were the principal reasons for this attitude. Even as late as January 1, 1928, only 200 farm - ers, less than one-tenth of those served from distribution lines, were connected on lines between towns. Data obtained prior to 1927 showed that the consumption of current was low and neither the consumers nor the distributing agencies were well satisfied. braska Farmers' Union: H. D. Lute, farmer, Paxton. Nebr.: Emory Peters, President, State Dairymen's Association ; W. R. McGeachin, Nebraska Gas and Electric Company ; HT J. McLaushlin. Secretary. State Department of Agriculture; S. R. McKelvie. Editor of The Nebraska Farmer; C. K. Morse. Curtis School of Agriculture; Mrs. C. B. Noyes. farmer. Waterloo. Nebr.: E. M. Pollard, farmer, Nehawka. Nebr.; Miss Robertson. Nebraska Power Company ; O. W. SJottren. Chairman, Department of Azricult.ural Eneineerinß, Univ. of Nebr.: Glenn Walker, Nebraska Power Company ; E. J. Way. farmer, Waterbury. Nebr.; C. N. Wright, farmer, Scottsbluff. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 5 Group 3 — The third group was known as the DJinne - brog Farm Line. The distribution system was built [as a community enterprise, the total cost being shared equally by the ten farmers connected, at a cost of about $600 each Exclu - sive of transformers. This was a 6600-volt, three-phase 1 sys- o m k °° ut . sl x miles long of 30-foot creosoted yellow-pine Ipoles and 5/16-inch stranded steel cable conductor, and had been m service about five years. Only one consumer used three-phase service, primarily for a 15 H. P. motor to operate a grinder StSr W M U f ed A y v, Ot l! er farmers of the community to some extent. Most of the homes were modern and well equipped with electrical accessories. The use of current outsidf the dwellings was limited chiefly to small motors for water pumps A small dairy farm also used a motor for milker and sep - arator. * The charges for service to this community were the lowest discovered m the survey. The power company read meters and did the accounting and collecting. All maintenance! and repairs were paid for by the community. The following is a tabulation of data from the nine consumers on the DanneVoir Farm Line during 1923 and 1924. This is the earliest [com - plete tabulation available m this state. Table 1. — Complete data on the Dannebrog rural electric line Item Av.kw-hrs. Ay. bill C ?" S ™i? r ' 8 . per month per month rerhSSr Smallest consumer (2 years) 24 . 8 $2 . 00 JO 0867 Largest consumer &lt;2 years) 187 . 6 7 B 6 040s Average per consumer (21 months) 71.8 8 . 47 04g7 Average with largest consumer excluded _ . 68.5 3.01 .0515 Including transformer core losses only and allowing 50 cents per customer per month for meter reading and account - ing, the revenue was 2.52 cents per kilowatt-hour. Thi« the power company considered unprofitable. An attempt had been made by the company to meter the total energy to this community but the meter was not m service long enough at any one time to give any data of value on energy lost m dis - tribution or total cost of energy. Group 4. — Information concerning the fourth group was secured on two lineß of the Blue River po Company near Seward (Table 2). The only electric range found m a farm home m Nebraska m 1924 was on one of these lines aijd it had been used through the summer months since its installa - tion m 1921. Current consumption on this farm is showh m Table 3 and is not included with the eighteen m Table 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 6 Table 2. — Summary of data from 18 rural consumers, Blue River Power Company, Seward, Nebraska Item 1918 1919 1920 1921 1922 ' 1923 ' 1924 1925 Total kw-hrs 4,289 4,623 4.919 5,942 6.668 6,011 6,616 6,807 Ay. kw-hr... per con - sumer per year 238.8 256.8 273.2 330.1 309.3 333.9 367.6 377.7 Ay. kw-krs. per con - sumer per month 19.9 21.4 22.8 27.6 26.8 27.8 30.6 31.6 Percentage of increase over previous year 8.6 6.4 20.8 -6.3 8.0 10.1 2.9 Kw-hrs. largest con - sumer per year 493 381 606 643 622 721 034 847 Kw-hrs. smallest con - sumer per year 126 76 47 61 80 63 63 97 No. consumers using 360 kw-hrs. or more during the year 3477679 8 Ay. kw-hrs. per year of these consume™ 403.7 373.5 394.6 607.7 485.2 512.7 545.6 679.2 Increase m consumption m 1025 over 1918 58.7% Greatest total by ere consumer for eight years 4,180 kw-hrs. His average per year for eight years.... 522.5 kw-hrs. The average per year for all farm connections m Nebraska m 1929 was 723.4 kw-hrs. (Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 254.) Table 3. — Increased consumption of electrical energy caused by the use of an electric range Item 1918 I 1919 1920 1921 1922 I 1923 1924 1925 Kilowatt-hours. 299 394 260 1,561 1,130 769 1,055 973 Total for eight years... 6,371 kw-hrs. Average per year ... , , &#132;...,..„ ~~ 796.4 kw-hrs. Average per year since installation of range 1,083.6 kw-hrs. Table 4. — Data from the same consumers represented m Table 2 after five years * Item 1930 1931 Total kw-hrs. _ 10,360 11,866 Average kw-hrs. per consumer per year 575.0 659.2 Average kw-hrs. per consumer per month 47.9 54.9 Kw-hrs. largest consumer per year...... — 2,433 2,096 Kw-hrs. smallest consumer per year................ — 105 183 Number of consumers using 350 kw-hrs. or more per year „ 9 12 Average kw-hrs. per year of these consumers — 926 854.5 1 All of these consumers were receiving service m 1982 with prospects of using as much electricity tl&lt;at year as m 1931, or more. This seems to indicate how those accustomed to the use of electrical energy value the service even m depression years. Between the years 1925 and 1931 extensive investigations m rural electric service, including some educational work and the use of more practical farm rate schedules by agencies sup - plying electrical energy, caused some interesting changes m </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 7 the use of electrical energy. In spite of low prices for farm products the people who were accustomed to making electric - ity work have not entirely discarded this convenient power source. Table 2 brings out one reason for much of the ef - fort toward increasing the use of electrical energy: the! av - erage use by the farm consumer was about 30 kilowatt-hburs per month. This apparently was true over much of the mid - west at the beginning of 1926. Table 4, however, seems to indicate a general increase m use of electricity m mord re - cent years. This increase was very greatly needed to] en - courage interest m placing electric service at the convenience of more farm homes. &#132; **£° U P 6 « — O n account of the many inquiries concerning the First Farmers' Electric District of Saunders county, Ne - braska, this being the first district of the kind m operation, and with the possibility that similar districts would be aro - jected, it seemed advisable that this enterprise be given care - ful study. This district comprised an area of approximately 22 4 square miles adjacent to Wahoo m Center, Marietta, Stock- i ng ' &lt;* a anAo n A^ aho ° P recinc *s. Twenty-year 5i/ 2 per cent bonds for $30,000 were voted by the electors residing within the district at a special election held according to the law then m iorce. Following the sale of these bonds, construction pro - ceeded under contract to those who had indicated that serVice would be used. To include some who decided to connect after the contract was let, funds m addition to the returns from | the loofr^ $ c,e ,_ b ? I l ds were re( l uir ed, and on January 1, 1925, $32,754.06 had been expended m the construction of 32 miles of pole lines complete with transformers and lightnine ar - resters. These lines were adjacent to 70 residents with 15 others within the boundaries of the district who would require ad - ditional construction before they could be served. Service was begun about November 1, 1923, to 32 consumers. The number of connections at later dates are indicated below.l Single-phase Three-phase January 1, 1924 connections connections January 1, 1925 !ZI!!!!!!i! 50 3 January 1, 1926 \[[[\[ 52 q Transmission was at 2300 volts, no connection being over nve miles from the station. Six of the consumers were rent - ers. Classification of the farms at the beginning of 1924 showed : </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin. 289 8 No. of farms Type of farming 1 Sheep feeding and general farming 2 Cattle feeding and general farming 1 Dairy farm 1 County poor farm 2 Retired, renting land to neighbors 33 Grain farms — small numbers of livestock The 48 consumers surveyed m August, 1924, showed use of current as follows: No. of farms Uses 48 Homes lighted 88 Other farm buildings lighted 30 Farms with one or more yard lights 26 ; Platirona 1 Percolator 2 Toasters 1 Curling iron 1 Battery charger 17 Motors under % H.P. on household accessories 5 Motors of Vz H.P. rating 3 Motors of 1 H.P. rating 1 Motor of 3 H.P. rating 3 Motors of 5 H.P. rating 1 Motor of 7% H.P. rating 1 Motor of 25 H.P. rating Although many additions have been made since the survey, the installation of additional equipment was retarded by an uncertainty m the minds of some consumers following the decision by the Supreme Court of Nebraska m 1924, m a case brought from another locality, declaring the law under which the district was organized and operating unconstitutional. An act was passed by the Legislature of 1925 validating the bonds of the district, but the validity of this act was ques - tioned and a suit resulted m a decision m 1930 that the or - ganization of the district was not valid. In spite of these conditions the current sold to consumers m 1925 increased 15 per cent over the preceding year, and similar increases were recorded for 1926 and 1927. 3 Electric energy was purchased from the City of Wahoo and metered at the power plant. Electrical losses m transmission during 1925 were 45 per cent of the total energy purchased. Some of this loss was due to factors that were corrected and the losses m 1926 were 31.9 per cent.* Similar losses were shown for this system for 1927, 1928, and 1929. Most of the power companies having rural lines m Nebraska estimate or calculate their rural-line distribution losses at from 30 to 50 per cent. ' Graph on page 15. Nebr. Art. Exp. Sta. Bui. 256. 'Nebr. Art. Exp. Sta. Bui. 236. p. 16. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 9 Table 5. — Summary of data on 37 consumers on rural electric lines two years prior to January 1, 1926, First Farmers' Electric District, Saunders county, Nebraska I Item 1924 1926 ■ | Total kw-hrs... „...„._ __......„„..__„ 8,647 10,171 ATcrage kw-hrs. per consumer per year 253.8 275 Average kw-hrs. per consumer per month 19.5 23 Percentage of increase over previous year 17.6 Kw-hrs. used by largest consumer. _ 658 1,38 I &amp;w-hrs. used by smallest consumer « 73 8 ) Number of consumers using 360 kw-hrs. or more during year 9 ' 1( ' Average kw-hrs. per year of these consumers.... 491 624.6 1 About one-fourth of the farm homes m this group were using 30 kw-hrs. or more per month. During the first year of operation taxes were collected by the county treasurer, bond interest was paid, and one $1,000 bond retired. The taxes were as follows: Total tax levied first year .-. $2,783.98 Tax levy on corporation property 417.17 Tax levy on farm property $2,366.81 Levy on farm property per quarter section (average) ....$ 26.42 Outside the household small motors were found most fre - quently pumping water, many of the installations being of a temporary character. Four grain elevators were operated by motors and one large grinder outfit was driven by a 25 HJ P. motor. The presence of tractors on most of the farms lim - ited motors to units of 5 H. P. and under. DISTRIBUTION OF USAGE IN AMOUNT AND TIME Usually the consumer as *well as the producer of electrical energy gives some thought not only to the total amount] of current consumption but to the amounts that certain uses will require as compared to others. Both groups also desire some knowledge of the continuity and fluctuations to be ex - pected m energy consumption throughout the year. Figure 1 shows the proportionate amounts of energy as used on the farm of a livestock feeder m 1929 and 1930. "]?he item "lights and miscellaneous power" included the ordinary use of lights m a seven-room farm home and the operation of the grain elevator, washing machine, and sausage grinder. Figure 2, arranged somewhat differently from Figure 1, shows consumption on a farm having a small dairy business as a side line. The first section typifies a two-meter rite. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">INebeaska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 10 / a TOTAL ENCRGY fOWCW UStS &lt;J OTTO CMC «c - i ' £ 3CWMO KICBR. £ J CtOUCt K. WELSH y , '/ '/ SCWAXO NCWASKA _™ • v ■ / / * k i ■ M *I * ' i ", I ' '' b« • g--2 t.° / V - Il ■ -ll i||| H ■ Figs. 1 (left) and 2 (right). — Distribution of energy consumption on two farms. On a livestock farm (Fig. 1) the amounts used outside and inside the house can be evenly divided. A farm (Fig. 2) on which dairying is practiced even m a small way changes the im - portance of uses. During the period through which the data for these percent - ages were obtained, a small motor was used for filling the silo and operating a hammer mill which ground feed for an average of 20 cows and 4 horses, and also for a corn sheller and a green-feed chopper. This is the first item m the second section of Figure 2. In each figure relative use of energy only is shown. The figures show two types of Nebraska farms that are fairly representative. Figures 3to 8 indicate how the seasons of the year influence the total monthly use of energy, how the type of farming influences total usage and causes fluctuations m energy consumption, how each follow - ing year varied m total energy consumed, and something of the total monthly requirements m kilowatt-hours needed on representative Nebraska farms. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 11 Figures 3, 4, and 5 represent data from the same faj-ms indicated m Figures 1 and 2. Borrowed equipment, added to that owned by these farmers, may have been partly the caW of rather high energy consumption, over 100 kilowatt-hours Joo | i 1 1 1 r — i 1 1 1 I—f-4001 — f - 400 ~ OTTO GAOE o A SEWABO NCSR. f I \ X LEGEND / / \ £ 1938 / / \ O 1929 / / . V | 1930 . j \ tf 300 ~ / I \ 8 / / \ §/ / \ i 2oc - ■ • '/^£\ &gt;^ \ 100 .y/ v /l ; : . ■ ' " .: ; . ■■■;■;■■ , V ol I i i i I i i i i , J *N FES MAS APR. MAY JUNE JULY AUg! SeP 0^ NCV. DEC Fig. 3. — Electrical energy consumed throughout the year. 400 | 1 1 ) 1 1 -J 1 1 1 1 |" f\//7\)A ■ §200- / \ \ a ' gs^ CEO.K.WEUSH \ \ + / Jr scwuo, wk \ \ t c Ijf LEGEND *&gt;&gt; N k S *"*"yL^^ s^V/' 1»2» N /° 2/ I9X) &gt;*--_. '■■-■■ '.- ■ - . ■ ■ ■■ ■ ■ ' I ■* ■ .:■ -(;.:■■ ■' ." : V ■ i'iiii i i i i L JAN FEa MAR APO MAC JUNE JuJ AuS SEPT OCT NOV JXC Fig. 4.— Electrical energy consumed throughout the year for farm pov rer. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 12 40 1 I I I I I I I I I I \ GEO. K.WELSH 1 J \ imo Nts«. /&gt; Z 3O ~ \ LEGEND a f 2 &gt; \ s\ ills /r\ / c \ V\ — a* 3o //\ ■ y I I I T I I I I I I JAN. FEB. MAR. APR. MAY JUNC JUUT AUG. SEP OCF. NOV. DEC. Fig. 5. — Electrical energy consumed throughout the year by lights. m the low-consumption months and nearly 400 kilowatt-hours m the summer months, but data for other years indicate that these representations are fairly typical. Figure 6 shows the steady load of a dairy farm m the 1928 curve and then the large increase and total consumption / \ / A / / v "\ iA/ ' \ ' w v / \&gt; £ V / LEGENO ? goo _ J 1929 t 600 " y S 1930 &#132;1111111 111 JAN FEB. MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JUUT AUG. SEP. OCT. NOK DEC Fig. 6. — Electrical energy consumed by the Rolfsmeier dairy. The increases m consumption were due to an increase m the size of the dairy. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 13 '"I I 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 i A&lt; § 100 - /^ yy X s . / / • . * . . . N I™^ / / X - f- ,/ / JOE REDIGER &gt;»-- " O *^_ / ». / somiwo ncbr. ; \ / LEGEND 2 SO - S v' '929 _ * 1830 "I 1 1 1 1 I I ' I 1 I I JAN. FEa MAR. APR MAY JUNE JULY AUG. SEP OCT NOV DEC Fig. 7. — Consumption of electrical energy on a farm smaller th m the average. shown with the doubling of the dairy herd, along with the installation of mechanical refrigeration and sterilization equipment. These curves, while not representative of the average Nebraska farm, are fairly typical of the specialized farms whether poultry raising, livestock feeding, dairying, or gardening is practiced. Figure 7, m contrast to FiguFe 6, represents the total monthly energy consumption on a farm smaller than the average, on which the owner milks 6 to 8 cows, raises 30 to 50 hogs and 300 to 500 chickens, does some gardening, has some fruit, and does some general grain farm - ing on his 80 acres. This farmer's use of energy is fairly as l 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 T-j— J.BURGE 100 — LANCASTER CO. J LEGEND Ji I r ' * y^s\,^- j ' \ ' / * — \ 3 .»_- / MOTI: N. 2S ""'-^^ / njurr usco. oIJIIII I I I I | JAN FEB. MAR. APH. MAY JUNE JULY AUG. SEP. OCT. NOV. DEC Fig. 8. — Consumption of electrical energy on a grain farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 14 constant from month to month and is slightly higher than that of the average farmer as shown by complete statistics. Fig - ure 8 shows the use of energy on a fairly typical grain farm where about the only use of electricity outside the house is for the stock-well pump. This home is well equipped with the ordinary household helps, such as water system, refrig - erator, washing machine, iron, percolator, toaster, radio, and churn, all electric. A quick glance at all curves m Figures 3 to 8 seems to in - dicate no very abrupt change m the amount of electrical energy used by average Nebraska farmers either month by month or season by season. It also appears that where the investment could be undertaken for the wiring installations and the necessary appliances and equipment, enough energy was consumed to make these farmers good patrons to dis - tributing systems. A few feeders and dairymen m the state use 800 to 1500 kilowatt-hours per month regularly but the number of these specialists is small m comparison with others using rural electric service. ELECTRICAL REFRIGERATION IN RURAL HOMES Refrigeration was one of the first uses for electric energy lending itself to study. The investigations of 1920-24-25, pre - viously mentioned, showed that the electrically operated re - frigerator was one piece of equipment m which most of the Nebraska farmers who had electric service were interested. Attention was directed primarily to domestic installations rather than to large dairies or places which, although agri - cultural and rural, come m a special class which has but small bearing on the success or failure of general problems of rural Table 6. — Operation of four mechanical refrigerators during summer months Farm No. m Size Period Length Total Ay - Ay - kw-hrs. No. family of box beginning of period kw-hra. kw-hrs. per. day per per day cv. ft.' Cu. ft. Days 18-4 9 June 1, 1926 122 212.9 1.74 0.1958 Hay 1, 1927 158 278.0 1.78 0.1922 remote * 2 _.. MayS, 1925 164 683.0 8.79 0.2528 June 1,1926 866 834.0 2.28 0.1619 remote * 3 7-8 6% May 1,1925 199 718.0 8.67 0.6415 » Aug. IS, 1926 65 121.0 2.20 0.8886 cabinet June 1. 1927 61 168.0 2.60 0.8846 1 I" 8 *2« Aug. 1,1927 68 148.0 2.66 0.2660 cabinet 6 ' 6% Aug. 8. 1927 68 125.0 d.83 0.2816 cabinet 1 Food storage space, net. "Motor and compressor installed outside cabinet. 'Not properly serviced. Note: On farms 1 and 6 the electrical energy was supplied from individual battery - tyye plants. . </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 15 electric service m Nebraska." Table 6 shows the variation m energy consumption encountered with units of different sizes and types m early usage. Farm No. 3, Table 6, had an early experience with poor servicing. This farm is a small dairy farm and the uni; was smaller than needed and consequently the storage space was usually overflowing although no difficulty was experiencjed m maintaining the desired temperature m the refrigerator. This unit was replaced by a larger one m 1927, which fillel the requirements with a greater degree of satisfaction and at approximately the same energy cost. The difference iii the consumption of electrical energy shown m Table 6 was not due so much to difference m size as to the construction of the cabinets, the temperature and movement of the air around them and around the compressors, and to the nature and quan - tity of materials placed within the storage and cooling dpace. Although most of the farmers were interested m electric refrigeration, and although electric distributing and servicing agencies desired the type of load needed by its operation, very few mechanical refrigerators were found on farms previous to 1927. Several reasons contributed to this fact. Thd first cost of a cabinet was high, the cost of energy m many instanc - es was too great, and lack of stability as to dealer and service organizations and the rapid changes and developments iii the equipment all tended to cause a hesitancy m trying out: this new piece of electrical equipment. During 1927 several pieces of electrical equipment, includ - ing two new refrigerators, were loaned to the University for use m the Rural Electric Project. 6 These were used by farm - ers who were willing to pay the cost of the electric service. The two loaned models, another owned by the University , and several owned by farmers wishing definite information on the operation cost, constituted the field of study following the study m a preliminary way prior to 1927. In Figures 9, 10 and 11 representation is made of the con - sumption of electrical energy by three different-sized me dern cabinets m three different farm homes over a period of two or more years. The cabinet used by Mr. Gade (Figure 9) was a seven-cubic-foot box installed m October, 1928. ItJ was placed near an inside wall m the kitchen-dining room as far from the range as possible. However, the back of the cabinet was pushed too close to the wall to provide the best of condi - • M^'n'/rtf"^ re t rteep */ lo ?v? discussed m Nebr. Aur. Exp. Sta. Bui. 249 1 1930). Jn tafhl-rf. f^S"? ln P ia » nb " e « tl °»&gt; *m made possible by the installation, m farm homes, of up-to-date equipment loaned by manufacturers. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 16 lOOi I- /'■■■ S OTTO CADE / E SCWARO MM. / H LEGEND / ..-""^ 5 1928 / /*" \ S«0- , 929 // \ 1 "° JS \- p \ "_ . r[ ! V " \ / / V\ \ / / t \\ J \l V if I I I || I I JAN. FEBL MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JUly AUG. SCR OCT. NOV. DEC Pig. 9. — Electrical energy consumed by a seven-cubic-foot refrigerator. tions m ventilating the motor and compressor. 7 The family of six consisted of three adults and three children. The cab - inet used by Mr. Burge (Figure 10) was rated by the manu - facturer at nine-cubic-foot capacity. It was placed m the large, airy dining room m an almost ideal position as to ven - tilation for motor and compressor. The family consisted of four adults. The cabinet used by Mr. Welsh (Figure 11) was a ten-cubic-foot box. It was placed m a small, poorly ven - tilated pantry, and heat from the motor and compressor was •°| 1 I I T I I I 1 I I 3 / J. BURGE 2 ' LANCASTER CO. NOTE' 20 _ 6 LEGEND 3IVOLT delCO _ _____ 1929 PUUfTUiIO 1930 io| i i i i i i i i I I JAN. FE— MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JUiy AUG. SEP. OCT. NOV DEC Fig. 10. — Energy consumed by a nine-cubic-foot refrigerator. T See Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Circular 45, Fitting the Mechanical Refrigerator into the Home (1933). </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 17 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 -00- f /\ h. IP* \ - §40 _ /// CEO. K.WELSH \\ **° II I SCWARO NUR. \ \ - I LEGEND \ \ I 1028 \ \ /// . 1 1929 \ \ 20- // •*» \\ _ - /I \x JIXI*III I I I I \ \ JAN. FEa MAR. APR. MAC JUNE JUUf AUG. SEP. OCT. NOV DEC Pig. 11. — Energy consumed by a ten-cubic-foot refrigerator prevented from escaping readily. The family consisted of four adults and two half -grown boys. Mr. Gade is a cattle feeder, Mr. Welsh operates a small re - tail dairy, and Mr. Burge is a grain farmer. Both the Gade and Welsh refrigerators were overcrowded much of the time. Warm, prepared foods and milk and cream placed m these boxes probably caused the machines to operate longer than necessary if time had been taken to pre-cool the food. The position of the cabinet m the home seemed to have sone in - fluence on the electrical energy consumed. The cabinet shown m Figure 9 used 0.26 kilowatt-hour per day per cubic foot of storage; that m Figure 10, 0.16 kiloiwatt - hour; and the one m Figure 11, 0.28 kilowatt-hour fronJ May to September, inclusive, or an average of almost 0.25 kilowatt - hour per day per cubic foot of storage space for the three cabinets. These were all improved-quality boxes and prob - ably this fact is the greater part of the reason for the ower operating costs than those shown m Table 6. In fact, data on other more recently manufactured cabinets indicate thkt % kilowatt-hour per day per cubic foot of storage shoufd be about the maximum average energy consumption under heavy farm usage during the summer months indicated. On this </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 18 basis a ten-cubic-foot box would use about two kilowatt - hours per day m a room temperature of 80° F. Figure 12 shows the energy consumed by the refrigerator on the dairy farm indicated m Figure 6. I I I I I I I I I I if\/ ! \ §300- j • / / \ i V / I mw «br. / / LECENb / , . ... .... I 1029 / ' _.^_._ 1930 100 U ' - 1 | | I I I I I I I JAN. FEB. MAR. APR. MAC JUNE JUUf AUG. SEP. OCT. NOU DEC. PlO. 12. — Electrical energy consumed by a dairy refrigerator. Cool - ■'■:" ing fresh milk from above 90° F. and pasteurized milk from above •■: 145" F. to below 50° F. makes a load almost commercial m size. PUMPING WATER ELECTRICALLY On many Nebraska farms pumping water is the only appli - cation of electricity to be found outside the house. In many instances where this was found true, financial and other con - ditions had delayed piping the water, so pumped, into the house. Few shallow-well pumping systems except those pump - ing from cisterns or reservoirs were available for study. A large percentage of the wells m the state, except near one or two rivers, are deep enough to require the deep-well out - fits. Observations were made and data obtained on wells from 35 to 175 feet «deep. Some of the. pumps were required to operate under a maximum pressure of 50 pounds additional head over that of the well depth. On most farms small amounts of water under pressure were needed within short periods. The 40-to-80-gallon pneumatic tanks were ample for storage m these instances. Several installations were found m which the pumping speed was too fast, causing heav- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 19 ier demand on the motor and greater energy consumption per 1,000 gallons pumped as well as making too heavy A toll on low-producing wells. Lowered speed on one or two p ump heads reduced the demand 50 per cent and lowered the en - ergy from 2.6 to 1.5 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 gallons. The earliest data were obtained from installations where and as found. Information on the installation shown m Fig - ure 13 is shown m Table 7. The well from which the -sfater was pumped was 70 feet deep with no additional pressure head. The water pumped supplied 3to 5 m the family be- Pig. 13. — An old automobile wheel bolted and wired to the pullej of the old pump jack converted it into one that could be operated by the small motor. sides 6 to 8 horses, 3 to 5 cows, 20 to 50 hogs, 200 to 300 chickens, and a. small amount to a garden. Even with the ordinary gasoline-engine-type pump jack, on which the iront wheel of a Ford car had been wired as a large pulley for speed reduction, the energy required as shown m Talle 7 was not great. The idea prevails that the power required for the pump in - creases rapidly with increase m pressure. One test showed that 151 watts were required to pump 65 feet to ground llevel, and an additional 70 feet, or 135 feet of total lift, required only 25 watts (16% per cent) of added power. In 1928 the pressure pump head shown m Figure 14 was in - stalled to replace Figure 13 and pipes were connected to the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 20 HH^^H^^^HKH^HH|^^9H house plumbing. With f^^^|B^H^H[^^|H|Bßßm|i this new installation |H^HH|^^fl^^nH|^^B^^^H^Hß§j pumping against an fßJHl^BHH^Foill^i^HH^Kini additional pressure HJ head of 50 pounds El maximum, the de- I^^HpgjEi3ff^j§^^HK»fiffH mand was less to the ■BBKpS^MUW* B Bl^|KT?^ |^s3gw motor and the energy per thousand gallons 1 was ess&gt; With m KSj , stallations as m Fig - f^S? ItW ures an{ * pump - |Hl m # f or small families and small numbers of c ■-•-•-'y^^^S^s(^^ipPS^^BppßH| domestic animals, the r^^fe^^^^^Bj|^fc|HHS^^^^ energy consumption ■ "•'^ S5 '^^E5SS -- . averaged less than 20 kilowatt - hours per month. PlO. 14. — A better pump head for auto- Figure 15 ShO W S matic pressure water service plus the equipment on the concrete well platform improved ap- w«1 oi, t-, ™ ™n pearance and service when they re- vv ci s n Ia r m pre - placed those of Figure 13. Viously mentioned. Table 7. — The use of electric energy by Vfc H. P. motor" and pump jack T ; me I Period of I Total I Ay. enersy I Total enemy I observation I energy used I used per day I used on farm Dava Kw-hrs. KwJin. Kw-hrs. Aue. 28 to Oct. 13, 1924 46 24 0.52 Oct. 18 to Nov. IS, 1924 81 10 0.82 84 Nov. 18, 1924. to Jun. 2. 1925 49 16 0.32 42 Jan. 2 to Feb. 1, 1925 30 7 0.23 23 Feb. 1 to May 22, 1925...-. 109 28 0.25 ' 96 May 22 to Dec. 12, 1925 203 71 0.35 177 Dec. 12 to June 2, 1926 171 61 0.85 177 Jane 2 to June 23. 1926 22 10 0.45 Note: During the time these data were belts collected this family used electric energy for very little except the water pump and lights and one or two small appliances. This well and the well shown m Figure 14 were about the same depth, 50 pounds maximum pressure was used m each case, and each house had complete plumbing facilities. In Figure 14 the energy required was 2 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 gallons per 100 feet of total head, and m Figure 15 the energy required was 1.5 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 gallons per 100 feet of head. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 21 • _&gt; I "_ ■•■-■■.:.,-,- . - JM Fig. 15. — Cleanliness and dependability are demanded of the modern water system. Figure 16 shows the very small amount of energy required for toilet and bath for a family of six. A small amouni of soft water used m the laundry compensated a similar amount used from the deep well for lawn and car washing. Figure 17 shows the requirements for the livestock m the feed lot. The January to April requirements for the 225 cattle and 300 hogs were 55 to 75 kilowatt-hours per month. The wsiter was from a 55-foot well and was carried through 600 ::eet of 1-inch pipe to tanks 6 to 10 feet above the top of the well. Energy required m Figures 16 and 17 was 2.0 and 1.85 Mlo - watt-hours per 1,000 gallons raised 100 feet. Figure 18 shows the rather large requirements for a 75-cow dairy. The outfit from which these data were obtained pumped too :'ast for the inflow of the well and had to force the water through 1,800 feet of pipe and against 45 pounds of pressure. Re - quirements here were 2.5 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 gallons per 100 feet of head. The automatic water system or any water system electric - ally operated is not a great load builder for a distributing agency, is not expensive for the operator, and is a fairly con - stant load on a rural line. It becomes a good- will builder and not only eventually pleases the entire farm family but is one of the finest home-improving pieces of equipment fost - ered by rural electric service. The immediate results of the installation of this equipment were: sanitary well platforms and well curbs (Figures 14 and 15) ; many more samples of drinking water sent to the State Health Department; and im- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 I 22 T I I" 1 ""! I I k I 1 1 1 ft — I p «1 — \\A fj \/\ " I \// \/ \ / \ ■ J - * V soSK OO^, V V - LEGEND \ I 1828 \| » — — . — 1929 ll 011111 I I I I I I JAN. FEB MAR APR. MM JUNT MC/ AUG. SER OCT. NOW DEC. Fig. 16. — Electrical energy consumed by a deep-well pump. »o^— — — I fr" \ OTTO OAOE a ' \ . 3iw«hd Mian. 5 / \ LEGENO I / \ 1928 i , 1 929 I" " \ V /- J i i i i I i i .T i Xi JAM FEa MAR APR. MAY JUt* JUUT AUG. SEP. OCT. NCU DEC. Pig. 17. — Energy consumed by a stock -well pump. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 23 1 y&lt;Z? ' ' — ' — ' — ' — ' — ' — 1 z **» Olio — 2 ROLFSMEIER DAIRY - 3EWARO N»R. 5 LEGEND a 192 9 A &gt; sloe5 loe - / X/ - &lt; 50 — / _ Ol 1 I I I ■ '' I I I I | | •** **■ ****■ *«• mm junT~jus auo — sro — oct fS! — 5eS. Fig. 18. — Energy consumption by the stock well pump on a 75-cow dairy. proved plumbing and sewage facilities. 8 Although surveys show that more farmers have electric washing machines, irons, and radios than have electrically operated water sys - tems, the latter are more highly prized by every member lof the family than any other piece of electrical equipment or appliance. 9 Running water m the house and the conveniences that are closely related often are worth the total cost of the electric service. ELECTRICITY IN THE LAUNDRY Surveys show that approximately 82 per cent of the fann - ers who have electric service of any kind have washing ma - chines operated by electric motors and 84 per cent have hand irons heated by electrical energy. 10 The motors used on most of the washing machines were small, the machines were op - erated m such manner that the demand on the motor and service line was not excessive and the operation time to com - plete the weekly laundry was short. Although some vefy ingenious pulley reductions were found on some of the older machines, very little educational work has been needed |to place this equipment on the farms. Studies have shown that when water used m the laundry is about 125" F., most machines clean an average machineful of clothes m about 10 minutes. 11 Many of the machines could have better and more convenient controls and switches and 'Installation of water systems is discussed m Nebr. A*r. Exp. Sta. Bui. 245, Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems (1930). 'Nebr. Asr. Exp. Sta. BaL 236 (1929) and Supplement No. 1 of the U. S. D. A. Farm Housing Survey, 1984. "Surreys mentioned m footnote 9. "Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 66 (1931) is a technical study of types of washins machines: Circular 47 (1984) is a popular discussion of laundry equipment and methods. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 24 better protection to the operator m the manner of covering moving parts. Electrical energy requirements for washing the clothes of the average family of five to six persons vary from two to four kilowatt-hours per month, with the aver - age about 2.5. -Many times interruptions happen when the farm housewife does the laundry and the average time per machine load is greater than 10 minutes. With careful op - eration, the improved washing machine can be relied upon to use less than 2.5 kilowatt-hours per month if the family is no larger than six persons. More electric hand irons can be found m the farm homes than washing machines. In a few places where the washings were large and where ironing with the five-to-six pound hand iron was too great a strain for the wife, the ironing machine was found. Four different ironing machines were placed m the homes of farmer co-operators to aid m obtaining first - hand information. Some of the farm women never succeeded m operating the machine to their entire satisfaction but many of them learned to use the ironer well enough so that shirts and dresses were ironed as satisfactorily as "flat pieces". The wife on one farm machine-ironed all of a large washing about one week after her return from a hospital where she had undergone a major operation. A young girl, after two or three trials, ironed the following on one of the machines : 5 sheets • 6 dresses 7 pillow cases 2 starched shirts 4 large table cloths 1 pair lace curtains 2 small table cloths 10 towels % dozen napkins 1 night shirt 1 apron These and many other miscellaneous articles, which took about 15 minutes, were ironed m two and one-half hours. Approximately three kilowatt-hours of electric energy were consumed by the ironer for this amount of laundry. 12 Neither this young lady nor the wife previously mentioned felt any nervous strain or appreciable fatigue m sitting at the machine and operating the controls. This ease of hand - ling does not, however, come to all of the women who have tried out this appliance. While a few did a very creditable ironing of all shirts and dresses, it was found that many of those trying the machine felt that the hand iron must be used somewhat. It was found that the ironing machine com - pleted the ironing of the same size and type of washing m less than one-half the time required by the electric hand iron. The electric energy required was less m some instances (be - u Figure 19 shows the ironing machine referred to. This machine was the first of three loaned by one company. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 25 Ui \ : i. .:.'": I^ U : '-^ ■i'^^itn J^ iB : ij ■ Eh i r; ~ ■ I Jz^'mi'-mi' •■ ' ■'■m I ' i' :^^^?^ ■ * «i-it~- . ■ 'f •- --.=■«. •^.^lP^'^^fl^B IB ■ ■ ■ '■^ i&lt; - ■■- 1 1 Fig. 19. — Equipment for convenience and the saving of time und labor to busy farm women often makes the kitchen look more cheerful. cause of better mastery and adaptation by the operator) for the ironing machine than for the hand iron. It was also found that the ironing required 6 to 20 kilowatt-hours per fsmily per month or one to three kilowatt-hours per person per month with an average of about 1.5 kilowatt-hours per person per month. These data held for both the machine and the hand iron with a possible slight advantage for the machine *&gt;| I 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 16 - OTTO GAOE / \ - 14 - LEGEND / \ / g '92» / A. ** / §12- — 1830 I /\\ / _ §l °- V &gt;^ / I A \ / /\~^ be- f i \ / y \ \ _ h{ Y&lt;yif \ \ /~ - •hA*w \ \7 - AViWii . ! , V , JAM. FEa MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JULY AUG. SEP OCT NCV OEf Fig. 20. — Electrical energy consumed by an ironing machine. Al - though ironing machines consume considerable energy while m operation, they do not add a large number of kilowatt-hours to the monthly bill. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 26 **| • I 1 T 1 1 1 — — 1 1 1 r^\ JsPYv v \\: i m - A \ // V *-\ - -1 • /\ \ // GEOI k welsh \ 3° ~/ \ \ /^ »ewmo. nor v - * / \ • / LEGEND \ 6F ~ M/ 1928 -T1 O • ■•; ■ 1929 ' \| JIIIII 1 I I I | I •&gt;**&gt;■ FEBI MAR APB M/W 3*C JWy AUC SEP OCT. NOV. DEC. Fig. 21. — Energy consumed by another ironing machine. ironer. The first cost of the ironing machines was apparently too great for the advantage admitted by the farm housewives. The large pedestal-type ironer has been improved greatly m recent years and many of the smaller portable and washing - machine-accessory types have been priced more nearly within the means of the farm purchasers. This appliance will, m some period not far distant, take a place m the list of elec - trical appliances much nearer those chosen first by people who do the laundry at home. The curves m Figures 20 and 21 indicate the continuity of the use of the ironing machine through all months of the year and, although most of the laundry work comes within the first three or four days of the week, most of it causes a demand on the electric service lines at a time of day most desired by distributing agencies. RADIO ON THE FARM About 50 per cent of all Nebraska farmers having any elec - tric service have radios of the "all-electric" type. Those having radios of other types bring the total of radio owners to almost 90 per cent of all farmers. Figure 22 shows data taken on the farm of one of the co-operators. This figure (March, 1928) indicates, very typically, how the radio, when new to the home, is a comparatively large consumer of energy and then gradually the use falls to a point where a few pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 27 ferred programs are all that are m demand. The battery - charger and battery-eliminator types of radio required more electrical energy than the "all-electric" type. This is shown by lowered consumption after August, 1929 (Figure 22). The energy consumption of even the larger radios for the pro - *r i — i — i — i — i — i — i — i — \ — 22 — \ \ _ GEO.K.WH_SH __ \ r- v aonMo. new. 20 — \ / \ LEGEND — \ / "q 1926 W — \ I \ 1929 _ fc H4/V I \ \ \. *u.-&amp;zcn»c\ ,A -* H. luce ■aTALua _* *%_ sr -- v.^c^.^_ : : 2 — _ 0111111 I I I I I •*"* "*■ "«• APR M» JUNF X 5 AUc! SEP. OCT. NCV DEC. Fig. 22. — Electrical energy consumed by a radio. The average radio is never switched off because "it uses too much electricity". ] grams regularly heard by farm families is less than 20 kilo - watt-hours per month. Most of the seven- and eight-tube kets use less than 10 kilowatt-hours per month. The radio, wliile not a large consumer of electric energy, is an important ap - pliance and the all-electric is very satisfactory and inexpen - sive. One farmer, before buying an "all-electric," had been spending $24.00 per year for "B" batteries and about $i&gt;.oo per year for charging the "A" batteries besides the yearly cost of the "A" batteries. When this farmer found the all - electric used much less energy than the other radios, he was not long m finding a way to make the exchange. Weather and market reports, other programs of particular interest and value to the entire farm family, and music and comedy pro - grams of interest to individuals cause the energy consump - tion of the radio to be spread over every day of the week [and almost every hour of the day. The consumption of endrgy </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 28 and the demand of this appliance are such that both the con - sumer and distributor of rural electric service are mutually satisfied and benefited. COOKING WITH ELECTRICITY Before 1927 very few Nebraska farmers were using any electric cookery appliances or equipment. These articles were considered luxuries, to be used on a few occasions and orna - mental enough to be desirable. Even the toaster ranked eleventh m 1927 " and fifth m 1934. 1 * Waffle irons, pancake grills, pop-corn poppers, and other appliances for similar uses are m the same class as the toaster. The very few electric ranges on the farms previous to 1927 were considered too ex - pensive to own and operate under any comparison with other cooking equipment and fuels. There were also complaints about slower cooking on the electric than on stoves using gas, cobs, wood, coal, or other fuels. The data shown m Figures 23 and 24 were obtained from two improved electric ranges. ; A CO— GED.K. WELSH ' / / I — SIWUO, HIM. / q / 1 h« LEGEND . /l\ I \ 110 ~ 1928 •/ \ / \ • 1929 / / V V 1 \ gSO - / / / \ \ Ji \\ /is \\ - «S . i*-'' i i i i i i i I I JAN FEB. MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JUUT AUG. SEP. OCT. NOVi DEC. Pig. 23. — Energy consumed by an electric range. While most electrical cooking on farms will always be confined to the hot months, it also finds a place m the cool months. "Bulletin 254 (previously cited). "Federal Farm Housing Survey (previovdy cited). </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 29 "°| 1 1 1 1 1 C 1 1 1 ! _. OTTO GADE / LEGEND / i «» / r- — " /^-"\ oP — r~'" :::= ? ?^ r, i i i i i i i JAN. FEB. MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JULY AUG SEP OCX NOV. DEC Fig. 24. — Energy consumed by another electric range. Data m Figure 23 were obtained from the range shown m Figure 19. Many of the farm homes have little provision for heat : 'or the kitchen except that given by the range, and most Ne - braska farms have cobs and wood about the farmstead. Th jse two facts will continue to prevent the general use of the elec - tric range. Evidence of the desirability of the electric radge m the hot seasons is shown m Figures 23 and 24. The num - ber of kilowatt-hours used by the families indicated and -the distribution of the consumption over the different months are probably fairly representative for Nebraska farm families. It is also probable that energy rates for this class of electrical equipment will need to be much lower to change either ijhe total consumption or the distribution over the different months. Faster heating elements, better construction and in - sulation, and lower first cost have made the electric raige more desirable for the farm. Electric stoves have undergone so many changes and improvements during the last few years that many recommendations may be considered as obsolete. 10 The energy consumption of the electric range as used m Ne - braska varies from 25 to 50 kilowatt-hours per person per month, with an average of about 30. This energy consump - tion is influenced by the type of cooking, the training and carefulness of the operator, and the quality and adaptability of the electric range. Small electric ranges, table hot plates, "Nebr. Aer. Exp. Sta. Circular 47 (1934) discusses the subject. "Choosing and Operating Electric Stoves". </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 30 and cookers have not been accepted by the Nebraska farm wives because of the small cooking space. Some of these ap - pliances are used intermittently but their general use for regular farm meals has not had much appeal. The electric range will continue to use more energy than any other single piece of equipment in the farm home. This use of energy will not be particularly desirable for best dis - tribution practices until conditions change enough to cause electric cooking to be used more months of the year. ELECTRICITY ABOUT THE DAIRY In this state most of the farmers who milk more than two cows daily have some type of mechanically operated cream separator. Over 20 per cent of the farmers having any elec - tric service (power line or home electric plant) have a sep - arator operated by a small electric motor. Many separators are very sensitive to speed. Apparently no member of the family can be depended upon to turn the machine at the correct speed all the time. The amount of cream saved per milking when a motor operates the separator and the tedious - ness of manual operation have caused many to give the little inexpensive motor this job. Except on the larger dairy farms the $4 H« P- motor is used almost exclusively on the average sized separator. The average consumption of energy for those observed was 0.36 kilowatt-hour per 1,000 pounds of milk separated. Another job not highly relished by the young people on the farm is churning. About one-tenth as many electrically op - erated churns as separators were found on the farms. Most of the churns were the small-barrel individual churns or the small dasher type which came as accessories with some of the washing machines. None of these churns used motors over 14 H. P. in size and the electrical energy averaged nearly 1.5 kilowatt-hours per one hundred pounds of butter churned. About as many milking machines as churns were being op - erated by electric motors. These machines showed a wide range in consumption of energy. Part of these variations were due to operators and part to the machines. On the drive-rod, pipeless type of milkers the average energy con - sumption was 1.4 kilowatt-hours per cow- per month with a range of 1.2 to 1.75 kilowatt-hours per cow per month. With the one-pipe, two-unit machines an average of 1.5 kilowatt - hours per cow per month was obtained, while with the dou - ble-pipe, two- and three-unit milkers from 2.4 to 5.1 kilowatt - hours per cow per month was the range and 3.0 kilowatt - hours per cow per month was the average. On some of the farms no appreciable time or labor was saved; on others,. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 31 where as many as twenty cows were milked twice daily, as much as 40 minutes per milking and the services of one mfn were saved. On a few farms where six to eight cows were being milked twice daily, very little time or labor was really saved. The time and labor saved m milking m these instances were offset by that required to cleanse and sterilize the extra milking equipment. This shift often, however, relieved some - one who felt that milking was an irksome and disagreeable chore and gave the chore of washing and steaming the extra equipment to some member of the family who did not object. Usually much of the dust and other foreign material abo|ut the animals and m the barn, which often drops into an open milk pail, is kept from the milk when the milker with closed containers is used. However, great care is needed m keeping the equipment free from bacterial growth. As more and moire information is obtained on the causes of milk contamination, better care and more certainty can be used m sterilizing dai :y equipment and the milker is becoming more popular. Where the family consists mostly of young folks interest id m the dairy animals and products, the cost of equipment plus the cost of operation were often hard to justify." Where hired help had to be depended upon and the requirements for pro - ducing clean, pure milk were emphasized, the milker and t le cost of operating it were paid for through savings. This piece of equipment, with an operating cost varying from 10 to 30 cents per cow per month (at the average electrical ra!te for Nebraska rural consumers), has proved satisfactory jto both the user of the milker and the distributor of electrical energy. The cost of operation is slight and not burdensonie to the farmer and the machine is used mornings and early evenings when the electrical load caused by its operation is welcome to the distributor. Figures 25, 26, and 27 show typical consumption data for three types of machines. Where milk was retailed from the farm, some type of mech - anical bottle washer was usually found. Except on the f«w farms where more than thirty cows were milked daily, these bottle washers usually consisted of a rotating brush operated by a small motor. On a few of the large dairies the more elaborate steam pressure washers were found. Usually the investment m the simple equipment was very small m prjo - portion to the bottles washed and the time and labor saved daily. Mechanical bottle cappers were used on most of the farms where bottled milk was produced. Here, again, the equip - ment was very simple except on the farms where over thirty cows were milked daily. Many of the small cappers wete manually operated; however, a small motor attached to the </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 32 I""/V \V\ &gt;7 """" \ " (1 16 -7 W *^^ &gt; Sj %v _ v ■»* / CEO X WEUSH \ — 5 1/ \/^ «W*o N(H \ JIIiII I I I I T JAN. FE§ MAR. APR. MAY JO?C JULY AUG. SEP OCT NO! DEC Fig. 25. — Electrical energy consumed by a milking machine used with 16 to 22 cows milked twice daily. 30 | I I I I I I I I I 1 "\ ■■ ■• ■ ■ : ■ . '. - £ \ JOE REWGER t SCWARD NtS*. S\ LEGEND SO- \ 1929 a \ 1030 -\/ x \., J v v 0 i ? i i i i i i i i JAM FEB MAR APR MAY JUNE JULY AUC SEP OCT NOV. DEC Fig. 26. — Energy consumed by a milking machine used with from one to seven cows. capper used a very small amount of current daily, which cost less than manual operation. Electrically heated steam or dry-air sterilizers have been used by Nebraska farmer-dairymen only experimentally. Other fuels have shown heating costs much lower than those of electric energy, and the investments for the electrically heated sterilizers are enough greater than for most of the </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 33 I I 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 \ S N —^ ,' A "• \ \ • /[ * r^ N&gt; / \ Zioo - \ / — ROLFSMEER DART \ / SCVMHO. MCBR. If LEGEND 40 - 1928 — — 1529 1930 oII'III I I I I 1 JAf * FEB. MAR. APRi MAY Jl»3I JUL? 3jO SEP. OCT. NOW — DEC Fig. 27. — Energy consumed by a milking machine operating extr \ long periods to obtain herd milk records. This caused high con - sumption while the fifty cows were being milked. other types that very few of even the better-equipped dairy - men heat water for washing and sterilizing with electrical energy. Refrigeration on dairy farms of less than twenty cows is very limited. Lack of premiums for milk of high quality, the necessity of meeting health regulations, and financial limita - tions have combined to hold this convenience beyond the res.eh of all but a few._ Milk cooling and the essentials of refrigei-a - tion are recognized as future necessities by most milk pro - ducers. A great amount of investigation has been and is nbw being done on milk and cream cooling on Nebraska farms. 16 It is probable that new methods, less elaborate equipment, apd better returns for quality will advance the use of electricity m milk-cooling gradually but decidedly. Ventilation fans m dairy barns have been tried with more or less negative results. Positive ventilation with a smjall amount of electrical energy was accomplished m each case but it has never been proved that such ventilation results m increased milk production, better animal health, or better f &lt;*ed economy. Figure 28 indicates the energy consumption of three "Nebr. Aar. Exp. St«. Bulletin 249. The Mechanical Dairy Cooler (19S0). and Bulletin 266, Cooling Milk on Nebraska Farms (1932). </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 34 2°° 1 I I I I I I I I I 1 \SO - I \ BOLFSMBER DWRY — O I \ *eWAM&gt; NCSR. 3 ! P\ \ LEGEND I . // N \a =r~!HS S.oo- // rf \ " . — "*T*"^-4 i i i i i i Y"*~---L_ JAN. FEB MAR. APR. MAY JUNE JULY AUG. SEP OCT NOME DEC. Fig. 28. — Energy consumed by a ventilating fan m a dairy barn. ceiling fans used by one dairyman. These fans were installed m the spring of 1929 m a barn housing approximately fifty cows. The owner was anxious to make high production rec - ords with some Jersey cows and felt he was amply repaid for cost of installation and operation of these fans. After the electric meters were removed (July, 1930) , these fans were used more m the winter when the cows were kept m the barn continuously several months. The purpose for which they were used, that of drying the floors and ceilings and remov - ing odors, was accomplished as far as the owner demanded. A few exhaust-type fans were found or installed for inter - mittent operation. Usually they are run for short periods ir - regularly both winter and summer. The general practice of leaving the dairy cows out m open sheds except at milking time seems prevalent m Nebraska and the future for ventilat - ing fans does not hold great promises of beneficial returns either for the user or distributor of electric energy. Several dairymen made use of a small green-feed chopper m the late summer and early fall before the silo was filled and after pastures began to dry up and the milk flow to de - crease. Usually these feed choppers were very meagerly equipped. The cutters were mostly of the old lawn-mower type with or without a moving feed roll, no elevator or blow - er, small 8- to 10-inch width of knives and throat, and ad - justments and gears not as well made as on the newer ma - chines (Figure 29). The average rate of cutting of unbound green corn fodder was approximately 1.5 tops per hour with the consumption of energy averaging 1.5 kilowatt-hours per ton cut (Vfc-inch lengths). The operation of these little cut - ters was inexpensive and, where some type of chore motor was available, the daily task of cutting this green corn fodder was a paying one. In the fall of the year when the weather was </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 35 wHt j ; •- 1 1 n»*fflS n Wu mm*B't^^M Hi iH! - Fig. 29. — The green feed chopper used on the George Welsh farm near Seward. extremely wet or extremely dry, the small amount of time and labor consumed m chopping the fodder was soon paid for by the fodder the livestock did not tramp m the mud or leave m the yard because the cows had mussed over it finding the ears. The consumption of electrical energy about the dairy farm, whether large or small, is distributed evenly over the different months of the year and the hours of the day m such manner that practically all the electrical distributing agencies m Ne - braska are glad to make extra effort to give that service. The uses to which the dairyman or even the farmer who milks several cows as a side line can put electrical equipment ire of such nature that benefits can be readily seen. ELECTRICALLY OPERATED IRRIGATION PUMPS As pump irrigation is practiced m Nebraska, about 3ix weeks usually cover the irrigation season and often crop or climatic conditions shorten or completely eliminate pumping altogether. Usually the well is far enough from the farm - stead so that extra service equipment and extra investment are required. The presence of the general-purpose trad;or on many farms has prevented extensive use of the electric motor. The conditions m the pump-irrigation districts, more - over, have not been conducive to electric rates that would induce the farmer to use electric energy for pumping. Suv - eral electrically operated irrigation pumping units have been observed which show energy requirements of 1.53 to 3 kilo - watt-hours per acre-foot per foot of lift with an averagel-e - -quirement of 2.3 kilowatt-hours per acre-foot-foot compared to about y% gallon of fuel per acre-foot-foot for internal- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 36 combustion engines. 17 Attendance m labor and time at the pump was less for the electrically operated pumps. Until the irrigators m these semi-arid districts use water on more diver - sified croppings and during more months of the year, this use of electricity will not become general. Conditions must develop that will make the service beneficial to both consumer and distributor. PROCESSING FEED BY ELECTRIC POWER Silo filling, fodder chopping and grinding, grain mixing and grinding, and hay chopping by the use of electric power have been discussed elsewhere and are still being studied. 18 For many years equipment requiring power has been gradually developed to be used with the general-purpose tractor. Where rates prohibited the use of all but the small motor (10 H. P. or under) , this tractor-driven equipment proved unwieldy or otherwise poorly adapted to the smaller, higher-speed electric units. While there is very little question about the value of chopping green fodder for silage, there is still doubt con - cerning the benefits derived from grinding all grains and feeds for all classes of poultry and livestock. Where sufficient quantities of ground feed are consumed to justify ownership of the electrically operated equipment, its convenience rather than total costs incident to grinding is often the factor causing installation. The cost of power at the rates common to Nebraska is more for electrical equip - ment than for the internal-combustion engine and, where the tractor is needed on the farm for other work, buying a motor for a small amount of grinding has not generally ap - pealed to the farmer. On farms where a great part of the grinding can be done m cold weather or when the tractor is busy at other jobs, electric motor equipment has often been bought for the sake of convenience. The total costs of grind - ing are nearly the same if a kilowatt-hour can be purchased at 5 cents and kerosene and gasoline at 15 and 20 cents re - spectively. ELECTRICALLY OPERATED POULTRY EQUIPMENT Less than eight per cent of the farmers with electrical serv - ice use lights m the laying houses to increase winter egg pro - duction. Incidentally, most of those so using electricity get the energy from the home light plant rather than the power line. In many states, because, like the dairy, the poultry plant has many uses for electrical energy, both the poultry - "Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bulletin 282, Pump Irrigation Investigations m Nebraska (1938). " Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Circular 42, The Use of a Small Electric Motor m Silo Filling (1930). </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 37 man and the power distributors have sought the connection tor this type of service. In Nebraska a few of the very largest poultry plants near the edge of some of the towns had power-line service prior to 1929. The data m Table 8 taken from the poultry farm of Laßue Brown, Arbor, Ne^ braska, (Fig. 30) probably indicate one of the reasons why the Nebraska poultry farmer has not used all apparatus operated electrically. In the part of the table identified as 1928 data, the "total operation cost" for the farm light plant represents costs of gasoline and oil and the total of labor and repairs. An dver - haul job is included. In the 1929 data, all repairs and labor are prorated each month and interest and depreciation are calculated. In the last column m each part of the table are shown comparative costs if the nearest service line had been extended and the farm rate applied. This company began serving Mr. Brown m 1930. As can be readily seen, this poultryman used more than an average of 60 kilowatt-hlours per month, but his plant costs showed his average cost per Table 8. — Comparative energy costs on a poultry farti Total energy (Total operation Calculated cost, llmo used, farm cost, farm power-company . light plant light plant rate 1928 DATA ,„„„„, Kw-hrt. Dollars Dollars y,f n y o 24 8.62 8..2 »z===z=z=±=z g its tn August 81 c 5, : Be September |i |"?i . S" ? October :::..:::::::::::::: is ?32 ?: g November 125 10.8 7 10. l 0 December 162 12 .44 J" 8 Year — repair and labor ...... 147.84 Total 770 236.12 sT (0 1929 DATA J, a " uar y IBS 18.86 11. 2 February _ 104 14 .87 9. 6 March _ 46 g.20 6. 6 April S3 69 3 • 8 , 18 M°y 21 8.14 6.18 J une 13 4.74 4. 4 J»'y ••• 12 4.82 4.16 *"««"'• 16 8.74 4.f8 September 31 9.39 5i16 October „ 65 13.52 7. 10 November „ „ 135 1 7 . 55 10 0 Dgcanb" 154 2^66 11. 6 Total 783 129.32 87.60 Interest at 6% on $468.25 27.49 Depreciation *4BB— tlßO S4 ' 2o 9 * ****'"* Total cost — fuel, oil, repairs, and fixed charges 191.01 87.(10 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 38 kilowatt-hour to be 16 to 30 cents while that on the power company rates was less than 11 cents. The data in Table 8 were obtained from the carefully kept records of the Browns and from meter and fuel records kept by representatives of the Agricultural College Engineering Department. In the case of the farm light plant, the capacity was limited and the load as required was not adjusted to use the greater part of the energy available except when lights were used for the layers. Since this farm has been connected to the central station lines, many more uses of electrical energy have been added about the home as well as the poultry plant, and the increase in consumption of energy on the same rate as indicated in Table 8 has lowered the average cost of the kilowatt-hour to approximately seven cents. Fig. 30. — Part of the 5,000-hen poultry plant of LaRue Brown at Arbor, Nebraska. Where electricity has been made available and the poultry - men have been properly informed, the use of artificial light for poultry has become a recognized practice. Where broilers and friers are being rushed for market, where late-maturing pullets are being grown to large size before being brought into laying, and where production of eggs or molting control of old hens is desired, the use of lights together with the proper feeding has brought beneficial results. Careless use of lights has often given doubtful results. Increased winter egg production by the use of electric lights in the laying house is a certainty but the beneficial returns for the year or a period of years depend on the wise judgment in feeding and other control measures. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 39 The use of hovers, brooder units, and battery brooders is becoming increasingly popular m the state as these pieces of equipment become more improved. The energy requirements for brooding chicks vary greatly because of the great differ - ences m brooder house construction and climatic and oper - ating conditions, as well as the differences m type and quality of the brooders. Averages, however, show a range of 0.5 to 2.0 kilowatt-hours per chick per season with an averagle of these averages of about 0.8 kilowatt-hour per chick raised. Turkey poults averaged 1.1 kilowatt-hours per poult per sea - son, consisting of about 35 to 50 days of brooding. Safety and convenience m brooding chicks electrically rather ihan comparative costs have been the factors contributing to the increasing use of the electric brooder. Electrical energy must cost three cents per kilowatt-hoi; r or less to compete m operation costs with either hard coal or kerosene as fuel. Alarms of various sorts on the electrically operated brooders relieve the operators of much tvorry and many unnecessary observation trips that usually come m the schedule with brooders using fuel for heat. A few of the poultrymen having large flocks are equipping their plants with electric incubators. These do a commercial business. Very little home incubation is practiced by the peo - ple having 500 or fewer hens. An average of 0.15 kilovatt - hour per egg hatched m small incubators and 0.035 kilowatt - hour per egg hatched m the improved large incubators are the energy requirements for incubation. Refrigeration on the Nebraska poultry farm has just begun to be looked upon as a necessity. Except on the very largest farms no attempt is made to refrigerate eggs and refrigera - tion of broilers and dressed poultry is confined to commercial cold storage. The laboratory and experimental work on best methods of cooling eggs right after they are laid has been m progress two years and it is hoped that eggs produced m Nebraska can be placed on the New York market m dom - petition with the best eggs from any part of the United Sti.tes. Small green-feed choppers, water warmers to keep ice out of the poultry drinking water, feed grinders and mixer 3 of small sizes, egg candlers, summer drinking fountains aid a small amount of lighting to prevent rickets combine -\yith lighting, brooding, and incubation to make the poultry firm a consumer of electric energy very welcome to distributors. Whether the electric load is large or small, it is evenly jdis - tributed over most of the months of the year and makesl no suddenly increased large demands for service. It will show the consumer the economy of its use m a short time. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 40 THE ELECTRIC HAY HOIST One hay hoist, rebuilt from an old one formerly used on a cable stacker and operated by an 8 H. P. gasoline engine, has been operated by a 3 H. P. chore motor each season since 1929. The barn on which it is used is 50 feet long and 24 feet to the gable. The controls of the hoist can be operated by the man on the hayrack or from the ground (Fig. 31). With a medium-sized double-harpoon fork and a sling on the floor of the hayrack Mr. Welsh, the owner, stores alfalfa in the haymow at the rate of approximately 1.5 tons in twelve minutes. The maximum demand on the motor for short in - tervals was 2J4 horsepower and average energy consumption was 0.28 kilowatt-hour per ton stored. About a minute elapses from the time the hoist starts until the fork is back ready to be forced into the load again. Formerly the hayfork for this barn was operated by man and team power. The work us - ually fell to one of the boys. It is needless to say this hoist, though much cruder than the late-model hoist built especially for electric operation, finds much favor with the boys. This same hoist has been used for digging pit silos and has proved very satisfactory. While the hay hoist on most Ne - braska farms is used but a very short season, there are many farms that could use this equipment to good advantage. In - stallation cost rather than operation costs of hoist and motor have been factors preventing its more general use. The low power demand (Fig. 32) and the convenience of this use of electrical energy will make it popular in the future. II B m\x\a\m \\__________w_____W' _ l_ ■ i 1 yf____r^^^^*Ty^ T "*- . v _' ff^'R^Kyr? 7,T&gt;«-£:.*'. 1 &amp; *~- - __\ &lt;_yf____a^^_t^'_\_^ B^^^^^rS^t^^^^^^^^^TmiZ B*HnFTT _B w______&amp; __WSr^^^^^ * $Xr W&amp;ri jjg -^~^■s* - r ~7----. _ "-- : 7 7L7 . —. ■^p? : -H7 ;: '' -:' ■ w_m il Fig. 31. — The rebuilt hay hoist ready for a test run. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 41 \\\\\\ \ \ \ \l j i \ \ \ \ \ \ yyu * tpip lopk I £ ORK HITS TRACK '? ►" 2006/1 — 5 --BUI LING r ORK )UT OH LOAD o I Ti~JC_-&gt;-/i V"T 1 f I.' I -] |i / 7 / / / ~f = ~-? = —7 = '"f~~~TX~' I- I MINUTE — -4 !■ I MINUTE ' 'I Fig. 32. — A reproduced record from the set-up shown m Figure S l. ELEVATING GRAIN BY ELECTRIC POWER Not over four per cent of the Nebraska farmers who have electric service have grain elevators, only three-fourths of one per cent of them operate these elevators with electric - motor power, and approximately two per cent expect to! use electric power m the future. The rest of the four per |cent expect to continue to operate their elevators by tractors, either engines or horse sweeps. Very few of the installations planned for electric-motor equipment. Even with these handi- Fig. 33. — A portable drag elevator. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 42 Fig. 34. — A back-saver. caps the use of electric energy for elevating grain is an im - portant one m this state. A large amount of grain is raised m the state annually and much of this grain m the eastern half of the state is stored for several months after harvest. Probably two or three times as many portable elevators similar to those shown m Figures 33 and 34 are to be found on Nebraska farms as inside cup elevators such as are in - stalled m buildings similar to the one shown m Figure 35. Usually these elevators are operated by a 2 or 3 H. P. motor. The motor housed m the box shown m Figure 33 is 2 H. P. With the elevator shown (the trough is 20 feet long and the changed to fit the M"^""jBSSBBBB^.. and unload a 40-bushel / . Ak load of ear corn m jf Ak eight minutes. A m _ T^ maximum of 1.5 kilo- M watts was required m *■ the operation and 2.5 j|| kilowatt-hours were j-M Bl^ . — - -— required to crib 1,000 'a : PmSlßßi it bushels. In Figure 34 fHSfr ■ are?^B| f affl" the motor is 2 H. P., gZ- • ¥Qr*^TnJi m. ,_rnf ~^ ' 1 the elevator 30 feet b^Bßßjaß|^^^bu^r~^-L~^^7 ; I long, and the corn is p^a^'^^SgS^^pS S^SjS!?^' 1 raised 18 feet high. A maximum of 1.3 Fig. 35. — Elevator building at Mr. Gade's. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 43 kilowatts to the motor was required m unloading a 50 - ---bushel load of ear corn at the rate of nine minutes to the l(fad. In 1927 this equipment elevated 3,500 bushels of ear corn at an average use of 3.7 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 bushels, while m 1928 a total of 2,500 bushels was placed m the crib with 9 kilowatt-hours or 3.6 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 bushels. This farmer said his cost of energy each year was less than the price of a good scoop shovel. The inside cup elevators (Fig. 35) had an average spjeed of about 200 feet per minute, would unload 50 bushels, of shelled grain m approximately three minutes, and required about 2.5 kilowatts to the motor and elevated the grain 40 feet with an average energy requirement of 3.0 kilowatt-hours per 1,000 bushels. A few farmers had tried using a fan j for elevating the shelled grain. This method used approximately three times the energy per 1,000 bushels as the cup elevators. The data obtained show that electrical requirements for elevating grain are not excessive and the operating costs save time, labor, and storage space, the value of which pays many times over for the electrical energy consumed. As m many other instances, investment costs have prevented the installa - tion of the electric motor to replace other power units which are considered utility equipment. Often these other units had been previously purchased as had pump jacks, grinders, etc., with speed adjustments, pulley arrangements, and hous - ing conditions that need changing when electric motors are installed. COLD STORAGE PROVIDED BY ELECTRICITY .... The popularity of mechanical refrigeration, electrically op - erated, has spread to the rural districts to a small extent. Inquiries concerning cold rooms suitable for this type of re - frigeration are received by the experiment stations, and a few general cold-storage compartments have been built and a few more are being planned. Farm cold rooms, except the very few that are used for milk only, have requirements extremely hard to meet with entire satisfaction to the farmer. Most commercial refrigeration equipment can be controlled as to temperature, air movement, and humidity to suit one product. On the farm, however, the one cold room is ex - pected to care for any and all products raised or used by the family. The quantities of any of these products are not stable nor are the combinations of different products found the same even during the same periods m different years. The cooling and storage processes are often attempted m the same room and products are stored together when the tem - peratures and humidities best suited to any one or two of </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 44 them are not the best for some of the others. Satisfactory cold storage of the various farm products is being studied intensively and will be reported upon in a later publication. Usually the use of mechanical cold storage equipment has called for better construction than is usually found on the farms, and the investment has been too high for any general acceptance. The cost of operation alone, however, could often be justified by the savings in products, time and labor to the family, and in convenience. HEATING WATER ELECTRICALLY Water heating in the farm homes has not gained any popu - larity for two reasons, the cost of installation and the high operating costs. The $50.00 to $125.00 required is very high in comparison to costs for installation of water-heating equip - ment with which the farmers are more familiar. Operation costs for domestic water heating are very high in comparison to costs of operating much other electrical equipment on the farm. When 175 to 400 kilowatt-hours are required (often more than all other uses combined) per family per month to operate the water heater, and these kilowatt-hours cost five to fifteen cents each, the operating costs come high. Equipment for heating water electrically for poultry inside a poultry house has been arranged very cheaply, and the means to prevent ice from forming in the drinking vessels have been inexpensive. The warming of water by electric, heat for livestock is still in the experimental stage as far as economic benefits are concerned. Investigations are still under way to determine the best methods of heating and develop less expensive heating controls and devices. HEATING SOIL Soil heating for hotbeds and soil sterilization are still in the experimental stage in Nebraska. Electrically heated hotbeds have been made very practical in many places in the neighbor - ing state of Missouri. CHORE MOTORS The use of a motor that can be easily transported from place to place about the farmstead to operate feed grinders, corn shelters, concrete mixers, grindstones or other shop tools, water pumps, hay hoists, or line shafts, has not been developed in Nebraska as fast as the utility of the machine seems to warrant. Grindstones and shop tools and even a small con - crete mixer usually require motors of fractional horsepower, while the other uses require one to five horsepower. Speed requirements change with each chore and the load on the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Use of Electricity on Nebraska Farms 45 motor usually is different for all jobs and hard to control on some. Often the chore motor is overloaded in feed grinding because of a variation in moisture content of the grain or because of a change in the fineness of grinding. The farmer is not always a mechanic nor does he always have the patience to study all the changes needed in moving a power unit from chore to chore. Most of the chore motors have overload pro - tection — thermal cut-outs — but need load-indicating instru - ments to aid the operator in determining operating loads, speeds, or other requirements. Too often the chore motor is assigned to one chore. ANIMAL clippers Only a few animal clippers operated by an electric motor have found their way to the Nebraska farms. One clipper was loaned to the rural electric project and was used very extensively on small dairies in three counties. Usually the needs of these clippers have been recognized more for show - ring preparation than for grooming the milk animals at milk - ing time or to prevent contamination of the milk. The clipper under observation was badly abused by the operators. Too often matted hair on the cow's flanks and hips clogged the cutter and caused breakage of the parts. The clipper, which could be borrowed and operated at small cost, was appreciated but there seemed little desire to own one of these appliances for the extra cost over the hand-operated groomers. miscellaneous uses Over 60 different uses for electricity were found on Ne - braska farms ; 40 of these uses are fairly common and can be found in a canvass of the homes located on but a few miles of any rural service line or of several homes having farm light plants. In a few homes as many as 20 different uses of elec- Table 9. — Percentages of farms using various electrical equip - ment, based on surveys of 780 farms in five different counties, including both owners and non-owners Per cent fer cent 1. Iron 85.0 16. Battery charger 8.46 2. Washing machine fcl.S 17. Hot pad 7.44 8. Radio, all-electric 60.6 18. Grill 7.06 4. Water pump.. 81.8 19. Milking machine... 5.64 5. Toaster 29.7 20. Waffle iron 4.23 6. Vacuum cleaner 27.3 21. Water heater 3.46 7. Cream separator 19.5 22. Feed grinder 2.95 8. Radio (using battery of home 23. Food mixer _ 2.82 plant).... 18.3 24. Brooder 2.05 9. Refrigerator 15.9 26. Clipper 1.80 10. Percolator 18.6 26. Incubator 1.41 11. Fan 12.4 27. Irrigation pump 1.15 12. Sewing machine. 12.8 28. Ironing machine... 1.16 18. Hair curler 11.9 29. Hair dryer 0.90 14. Stock well pump 8.84 30. Grain elevator 0.77 IB. Stove 8.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 289 46 tricity have been found. In many of these places the vacuum cleaner, the curler, hair dryer, toaster, grill, waffle iron, hot pad, fan, heater, food mixer, and many similar appliances have been purchased as gifts for individual members of the family and are used in bettering the home conditiops at small operating costs. CONDITIONS THAT INFLUENCE THE USE OF ELECTRICITY ON FARMS The farmers of this state belong to one class as regards their attitude toward the use of electricity or electrical en - ergy. All desire and expect to make use of this source of light and power when and if they can afford the service. The amount and type of usage of electrical energy, when made available, varies about as much within a small district as between different sections of the state. Neither does the length of service govern the usage in a major fashion. Those who have had electric service for several years (either from power line or home plant) may or may not use the service to the greatest extent or to the best advantage either for con - venience or as a time- and labor-saving servant. The length of time a distributor has been serving different sections of the rural districts has not had the influence expected. Most of the distributing agencies have in recent years looked upon the rural electric service with more favor and have increased in - vestments to serve and lowered rates for service in general over the state. There is a better understanding of the problems confront - ing each as the consumer and distributor have tried to make contracts beneficial to both. There is a definite realization that changes must come in the financial conditions of the farmer, in the investment costs for wiring and equipment used by the consumer, in the investment costs to the distrib - utor, and in the total consumption of electrical energy in the large part of the state in which it will always be impossible to get two farm connections per mile of pole line. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Use op Electricity on Nebraska Farms 47 APPENDIX The rural electric project has had no spectacular growth nor has it assumed any demonstrative phases. All of the municipalities, power companies, and other distributing agencies in Nebraska, all the farmers who could be visited, and many out-of-state manufacturers have con - tributed to the data from which the information contained in this publi - cation was selected and averaged. A list of those manufacturers who made loans of equipment to ad - vance the studies is as follows: American Ironing Machine Company; Century Electric Company; Chicago Flexible Shaft Company; Crane &amp; Company; Cushman Motor Works; Delco Light Companv; John Deere _ Company; Duncan Electric Manufacturing Company; Easy Manufac - turing Company; Edison Electric Appliance Company: Electric House - hold Utilities Company; Federal Electric Company; Fairbanks, Morse &amp; Company; Frigidaire Corporation; General Electric Company; Goulds Pumps, Inc.; Hurley Machine Company; Hoosier Pump Company; Hud - son Pump Company; Kelvinator Corporation; Lauson Pump Company; Perfection Manufacturing Company; Landers, Frary &amp; Clark Company; Letz Manufacturing Company; Manning-Bowman &amp; Company; Malleable Iron Range Company; Papec Machine Company; Prater Hammer Mill Company; Rowell Hammer Mill Company; Wagner Electric Company; Westinghouse Electric &amp; Manufacturing Company; Frank E. Wolcott Manufacturing Company. tlOM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>