<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR FEBRUARY 1, 1910</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to tdi Governor Febbuabt 1. 1910 LINCOLN. NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">III The University op Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station- To His Excellency, Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor of -V&lt; bra Sir — In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the general assembly of the State of Nel&gt; - approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Twenty-third Annual Report of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State op Nebraska, Executive Department, Lincoln, February 1, 1910. Mr. E. A. Burnett, Director Xebrasla Agricultural Experiment Station : Sir — I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Twenty-third Annual Report of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor. E. A. Burnett, February 1, 1910. Director. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">IV THE GOVERNING BOARD. (tmc hiiinti op tnc umvtraiTT.) HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln.. .Term expires HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City Term expires 1912 HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha Term expires 1912 HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete Term expires 1914 HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin Term expires 1914 HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. . . Term expires 1916 SAMUEL AVERY, Chancellor. J. S. DALES, Finayicial Secretary.* THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE CHARLES S. ALLEN SAMUEL AVERY E. A. BURNETT THE STATION OFFICERS. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. W. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. J. ALWAY, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Agronomy and Farm Management. H. R. Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry. Erwin H. B arbour, Ph. D., Geology. G. R. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture. O. V. P. STOUT, C. E., Irrigation Etigineering. G. A. Loveland, B. Sc, LL. B., Meteorology. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Nortli Platle. Miss Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. G. Herbert Coons, A. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. R. S. Trumbull, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Cliemistry. P. B. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy {Soils). T. A. Kiesselbach, B. Sc, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). L. B.' Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. R. F. Howard, B. Sc, in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in Soils and Crops, North Platte. Erwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Crops and Horticulture, North Platte. S. W. PERIN, Farm Superintendent. tMiss Louise M. Allen, A. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing. •By an act of the legislature of the State of Nebraska approved and in effect February IS. 1890. tbe State Treasurer became ex offlcio custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July l, 1899. ♦Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">T..ETTER OF TRANSMITTAL, ill Governor's Certificate iii The Official Uoster of the Station iv Director's Review Exj&gt;erimental Work HI Plant Diseases v iii Soil Investigation viii Strength of Bone viii Tuberculosis Investigation ix Swamp Fever i.x Cereal Crops ix Winterkilling Investigation x Heredity Investigations x Hog Cholera x Cattle Feeding Winter Wheat Investigation xii Potato Investigations xiii Orchard Management Demonstrations Insect Pests xiii Cooperative Experiments xiii The North Platte Substation xitr Spring Wheat . . tn Barley xv Oats xv Forage Live Stock Experiments Cattle xvi Horses . . Hogs XTifi Horticulture \viii Forestry x ix Station Staff xix Improvements xx Farmers' Institutes xx Organized Agriculture xxi Publications </seg>
            <seg id="p006">New Experimental Substations xxii House Roll No. 114 xxii House Roll No. 18 Acknowledgments xxviii Financial Statements Hatch Fund xxix Adams Fund xxx Supplementary Funds Appropriations by the State — Substation (North PI atte) xxxii Farmers' Institutes xxxii APPENDIX (For Table of Contents of Appendix, see page 1. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p007">VII TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL REPORT EXPERIMENTAL WORK Phe work of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station for current year has been as follows : The Station is established to conduet investigations for the dis - covery of scientific principles which bear upon farm pra T'nder the law, a portion of the work of the Station must be con - fined wholly to original investigation of a strictly scientific character which is in some way related to the improvement of agricultural practice. The Adams fund appropriated by the Federal Govern - ment is limited to these lines of investigation and cannot be used for popular demonstration purposes or for general administration of Station affairs. The Federal appropriations known as Hatch appropriations and all State appropriations for experimental work are available for less technical lines of investigation, which may include a study of the adaptation of scientific principles already worked out to the practical needs of the farmer and the demonstration of some of these principles as proof that they can be used to improve general farm practice. The work of the Experiment Station has grown so much in re - cent years and the outside demand for information on farm prob - lems has been so great that many lines of investigation have been attempted without sufficient appropriation available to prosecute these investigations vigorously, and no rapid progress can be made in some of these lines without an increase in the State appropria - tion available for the central Station. The lines of investigation now in progress would be much facilitated and many new lines of work demanded by the people might be undertaken if the State would make a specific appropriation from the general fund to pro - mote the work of the central experimental plant or would appro - priate a sufficient amount of money to the University for general </seg>
            <seg id="p008">VIII Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska rsultural work so that more funds might become available from source. R lines of investigation carried on under the Adams fund are ily outlined for the Office of Experiment Stations in the States Department of Agriculture and are approved by that office before investigations in these lines can proceed. At the present time these lines of investigation are as follows: Plant Diseases. — Under plant diseases the dry rot of potatoes, scab of potatoes, alfalfa crown disease, the plum canker, and cedar rust are being studied to determine what method of treatment will be successful in exterminating or controlling these diseases. Soil Investigation. — In the investigation of soils the composi - tion and origin of humus and methods of determining humus are being studied, together with the characteristics of the soils of the transition region or the loess area in Nebraska which covers a large proportion of the southeast, central, and southwestern portions of the state. In the composition of soils extensive work has been done to determine the effect of cultivation and cropping upon the Ioe3s soils of different sections of Nebraska. In this study it has been found that all the loess soils under consideration are well supplied with potash, phosphoric acid, and lime, the losses of these constit - uents caused by thirty or forty years' cropping being too small to be detected by chemical analysis. The content of nitrogen, of vegetable matter, and of humus is high in the virgin soils but has fallen very rapidly under cultivation, the greatest Iosse3 being found where the surface has been washed or blown away. The destructive action of wind and water, however, does not extend to the mineral constituents and for this reason the restoration of the fertility of farms the soil of which has been impoverished should be an inexpensive matter where clover and alfalfa are used in a rotation to build up the humus and nitrogen in the surface soil. A full report of this investigation may be found in Bulletin 111, recently published. Strength op Bone.- — The work of investigation to determine the effect of food on the strength of bone reported in Bulletin 107 has been continued in two subsequent experiments. In the experi- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Txctnty -third Annual A IX fects on the strength of bone in growing pigs of various supple - mentary feeds. Tankage, 3odium phosphate, lime water, bone-meal, as supplementary feeds to corn, are compared with corn alone, all lots receiving 10 per cent of ground alfalfa in order to furnish some variety to the feed. The experiment is not yet completed. Tuberculosis Investigation. — The investigation of the preva - lence of tuberculosis in hogs and the method of their infection is being studied in cooperation with the Bureau of Animal Industry. Examination of the fecal matter from cows has shown the pre - of virulent germs of tuberculosis, which readily becomes a means of infecting hogs following these tuberculous cattle. A prelimi - nary report on this subject was contained in the Twenty-second Annual Report and a further discussion will occur in the appendix of this Report. PIwamp Fever. — A disease known as "swamp fever" has been valent in the central northern portion of the State for the piist three or four years and efforts have been made to determine the cause and treatment for the disease. We have found that it is pos - sible to transmit this disease from a diseased to a healthy horse by blood inoculation in the infected districts. A solution of this prob - lem would be worth many thousand dollars to the infected areas, and it is believed that some solution can be reached and a remedy applied by a continuation of the investigation. Cereal Crops. — A study of the water requirements of grow in? corn has been carried on for several years to determine the relation between leaf area and water requirements, with an idea of securing a type of corn giving the largest yield per acre for a given use of water. When once this question has been thoroly worked out, it will be of great importance to those sections of the country which are likely to be visited by periodic drouths before the maturing of the crop. k Investigation of the effect of competition in cereal crops has also en carried on for a number of years with corn, and the evidence ;ms to indicate that where corn is grown at the rate of three or more stalks per hill the good ears which develop under this compe - tition produce larger yields per acre in subsequent years than even better ears may produce when selected from fields where only one </seg>
            <seg id="p010">X or two stalks per hill have been used and where there was little or no competition in the production of perfect ears. The effect of inbreeding and crossbreeding corn is also being studied to determine how much inbreeding is necessary to fix the type of corn and to what extent crossing is permissible in securing a maximum yield of corn. Winterkilling Investigation. — Investigations are in progress to determine the effect of different moisture content in the soil and of different degrees of cold upon winterkilling of raspberries, ap - ples and peaches. These temperatures are produced largely by artificial means. Heredity Investigations. — In heredity studies considerable work has been done to determine (1) whether Mendel's principles of heredity apply to the inheritance of fluctuating variations as well as to discontinuous variations and (2) whether it is possible to "fix" true "intermediates" in case of hybrids, and, if so, how this may be done. Crosses have been made between many of the races of the following plants: beans, corn, petunias, gourds, nas - turtiums, sweet peas, snap dragons, phlox, verbena, balsam, and geraniums. A discussion of the inheritance of color in seeds oc - curs in the Twenty-second Annual Report. If the law governing variation in plants can be worked out, it will be of great impor - tance in determining the methods which will be used in the im - provement of varieties for economic purposes. Lines of investigation pursued under the Hatch or State appro - priations are as follows: Hog Cholera. — The immunization of hogs against cholera has became a matter of great economic importance to the farmer. The work of the Bureau of Animal Industry of the United States De - partment of Agriculture and the work of this Station have proven, after many years of labor, that a blood serum may be produced from hyperimmunized hogs which, when injected into healthy hogs, will protect them against cholera for a limited time and has a con - siderable degree of protection to hogs which have been infected with cholera but have not yet sickened with the disease. Our Ex - periment Station recommends the use of this serum in all herds </seg>
            <seg id="p011">XI possibly be subject to infection with cholera on account of its pres - ence on adjoining farms. By the systematic use of this serum it is thought that cholera can be entirely stamped out. The last Legislature appropriated $5,000 to be used by th&lt;&gt; K\ periment Station for the production of hog cholera serum to be available to the farmers of the State thru the deputies of tho State Veterinarian who are located in different sections of th»&gt; State. A report on the means by which this serum can be secured is found in Press Bulletin 31, recently issued. The production of this serum has proved to be so expensive and so slow a process that the $5,000 above mentioned is entirely ina&lt;li - quate to produce the serum called for by the hog raisers of the State, and it is apparent that an extensive plant with a laboratory, adequate housing, and sufficient land to carry 200 or 300 hap must be available if this Station is to furnish the serum which will be demanded in stamping out the outbreaks of hog cholera in the State. Such an investment of State funds would probably save a million dollars annually to the State when once the system was thoroly enough established to furnish an unlimited amount of serum and sufficient service of veterinarians to vaccinate all the hogs in a locality whenever an outbreak occurred. Since it is possible to produce this serum and keep it for some time in storage, it would seem as tho a plant might be established which would ab - solutely control the hog cholera situation in the State if suft: money was available and the farmers would be prompt in notifying the State Veterinarian of cholera outbreaks. Cattle Feeding. — The Station is continuing its investigation to determine the most economical proportion between corn and alfal - fa for fattening cattle, using heavy, medium, and light rations of corn for this purpose. A bulletin upon this subject will soon be issued. The feeding experiments conducted for a number of years have proved the efficiency of alfalfa hay as roughage when fed with corn, and also that corn-stover is a very profitable feed to use as half the roughness in connection with alfalfa hay. The utilization of corn-stover in this way where cattle feeding is practiced will add about 25 per cent to the value of the corn crop in comparison </seg>
            <seg id="p012">XII with utilizing only the grain produced. The very high price of hay at this time is due to the fact that little attention is given to preserving the roughage grown in our cornfields, and the evidence is conclusive that upon our high-priced land we must utilize the fodder by harvesting and feeding the corn either without husking or by the use of improved husking machinery which makes the stover available in the best possible form. The Experiment Station for several years has used a silo in feeding both beef and dairy cattle, altho it has reported no tech - nical experiments. The evidence all points to the fact that in no way can the corn crop be made to produce as much feed per MM as thru the silo where a herd is kept large enough to consume the silage from a medium-sized silo of 14 or 16 feet in diameter by 30 feet in height. Where a herd of dairy cattle is kept, the profits will be even greater than with beef cattle. The introduction of the silo will practically double the number of cattle which may be kept upon any farm if silage is used for both summer and winter feed- Winteb Wheat Investigation. — For many years this Station has endeavored to extend the area of winter wheat production anJ increase the yield per acre by the selection of suitable varieties and by the improvement of methods. The improvement of Turkey Red wheat by the selection of indi - vidual plants which show desirable characters and high yield - ing power has been carried on for the past seven years. The most desirable plants have been retained and in - creased from year to year until a number of such selected strains are now available in considerable quantities and within a year or two will be ready for distribution among farmers who can give them special care and attention. An effort has been made, thru crossbreeding other varieties with the Turkey Red wheat, to secure a smooth-headed variety with a hard berry. Two or three promising strains of thi3 character are being developed, but their yielding power has not yet been tested. Variety tests of oats have shown that the early varieties are superior to the later varieties in yield and in escaping possibility of drouth during the ripening period. Selection is being carried </seg>
            <seg id="p013">XIII on with Kherson oats to improve the character of the grain. Bulle - tin 113, in press, gives a report of the experimental work on this subject. Potato Investigations. — Investigations have been carried on to determine the best varieties of potatoes, and the relative value of seed from different regions. Up to the present time, local-grown potatoes which were grown under a straw mulch have given the best results where all seed was kept under the same conditions thru the winter in order that one variety might not be favored by better winter conditions than those afforded to other varieties in the test. Under this condition the results were as follows : Local seed grown under a mulch from two to four years gave the largest yield, fol - lowed by North Dakota and Minnesota seed, and then by South Dakota, home-grown cultivated, Hemingford, Nebr., Greeley, Colo., and Callahan, Colo., in the order named. Orchard Management Demonstrations. — Spraying demonstra - tions carried on for the last three years have shown that profitable crops can be grown where proper care is given to the trees and care - ful spraying methods are followed, and that without such methods there is little or no profit in growing orchard fruits. Insect Pests. — The life history of a number of insect pests has been studied in detail within the past year and methods for pre - venting their depredations have been offered where possible. This investigation has included work upon the seed wheat Eleodes, the parasites of the White-marked Tussock Moth, the melon aphis, th&gt;&gt; squash borer, cucumber beetle, and squash bug, the Pine-tip Moth, the Corn-ear Worm, Potato Stalk borer and Strawberry Leaf-roller. COOPERATIVE EXPERIMENTS Cooperative demonstrations in spraying apple orchards are car - ried on with a number of farmers in the State to prove the advan - tage of spraying commercial orchards as a business proposition. Each demonstration, where carefully carried out, in the past has furnished convincing proof on this point. About 40 farmers are cooperating with the Station in testing a large number of local varieties of corn to determine what varieties are best adapted to the several localities. A few farmers are test- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">XIV ing winter barley, which has not proved hardy except in the south - eastern portion of the State. A line of cooperative experiments will be carried on with farmers in certain sections of the State to determine the advisability of using sweet clover as a green manure crop and as a crop for preparing the ground for alfalfa. E umber of farmers will cooperate with the Station to test the of commercial fertilizers on various soils in different sections State. r^he Station is cooperating with the Bureau of Plant Industry the United States Department of Agriculture in the breeding and selection of improved varieties of winter wheat and in testing the milling and baking qualities of the same, in an effort to secure an improved strain of Turkey Red wheat of superior yielding and milling qualities. Beed Laboratory is maintained in cooperation with the Bureau ot Industry, U. S. Department of Agriculture, to determine id of adulterants and impurities and the percentage of ger - on of seed sold upon the market. At the North Platte Station we are cooperating with the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture, to test different rotations and methods of tillage, to study alkali re - sistant crops, and in growing forest trees. THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION Eestigation at the North Platte Station is carried on to deter - the best varieties of winter and spring grains, the best forafa , the best methods of tillage, and rotations for crop produc- I'e have demonstrated that winter wheat can be grown with it on the hard table-lands in this region by a period of summer jw preceding the time of sowing grain. The yields per acre the past four years on summer tilled land have been as follows : 5, 42 bushels per acre; 1907, 59 bushels per acre; 1908, 50 to 67 bushels per acre; 1909, an average of 40 bushels per acre on a 15-acre tract. Wheat on adjoining fields not summer tilled pro - duced in the same years 20 to 24 bushels per acre, with a yield in </seg>
            <seg id="p015">XV rainfall. Experiments to determine the time of seeding have in - dicated in general that winter wheat sown about the middle of September gave higher yields than that sown at later dates, altho the late seeding of 1908 harvested in 1909 gave a little higher yield than the earlier sown grain. This was probably due to the that a 3-ineh rain occurred very shortly after the late sown wheat was planted in that year. The two leading varieties of winter wheat have been the Kharkov, introduced thru the United states Department of Agriculture, and the Turkey Red, a standard vari - ety long in use in this State. Spring Wheat. — Several years' test with sprim: wheat has shown the durum wheats to be very much superior to the varieties in common use in this region, and durum wheat is now largely used for spring sowing. The different varieties of durum wheat in 1908 produced from 26.5 to 33.6 bushels per acre, where the average for the three previous years had been about 28 bushels per acre. Some farmers discriminate against growing durum wheat because it does not sell at as high a price on the market as winter and local spring wheats. The Station has proven by experi - ments that durum wheats are worth at least as much as corn, pound for pound, in feeding hogs, and that, at current prices of corn, durum wheat can profitably be fed to hogs in the production of pork. Barley. — The yields of barley for the year 1909 were small, pro - ducing on an average about 20 bushels per acre. This low yield was partly due to the blowing of the soil and injuring the grain after sowing, which caused a very poor stand. Common barley pro - duced 21.4 bushels per acre, which was a larger yield than that given by any of the other varieties. E:. — Of the twelve varieties sown, the Kherson oat produced hels per acre, the Burt oat S8 bushels, the Texas K ;, the Black American 37 bushels, the Sixty Day on' bushels, and other varieties made lower yields. In every instam-e the early varieties were superior to the late varieties. Forage. — Among the annual forage crops, sorghum, or cane, has given the most satisfactory results at this Station for hay. We </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska XVI have never failed to secure large yields per acre of forage upon land which was under thoro cultivation, and have been very suc - cessful in raising sorghum for hay by breaking sod land in May and sowing to cane with a press drill after thoroly working the sod with a disk harrow. Upon other land we have sometimes produced eight tons of forage per acre, tho five or six tons is an average crop. Alfalfa has produced about four to five tons of hay per acre on the bench land where it has not been pastured, and upon land which has been pastured with eight or ten hogs per acre as much as three tons per acre of alfalfa hay has been produced. Alfalfa can be grown in all of the valleys in Western Nebraska and will probably prove the most profitable crop which can be grown upon iaese lands. Upon the high table-lands it will produce from one to two tons of hay per acre in the region of the North Platte Station after it is thoroly established, depending much on the timely rain - fall, but even one ton per acre where hay is worth from $6 to $8 per ton makes a valuable crop and in any normal year a ton and a half to two tons per acre may be grown. Abun - dant alfalfa may be grown on the table for pasturing hogs, provided the land is not overpastured. The value of alfalfa in wintering cattle, horses, and hogs has been shown to be superior to prairie hay or to sorghum hay. It has, however, been shown that where a sufficient amount of alfalfa is not available to use exclusively for roughness it should be fed with about an equal amount of either prairie hay, cane, or wheat straw, or any of the common rough feeds available in the country, both feeds being available all the time so that the animal may choose between them. Animals thus fed will do almost as well as upon alfalfa hay ex - clusively and can be wintered more cheaply in this way. LIVE STOCK EXPERIMENTS Cattle. — Experiments are in progress to determine the relative value of different kinds of roughness in wintering cattle. This ex - periment is largely a duplication of the one reported in Bulletin 105. One hundred and eight head of steers were selected as calves in 1907 and divided evenly into six lots, to test the following ra- </seg>
            <seg id="p017">XVII tions, namely: alfalfa and prairie hay, alfalfa and cane, prairie hay and cane. These steers are being kept for the third winter upon the same rations. During the summer they all run together upon a good native canyon pasture consisting largely of buffalo, grama, and wheat grasses. It is proposed to determine the cumu- K effect of three winters' feeding upon the different rations put these cattle upon the market in the fall of 1910 as three - d steers. On November 1, 1909, these lots averaged as fol- lows: Kt 6, fed prairie hay and cane in winter 973 pounds experiment it has been found that the steers going upon grass in the thinnest condition in the spring make the largest sum - mer gains, but these are not sufficient to overcome the losses in winter, so that all lots receiving alfalfa hay in winter were heavier at the time they went into the feed lots in November, 1909, than the lots which had received no alfalfa hay. Horses. — A similar experiment, to test the efficiency of different Eof rations for wintering horses, has been carried on. Thirty ing colts and mules were selected in 1907 and divided into lots as evenly as possible with eight colts and two mules in lot. When these colts came from the pastures November 1, as two-year-old colts, they weighed as follows: Piot 1, alfalfa hay in winter and alfalfa pasture, 1162 pounds rage. Lot 2, alfalfa hay in winter and native pasture, 1063 pounds Lot 3, native hay in winter, native pasture, 1026 pounds average. rng the two years these colts have been on experiment, Lot 1 has gained 574 pounds average. Lot 2 has gained 476 pounds average. Lot 3 has gained 409 pounds average. 2 Lot 1, fed alfalfa in winter 1022 pounds Lot 2, fed prairie hay in winter 930 pounds Lot 3, fed cane in winter 985 pounds Lot 4, fed alfalfa and prairie hay in winter .1057 pounds Lot 5, fed alfalfa and cane in winter 1009 pounds </seg>
            <seg id="p018">XVIII All colts were fed four pounds of grain per day during the first winter, and Lot 3, upon prairie pasture and prairie hay, was fed some grain in winter as yearlings. These colts will be kept until they are four years old to determine whether or not those receiving alfalfa are heavier than those not receiving alfalfa when in the same condition of flesh. Pkjs.— Extensive experiments have been carried on to deter - the methods of feeding hogs which will prove most profitable he farmer in western Nebraska. One chief line of investiga - during the present season is to determine the most profitable method of feeding alfalfa to hogs during the fattening period. Alfalfa meal is being fed in comparison with alfalfa hay, both cut and fed in racks without cutting. Different proportions of corn and alfalfa are being used to determine what is the most profitable ratio between the corn and alfalfa. In both cut and ground alfalfa we are feeding 10 per cent alfalfa and 90 per cent corn, 25 per cent alfalfa and 75 per cent corn, 50 per cent alfalfa and 50 per cent corn, during the winter season. It is probable that in fatten - ing hogs somewhere between 10 and 25 per cent of chopped or ground alfalfa fed with corn will be more profitable than a larger proportion; while in feeding brood sows, as much as 50 per cent alfalfa can be used to advantage and possibly even a larger amount where the alfalfa is of extremely high quality. In pasturing alfalfa in summer, brood sows upon weaning their litters have been found to make gains of about one-half pound per day with no grain, while it has been found more profitable to feed young pigs after weaning time a medium grain ration thruout the summer season rather than ask them to live upon alfalfa pasture alone, since the young pig finds it impossible to eat and to digest enough alfalfa to make reasonable growth. A bulletin covering three years' work on this subject will soon be ready for distribu- Horticulture. — Apple, plum, and cherry trees planted during the past season are making satisfactory growth, and an orchard three years old is showing splendid growth and a thrifty, vigorous </seg>
            <seg id="p019">XIX ranting 200 apple, cherry, and plum trees on the table-land, which 225 or 250 feet above water, with an elevation of 3,000 feet, eral kinds of shrubs and ornamental trees have been planted to determine what shrubs can be grown successfully by the farmer to beautify his home. Some of the hardy perennial flowering plants are also being tested. Peonies, phlox, and roses promise to give very satisfactory results, while spireas and syringas, tar - tarean and orange honeysuckles, lilac and snowballs and a much more extended list seem to be reasonably hardy. It is proposed to extend this work considerably in the future. Ksstry. — The area being planted to forest trees in cooperation he United States Forest Service consists of ten acres of land and about fifteen acres of high table-land and canyon land. The canyon land will be largely increased in the future. The PI of conifers on the sides of canyons with north, east, and st slopes has been very successful up to the present time, outlook is very encouraging. It is necessary only to plant nifers and to protect them against live stock and fire. The in planting conifers upon level cultivated land has not thus i satisfactory but we hope for better results in the future. The deciduous trees which have been planted have been very successful. Cottonwoods are being grown upon the bench land. Some of these trees three yeare from planting are 12 and 15 feet high. Black locust and honey locust are extremely vigorous and hardy, and catalpas, elm, green ash, golden willow, and many other sorts are growing successfully. On the high table-land the planting has been limited to black and honey locust, catalpa, green ash, white elm, with a few other varieties. A detailed report upon this planting will be made thru bulletins at a later date. STATION STAFF Within the past year the following changes in the Station staff have taken place: Bthe resignation of Dr. A. T. Peters the Station has lost one oldest and most efficient workers, Dr. Peters having been en - in Station work in Nebraska for the past sixteen years. Dr. J. H. Gain, for some years associated with Dr. Peters in </seg>
            <seg id="p020">XX Animal Pathology, has been placed in charge of the Department as Animal Pathologist. Mr. Alvin Keyser, of the Department of Soils, resigned in April, 1909, and his Department was reorganized and Mr. C. W. Pugsley was transferred from the Department of Animal Husbandry and placed in charge of the Department of Agronomy and Farm Man - agement, carrying the investigation in farm management, crop rotations, and commercial fertilizers. I The Department of Field Crops was reorganized as a Department Experimental Agronomy, remaining in charge of Mr. E. G. ontgomery. Mr. E. M. Little resigned as Assistant in Dairy Husbandry March 1, 1909. I Mr. T. A. Kiesselbach was appointed Assistant in Agronomy Jrops). I Mr. Erwin Hopt was appointed Assistant in Crops and Horti - lture, Substation, North Platte, June, 1909. Mr. G. Herbert Coons was appointed Assistant in Agricultural Botany November, 1909. IMPROVEMENTS Since the last Report, a standpipe has been erected at the Uni - versity Farm and a complete pumping plant installed, at a cost of $6,000. tA greenhouse and potting sheds have also been erected for the use the Landscape Gardener, at a cost of $3,000. Four acres of land has been added to the University farm for general administrative purposes, at a cost of $3,750. None of these improvements deal directly with experimental FARMERS 1 INSTITUTES Several members of the Experiment Station staff have assisted in Farmers' Institutes during the year. One hundred and fifty Institutes were held during the season of 1908-1909, and 154 In - stitutes, 38 Boys' and Girls' Contests, and 6 Farmers' Institute Schools are scheduled for the year 1909-1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">XXI The demand for both Farmers' Institutes and Farmers' Insti - tute Schools exceeds the ability of the University to furnish such Institutes by at least 25 per cent for the regular Institutes and 100 per cent for the Farmers' Institute Schools. Since it costs at least five times as much to hold a Farmers' Institute School as to hold a regular Farmers' Institute, it does not seem good poli&lt; the part of the University to increase the Institute Schools beyond the number now held until sufficient money is available so that this can be done without cutting down the regular one- and two-day Etitutes. It is to be hoped that the funds available for this work i be increased. ORGANIZED AGRICULTURE The various agricultural societies meet at the University year, under the name of "Organized Agriculture," the following societies participating: Association of Agricultural Students, the State Board of Agriculture, the State Horticultural Society, the Nebraska Dairymen's Association, the State Corn Improvers' As - sociation, the State Home Economics Association, the Improved Live Stock Breeders' Association (which this year for the first time included a Special Horse Session), with sessions for the Aber - deen-Angus Breeders', the State Swine Breeders', the Red Polled Breeders', the Sheep Breeders', and the Shorthorn Breeders' Asso - ciations. The Farmers' Institute Conference for delegates from the various local societies met with Organized Agriculture. A Good Roads Meeting was held in the City in connection with Organi/fl Agriculture. PUBLICATIONS Bulletins giving the results of investigation in the Experiment Station are published in editions of 20,000 to 25,000 each, e\ where limited editions are published upon some technical subject. These bulletins are distributed free of charge to any resident of the State making application. There is at the present time a regular mailing list within the State of 15,000 names. These are continu - ally being added to, and it is desired that all farmers who are Kted in the publications of the Station should ask to be placed regular mailing list. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">XXII The publications of the Station since those named in the last Annual Report are as follows : Twenty-second Annual Report. Presented to the Governor Feb - ruary 1, 1909. 5,000 copies. Elulletin No. 110 (Vol. XXI, Art. IV). Report of the Nebraska d Laboratory. By E. Mead "Wilcox and Miss Nelle Stevenson, tributed June 25, 1909. 22,000 copies. Bulletin No. Ill (Vol. XXII, Art. I). Changes in the Compo - sition of the Loess Soils of Nebraska Caused by Cultivation. By F. J. Alway. Distributed December 15, 1909. 25,000 copies. Bulletin Xo. 112 (Vol. XXII, Art. II). Experiments with Corn. By E. G. Montgomery. Distributed December 15, 1909. 25,000 Bulletin No. 113 (Vol. XXII, Art. III). Oats. By E. G. Mont - gomery. (In press.) 25,000 copies. Press Bulletin No. 30. Rolling Winter Wheat. By E. G. Mont - gomery. Distributed April 3, 1909. 25,000 copies. Press Bulletin No. 31. Production of Hog Cholera Serum. By J. H. Gain. Distributed December 15, 1909. 21,000 copies. NEW EXPERIMENTAL SUBSTATIONS Ee Legislature of 1909 passed two bills for the establishment (W experimental substations, as follows: AN ACT to establish an experimental station north of the sixth standard parallel and west of the second guide meridian in the State of Nebraska, including the counties of Sioux, Dawes, Box Butte, Sheridan, Cherry, Keya Paha, Brown and Rock, fixing the control and management of the same and making an appropria - tion therefor. Be it Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska Section 1. That for the furtherance and promotion of agricul - tural, horticultural, forestry and live stock interests of this State, an experimental sub-station shall be established north of the sixth House Roll No. 114 (Introduced by Mr. Carr.) </seg>
            <seg id="p023">XXIII standard parallel and west of the second guide meridian in the State of Nebraska, including the counties of Sioux, Dawes, Box Butte, Sheridan, Cherry, Keya Paha, Brown and Rock, which sta - tion shall be under the control and management of the board of re - gents of the state university. Section 2. The board of regents are hereby authorized and em - powered to select the necessary lands, not less than one section and purchase the same and to make all necessary improvements in the way of buildings, fences, etc., and to take such steps as they deem ssary to successfully establish such station. Section 3. The board of regents shall have control and super - vision of said station and shall appoint skillful superintendents and such other employees as to them may appear necessary, to ob - tain the best results. They shall fix the salaries and compensation of employees and establish such rules and regulations as they may from time to time deem best. Section 4. The object of this experiment station shall be to determine the adaptability of the arid and semi-arid portions of Nebraska to agriculture, horticulture, forest tree and live stock growing, such as the producing of grain, grasses, root crops and fruits of kinds commonly grown in same latitude in other states, also the most economical methods of producing such crops without irrigation. Con 5. The proceeds arising from the sale of products of ition shall be applied to the liquidation of the running ex - and all money so accruing shall be credited as coming from the state and be applied as part or whole payment of any amount which may be appropriated from the funds of the state for the maintenance of said station. Section 6. To enable the board of regents to carry out the pro - visions of this act they are hereby authorized to expend such amounts as they may deem necessary from any moneys hereafter appropriated to carry out the spirit and intent of thi3 bill, either by the state or the United States as the case might be. Section 7. That the sum of fifteen thousand dollars ($15,- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">XXIV Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 000.00) be and is hereby appropriated out of the moneys in the temporary university fund for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this Act. Approved March 20th, 1909. AN ACT to establish an experimental station west of the one hun- dred and second meridian, in the State of Nebraska, fixing the control and management of the same and making an appropria- tion therefor. Be it Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska : Section 1. That for the furtherance and promotion of agricul - tural, horticultural, and forestry interests of this state, an experi - mental sub-station shall be established west of the one hundred and second meridian in Nebraska, which station shall be under the control and management of the board of regents of the state uni - versity. j fog Section 2. The board of regents are hereby authorized and em - powered to take such steps in conjunction with the authorities of the United States as they deem necessary to successfully establish such station. Section 3. The board of regents shall have control and super - vision of said station and shall appoint skillful superintendents and such other employees as to them may appear necessary, to ob - tain the best results. They shall fix the salaries and compensation of employees and establish such rules and regulations as they may from time to time deem best. Section 4. The object of this experiment station shall be to de - termine the adaptability of the arid and semi-arid portions of Nebraska to agriculture, horticulture and forestry such as the pro - ducing of grain, grasses, root crops and fruits of kinds commonly grown in same latitude in other states, also the most economical methods of producing such crops with and without irrigation. House Roll No. 18 (Introduced by Mr. Bushee.) </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Twenty-third Annual Report XXV said station shall be applied to the liquidation of the running ex - penses, and all money so accruing shall be credited as coming from the state and be applied as a part or whole payment of any amount which may be appropriated from the funds of the state for the maintenance of said station. Section 6. To enable the board of regents to carry out the pro - visions of this act they are hereby authorized to expend such amounts as they may deem necessary from any moneys her* appropriated to carry out the spirit and intent of this bill, either by the state or the United States as the case might be. Section 7. That the sum of five thousand dollars ($5,000.00) be and is hereby appropriated out of the moneys in the temporary university fund for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of Approved April 3rd, 1909. Pursuant to the instructions of the Legislature, a committee of the Regents on June 15, 1909, started to investigate the sites which had been offered for the proposed substations, visiting the lands in Scotts Bluff County which were made available by the Interior Department for experimental work carried on by the United States Department of Agriculturs, a committee of this Department hav - tbeen appointed to select a suitable site for their experimental i. After due investigation a site was recommended by the nittee of the United States Department of Agriculture which to be in charge of this experiment station for the Government, site selected being the southeast quarter of section 21, town - ship 23 north, range 55 west, located five miles east of the town of Mitchell and seven and one-half miles northwest of the town of Scottsbluff, in Scotts Bluff County, Nebraska. This site was agreed to as acceptable to the Regents of the University. Investigation of the sites offered for the station in the northwest section of the State were made with an effort to secure land in the Sand Hills region where the agricultural and forestry possibilities of sand hill land could be determined along with the management </seg>
            <seg id="p026">XXVI Agricultural Experiment S/ntion of Nebraska of other agricultural lands. After some investigation the Regents indicated that the region of Valentine would be an acceptable re - gion for this Station but did not select any definite site for this E.t this juncture, when the Regents were about to begin the ex - diture of money for the establishment of these stations, a doubt ing as to the availability of funds under the forms of legis - lative appropriations, a friendly mandamus suit was filed in the Supreme Court of Nebraska to determine the legality of the use of moneys from the temporary university fund for the establishment of these stations. The decision of the court, rendered in December, 1909, confirmed the authority of the Regents to proceed in the es - tablishment of these stations in accordance with the act of the Leg - islature.* In December, 1909, the agent of the United States Department of Agriculture with whom a cooperative agreement for the opera - tion of the experiment station in Scotts Bluff County was in prog - ress informed the Director of the Nebraska Experiment Station that a ruling had been made by the Secretary of the Interior to the effect that the money which had been promised by the Interior Department for the erection of permanent buildings upon the site Ptte. — On January 17, 1910, Senator Norrls Brown introduced in ited States Senate a bill granting to the University of Nebraska lands embraced in the Fort Niobrara Reservation, for the pur - pose of aiding in -the establishment and maintenance of this station. This bill grants a perpetual lease to the University on "all of section thirty-two, six hundred and forty acres; west half and west half south- Eit quarter section thirty-three, four hundred acres; lot one (thirty - en and thirty one-hundred ths acres) and lot two (sixteen and twen - one-hundredths acres), or section thirty-three, fifty-three and fifty one-hundredths acres; in all, one thousand and ninety-three and fifty one-hundred ths acres; all of township thirty-four, range twenty-seven west of the sixth prime meridian." This land is located about one half mile east of the town of Valentine. It is expected that this bill will pass Congress, and preparations are being made to occupy this land tor experimental purposes. Mr. James Cowan has been appointed Superintendent of the Valentine Substation. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Tieenty-third Annual Rejtort XXVII above mentioned could not be legally expended for this purpose without additional authority from Congress. The experimental work to be conducted in Nebraska by the United States Department of Agriculture is but one of a number of experimental or demon - stration farms which it is proposed to establish upon land under the Reclamation projects which are subject to homestead entry in the Department of the Interior. The purpose of these experi - mental farms is to give information to the settlers on these lands which will assist them in determining practical farm problems and aid them to pay their annual assessments for water rights and build up prosperous farm communities. The understanding between the Regents of the University ami the United States Department of Agriculture was that the Int Department would furnish the land for this experiment station site and would construct the necessary buildings to permit th&gt; rying on of this experimental work, out of appropriations made l&gt;y Congress to the Reclamation Service. The recent rulinjr of the Secretary of the Interior calling for specific authority to use money for the construction of these buildings will delay the experimental work upon this station until Congress shall authorize this expend - iture. The Bureau of Plant Industry of the United States Depart - ment of Agriculture rules that it has no authority to expend any moneys now available for permanent improvements upon this land, and the Regents of the University hold that they have no authority to expend money for permanent improvements upon land to which they do not hold title, since the discontinuance of the cooperative agreement would cancel their rights to the property in qiit and would tranfer this property, without recourse, to the Interior Department of the Federal Government. Unless the difficulties above mentioned are overcome so that experimental work can progress during the season of 1910, it would seem that the State, if it desires to carry on experimental or demon - stration work of a permanent character in the extreme wm portion of Nebraska, could better afford to own and operate its experimental plant as a State proposition, allowing the Regents at their discretion to cooperate with the United States Department </seg>
            <seg id="p028">xxviii Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska of Agriculture at these stations .as they are now doing at other sta - tions. This would enable the Regents to shape the policy of the station in conformity to their views of the needs of the locality.* ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The agricultural press, especially those papers located within the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experi - ment Station by giving liberal space to the experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. •Note. — On March 7, 1910, Secretary R. A. Ballinger approved a memorandum authorizing the use of $5,000 for the erection of build - ings on the land set aside by the Reclamation Service for experimental work in Nebraska. On March 15 a memorandum of cooperation was signed by this Station and the Bureau of Plant Industry of the United States Department of Agriculture. Mr. Fritz Knorr was appointed Superintendent by the Bureau of Plant Industry and approved by the univenii/. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">7V-. nttj-third Anmmal R XXIX THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT RECEIPTS ■ved by the state treasurer of Nebraska m the treasurer of the United States, in- Uments for the year ended June 30, )9, under the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887 (Hatch Fund) 15,000 00 DISBURSEMENTS Salaries Labor . 10,113 68 198 51 Publications 2,116 17 761 51 Postage and stationery Freight and express ... II Chemical supplies Seeds, plants and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs Tools, implements and machinery Furniture and fixtures 154 75 181 25 Scientific apparatus Traveling expenses Contingent expenses Building and land . 115,000 00 15,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska XXX FINANCIAL STATEMENT — Continued Bived by the state treasurer of Nebraska &gt;m the treasurer of the United States, in - illments for the year ended June 30, 09, under the act of Congress approved March 16, 1906 (Adams Fund) 11,000 00 DISBURSEMENTS Labor . 8,446 23 24 10 Postage and stationery Freight and express .... llll Chemical supplies 626 45 Seeds, plants and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs 4 ::s Library Tools, implements and machinery Furniture and fixtures 120 80 Scientific apparatus Traveling expenses 1,096 29 $11,000 00 11,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">'•/-third Annual /.' XXXI FINANCIAL STATEMENT — Continued SUPPLEMENTARY K received by the state treasurer of Ne - i from sources other than the United for the use and benefit of the experi - station and covered into the "Uni - f Cash Fund." RECEIPTS Balance on hand July 31, 1908 6,858 58 Receipts for the year ended July 31, 1909, from sales of farm products, live stock and sundry other sources 23,831 54 DISBURSEMENTS Salaries Labor 5,390 02 3,534 61 Publications Postage and stationery Freight and express .... 605 39 1,003 09 Heat, light, water and power Chemical supplies is 1: Seeds, plants and sundry supplies Feeding stuffs 3.476 09 8,93: 1,726 93 Tools, implements and machinery Furniture and fixtures .:;:: Scientific apparatus Live stock Ill II Traveling expenses Building and land 1,153 05 2,345 75 Balance, July 31, 1909 $30,690 12 30,690 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">XXXII Agricultural Exfteriment Static, of Nebraska FINANCIAL STATEMENT — Continued APPROPRIATIONS BY THE STATE SUBSTATION AT NORTH PLATTK Kive appropriation of 1909 from the general fund for support of the sub - n at North Platte, for the two years g March 31, 1911 25,000 00 Eded, year ended November 30, 1909, for [, labor, live stock, permanent improve - its, machinery, services, supplies, super - ndence, tools and general maintenance- 11,655 03 13,344 97 Appropriation balance, November 30, 1909 $25,000 00 25,000 00 FARMERS' INST1TUTI8 Balance, November 30, 1908, of legislative ap - propriation of 1907, from the state general fund for support of farmers' institutes 6,754 62 Legislative appropriation of 1909, from the state general fund for support of farmers' Institutes, for the two years ending March 31, 1911 20,000 00 Bed, year ended November 30, 1909, for :al services, labor, lecturers' services traveling expenses, printing, supplies, rintendence, and other necessary ex- 9,367 75 17,386 87 Appropriation balance, November 30, 1909 $26,754 62 26,754 62 J. S. DALES, Financial Secretary. Lincoln, Nebr, January 31. 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">CONTENTS t Importance of the Inoculation of Alfalfa on Nkhraska Upland Soils 3 Results of investigations elsewhere 3 The recognition of inoculated plants 4 Observations in alfalfa fields in Nebraska Lancaster County . . o Furnas, Harlan, Phelps, and Kearney Counties 14 Buffalo County '. ; Hall County 15 Hitchcock, Dundy, Chase, and Perkins Counties 1"&gt; Dawes County . . lfi Other Counties 16 Sources of inoculation lrt Summary and conclusions 19 The Determination of Nitrogen in Dried Uncjrouxu Cblealc The method - 1 Accuracy of sampling Completeness of the drying Agreement of duplicate determinations The Color and Ash Content of Different Grades of Nebraska Flour 26 The Relation of the Breaking Strength of Hog Bones to the Composition of the ash 31 b Nitrogen Content of Inoculated and Uninoculated Al - falfa Plants 33 On The Occurrence of Prussic Acid in Sorghum and Maize... 35 Abortion in Cattle 37 Accidental abortion 38 Contagious abortion Symptoms 38 The cause 3» Sterility 40 Conclusions . 41 Tuberculosis 42 Sample of the questions prepared on a bulletin which was sent to the members of the Tuberculosis Heading Club, and the answers to the same H Production of a New Form in Wheat Soil Moisture Studies at the North Platte Substation 62 General conditions 62 Type of soil Manner of sampling 6-&gt; Depth of sampling 66 Explanation of tables 66 History of the fields 68 On the Strength of Wheat Flour 100 History of Hog Cholera Experiments in Nebraska Ill Laboratory Work 112 Post-mortem 113 Immunity of Hogs recovered from Cholera . ... 1 15 Transpiration Experiments with the Corn Plant lil 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035">THE IMPORTANCE OF THE INOCULATION OF ALFALFA ON NEBRASKA UPLAND SOILS By F. J. Alway It is commonly believed that in Nebraska it is unnecessary to inoculate newly sown fields of alfalfa. The rapid increase in the area devoted to this crop, it now having reached 615,329 acres for the whole State, and the ease with which men who have already had experience with alfalfa secure a satisfactory stand, are certainly strong evidence in support of this view. The author, however, is convinced, from observations made in various parts of the State during the past eight years, that the popular opinion is ill-founded and that every man in the State who sows a field of alfalfa should give attention to the matter of its inoculation before the plants are past recovery in case artificial inoculation should be needed. In some cases a half -hour's examination may suffice for a large field, while in others a day or two's labor may be necessary to make sure of the inoculation. RESULTS OF INVESTIGATIONS ELSEWHERE. Since Hellriegel and Wilfarth in 1886 proved that the ability of legumes to make use of atmospheric nitrogen is dependent upon the presence of certain bacteria on the roots, many investi - gations have been conducted to determine the necessity of the artificial inoculation of alfalfa. In the United States, bulletins in which this has been dealt with have been published by the United States Department of Agriculture 1 and by various Ex - periment Stations. Inoculation of alfalfa by means of soil from fields in which the crop has been thriving was used by Dugger 2 in Alabama in 1897, by Otis 3 in Kansas in 1898, and by Hopkins 4 lFarmers' Bulletin No. 339. 2Bulletin 87, Alabama Experiment Station. 3 Bulletin 96, Kansas Experiment Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">4 F Illinois in 1902. Hopkins showed that soil in which inoculated nts of sweet clover (Melilotus alba) were growing did as well that in which alfalfa itself had grown. The New York Experiment Station 1 has conducted what is probably the most comprehensive field investigation of the need of inoculation for alfalfa. This investigation included coopera - tive experiments on one hundred fields in different parts of the State. It was found that the desired bacteria were present, at least in small numbers, in practically all the fields, but that in only about one-third of these were the bacteria present in suffi - cient numbers to produce inoculation of any considerable number of young alfalfa plants. THE RECOGNITION OF INOCULATED PLANTS When the alfalfa seed has been sown in the spring, it is usually possible by the middle of the summer to recognize the uninoculated plants by their more yellow color, smaller size, and general lack of vigor as compared with the inoculated plants. If the field is in a high state of fertility from previous manuring, none of the plants during the first season may show the characteristics of unin - oculated plants — really the signs of a deficient supply of nitrogen. Virgin soils, also, when plowed and put in fine tilth may show the same lack of difference. A good illustration of the latter is the field of J. S. Campbell described below. Even in the case of very fertile fields the difference will ordinarily be seen in the sec - ond season. The smaller the supply of readily available nitrogen in the soil the more quickly will the want of inoculation become apparent. The only reliable method of deciding whether a plant is in - oculated or not is to examine its roots for the presence of nodules. Even this method fails at times to give conclusive evidence, as it seems that if the supply of nitrates in the soil is very abundant nodules may not develop, even tho the necessary bacteria be pres - ent. Such unusual supplies of nitrates, however, are not fre - quently met with. lBulletins 300, 303, 313. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">5 The nodules, or tuborcules, occur either singly or in etoaten attached to the fine roots. They are about as large as alfalfa t, or a little larger, and somewhat of the same shape, quently they are pear-shaped. The color of the young nodu white, sometimes with a pink tint. They are most abundant dur - ing the growing season. An examination of the roots during the winter may show but few nodules present, and those dark and shrunken. On account of the readiness with which the nodules become detached, it is usually necessary to remove the plant to - gether with much adherent soil by means of a spade and then piek or wash away the soil. If a pail of water be carried to the field and all the roots and adherent soil soaked and then washed in this, the rootlet! with the nodules can usually be secured without diffi - culty. When a red clover plant is pulled up bodily, numerous nodules remain attached to the roots, but when an alfalfa plant i&gt; similarly treated the nodules remain in the ground. Before deciding that a field contains no inoculated plants. one .should dig up and carefully examine a large number of the gill and most vigorous plants. On the other hand, lack of complete inoculation should not be considered proven until a large number of the most yellow and unthrifty plants have been similar - ly treated. The yellow color of the plants is often due to parasitic disease and not to lack of the necessary bacteria. I he author has failed in only two of over 100 alfalfa fields he amined in Nebraska to find at least a few inoculated plants, h of these exceptions the supply of available nitrogen was ndant that all the plants were dark green in color and very us in growth, thus rendering the search for inoculated plants ally difficult. OBSERVATIONS IN ALFALFA FIELDS IN NEBRASKA. E Lancaster County. — The oldest fields of alfalfa near Lincoln those on the Experiment Station farm, two being indicated on hi nipiinying map ;is A and B. These were sown in tlie spring B95. The former and part of the latter have since been plow - p. In the spring of 100.3, both of these fields as well as C on </seg>
            <seg id="p038">6 the south side of Holdrege Street and separated from A only by the roadway, as well as the west half of Block 77 (H) and Lot 1, Block 108 (D), University Place, were found fully inoculated. The small field on Lot 1, Block 108, marked D on the map, had been seeded by the author in April, 1900, and a partial stand secured, no inoculation being tried. Lots 3 and 4 (E) were pre - pared similarly and seeded at the same time ; but, altho they were given the same care, the alfalfa plants on these were nearly all dead by September. The previous history of the two areas hail w-f*E scale o{ vmUfc . Map showing the location of the alfalfa fields of Lancaster Count; that are referred to in this article, been somewhat different. D had been used as a garden, being manured yearly, while E had been kept continuously in corn with - out manuring and accordingly did not have the same supply of available nitrogen. Early in April, 1903, E was plowed, harrowed several times to secure a firm seed bed, and sown with alfalfa. Before harrow - ing in the seed, about 100 pounds of inoculating soil from D was scattered over the south half of E. Then the uninoculated </seg>
            <seg id="p039">half was harrowed first in order to prevent the spreading of the inoculation by the harrow and the hoofs of the horses. The germinated well and a good stand was secured, equally good on both halves of the field. At the end of the third week in May, the plants were from three to five inches high and all of good color. One hundred plants were carefully removed from the extreme north (uninoculated) end and the same number from the south (inoculated) end. On only 5 of the first 100 plants were any nodules found, while 95 of the second had nodules. No distinct difference between the inoculated and the uninoculated plants was to be seen in the color, size, or vigor. A very heavy rain fell a few days after the above examination was made, half of the field being covered by water for a short time. Three weeks later an - other examination of both ends of the field was made but no unin - oculated plants were found. The heavy rain had evidently spread the inoculation over the whole field. No difference was obwrred between the two ends from that time on. On about the same day as E was sown, Mr. I. M. Clark - alfalfa on Block 122 (F), University Place, only one humliv 1 yards from D but on another slope of the same ridge ; accordingly no storm water from the latter could run over it. The field was in equally good condition and the seed bed was as well prepare]. No inoculated soil was scattered on this, however. A good stand was obtained, but from the middle of June on the plants were of poor color and lacked vigor. Examinations made at various times failed to show any inoculated plants. In the sprinsr of 1904 the stand on the field was rather thin and at the time of the first cutting, about the 1st of June, no inoculated plants were found. Immediately after the removal of the first cutting of hay, which was not more than one-third as heavy as that on E, the field was inoculated with soil from the latter. The second cut - ting seemed almost as heavy as that on E. An examination at this time showed no uninoculated plants, while the stand seemed to have much improved. Of course there had been no increase in the number of plants but each plant bore several times as much foliage as it had before the first cutting. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 8 In the spring of 1904 Mr. I. M. Clark sowed to alfalfa the east end of the land belonging to the Nebraska Wesleyan Univer - sity campus. The field formed the summit of a ridge, the high - est part now constituting the Wesleyan athletic field. It had for many years been in cultivation to corn, sorghum, etc., and proba - bly had never been manured. Adjoining this field on the west slope of the ridge was a considerable area of virgin prairie well supplied with native legumes. 1 In 1903 part of the field had produced a very heavy crop of sorghum hay while the rest had been in potatoes. The alfalfa came up well, an excellent stand being obtained, while the number of weeds was unusually small. From about the 1st of July on, the field was examined at fre - quent intervals. At that time it was as a whole a light yellowish green in color but there were very many spots where the plants were dark green and much taller and more vigorous than on the rest of the field. Nearly all of these spots had a more or less circular form with a diameter of from 10 inches to 2 feet. A very few were still larger. All the dark grsen plants examined from these patches bore nodules, while the yellow plants which formed the main portion of the field bore none. Here and there among the yellow plants, individual green ones were found and these bore nodules. As the summer advanced, the green spots in - creased greatly in number and size, many of them being from 6 to 12 feet in diameter by the middle of September. The following May, after growth had well started, it was found that the inocu - lated areas were still larger than in the previous autumn, many of them being 30 feet in diameter. They were still more or less circular in outline except where several had grown together. The first cutting was not more than half a crop, the uninoculated areas giving very little hay while the inoculated areas produced heavily. About a month later, when the field was ready to cut a second time, it was examined. The yellow areas had entirely disappeared, the whole fneld being dark green in color and the lWarren, Circular 31. Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture, June, 1909. Alway and Pinckney, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chem - istry, Vol. I, page 771. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Twenty-third Annual Report 9 crop everywhere uniformly heavy. From that time on until part of it was plowed up in 1909, the field remained uniform. E recent article in the Nebraska Farmer of March 2, 1910, by G. of Elk City, Nebr., describes a very similar spread of in - ion in the case of a field on high upland in Doaghi County, blowing extracts are from the article: E"I will state first that our place lies in the extreme eastern t of the state (Douglas county) and at about the highest point ween the Elkhorn and Missouri valleys." ' ' The first piece of alfalfa was seeded early in the fall of 1904. From continuous cropping the soil was low in productivity but was given a good coat of manure before seeding. No artificial inoculation was given this piece. A good stand was secured and it wintered perfectly and grew well the next spring until it was about six inches high when it began turning yellow, excepting small spots here and there which remained dark green and v ous. These green spots showed that they had become inoculated by natural means and they gradually spread out, but not until the following spring did they claim the whole field. Very little hay was obtained until that year, but from that time on until 1909 .it showed a thick stand and did fine." "I have seen seedings in this locality where inoculation has taken place by natural means almost as quickly, but I have seen more of them that haven't and certainly wouldn't advise anyone to try it without inoculating unless they wish to gamble on the chances of losing the use of their land for about one year and maybe the seed also." EIn the spring of 1907, a large field, the Hubbel &amp; Njlson , lying two blocks south of the Experiment Station farm marked I on the map, was sown to alfalfa. As it has since passed by the author nearly every day, it has been kept under observation. ■iring the first season, incidental to a study of the soil of d, a few inoculation experiments were tried on a very small The field is comparatively level except near the north- </seg>
            <seg id="p042">10 east corner, where a small draw erosses it, leaving this corner above the reach of water flowing thru the draw. The accompa - nying photo shows this. An old alfalfa field, J, had been just northeast of Field I, and before the grade for the railway was thrown up in 1905 part of the run-off from this old alfalfa field on its way to the draw had crossed this corner of Field I. This is the probable explanation of the differences in growth between the alfalfa on this corner and on the rest of the east half of the field. Photograph of alfalfa field I, taken April 22, 11)10. shosvinjr northeast portion of tield. The man is standing in the bottom of the draw. Between the draw, the road, and the railway lies the small triangular area in which all the alfalfa plants were inoculated frum the first time of observation. Thesouree of this inoculation was the tield diagonally opposite, which is now separated from I by the railway grade. The field had been in continuous cultivation for 30 or 40 years, wath many heavy applications of barnyard manure. In 1906 it had been in sorghum, which had been allowed to mature seed and much of this seed had been left on the ground and germinated among the alfalfa in 1907. The volunteer sorghum on the west end of the field was much thicker, and its growth much more vigorous, than on the other end, but there was, however, no sharp line of change, it being especially rank near the northwest </seg>
            <seg id="p043">11 previous year, and becoming gradually poorer toward the east thick uniform stand of alfalfa was secured on all parts of the field, but after warm weather set in the growth on the different parts was far from uniform. On the west end there were many spots where the growth of alfalfa and sorghum was very vigorous, while on the east end, except on the northeast corner, shown in the photograph, the growth of both was weak. On this corner of the field the growth of alfalfa was everywhere vigorous while that of the sorghum was as poor as on the rest of the east end. On the west end the sorghum was so thick and its growth was so vigorous that in order to protect the alfalfa this part was mown near the end of June as well as several times later during the season, while on the east end the sorghum was neither sufficiently thick nor vigorous to seem to need cutting before it was gone over about the middle of August. From June on, the differences between the inoculated and the ordinary uninoculated plants could be seen on both end the field. On the west end, even before the first mowing, there were many large patches where the plants were all inoculated, and between those patches were many inoculated individual plants. Not all of the dark-green plants dn the green patches, however, nodules. All the plants on the northeast corner were inoculated, as were also those on the lower part of the slope on the northwest side of the draw this evidently being due to water having stood in the draw for some time after a heavy rain. From this green margin of the draw the number of inoculated plants thinned out rapidly until at a short distance they were no more numerous than on the rest of the east end. No large patches of inoculated plants were found on this end, but there were many individual inoculated plants. After each successive mowing, the west end assumed a much more uniform appearance, the uninoculated areas becoming smaller while a distinct line with dark green plants on one side and yellow or yellowish green plants on the other marked the east boundary of the mown area. ■n August 3 a careful search for inoculated and uninocu - plants was made on the west end of this field as described </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 12 rve (page 34). x On the same day a typical uninoculated area feet long by 3 feet wide was selected on a gentle slope where there was little chance of drainage from one part of it to another. This was marked off by means of wooden pegs into 32 plats 3 feet by 3 feet. Part of them were given different treatment, as indicated below, the others being left untouched. Those that were weeded had every plant other than alfalfa pulled up by the roots, thus somewhat disturbing the surface soil. To avoid this disturbance of the surface with the consequent aeration of the soil and the formation of light mulch, all the weeds on Plats 5 and 7 were clipped off level with the surface by means of scissors. The inoculated plats were separated from those treated but not inoculated by four untreated plats and from one another by un - treated plats. The inoculation was effected by scattering over the surface of each square about five pounds of soil from the northeast corner of the field. On August 10 the plants on every treated plat was counted. Part of these data was lost. On this date only four plants, judging from the color and vigor, wore inoculated, one each on Plats 1, 3, 13, and 30. On August 19, a day or two after the field had been mown and raked, the plats were examined again. The mower knife had been set so high that the tops of only the inoculated plants, together with the weeds, had been cut. Every plat showed the imprint of the wheels of the mower or of the horses' feet. The plats which had been only weeded, clipped, or raked showed very slight improvement over the untreated plats, while those that had also received a dressing of the inoculating soil showed a distinct im - provement. Just before frost occurred in the autumn, the form of the plats which had been treated with the inoculating soil could be made out easily at a distance of fifty yards, while those of the others could not. During the autumn the uninoculated plants died out rapidly. The large number which thus disappeared is evident from the count made on April 4, 1908. The loss varied from 50 to 97 per cent of the stand of August 10, 1907. The growth at the time was not yet sufficient to indicate how many of the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Twenty-third Annual Report 13 plants were inoculated. At the time of the second cutting of liny in 1908 all uninoeulated plants had disappeared. Since that time the field has become more uniform in appearance, the isolated plants growing larger th;in those closely crowded together, hut a larjre part of the cast end of the field still produces only a partial crop. Plat Treatment on Aug. 3, No. of plants No. of plants Appearance 1907 Aug. H&gt;, 1907 Apr. 4, 1908 Aug. 19, 1907 5 Weeded 222* 106 Slightly bet- Clipped 2»3* 9 ter than un- Clipped 2»3* 9 ter than un- Weeded 234 44 treated plats Clipped 350 11 and surround- 2»3* 9 I ten than un- Weeded. 234 44 treated plats 5 Clipped 350 11 and surround- 1 B Kaked 14 ing growth " 40 Raked 14 ing growth B 40 Weeded and raked.. • 80 " " 13 Weeded and raked.. • 80 " i . 1 1 Treated with inocu- 130 Somewhat bet - lating soil 63 ter than above Treated with inocu- 130 Somewhat bet - lating soil 63 ter than above Treated with inocu - lating soil and raked 118 " Treated with inocu - lating soil and raked 118 Treated with inocu - lating soil and raked 64 " Treated with inocu - lating 8 o il and raked 64 .. H Weeded and treated with inoculating soil Weeded and treated with inoculating soil 417 . 148 Much better 148 Much better Weeded and treated w ith inoculating soil Weeded and treated .. « .,.-, *,. with inoculating than 20, - soil 4*7* 160 and 26 than 20, 22, 24. 32 Weeded and treated with inoculating soil and raked 135 " Weeded and treated with inoculating soil and raked . . t . Like 28-32 but M Weeded and treated onlv a small with inoculating number of soil and raked I 44 | plants •One inoculated plant on plat on Aug. 10, 1907. Several other small fields — K, L, M, — near the Experiment Station farm but situated so that there was no chance for inocu- lation by washing from an established field, have been given some attention. In most of these, after the plants were well started, only a small proportion of them were found inoculated, these being scattered over the whole field. Later most of the plants were found to have died out, leaving so few plants that the owner 417 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">14 was disappointed in the light yields of hay and yet did not care to plow and sow again. Furnas, Harlan, Phelps, and Kearney Counties. — In the latter part of June, 1903, the writer wheeled from Arapahoe to Kearney by way of Oxford, examining every field of alfalfa along the road. Between Arapahoe and Oxford in the Repub - ican valley, alfalfa was even at that time the most important crop, while on the high land between Oxford and Kearney some eight or ten fields were seen. Some forty old fields in the valley were examined and all found to be inoculated, while in only about half of those on the high land did the inoculation seem to be com - plete. Only two newly sown fields were seen, both being in the Republican valley. The one was part of an old alfalfa field which had been resown. The plants were only about two inches high, but every plant bore nodules. The other field was on the bank of a creek. The plants in this were about as large as in the former and all nearest the creek were inoculated while those farther away were uninoculated. The explanation of this probably is that the creek rising above its bank had inoculated the lower side of the field, the upper edge of the inoculated area seeming to be practically a contour line. Buffalo County. — On June 23, 1903, the Watson ranch west of Kearney, the pioneer alfalfa farm in Nebraska, was visited. The old fields in the valley were all inoculated, and Mr. N. C. Dunlap, the manager of the ranch, had been shipping soil to Illinois and New York for inoculation purposes. In a newly sown field on the crest of the ridge to the east of the buildings, every plant was found inoculated. The explanation of this was that Mr. Dunlap, to make sure of inoculation, had, before sow - ing the seed, given the field a light dressing of manure from alfalfa- fed cattle. Pin the early years of alfalfa production on the Watson ranch was usually necessary to seed a field twice before getting a satisfactory stand, the inoculating plants surviving from the first sowing serving to inoculate the whole field when the latter was plowed and cultivated in preparation for the second sowing. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">15 PHall County.— On June 24, 1903, the Taylor ranch near tt station, northeast of Grand Island, was visited. Several red acres of alfalfa had been sown in 1902 on virgin soil on sand hills. A perfect stand had been obtained and the alfalfa did well the first season but at the time of the inspection in 1903 it was looking rather sickly, nearly all the plants being yellowish green in color. These were found uninoculatcd, wkila only an occasional dark green inoculated plant could be found. On the same ranch there were several hundred acres of old alfalfa, all inoculated and all doing well. One old field which had been killed out had been plowed up and reseeded in the spring. AIL the young plants on this were found inoculated. Hitchcock, Dundy, Chase, and Perkins Counties. — In August and September, 1903, many fields near Wauneta and Champion in the Frenchman valley and between Culbertson and Benkel - man in the upper Republican valley, were examined. In all of these the plants were found inoculated, hut on many fields in the Re - publican valley the stand was thin, as tho most of the plants had succumbed before becoming inoculated. In the whole distance between Culbertson and Benkelman only two good alfalfa farms were seen. One of these was above Max, while the other was on Indian Creek just where it enters the Republican valley. The former was entirely in the valley but the latter was partly on the hillside. While the growth was much shorter on the hill, all the fields were inoculated and showed a food stand. In May, 1907, Mr. J. S. Campbell of Imperial plowed a small field of virgin prairie, worked it up to make a fine seed bed, and sowed alfalfa in drills about 12 inches apart. This was kept hoed and weeded like a vegetable garden thruout the summer. The first week in September, the plants were in bloom and were being cut for feed. All were vigorous and dark green in color and gave every evidence of being inoculated. A careful search for nodules was made by Mr. Campbell and the author without finding any, tho we found a supply of inoculating soil in a field not far distant. This field had been sown to alfalfa the previous year and at the time of inspection the plants were in seed. A careful search re- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">16 vealed that in the part of the field where the stand was thickest and the plants largest all the plants bore nodules, while on much of the rest of the field most of the plants carried no nodules. A field four miles east of Imperial had been sown broadcast in the spring of 1907, and in September there was a good stand of plants, about one-third of them bearing nodules. The inocu - lated plants were readily recognizable, they being larger and dark - er in color, altho all the plants were in healthy condition. LWhat is probably one of the most isolated valley farms of alfa occurs on the upper part of the Stinking Water valley in Chase County. The fields belonging to Mr. Inman were exam - ined in September, 1907, and found to be thoroly inoculated. A newly sown field just below these in the valley and belonging to Mr. McCoy was found to be fully inoculated. In November, 1907, two fields on the H O ranch near Mad - rid, Perkins County, showed a thin stand of fully inoculated plants. The seed had been sown the previous year. Dawes County. — In August, 1903, a small field of fully inocu - lated young plants was found between Crawford and Adelia. The field had been sown that spring and had been flooded several times by storm waters from the adjacent hills, embankments hav - ing been thrown up in order to keep the storm waters on the field until they could soak into the soil. This flooding accounted for the full inoculation. Other Counties. — Inoculated fields have been found in vari - ous other counties of the State, no field having been found which was not partly inoculated except the two already referred to. Fields which are only partly inoculated are evidently found but rarely after the early part of the second season, the plants that do not become inoculated dydng out. SOURCES OF INOCULATION. The establishment of satisfactory stands of alfalfa in all parts of the state and the finding of nodule-bearing alfalfa plants in practically all newly sown fields examined indicate that the </seg>
            <seg id="p049">17 Pare already present in the soil. It has been most commonly uned that the bacteria carried by the seed constitute the source the inoculation of the few scattered inoculated plants almost ays found. Rhe agent that has been most relied upon in Nebraska for the ation of fields in a district where alfalfa is already estab - is the wind. As is well known large amounts of soil are car - ried by the high winds, especially by those from the southwest. If the soil thus transported carried the bacteria, we should expect to find all the fields to the immediate northeast of the Experiment Sta - tion farm fully inoculated, as large fields of alfalfa have been grown on this farm for the past fifteen years. Yet the fields less than half a mile distant, as described above, have been shown to need inoculation. In view of this it seems probable that the wind is unimportant as a carrier of inoculating soil, the bacteria being killed by exposure to the bright sunshine characteristic of Nebraska. The soil transported by the wind has been dried and exposed to the sun often for many days. The winds carry the soil chiefly during the daytime, thus exposing it in a fine state of division to the sunlight. Even after the transported soil has been deposited on the surface of other fields, it may still be ex - posed for several days to intense sunlight before a rain carries the accompanying bacteria down into the soil beyond the reach of the light. Water is the most effective natural means for the dissemina - tion of the bacteria. A heavy rain falling on sloping ground more rapidly than it can be absorbed by the soil will flow over the surface of an inoculated alfalfa field, carrying the inocula - tion to all fields traversed. All newly sown fields receiving run - off from an inoculated field will be found fully inoculated. The inoculation of new fields on river bottoms exposed to occasional inundation i3 to be attributed to the same cause, some of the wa - ters having traversed inoculated fields. Where only part of the plants are inoculated a flooding of the field may be counted upon to inoculate all of the others. To this is probably due the usual lack of any necessity of intentional inoculation in the case of irri - gated fields. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 18 rFhe soil carried on farm implements from inoculated fields serve to inoculate other fields. In the case of a partially in - oculated field the mower, the rake, and the hoofs of the horses serve to spread the inoculation. The more frequently the young stand on such a field is cut, the more rapidly is the complete inocu - lation effected. The complete inoculation of a field usually on - served after the removal of the first crop of hay is thus to be explained. The droppings from alfalfa-fed animals in fields which are later sown to alfalfa may account for the occurrence of the jrreci patches observed in some newly-sown fields. Eweet clover, as it occurs widely scattered as a weed along the des and railways, seems almost inoculated. Nowhere has the ■ found uniinoculated plants. It is quite probable, how - ever, that where the sweet clover is sown as a field crop it will show only part of the plants inoculated during the early part of the first year. Any of the above-mentioned methods will serve to carry the bacteria from the soil where the inoculated sweet clover is growing to uninoculated alfalfa plants. The bacteria associated with some of the native legumes may, as has been sug - gested by various writers, be capable of inoculating alfalfa. EOld alfalfa fields plowed up and reseeded, as well as those perly dressed with soil from inoculated fields, will show com - « inoculation. There are, however, instances known where soil carrying an abundance of nodules has, when allowed to dry out and remaiin in this condition for some time, failed to cause any inoculation. In Bulletin 313 of the New York Experiment Station two instances are mentioned. In one of these the bag of soil was held in a dry place for three months before being sown, and in the other, one year. The author, early in July, 1903, shipped a bag carrying 150 pounds of inoculating soil in which nodules were extremely numerous, to Ontario, where it arrived late in September. The soil was at once scattered over a half-acre field which was sown with alfalfa and harrowed. The next sum - mer the author inspected the field. A very thick stand of sickly looking plants had survived the winter, but a prolonged search </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Twenty-third Annual Report 19 Eled to reveal a single inoculated plant. The inoculation of field was then secured by treating it with soil from a roadside eh of inoculated sweet clover. Manuring a field for alfalfa insures its inoculation in case the manure is from alfalfa-fed animals. Even if no alfalfa has been in feeding the animals, the manure will still be an important help to the young plants, as it supplies them with available nitrogen and thus enables them to survive longer than they would without. The longer the plants survive, the greater is their chance for inoculation by some of the various means mentioned above. SUMMARY AND CONCLUSIONS. Alfalfa sown on tields subject to occasional inundation or on upland fields receiving storm waters from well-established alfalfa fields may be expected to show complete inoculating from the first. &lt; &gt;n upland fields receiving no run-off from old fields there may be expected to be found a considerable number of inoculated plants. These may be identified both by their color and vigor and more surely by the examination for nodules on their roots. On upland fields on which alfalfa has been grown before in very recent years or on which manure from alfalfa-fed animals has been scattered, complete inoculation may be expected. On farms in which there are already fields of alfalfa, the newly sown fields have several sources of more or less complete inoculation — the wash from the old fields, the carrying of the inoculated soil by farm implements, and the droppings from the alfalfa-fed farm animals pasturing or working in the field. For this reason, other things being equal a farmer already having alfalfa is more likely to get a good stand than his neighbor who has not. Some upland fields will, without any attention to their inoculation, give satisfactory stands, but others will give very thin and unsatisfactory stands, even where the preparation of the seed bed has been properly carried out and the weather conditions have been favorable. Everyone sowing alfalfa on Nebraska upland should either provide for its inoculation at the time of sowing the seed by dressing the field with inoculating soil or with manure from alfalfa-fed animals, </seg>
            <seg id="p052">20 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska or, after the plants have been growing long enough to show that they are not all inoculated, by dressing it with the inoculating soil. In the latter case, this soil, which usually can be found in some part of the newly sown field or obtained from some adjacent old alfalfa field or from roadside patches of sweet clover, should be scattered over the field just before a rain. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">GROUND CEREALS By F. J. Alwat and E. S. Bishop For some years past this laboratory has had to make, for the Department of Agronomy, a very large number of determinations of nitrogen in winter wheat. During the past three summers it has been desired that the results be gotten out with all speed, so that full data in regard to the grains harvested in July might be available before time for seeding, which is usually about the mid - dle of September. Extreme accuracy in analysis was nut tial, but it was necessary to be able to distinguish with cer - tainty between samples with a medium and those with either a high or a low nitrogen content, the percentage on a dry basis rang - ing from below 2 to over 4 per cent. After some preliminary work it was found that by not grinding the kernels a great saving in time could be effected without seriously lessening the accuracy of the determinations. The various stages in the analysis where time may thus be economized will be so evident to anyone havin,' had occasion to make wheat analyses that these do not need to be mentioned here. Requests have been received from other laboratories for a detailed description of the method, and in order to show its accuracy compared with the ordinary method we have made the determina - tions reported below in Tables II, III, and IV. While the method has not been used in this laboratory with any other cereal than wheat, we have included in these analyses a sample of rye and two samples of oats in order to test its applicability in the case of other cereals. Ee Method. — The grain, freed of broken and badly shrunken is sampled and about 2*A grams transferred to a glass g bottle. From 100 to 300 specimens thus prepared are placed in a drying oven kept at 110°C by a thermoregulator. In case Kl such charge, from four to six 2-gram specimens taken from sample of wheat used as a check are placed in different parts oven. At the end of four hours the check samples are taken </seg>
            <seg id="p054">22 out, allowed to cool, and weighed. They are then returned to the oven and after two hours further drying are weighed again. If the loss in weight during the last two hours has been slight and the total loss in weight by all the check samples is normal, it is assumed that all the samples are dried ; otherwise the heating is continued two hours longer. Then the weighing bottles are quickly removed from the oven, stoppered at once, and allowed to cool in desiccators. From each dried sample a 1-gram portion of wheat is weighed out, transferred to a Kjeldahl flask, and the nitrogen determined as in the ordinary method. When entire kernels are used, it is often necessary, in order to get approximately one gram, to either split a kernel or substitute a lighter kernel for one of those first placed on the scale pan. The latter, has been found the preferable method, and it has proved to be a simple matter to thus get within .0020 gram of the desin-.l weight. As this difference in the weight of the wheat used would make a difference of less than .005 per cent of nitrogen, it is so ••lose that it is safe in calculating to assume that a whole gram has been used. Thus, assuming that exactly one gram of wheat has been used, the error is shown in the following: Weight of wheat used. Actual per cent of nitrogen. 1.0000 gram 2.2400 1.0020 gram 2.2355 0.9980 gram 2.244.") Accuracy of Sampling.— In Table I are given the results of the nitrogen determinations in the case of two samples of unground undried wheat. The one sampling was very uniform, all the kernels being plump, while the other was a mixture of plump and badly shrunken kernels, it being from a field in which parts had gone down some little time before harvest. The 1-gram portions were transferred from the pint jars containing them to the weighing pan by means of a spoon. In order to deter - mine the nitrogen content in the well ground and mixed sample • if the same wheat, half of eaeli pint sample was ground so that it passed thru a millimeter sieve and was then sampled by quarter ing. One gram portions of this also were analyzed. The results </seg>
            <seg id="p055">23 of the table indicate that in the case of the uniform sample as concordant results are obtained from the unground as from the ground, but that in the case of the uneven sample the results are not quite so concordant in the case of the former as in that of the latter. It is evident that with uniform samples or with uneven samples from which the smallest and most shrunken kernels have !&gt;een removed by sifting, strictly representative 1-gram portions tiiiiy be obtained without the necessity of grinding. PTaiu.k 1. — Agreement of nitrogen determinations of ground unground wheat. Completeness op the Drying. — From Table II it will be seen that nearly all the moisture in the unground kernels is lost during the first four hours, but that in the case of the wheat and rye small amounts continue to be lost, even up to the 28th hour. With the oats the drying is practically complete at the end of the 8th hour. The amount of moisture retained after six hours, drying is so small that the error occasioned by assuming that the sample is water-free amounts to less than .03 per cent, as shown in Table III. The percentages in this table have been calculated from the .lata given in Tables II and IV. Agreement of Duplicate Determinations. — In Table IV are shown the results of five individual analyses of each of the Analysis No. sit Ground iple uniform Sample not uniform Unuround Ungrround ; Ground ; Series I Series II Series I Series e uniform Un(j round Series II 2 14 2 .20 2 14 2 28 2 20 2 08 2 14 2 14 2.39 2.20 2 H 2.18 2 11 2 43 2.38 2 22 2.20 2 21 2.43 5 2.17 2.2(1 2 18 2 38 2 31 6 2 15 2 11 2 lit 2.38 2.25 7 2.10 2.13 2 18 2.41 2.31 8 2.11 2 21 2.11 2.39 2 38 9 2.0* 2.18 2.11 2 31 2.41 10 2 08 2 11 2.13 2.34 2.34 2.20 211 2 H&gt; 2 31 2 22 2.11 2 20 2.11 2.37 2 ■ re 2 14 2 lei 2 14 2.37 2.30 urn depar- &gt;m average .08 .ftS 07 00 .11 „ Completeness op the Drying. — From Table II it will he se-T, that nearly all the moisture in the unground kernels is los **. *u_ c 4. t i. u— i. 4i..i :_ a. _« it. i *. ,nA ■_&gt; tflA fir«t fmir hnnwj Knt that in Tha naaa nf fha whaoi </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 24 samples referred to in Table I. All had been dried at 110° for 28 hours. The results for all except the sample of light oats are concordant. From a bottle holding about 50 grams of very uniform wheat, twelve 1-gram samples were poured out, one after the other. An - other sample of wheat in which about one-third of the grains were badly shrunken was treated in the same manner. The results in the case of the former ranged from 2.20 to 2.39, with an average of 2.30 per cent, while those of the latter ranged from 2.36 to 2.60, with an average of 2.53 per cent. The maximum departures from the average were .10 and .17 per cent respectively. In nei - ther case were the results as concordant as where the 1-gram por - tions were removed from the large sample by means of a spoon and forceps. When the whole sample weighed only from 3 to 10 grams, C'te as concordant results were obtained by the one method as by other. Table II. — Rate of loss of toater from uvground kernels \chen dri at 110° C. Per cent of ioisti re lost in successive intervals 1 M Sam- ple 0—4 4-« hrs. hrs. 6—8 hrs. 8—12 12—1616—2020—24 hrs. hrs. hrs. hrs. 24—28 hrs. TE 1 2 3 Av. 10.60 10.65 10.96 10.74 .44 .41 .36 .40 .34 .38 .36 .36 .2t&gt; .22 .21 .23 .15 .15 ,14 .15 .27 .14 .20 .05 .26 .12 .24 .10 .05 .10 .05 .07 1 T| 1 2 3 Av. 10.84 10.56 10.23 10.54 .36 .39 .31 .35 .32 .32 .36 .33 .17 .13 .27 .19 .17 .16 .19 .17 .22 .06 .21 .05 .36 .11 .26 .07 .08 .14 .09 .10 II 1 2 Av. 10.93 10.35 10.64 .42 .51 .46 .26 .50 .38 .26 .24 .24 .08 .13 .11 .24 .07 .18 .07 .21 .07 .11 .08 .10 il * 1 2 3 Av. 10.17 10.17 10.16 10.17 .16 .03 .12 .10 .18 .37 .10 .22 .07 .15 .09 .10 .03 .00 .00 .01 .12 —.02 ."•9 .00 .13 .02 .12 .00 —.03 .00 .00 — .01 I Oats II... ' I. 1 2 3 Av. 9.95 9.88 9.82 9.88 .23 .21 .12 .19 .18 .27 .23 .23 .08 .12 .02 .07 .05 .00 .00 .09 .05 .18 .04 .18 .01 .00 .00 — .03 I </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Twenty-third Annual Report 25 Percentage e of nitrogen that would be found in train o rie&gt; for &lt; »J rent ■engl '(.•&lt; 0 time at 0° C. Wheat I Wheat II Rje Oats I Oats II Cereal 4 hrs. 2.16 2 36 2.36 1.72 2.14 6 hn. 2.17 2.37 2.37 1.72 2.14 8 12 16 20 bra, hrs. hrs. hrs. 2.17 2.18 2.18 2.19 2.38 2.39 2.39 2.40 2.38 2.39 2.39 2.40 1.73 1.73 1.73 1.73 215 2.15 2.15 2. It 24 28 hrs. hrv 2.19 2.19 2.40 2.40 2.40 1.73 1.73 2.1.5 Table IV. — Agreem, •nt of duplicate determination* of nitro- Iried 28 hours at 110° C. gen in unground cereals &lt; Cereal 1 2 Per cent nitroi 3 4 •en Maximum departure I I Aver- age average Wheat 1 2.20 2.20 2.22 2.17 Wheat II 2 39 2.42 2.39 2 41 Rye 2.42 2.38 2.38 2.42 Oats I 1.70 1.72 1.72 1.72 Oats II 2.17 2.11 2.27 2.18 Ml 2.39 2.38 1.79 2.04 2.19 2.40 2.40 i.73 2.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">THE COLOR AND ASH CONTENT OF DIFFERENT GRADES OF NEBRASKA FLOUR Bf F. J. Alway and V. L. Clark CTp to the present time there are no chemical tests known by which the bread making qualities of a flour may be definitely ascertained. In order to determine these it is necessary to convert a sample of the flour into bread, using as a standard a flour of known bread making value. However, the most satisfactory re - sults are obtained when the flour is subjected to both baking and chemical tests. Among the latter, the determination of the ash probably gives the most definite information because it indicates the commercial grade of the flour. P definite standards for flour have been adopted by chemists, or dealers. Commercially the flour ia graded as first and patent, straight grade, first and second clear and "Red The last mentioned is used but little for human food. "By mixing various amounts of the different standard grades of flour, large numbers of flours with different trade names are obtained. Many of the brands of flour sold on the market are produced by blending different amounts of the patent and clear grades of flour."i P percentage of ash in both the different grades of flour shorts and bran obtained by the roller milling process are 3 in Table I, which is taken from Bulletin 101 of the Office ;riment Stations. While the percentages of ash in the t grades will vary more or less from mill to mill and for t lots of wheat, they will not be far from those given in the </seg>
            <seg id="p059">tBi.E I. — Percentages of ash in different grades of flour and in the by-producta and approximate percentages of the total weight recovered in the products- Ash llt'o The color has also been used in the grading of flour. The high irrnde Hours contain very few particles of bran and are there - fore of a white color with a tinge of yellow. The intensity of the yellow tint varies greatly. The lower grades of flour contain more particles of bran and have a darker color with a grayish tinge. The amounts of yellow coloring matter in the different grades of flour obtained from the same wheat appear to be about the sam*. The most characteristic property of the flours made from the hard winter wheat grown in Nebraska is their unusually deep yellow color. This color, however, is not indicative of an inferior quality, but it is not attractive to the purchaser. This intensity of color serves to partly obscure the differences between the differ - ent grade*. The difference becomes much more apparent after bleachinir, the hrisrht yellow or butter yellow patent becoming white while thi' lower bakers' becomes gray. For this reason the bread from a bleached high grade Nebraska flour is more inviting in appearance than that from the unbleached flour. Bread from a bleached low grade flour, on the other hand, has a most uninvit - ing appearance. From this it is easy to understand why millers bleach their high grades and place their low grade flour on the market in an unbleached condition. LThe straight, or standard patent, flour is made up of the first d second patents and the first clear. This is the ordinary bread flour most commonly placed upon the market. The first clear is frequently called "taken," grade, but many mills do not place any bakers' grade upon the market. First patent flour Second patent flour Straight or standard patent flour First clear grade flour, or bakers' Second clear grade flour, (low grade flour) "Ked dog" flour Shorts Bran Percent 0.31 i 0.42 \ 0.50 0.80 1 . 76 :t.4* 4-&gt;; e.oe Per cen tiO.o 72.0 lt.O 2.0 11.0 H.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">28 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska In connection with an investigation of bleached flour during 1906 and 1907, samples of both bleached and unbleachd flour were secured from a large number of Nebraska mills. Requests were sent to the different mills for samples of three grades — patent, straight, and bakers'. The ash was determined in eleven sets of these samples. The color also of each sample was determined by a modification of Pekar's method. Wedge-shaped masses of flour fere prepared on small rectangular plates of window glass, using nickel flour slick. After all the samples that were to be com - pared with each other had been thus prepared, usiner a separate piece of glass for each, they were dipped below the surface of water, allowed to remain one minute, withdrawn, well drained, placed in an oven at 205° F. and heated half an hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Table II. — Relation of color of flour to ash mid to grade reported by miller. i Highest per cent of ash 47 Straight... &lt; Lowest per cent of ash 35 ( Average per cent of ash +'- X M I Highest per cent of ash "1 Bakers' . . . . ■&lt; Lowest per cent of ash 50 ( Average per cent of ash 58 50 M •In the case of 3 samples of flour from other m411s, all tent aa "Patent," the a?h content was 0.48, 0.40 and 0.51 per cent tb^«B *!!! Grade reported by miller Ash Color Percent Patent .37 Clear yellowish white. Straight .40 Butter yellow. Bakers' .53 Yellowish gray. '2 Patent .M Clear yellowish white. Straight .35 Yellowish white with trace of gray. Bakers' .51 Yellowish gray. I Patent .36 Clear yellowish white. Straight .42 Deep yellow with gray tint. Bakers' .60 Yellowish gray. Patent .36 Clear yellowish white. Straight .4«i Yellow with gray tint. Bakers' ."&gt;*&gt; Yellowish gray. ■ 3 Patent .4(1 Clear light yellow. Straight .42 Yellowish white with no trace of gray. Bakers' .50 Yellowish gray. I Patent .33 Clear butter yellow. Straight .47 Yellow with gray tint. Bakers' .52 Yellowish gray. - Patent .37 Clear yellow. Straight .44 Clear butter yellow. Bakers' .66 Yellowish gray. * Patent .30 Clear white with very faint yellow tint. Straight .37 Clear white with more yellowish tint than the Bakers' .54 Yellowish gray. [preceding. Patent .42 Clear light yellow. Straight .46 Light yellow with gray tint. Bakers' .68 Gray. 10 Patent .38 Clear light yellow. Straight .43 Light yellow with gray tint. Bakers' .71 Yellowish gray. Patent .35 Clear butter yellow. Straight .37 Yellowish white with trace of gray. Bakers' M Yellowish gray. - IHigt &lt; Liowi / Avei lest per cent of ash est per cent of ash rage per cent of ash .42 .3C </seg>
            <seg id="p062">30 Agricultural Experitm ut Station of Ntbrmakm A com parison of the ash cont6nt ot these 33 samples of flour with the data given in Table I will show that none of them is below the grade reported by the millers. Tn all oases the bakers' iinicie shows more ash than the itnugkt n-oiii ita same mill and the straight shows more .ash than the patent from the same mill. The same statement does not hold true when the samples from different mills are compared. The colors correspond to the grades, the bakers' grade in all earn showing a more or less gray tint. iMost of the samples of the straight grade show a trace of gray, while none of the patents do. It is evident that these eleven sets may be considered strictly representative of the three grades rcquebicii. ikons n&lt;-i&gt; wtic MHiii'd by cajtnee truu ihe samples sent in by over twenty mills, it is safe to conclude that the large collections of flours dealt with in Bulletin 102 of this Experiment Station were as truly representative n eoutd wL </seg>
            <seg id="p063">■ RELATION OF THE BREAKING STRENGTH OF HOG BONES TO THE COMPOSITION OF THE ASH By F. J. Alway and W. L. Hadlock In Bulletin 107 of this Station it has been shown that there is a close relation between the nature of the food supplied to growing hogs and the strength of their bones, and, further, that an increase in the strength of the bones is not accompanied by any distinct increase in their length, circumference, or volume. The per cent of mineral matter, or bone ash, the specific gravity, and the wall thickness increase with the breaking strength. In order to determine whether any change in the composition of the bone ash accompanies the change in the percentage of mineral matter and in the strength of the bones, we analyzed samples of ash from both the strongest and the weakest bones reported in The ash used as representative of the weak bones was a com - posite of that from the right and left femur, tibia, humerus, ra - dius, and ulna of the lot of four hogs having the weakest bones, while that used as a representative of the strong bones was a similar composite from the lot of four hogs with the strongest bones. The first lot of hogs had been fed 100 per cent corn-meal, while the second had received 10 per cent bone-meal and 90 per cent corn - meal. The bones were reduced to a fine state of division and dried. Those of the first lot were soft and easily pulverized, while the others were very hard and with difficulty reduced to a powder. In order to replace the carbon dioxide lost during the destn; of the organic matter, the samples were treated with a saturated solution of ammonium carbonate, dried and heated in a muffle, kept below redness, to constant weight. Portions of the ash so prepared were dissolved in dilute hydrochloric acid for the determination of calcium, magnesium and phosphoric aciil. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">32 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Weak Strong bones. bones. !verage per cent of mineral matter in green bones 25.4 37.Z verage specific gravity of green bones 1.167 1.346 Average wall thickness of green bones 2.8 mm. 4.1 mm. Average breaking strength of green bones 702 lbs. 1505 lbs. Composition — Calcium oxide, CaO, Magnesium oxide, MgO, Phosphoric oxide, P t O 5 , 52.47% 52.98% 1.24% 1.05% 41.61% 40.93% 95.32% 94.96% Total constituents determined Both lots had practically the same composition, thus indicating that the nature of the food has no effect upon the relative pro - portions of the different constituents of the mineral matter of bones. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">INOCULATED ALFALFA PLANTS. By F. J. Alway and R. M. Pinckney rShutt* has very recently reported the analyses of two samples alfalfa hay produced in 1908 on an Experimental Farm at Lacombe, Alberta. One sample was from a plat which had been thoroly inoculated, while the other was from an adjacent unin - oculated plat. The yields had been at the rate of 7,200 and 2 pounds respectively. There was a marked difference in the pro - portions of nitrogen, the sample from the inoculated plat con - taining 2.8 per cent and that from the other only 2.5 per cut. The above is in accord with the results obtained at this Station in 1907 and 1908. We employed plants from the same field, however. For the analyses alfalfa plants were obtained from a large field which lies two blocks south of the Experiment Station farm, it being marked on the maps as the Ilubbel &amp; Xilson tract. This field had been sown to alfalfa in the spring of 1907 and an ex - cellent stand of plants obtained. At the time the samples were taken in 1907, the number of alfalfa plants per square yard varied from 150 to 450. On the east half of the field a great majority of these plants were uninoculated. One hundred uninoculated plants, including both the above-ground portion and the root to a depth of nine inches or more, were collected, carefully washed free of adherent soil, divided into root and stalk, dried, weighed, and analyzed. The same number of inoculated plants was treated in the same manner. The results, which are shown in the table below, were so unexpected that fresh collections of roots were ni;nli - eleven days later. On the second occasion, three lots of M) in the case of the uninoculated plants were collected on three dif - ferent parts of the field, and two lots of ten each of inoculated plants from the same parts of the field. The result from these are given below. In 1908 the plants were collected early in June, just before the first cutting for hay, fifty of each kind being se - cured from the east end of the field. In selecting the inoculated plants, those of a healthy color were carefully removed from the ground by means of a spade, and the soil detached frrm the roots by washing in a pail of 'Annual Report of the Experimental Farms of the Dominion of </seg>
            <seg id="p066">34 r. After the soil had been washed from the roots, if no nod - ules were found attached the plant was rejected. In more than nine eases out of ten, however, a plant selected on account of its color was found to have nodules. It is probable that the other gram plants were inoculated and that their nodules had been detached in removing them from the ground. The plants selected on account of their color as uninoeulated ones were treated similarly, but in the case of none (if these were nodules found attached to the roots. The plants analyzed were typical in size of the two kinds, the dark preen and the yellowish preen. The inoculated plants were much larger and more vigorous than the uninoeulated. The leaves of the former were dark preen in color, while those of the latter were a lipht yellowish preen. The roots of the inoculated plants were much larper than those of the uninoeulated. Weight a)i&lt;l nitrogen content of inoculated and luiinoculateil alfalfa plant*. r« of a method for distinpuishinp between inoculated and un - ulated plants were it not such a simple matter for any farmer who has once actually seen alfalfa nodules to distinguish between inoculated and uninoeulated plants. No. of plants collected Average weight for each plant Per Cent Nitrogen ~r Inoculated or uninoculated Stalks and Roots leaves In stalks i Aug. 14 Aug. 14 Aug. 14 Aug. 14 1908 June 4 June 4 Inoculated Uninoculated Inoculated Inoculated Uninoculated Uninoculated Uninoculated 100 100 10 10 m 30 Gram* Ornm* 0.1789 0.10K6 2.48 0.0289 0.0279 1.14 0.1476 0.0551 0.0161 0.0200 0.0184 1 Inoculated Uninooulated 50 18.2200 4.8800 2 34 0.3672 0.386(1 1.77 H The ) roots and stems of the inoculated plants were not only from thi ree to fifty times as heavy as the corresponding parts of the lated plants but they also contained about twice as ttfh a on of nitrogen, i above differences in nitrogen content might be made the iminocul The </seg>
            <seg id="p067">ON THE OCCURRENCE OF PRUSSIC ACID IN SORGHUM AND MAIZE By F. J. Aiavay and R. 8. Thimbu,!, E Bulletin 77 of this Station there appeared a full account presence of prussie acid in sorghum plants and of its to the poisoning of cattle by sorghum. Since that time ave felt inclined to attribute the deaths of cattle from [ "cornstalk disease" to the same poison. E. Avery while Chemist of this Station tested many samples stalks from fields in which cattle had died, as well as the is of the dead animals, without finding any evidence of" son. In 1903, Bruennieh* of Australia reported finding prussic acid in Indian corn as well as in sorghum and made quantitative determinations of it in each. He also found that the more abundant the supply of available nitrogen in the soil, and con - sequently the more luxuriant the growth of the sorghum, the higher was the proportion of prussic acid. In the summer of 1907, samples of corn plants from both fertile and impoverished fields were tested at frequent intervals from the time they were four inches high until they formed ears. In no case was even a trace of prussic acid found. The test for this poison is very delicate — so delicate that a single sorghum plant four inches high gives a very distinct reaction ; yet even where a pound of the green stocks of maize was distilled and tested there was no indication of the presence of the acid. A quantitative study of the prussic acid in sorghum was car - ried on at the same time as the above, and Hru.'iinich's finding on sorghum were confirmed. As an illustration of this, the results of the analysis of three samples of sorghum from the same field are given below. Part of this field had been heavily manured and part had received no manure. All of the sorghum plants were of volunteer growth among alfalfa. •Journal of the Chemical Society (London) 1903. Transactions, </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 36 Lot Color Average length Per cent of of stalks. prussic acid. I Dark green 50 cm 0.01215 Yellowish green 35 cm 0.00499 Yellow 22 cm 0.00405 rln February, 1907, a field of cornstalks near Broken Bow in ch several cattle had just diied was visited by one of the authors company with Dr. Peters, and all the suckers collected from the stalks on one acre. Part of these were fed to some calves and the rest were subjected to a thoro test for prussic acid, the test being made at Broken Bow as soon as the suckers were brought in from the field, so that there might be no possibility of its being lost between the time the plants were gathered and the time the test was made. No trace of prussic acid was found. The calves which were fed as many of the suckers as they would eat and were al - lowed no other food for twenty-four hours showed no ill effects. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">By A. T. Peters This disease is hy no means new. It has been reported for many years and the theories regarding it are numerous. Some of the best pathologists have busied themselves with the investigation of this disease. From time to time commissions have been appointed by agricultural societies of the different countries to study the breeding of live stock, and the infectiousness. cans*', and dire of this disease. Very little can be learned from the early writers. In fact, the early literature on this subject has a tendency towards superstition, in that it invariably attributes the cause of epidemic abortion to sympathy, by saying that the animal is endowed with the instinct to know when another animal is so affected and that the odor or some mysterious omen would cause the animals to abort. The next theory was that abortion was caused thru bad feed, especially moldy grain. Investigation has shown that this is possible only in very rare instances. It was not until about 1885 that Nocard, who had then undertaken the investigation of this disease, clearly pointed to the contagiousness of this affection. He was the first to study carefully the exudate from affected ani - mals in order to discover, if possible, the true and exciting caust&gt;. Prom that time the cause of this disease was attributed to the dis - charge of aborting cows, this discharge being carried on the straw and litter to the other animals, and this to a certain extent is true. It was in 1897 that Bang verified the idea that this disease is contagious and demonstrated how the bacillus could be cultivated on artificial media and described the organism in detail. It was also thru Bang's investigations that the real cause of this disease was discovered and the fact determined that a large portion of thi3 was due to the male. Heretofore the experiments had been exclusively made on the female by using strong disinfectants both internally and externally, thereby hoping to eradicate the disease, but it was found that by the most painstaking aseptic methods abortion could not be prevented. Prof. Bang called </seg>
            <seg id="p070">38 attention to the male and now by a combination of disinfecting the male and the female good results are obtained. Accidental Abortion. — In dealing with abortion it should be first ascertained if it is of a noncontagious character. Nonconta - gious or accidental abortion may be due to a number of different causes; such as fright, spoiled food, violent purgation, injuries, thru bad treatment by an ill-tempered attendant, slipping on the ice, etc. One may enumerate a number of things that may cause this trouble but suffice it to say that when one cow aborts the owner should be very careful to look into the details and to ascertain whether it occurred thru an accident or whether it is contagious abortion. It is far better to be cautious and advise the owner to use the necessary precautions which are prescribed under conta - gious abortion. It is better to start the treatment early than too late. It has been the writer's experience that lit is best to take this precaution. Contagious Abortion.— If a considerable number of cows in a herd haw alxnted within a certain season or if the same cows aborted in two or more successive seasons, if the disease has the tendency to spread to the other cows and especially if there is a history that the neighboring herds are affected with contagious alx&gt;rtion, then there is little doubt but that one is dealing witli a case of contagious abortion. It is important to know whether any new stock has been added to the herd, for in a large per cent of cases the herds have been affected thru this channel. Proof was not always conclusive that the cow that aborted came from an nfTected herd, but it is true that cows brought into a herd very often abort, even when there has not been a case of abortion in the herd from which it came. This is not a case of contagious abortion but it can so affect a herd if drastic measures are not pursued. This is one of the sources of infection that should be carefully guarded against. Symptoms. — The symptoms of this disease are not plainly vis- ible in the early stages, but when one examines a number of cows in a herd where abortion exists and the vagina is carefully studied he will find that the mucous membrane is somewhat reddened and </seg>
            <seg id="p071">39 I it it has a very slight elevation on which there is a peculiar erup - n. This eruption may escape the eye that is not thoroly trained, it is not very proiniiit'iit. Frun •bottiBg cows there is usually I ny, fiocky discharge. The cow may be restless for thre • &lt;&gt;r four in-s before the expulsion of the young. In some instances Ub ma symptoms for a day or two by the udder filling up and the s of the vulva thickening, showing the signs of natural gestation, lis is accompanied by nervous excitement. Where cows carry ■ir foetus for five to seven months the usual symtoms are the ollen condition of the vulva and later on entire taxation. In dition to these symptoms there may be a free flowing of exudate d as the symptoms increase this becomes more copious and may streaked with blood. When these symptoms appear the expul - &lt;n of the young is near at hand. Thk Caisk. — There is no question that the disease is o by a germ, which has been described by Nocard and Bang. This germ cannot be killed very readily and on account of its 1 found in the discharge from the vagina and also on the male animal it is important that the stalls and floors be thoroly disinfected and that the bedding which may have been contaminated be burned, and also the foetus. Cows affected should he isolated and should have ( ne attendant who does not take care of or come in contact with the healthy cows. It is important that one person be Mngaad to the infected herd and that he use the necessary precautions and that he do not walk into the stables where healthy cows are kept. Before he leaves the infected herd he should thoroly disinfect him - self and leave the infected garments in a suitable place so that they can do no harm. If a cow aborts in the main stable she should 1k&gt; immediately removed and the premises should ba as carefully dis - infected as possible, using strong lye solution with plenty of hot water and a five per cent solution of carbolic acid. The most painstaking disinfection should be at once commenced. The ani - mal in the quarantine pen should be treated immediately as follows : If the afterbirth has not come away within five to eight hours it should lie taken away by one who knows how to perform this Dj tion. The animal should then l&gt;e irrigated with a two per cent solution of permanganate of potash, and the limbs, tail, etc., should </seg>
            <seg id="p072">40 be washed with soap and water and then with this permanganate of potash solution. One capsule containing oil and kreso is then placed into the vagina. This capsule on dissolving disinfects the vagina and the vagina should be irrigated every other day with this permanganate of potash solution and a capsule inserted. In addi - tion to this the cow should be fed carbolic acid in the feed. The carbolic acid should be prepared as follows : Crude carbolic acid is liquefied and a small amount of glycerin is added to this to keep it in a liquid form. You start in by mixing with the bran two drams of this solution and then gradually increase the dose until it amounts to about six drams per day. The dose is increased according to the virulence of the disease. Best results have been obtained by jriving large doses to cattle where the per cent of loss w;is very prreat. We have had the best of success with this treat - ment. Eighty-one out of 211 herds treated reported good results. EPhe bull is probably the carrier of the infection, and there - the bull should be thoroly disinfected before and after each e. Use seme antiseptic solution, as a tablespoonful of perman - te of potash to a pailful of water. A rubber tube can be used enough to slip into the sheath of the bull, a funnel is fitted I other end of the tube, and when this funnel is elevated it will the solution well into the sheath and with the right hand the itor can work the solution thoroly to all parts of the sheath, imbs of the bull should also be sponged with a good antiseptic Sterility. — Sterility is one of the sequels of contagious abor - tion. The reason for this is that the microbes enter the Fallopian tubes and affect and eventually destroy the ovaries and therefore (•(inception cannot occur. Many treatments have been used for this affection and there are a great many patent medicines on the market to be used for this disease but our investigations have shown that medicinal treatment has little or no effect. Out of 209 animals that were apparently sterile, 86 remained sterile in the herd for ar or more, 41 for eighteen months or more, while conception occurred in 11 which successfully gave birth to a calf. Post - mortems were held on 74 of these animals and all were found to have diseased ovaries, 42 out of the 74 having one ovary affected </seg>
            <seg id="p073">41 while 32 had both ovaries affected. It is interesting to know that the owners of these animals used the following remedies: dilata - tion of the us utiri, irrigating with sterilized alkaline water, usim: yeast treatment, and the various patent medicines offered for the cure of this disease. We lost trace of 135 of these animals, but our mTWtiiffrtiriB shows that remedies are of little avail sin&lt;-. - 100 per cent of those on which we held post-mortems had diseased ovaries. This should discourage the owner from keeping cows that will not conceive, especially if the animal has aborted. The animals should be fattened as soon M possible and sold on the market. Conclusions. — Abortion in cattle is caused by a germ which is found in the exudate of the female and of the bull. Therefore both cows and bulls should be thoroly disinfected before and after breeding. Newly purchased cows should be kept in quarantine and should lie washed with an antiseptic solution. A cow that has aborted ; h aid be immediately placed in quarantine and an attend - ant should take care of these animals and avoid MBUBg in contact with healthy animals. The bull should be disinfected before and immediately after each service. Cows should not be allow - calve in the presence of other animals. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">TUBERCULOSIS By A. T. Peters • Pi ring the winter of 1907, when the legislature was in session. ution was passed requiring the Department of Animal Pa - r to investigate tuberculosis among swine in our State. An appropriation of $1,000 was made to carry out the provisions of the resolution. Prior to this time there had been nothing done on ac - count of laek of funds. Our State Veterinary Department has only a meager appropriation, which barely covers the expenses of police work. For this reason it eoidd not take up in detail the work of tuberculosis. After the appropriation became available, our department im - mediately began to study the question of tuberculosis. We made arrangements with the Bureau of Animal Industry whereby « cured the names of owners who had shipped live stock to the South Omaha market and who had part of their animals condemned for tul&gt;ereulosis. We afterwards tried to visit their farms to ascertain the conditions existing on these farms. It was important for us to lie familiar with the kind of live stock these farmers owned, the number of cattle and hogs on the place, the way they were fed, and whether, previous to our visit, they had any knowledge of their stock having tuberculosis. The (iovernment repotted iJSl farms as sending tuberculous stock. These 12M1 farms were located in fifty - five counties. Of these fifty-five counties, forty-seven were for swine tuberculosis and forty-one for tuberculosis in cattle. In thirty-three of these counties tultcrculosis was reported in both cattle It is interesting to note that tuberculosis both among cattle and mmmg hogs has Ix-en confined largely to one center in our Stat.\ This was indeed very surprising to us. Certain groups of counties are very much more affected with tuberculosis than others. It has also Ixen found that when large shipments, especially of hogs, come </seg>
            <seg id="p075">43 from these counties, the percentage of eoadeoffistmM is very la running HMtiwi more than :{ per cent. When the perrwtag* of condemnations for any gvrtn day has ben very large, an exami - nation of the records showed that the counties known to be greatly affected with tuberculosis in swine had supplied the &lt;rreater per - centage of that day's killing. This was tested repeatedly when we would receive information from the ( ioverninent Inspector that the condemnations were unusually numerous. This proves the assertion made by Dr. Burton Rogers several years ago, when he undertook to tag MM hogl before the fanueis unloaded them from their wagons. These tagged lious were always killed separately. In this way he was able to trace back to the owner every tuberculous h&lt;&gt;tr. He - that &lt;*ut of about 600 different bog-raiaen bringing li&lt;&gt;«.'s to this one market, thirty-ivne brought in all the tuberculous hog*. Our work in Nebraska in cooperation with the (ioverninent in trying to trace the source of tuberculous animals is giving evidence that Dr. Rog - ers 's statement is true that infection comes from a small area, and that if the State was so provided with funds and facilities and a defi - nite knowledge of where the infection existed that it could parehaaa and slaughter these animals, and thereby clean up infected ur. would materially aid in stamping out tuberculosis in a short time. I wish to mention here that not only is it necessary for the State officers to be provided with ample funds to carry on this work, bat I find that it is also necessary to have the people well educated in the fundamental principles of tuberculosis, and the owners of live stock thoroly conversant with the danirers of this disease. They should know how the disease spreads, how to prevent it, and that it economical proposition to them to study the importance of hlher culosis. Tuberculosis amenjr bog* is far more treacher.ni-; than hag cholera, which only vis : ts the farms once in many years, as proved by statistics, while tuberculi sis remains on the premises permanently if the owner does not do anything to eradicate this disease, and will eventually drive him out of business. For this reason it is ini|&gt;or- fhat the methods in our State work should Ir&gt; thoroly revised, t not only lanre appropriation shall be grated, but provisione be made to thoroly educate the farmers and stockmen as to the dangers of tlvs disease. This education should lx- one that would </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 44 f scare or frighten the owner so that he would feel that the rature he was receiving was an exaggeration, thereby making him an enemy to tuberculosis legislation instead of promoting the cause. I have been watching the progreai that is Ix'ing made in other States regarding th : s important subject, and the more I have studied the question the more I have become convinced that when the stockman is thoroly familiarized with the issue and given plenty of time to think over the question, he is a very good man to work with, and would favor reasonable legislation. Knowing this fact, I started the work in our State by organizing a reading club. This reading club is largely composed of Carmen and stockmen thruout the State. Ninety per cent of the members make stock-raising their principal occupation. These men were interested in the reading club, and the only requirement made was that after ■ certain period they must return question blanks, properly filled out, before they could secure new literature. Lack of funds prevented us from printing literature, but the Government and the experiment stations, having a large number of pamphlets that are well adapted for this work. were applied to and sufficient copies se ured. The.se were then gone over and questions prepared. These questions were sent to the mem - bers of the club, who filled out and returned the reply blanks to the office. After the blanks had been returned, another pamphlet was sent to them. Xot only have we used the members just for the read - ing club, but we have secured a number of them to do missionary work in their own locality and secure new members. Many of the members have urged stockmen and dairymen in their community t &gt; have their herds tested for tuberculosis by our Department or by the local veterinarian. In this way much good has been accomplished. We also feel that thru this reading club we are securing a large number of people who will be willing to give accurate information to our various stock associations and to the members of our legislature if it becomes necessary to pass a suitable law for the eradication of tuberculosis from the State. Largely thru the reading club and thru cooperation of the Bureau of Animal Industry we have been able to test 63 herds of cattle, with a total number of 3602 head. Three and sixty-eight hundredths per cent of these cattle reacted to the tuberculin test. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Tut itty-tltird Annual Report 45 Out of 281 farms reported to us, 222 were visited by repr atives of our department and the conditions carefully studied. We found that on many of the farms where tuberculosis existed mOBfl the hogs they were receiving separator milk. We noticed, however, that a larger percentage than had been expected had never rtehred dairy products, and that skim milk was by no means entirely ac - countable for the infection of tuberculosis in hogs. Two herds in particular where there was a large condemnation had not been re - ceiving dairy products. It was discovered later thru the tuber - culin test and the post-mortem examinatii us that tuberculosis existed among the cattle. Previous to destroying these animals, sam - ples of the fecal matter were secured, and examinations of the same revealed tubercle bacilli. The method given in Bulletin No. 99 of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United States Department of Agri - culture, was used for making these examinations. I have become more and more a believer that hogs bt affected to a large extent through fecal matter, because of the habit of breeders of allowing their hogs to follow cattle. There i - question but that this practice gives occasion for a large percentage of the condemnations among the hogs. Thru this matter the lym - phatic system becomes infected, and glandular tuberculosis, which is by far the most frequent, is caused by hogs being compelled to fol - low and gain their sustenance thru the offal of diseased cattle. We are making careful examinations along this line to verify mon clusively this statement. But enough evidence is at hand at this time to warrant the assertion that if our system of feeding hogs changed the number of tuberculnis hogs would l&gt;e greatly red There is no question but that we have overlooked the great source of infecticn, that is the fecal matter, and on account of this oversight the States that are supplying a large percentage of the hogs have suffered such a rapid increase in the disease. The conclusions of our laboratory work are as follows : 11. Tubercle bacilli may pass thru the intestinal tract of cattle d retain their virulence. 2. Tubercle bacilli in the feces of cattle may readily contami - nate dairy products and cause infection in hogs. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">46 us produced are necessary to definitely establish the presence of 4. Ingest ion experiments with hogs, previously proven to be free from the disease by application of the tuberculin test, are val - uable means of demonstrating tulwrcle bacilli in the manure of ■ Hogs should not be permitted to run in the same pens with especially if the latter are known to be tuberculous. E6. Consuming milk from tuberculous cows, even tho there is no ection of the udder, is a source of danger to man. RThe number of tuberculous cows which show no symtomsof but which excrete virulent tubercle bacilli in their manure 2iently large to make this an important factor in the control ;rculosis. E operation at the packing centers between the Government ; State is practical, fruitful of results, and important, and be cultivated and perfected. The Government is in a position to aid the State authorities in a most effective way if the State au - thorities are only willing to accept the assistance. It is thru the Government Inspectors that the State can locate the infected cen - ters ; and then if these places are visited by representatives and the conditions noted, the representatives can &gt; ; n the larger percentage of cases persuade the owners to clean up their herds. It is a pleasure to me to report that 66 of the 281 farms reported to us have cleaned up their herds in one way or the other, either by using the tuberculin test or by sending the animals to the abattoirs subject to inspection ; and that these people are assisting the department at this time. They are very desirous of not having diseased stock on their premises. It is a remarkable fact that 92 per cent of the 281 farmers reported that previous to our visit they had no knowledge of any disease in Sherd, and were very much surprised when they were informed animals had been destroyed. This is all the more emphasized e hogs had been condemned by the inspectors of the Government . One of the embarrassing features that we had to contend with siting these farms was to inform the owner that the Govern- </seg>
            <seg id="p079">47 merit had condemned animals of his shipment, for it is a fact that repeatedly some of the best-looking animals, and the ones that topped the markets ;it the abattoirs, have been condemned. It has been a surprise to the owner when we would visit him a week later and tell him that four, five or six of his animals had been condemn - ed, and it is a very difficult matter to explain to the stockman how f;it animals in a prime condition and lopping the market could lx - condemned by the Government Inspectors. And then comes the task of convincing this man that the Government official really did find the disease in the carcass, and that it would be well for him to clean up the remainder of the herd. Here ajrain comes in the value of resorting to literature and correspondence. I will admit that we could not at the first time convince an owner that the remainder of his herd was in danger, but by supplying him with literature we convinced him that it is possible for animals in the best condition to be diseased. These men have beeOMM thoroly interested and are working for better conditions. In going over the map of our State which shows the affected areas I must again call attention tfl the fact that has been observed by Dr. Rogers, that the infection is located in but few districts, and to secure this information I believe that it would be well for our Government to make regula - tions by which the animals could be identified when they reached the killing floors. Much as I have investigate.! this matter and spoken with the proper authorities about a tagging and identifica - tion system of this kind, they have not thought it feasible. I am sure that the time will come when such tairging will be necessary, for if the Government or the States will continue to follow the sounr of infection and find the same, as we have done in our State, it will show that tasrginsr i s the only feasible way of eradicating; this disease, and that it is much cheaper than any other method. At the present time it does not seem popular, but I believe that by proper agitation, bringing the matter before the public, the opposition would soon be greatly diminished. The work that is in progress at this time is a continued study of the source of infection and the promotion of our reading dub thruout the entire State, so that the people will make re&lt;|iie - have their herds tested instead of being compelled by law to have </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 48 it done. From now on this work will be conducted by the State Veterinary Department. The importance of this campaign of education is shown by the fact that if we had assistance enough wj could test practically as many herds in one month as we tested in the twelve months last year. It is hoped that aid will be given tc the State authorities to meet these demands by the creation of sani - tary boards similar to the ones existing in Pennsylvania and Min - nesota. From our reports and from the statistics at hand it seems as tho the infection has not gained any considerable foothold in the State of Nebraska, and that if suitable measures were to be enacted at an early date, the disease could be prevented from spreading and eventually stamped out. The Bang system has been advocated in our State, and also a modification of this system made by Dr. Johnson, but neither of these has been found to be practical on our farms, for it seems to be very expensive to maintain this system. Several of the best breeders in our State have been investigating the question, and no doubt ex - periments along this line will be taken up. P Vaccination against this disease has not been recommended, ccount of lack of funds ; and, furthermore, as our department considered it still in its experimental stage, we for this reason did not care to use this treatment, as it may prove a hindrance to the eradication of tuberculosis. The department is watching with great interest the experiments conducted by others along these lines. The tuberculin test has proved very satisfactory, and thru this agency we have a means for detecting tuberculosis in a herd, and we can very readily clean up a herd. This work encountered a great deal of opposition, for the reason that the State had no compensation to offer for these cattle. It is interesting to know that in every instance where tuberculosis had been found on the post-mortem floors and the remaining herd visited and tested with tuberculin, evidence of the .lisetse was found in the herd. K conclusion I wish to say that by giving our State proper leg - i, and by a continual and plentiful dissemination of proper ire to the stockmen and farmers, thereby enlisting their </seg>
            <seg id="p081">49 Ety cooperation instead of their antagonism, and by the splen - aid of the agricultural press, progress in stamping out tuber - sis will be achieved. E following is a list of bulletins of the Bureau of Animal In - and the Experiment Stations that haw lieen secured for the r club in our State : Eular 118 of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United States ent of Agriculture: "The Unsuspected but Dangerously ous Cow." Bulletin 92 of the Iowa Experiment Station, Ames, Iowa: "Tuberculosis in Swine." Elletin 277 of the New York Experiment Station. QoMVa, "The Bang Method of Controlling Tuberculosis, with an tion of ats Application." BJulletin 44 of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United States rtment of Agriculture: "Infeotiveness of Milk of Cows which Reacted to the Tuberculin Test." Elletin 38 of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United States nent of Agriculture: "Tuberculosis of the Food-produeinu' s." Paper by Dr. G. A. Johnson, of Sioux City, Iowa: "The Dispo - sition of Tuberculous Cattle." Brcular 79 of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United States ment of Agriculture: "The Tuberculin Test for Tab Bulletin 78 of the New Hampshire Experiment Station, Durham. N. H. : "Bovine Tuberculosis." Bulletin 77 of the North Dakota Experiment Station, Agricul - tural College, N. D.: "Bovine Tuberculosis in Herds." Bulletin 126 of the Wisconsin Experiment Station, M;i Wis. : ' ' Two Ways of Treating Tuberculosis in Herds. ' ' Krcular 70 of the Bureau of Animal Industry. United States ment of Agriculture: "Tuberculosis of Cattle." Bulletin 108 of the Ohio Experiment Station, Wooster, Ohio. : "Bovine Tuberculosis." I </seg>
            <seg id="p082">50 /&lt; of the questions prepared on o bulletin which ims sent to tin tin mix rs of the Tulx -ratios-is Reading Club and the ansin rs to the same. EWhafl is the cause of tuberculosis? — Lack of ronlight, too tabling, poor vi ntilation. feeding milk from tulxTculous , and coming in contact with tuberculous animals. The au-e of this disease is the growth within the animal tissues retable organism known as the tubercle bacillus. Bis tuberculosis hereditary 1 — Tuberculosis is not hereditary tendency of making the individual more liable to tubercular in may be inherited. 3. What is tuberculin! — Tuberculin is a liquid obtained by heatinir tubercular material until the germs are killed and then ■trauriag the same to remove their dead tissues. Els tuberculin a cure for tul&gt;ereulosis! — Tuberculin is not 1 for tuberculosis, but it has proved to be the best tiring Id tc the presence of the disease. E5. Can people take or pet tuberculosis from meat or milk ot' rculous animals ? — People can take tuberculosis thru milk from rculous animals if it is not sterilized and thru the meat of rculous animals if it is not thoroly cooked. Els tuberculosis contagion* like measles or smallpox? — No. perm disease and can be caught from the sputum or feees of i animals and also from the sputum of the human family, tnes the whole herd becomes infected from a single animal the carelessness of an attendant. 7. How is the tuberculin used in testing for tuberculosis? — Four temperatures are taken two hours apart, then the tuberculin is injected, and within eight to ten hours after the injection four temperatures are again taken two hours apart. If there is a rise of two or more degrees in temperature after the injection then the animal is said to react. 8. If a cow has tuberculosis, how can you tell it by using tuber - culin? — A rise in temperature of two or more degrees within eight to sixteen hours after the injection and continuing for several hours will indicate that the animal has tuberculosis. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">51 ■9. Does tabennlin always cause reaction when an animal hut rculosis? — It does not cause reaction in animals that are in the stages of the disease. 10. "Why do you think that there should be more case - tuberculosis in hogs than in cattle! — As a rule hogs are confined in darker and damp quarters and they are more susceptible to E;. They get it from following tuberculous cows and from ng the milk of tuberculous cows, as the trerm passes off in the e and also to some extent in the milk. 11. Why should cattle kept in close, dark barns be more liable to have tuberculosis than when kept in light, airy barns or on pas - tures? — Hecause the conditions for the bacteria to multiply are not vi tv favorable in light, airy barns or on pastures. The germs will thrive in darkness and foulness but when they come in contact witli the sun and fresh air they are destroyed. Poor ventilation soon affects the lungs, putting the whole system in poor shape for resist - ing the disease. E. Are you able from external appearance to tell whether or animal has tuberculosis? — Xo, not until it is in a very an state and not always then. 13. Will tuberculin produce tabereokMMi — Xo. Why? Be - cause tuberculin is obtained only from dead bacteria of tuberculosis ; that is, the germ is killed during the process of making the tuber- E Is meat from a tuberculous animal always dangerous? — hy? — Tt is only dangerous when some of the body glands arc 1, but when some of the minor glands are affected the whole eed not be condemned. The disease may be only specialized t generalized. 1"). After an animal is killed how can you tell whether it had tuberculosis? — One can tell by the grayish white granules Ik of millet seed usually found on the liver or digestive organs and on the lungs or glands of the neck. If the animal is badly at! the insides of the ribs, where the lungs are located, are full of white grayish granules. 16. Do calves inherit tuberculosis from their parents? — 0, </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 52 do not inherit tuberculosis from their parents but may get it thru drinking the milk and by coming in close contact with the parent. They inherit a tubercular tendency. 17. Why is it necessary to take the temperature of an animal before injecting tuberculin? — To determine whether the tempera - ture is normal. When an animal is driven or excited or in periods of sexual heat the temperature affects the accuracy of the test. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">PRODUCTION OF A NEW FORM IN WHEAT By E. G. Montgomery The accompanying chart gives some interesting historical data regarding the occurrence of what appears to be a new type of wheat. At least it seems new so far as the ancestry of either parent can be traced. In 1903 a number of crosses were made of Turkey Red, ■ bearded wheat, by Big Frame, a smooth wheat. Records wwt kept by Professor Keyser on a number of these crosses for three generations, in a study of Mendelian characters. The only char - acters which could be followed with accuracy were the bearded &lt;&gt;r beardless type of spike and in this the eroaaei followed Mendel's law, 1 the hybrids being distinguished as an intermediate type. From the first generation, grown in 1904, three intermediates were selected for planting, 100 seeds bang planted from each. Fran the second generation in 1905, five bearded (b), five intermediate (i), and five awnless (a) plants were selected from each. x were taken on all progeny in 1906, and the study of Mendelian characters was then dropped, but a few selections were made and continued, to test their possible value as new stocks of wheat. In 1906 and previous to that, no unusual form had been noted, but in 1907 one centgener, No. Ill, was markedly different from the others. The straw was about 6 to 10 inches shorter and the wheat nipened fully one week earlier than the other plats. All the plants in the centgener of 100 plants appeared to be of thi3 type. None of these plants were noted in other centgeners. (For convenience we will hereafter refer to this as new type A.) In the fall of 1907 three plants from this centgener of new tyi&gt;e plants were planted each to a separate centgener, and these all came true to the new type in 1908. Other centgeners from plants of the pure bearded or pure awnless type were also planted. All the 1908 plats came true as expected, but in four other </seg>
            <seg id="p086">54 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska eentgeners, all from 1907, Plat 108, a few plants of the new type occurred, 2 or 3 plants to each centgener. Also 5 eentgeners were planted from 5 selected plants from 1907, Centgener No. 113. All these came true to the regular bearded type except that in one, No. 35, a few plants of a new type occurred, similar to the other inen - tioned above except a little taller and later in maturing. (Here - after referred to as new type B.) In 1908 we could divide for convenience the new types into ups: first, the three plats 3"2 to 34, from l!)O7 Plat No. Ill, — all of this type A ; second, the few new type plants exactly like them occurring for the first time in Centgeners 27 to 31 ; and third, a few plants of a similar new type but larger and later in maturing, in Plat No. 35. A few plants were selected from each of the three classes and planted, each plant to a centgener, in the fall of 1908. In every case they came true in 1909, except that a few reversions, less than one per cent, of both the original bearded and the beardless type occurred. Also normal plants were selected from each cciit - gener in which the new type occurred, as well as normal plants from centgeners that had not borne such new type. In most of the centgeners from normal plants that had sister plants of the new type, as Centgener 68, a few type A plants again occurred altho most of the plants would be normal. Also the plants of new type B from 1908, Centgener 35, came true but, as in 1908, they differed from the other new type in being larger and later. A most interesting occurrence, however, was the appearance of a few plants of type A in 1909, Centgener No. 43 to 4&lt;i, this being the sixth generation from the cross and the first time in this direct line that the new type had occurred. Ee number of plants grown from each type and the amount ation from type is shown by the following table, which te data for 1909. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Twenty-third Annual Report Type This table shows that when normal plants were selected from plats where a few new tjf* OMWNd for tlie first time to 32, see chart) out of 1660 plants produced, 51, or about 3 per cent, were of the new type. Erom 31 selected plants of new type A about 2170 plants were ied, all coming true except 23 reversions to both the original t types. An interesting point in regard to these uiiii case of the 9 smooth plants of the parent type, since all these ons had been from pure bearded parents, and none of the ti type had ever appeared. Five selected new type B plants produced about 350 plants and 3 reversions. I our composite samples were taken in 1908 from 4 plats, plats to 3f&gt;, the one which produced type \i. This.' did not show any of this type in 1908 produced in 1901) ants, 18 of which w,&gt;re type I hut). This was the generation from the cross. It seems that the new type A must have been in some way the result of crossing Turkey Red and Big Frame wheat. this type remained latent four, five and six generations before appearing as a new form. Then when planted it came true to type as a mutant is supposed to do. This suggests the possibility of a new type, resulting from a cross, lying dormant for many £. :|I. #!=££:: El) e a r d e d i from plats g few type A K , plants se- in MHIH Tvpe B plants w- leotedio 1900.. Plata 4:$ to 4i&gt;, com- posite samples of r plats to :!.'&lt; in 1908. All nor- inal plants 25 31 5 4 lfi.")0 2IT0 350 00 t itiOO 14 2(12 ."&gt;1 9 2147 1 a </seg>
            <seg id="p088">56 generations and then appearing in numbers as an apparently new form. Another interesting feature was the occurrence of sterile spikes among the new type plants. The heads were much longer than ordinarily while the spikelets usually developed 4 to 5 flowers, the ordinary being 2 to 3 flowers. The sterile flowers had well developed ovaries but the anthers were undersized. DeVries also mentions the occurrence of sterile flowers in one of the "mutants" of ()&lt; hhUk ra Lamarckiana. In fact the whole behavior of thi&lt; wheat is very similar to the case of mutation DeVries reports in O, Lamarckiana, especially in the constant recurrence of the new type in selected strains of the original, and in the reversions to original type which occur in pure selections of the new type. This all suggests the possibility of a cross sometimes causing the pro - duction of ■■teats. The fact that all other wheat crosses «r«i have made have followed Mendel's laws so far as observations have been nuidc. and only this one has given the new type, suggests I II ' 1 t Tl i \\\* ** Tl I I \ II i iW Q fiWICO YV\ AIT Q f%^ % Wl Q W% 11 VI 11O11 O 1 II* Q \T liidl Ji&gt; m\ it iit.1 i i it n it ii una in tl &gt; all ill dii nil U.Ml&lt;il nav, </seg>
            <seg id="p089">57 1 3 •&gt; Pig. 1. The new type and two parents. 1, Turkey Red; 2, Big Frame: 3, the new type A. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 58 Fig. 2. The occurrence of one of the new type wheat plants in a plat of ordinary type, 1909. The above plat No. 44 had come true, normal bearded from selected plants for six generations before the new type appeared. About six per cent of the plants proved to be new type. They are about eight inches shorter and seven days earlier than the normal tvnft. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">59 Twenty-third Annual Report t3. Plat of the new type A in 1909, showing reversion of one plant .to original tvpe of Big Frame. No Big Frame plants &gt;&gt;»«» «« u "^ for six generations, hence its omirrence here was all the more striking. In 2500 new type plants, 10N 3 and lb No plants occurred. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">WINTFR WHfAT PEDIGREE. Hoymml hf-rJed CD Moriuye of ijp*$ </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Turkey red x bic frahe. 6 Gf/Kf/e/moNs /90S /fCf </seg>
            <seg id="p094">SUBSTATION By W. W^ Bubr. Bn the spring of 1907, studies were commenced to determine most practical method of storing water in the soil and the lods of cropping which would utilize to the best advantage soil moisture. GKNKKAL CONDITIONS. FPart of the land used in making these studies is bench or sec - bottom land, and part is table-land. The soil on the table-land very similar to that on the bench. On the bench land, sheet water is only 35 to 40 feet below the surface. It may be that sub - irrigation takes place with deep-rooted plants like alfalfa. On the table-land the sheet water is from 200 to 250 feet below the surface and crops can not get water by subirrigation. This absolute de - pendence of the crop on surface precipitation gives the best con - ditions for the study of soil moisture. TYl'KOF SOIL Before taking up the discussion of the sampling it may be well to consider the type of soil that is found on the Station farm. as it is very important that one bear in mind the character of the soil on which one is working. Different results will necessarily be obtained as the character of the soil vares. The soil of the Station farm is what is known as "hard" or "short grass" land, this term being used to distinguish this type of soil from the sandier soils. It is called "loess" soil and would he classified as the silt loam. On the more level portions of the farm the native vegetation EPhe data presented in this article are the result of work done thru cooperation of the Substation and the Physical Labora - ureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">63 Iainly buffalo and fTUM grMM, while on the broken i&gt;or - »f the farm the vegetation is mainly bunch grass. The soil te uniform to a considerable depth, the most noticeable ; being less organic matter in the subsoil, indicated by the ; in the color of the soil. This change in color usually be - ithin three or four feet of the surface. The following table ghrw the results of Mght mechanical analyses made of the upland soils : </seg>
            <seg id="p096">Agrti ifurai £ ■peril :en£ tatio 0/ eftras, va g us o&gt; m v © — m 5 f-H i-h i-^ « — © t-'aj©' i—i ©aoo i— t i-^ «cr-ac aor-iH id CD 00 -i / — a o'ra »-* i— t * fc I | I h- i 2 1 4 &lt; 4* I 8 •* 1 °. v rt rt C3 JOI.T* -h so eo S9$ 35Jg5 oo r-ao ?^ c^ cc to-* co 388' KS I I I I I h- J * I s l g looo?) k SS3 Ki 3'SS ioaoa&gt; ■■^ M ■* ao r-r- — ft- 335 isco 983 xna r,3 1 S Q I I 00 O N us id oo I I ©ad &gt;d | I vtf©i-l Hoe # ::: I | I I •5 gj- C « la r~i 1 a 1 8 .'on — i • 'Eh h-.i rji-c© S»)M^- ■M I-H l-l « h h I s eccMO t-Ni-i ,,- «-H &lt;— ~- »Csl — * ■s g r~ i g w— I i L ©£© ooo ooo ©oo ... OSO poo SO© 5 a 2 u IS 8 HOOO fe &lt;n"i-h I-BM 3: a: ■&lt;»• r-io© i— i ooor^ ,., 3* 5) ci« i-i IMM Ump) rtSMM --©»« •-INM -hpjco H«« </seg>
            <seg id="p097">65 From Table 1 we note that the soil has a low per cent of all material coarser than a very fine sand. This with a low per cent of organic matter would indicate that the soil would bake or crust badly. There is, however, a correspondingly low per cent of clay and the soil is easily tilled. No trouble has been experienced as yet with the soil baking or running together badly. We do, how - ever, find that under the drying winds of spring before tillage commences the soil cracks open. MANNER OF SAMPLING The soil samples are taken with a tube sampler. The cutting edge of the tube is about three thirty-seconds of an inch smaller than the inner diameter of the tube. The tube is marked in foot sections. After a core of soil is taken the tube is simply inverted and the sample slips out. This method of sampling allows very little chance for the mixing of the various foot sections. After taking the sample it is put in an air-tight box, taken to the labora - tory, and weighed, to get the moist weight of the soil. It is then heated to 110° C until dry, and reweighed, the loss in weight being considered the weight of the water. DKFTH OK SAMPLING. During the season of 1907, most of the samples were taken to a depth of only three feet, but some to a depth of six feet. It was found that the moisture was affected below this depth, and be - ginning with 1908 most of the sampling was carried to at least six feet. During the latter part of the season of 1908 a ten-foot tube was procured, and samples were taken to a depth of ten feet. This year (1909) we have sampled all of our fields to a depth of 15 feet, as we found that the moisture was affected even below 10 feet. The reason for such deep sampling is to find the point where the moisture content remains constant; that is, the point where the moisture is not affected by the tillage on the surface or by growing crops. We feel that it is necessary to do this deeper sampling in order to determine how far moisture may move up from below and supply water to the crop, and also to find out if </seg>
            <seg id="p098">66 • the water that is below the reach of the plant this year may not be drawn upwards during the winter and be used by the crop the following year. "We must have these determinations before we can ascertain how much water was used by the crop, for altho we know how much water has been used from the upper six feet of the soil we can not say that this represents all the water that was used unless we know that no water was used from below this depth. A portion of the farming land is what is commonly known as bench or second bottom land. The remainder is table or upland. On the bench land, sheet water is from 35 to 40 feet below the surface, and on the table it is from 200 to 250 feet below the sur - face. The soil on the bench is very similar to that on the table. EXPLANATION OF TABLES. kThe column marked "depth" gives the depth in foot sections t the samples were taken. The date of sampling appears at top or above each column. All moisture weights are figured on the basis of the dry weight of soil ; for example, 10 per cent represents that for each hundred units of dry soil there were ten units of water present. The percentages given are the averages of all the samples taken at that depth and on that date in the field or plat. The averages shown are made by averaging three. six, or ten feet as the case may be. HISTORY OF THE FIELDS. The results given under the head barley, oats, wheat, and corn were obtained on the table-land under a system of cropping, which is being carried on in cooperation between the Office of Dry Land Agriculture of the U- S. Department of Agriculture and the Substation. Ele field on which this work is carried on was broken out 1887 and has been under cultivation since that date. In the of 1906 the plats were laid out as they are to-day. In each case Plat A was spring plowed and harrowed before planting. Plat B in small grain is disked after the binder, fall plowed, and </seg>
            <seg id="p099">67 usually disked and harrowed in the spring. In ease the soil is rather loose in the spring the disking is omitted. Plat B in is fall plowed as soon as the corn is taken off. Plats C and D are given alternate cropping and summer tilling; that is, one season Plat C grows a crop while Plat D is being summer tilled. The following season D is cropped and C is summer tilled. Table II. — Soil moisture determination*, L April April May May June 6 22 6 21' ti August •&gt; Feet Per cent Per cent \ Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent \— 1 14.6 10.8 19.1 15. IS 21.5 12.3 2 Ki.l 11.5 15.2 15.7 17.4 9.4 3 15.6 12.1 14.5 14.4 14.7 6 125 3 15.4 11.5 Ki.:i 15.2 17.9 !«.] Average to Averageto « 10.8 1 15.9 12.2 2 16.9 12.6 3 Hi. 4 1X9 4 its 5 1 15. fl 12.3 2 16.6 12.7 3 15.5 113 4 19.2 17.6 21.9 16.5 17.1 2iM&gt; 155 15. !♦ 17. ti 5 « Averageto 3 15.9 12.4 17.1 lti .9 l«».s Averageto 6 ■ I) 1 14.7 12.9 2 14.2 12.7 3 15.9 12.1 4 20.1 1«.7 20.4 lti.4 16.5 17.5 14.8 15.8 15 s 5 ti Averageto 3 14.9 12 « 17.1 Hi.:! 17. it Averageto 6 17.6 17.0 20.5 16.2 16.4 l*.'.i 1K.2 16.1 lti.7 6 Average to 3 lfi.4 12 H 16.7 lft.fi I s . 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">68 Table III. — Soil moisture determinations, 908. ■S April May May 8 22 June 6 June 25 July 11 August 8 ■r Feet Percent Per cent Per cent 15.9 16.6 8.7 11.7 9.2 8.3 9.3 12.3 12.9 Per cent Per cent 15.9 11. 1 10.7 Per cent Percent ,_. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 'I 6 10.2 8.3 8.6 14.4 12.9 8.2 8.5 10.5 11.4 8.9 7.7 8.5 8.2 10.0 10.7 9.1 9.1 9.2 9.4 12.3 13.3 :::a '9.6 ii.2 ii'2 114 I ii'.s 22.0 12.6 ' "k'.i 9.0 9.i 10.4 u. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 6 14.0 12.7 10.1 19.2 14.9 12.8 16.3 9.1 10.7 9.4 12.7 13.2 .... 11.6 12.9 10.6 9.0 11.9 12.8 17.0 11.6 11.5 I 1 8.8 7.9 9.1 9.4 12.3 12.9 12.4 8.8 9.0 9.8 12.5 13.5 I iv.to| 13.8 li.9 12.2 13.4 13.4 8.6 10.1 h.o 11.0 ■_ 1 2 3 4 ! 7 8 9 10 3 6 14.5 15.3 15.3 19.1 15.9 16.1 17.2 14.6 16.2 14.2 16.9 16.3 10.2 12.4 14.1 14.5 18.9 17.2 18.5 12 .3 13.2 •• 8.3 8.6 8.7 9.3 15.4 14.9 9.8 9.0 90 9.4 14 2 14.8 I I I I I Av.to Av.to ' is! 6" 1S.6 16.4 16 2 "l2 2 14.5 ii.«' 8.5' 10.9 9.3' 11.0 D- 1 t 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 14 0 13.6 9.1 19.2 12.2 8.2 9.1 12.5 12.4 19.6 18.5 12.8 10 3 12.1 12.3 20.3 18.0 17.0 15.4 14.6 13.1 17.1 17.3 16.6 15.9 17 8 17.5 I ' i^i:' 13!2 '.'.'.'.'.'. 12.3 n'.o' 14.3 "18.4' 16 4 lit' 17.0 I </seg>
            <seg id="p101">Twenty-third Annual Report 69 ■r. fc. c 3 a I aa — ~ a is it a a ■*■* 2 Jo^'-w^- t- t- S 5 O XI ~ «3 "T — ■Vk « g » as r- 3 — L- O tow — t- «» K •««• •m • i *. B* o :•::::::: ■»-» I o -^ — ' -4 d « h 2 S (1. ■** ; x ■• h *» &lt; L« B, S * O — M -r ■X 2 * ft. 22S3 * * * * _ — _ — I 0) li » u ~ 0&gt; g — 1- 3: — 30 •- X . «* |M 1- ?J — TC K -i M3 «3 W ■5^, o iM-i-i-io'ii'ai-'i-t-i-i'-'-'i'i'" I i " qidaa | -™*-r«=*&gt;r- 2 = 22212 u Z u &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; &lt; £ . . ■ • r^ Ti — *• .!. •• Jioof|»3s : : : . : : : . ; •* o • ; u xici-d -so - • I ---;:;; = ';;;- = : ■ 1-5 ■w * '„ * . . 5 ic-jnco^i ■ ; ; : : : ; : f- ~ : . &gt;-9 •«« * ■ • • •- § ~. r~ o • « © • • • • ; ; ;»c ; . B «i r-: '. « ~ r- -T ■ ■ fe ™ — : «::•::::. . : a. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">70 cui&lt; (urai Station of Nebraska |g £ 5 C iqiOOI-«ONNiOSNS30««l-S«- i JJ d x' x x a « o a oo t-^ t^ r o id "O c r 1 » «i « « ::::::: : : : : Js-^ati :::!::: as : : i « : : : : : : J t-a-);*"a"es«r]« ; ; ; ; ; r- a u; ; r «= — =; = = ! - ; |» Z '-&gt;-^«^= j : j ! : : I : '•** : ; © B i E *- &gt;. • — B O &gt; s: * 3 1 DO w &gt; I o 55 i&gt; S sno-ft-t- ;;;;;;■ ,*"; ; S ?, r cr c s o ?i H : ■ : : : : : • d -« : ~^_ rtrH^ rt ... ...... p,-. i. ::•:::::: : : :::::::: : : a 3 oo oq « r- &lt;m ;;;■;;;; ••••;; S -* p i- c r' « n co m • • I S ij::::; j j* 9 j j I 2 ? -i" '&lt;i — o « • ■ « ri • • C :::::•: : : s I m I!!:;!**:; J I £ o -» o r- d ; ; • ; ; ; • • • «e &lt;ei ; ; ° ei «i c si c-i ic • • ' • ■ ■ I • ■ ei oi ■ ■ t —^rH — ih • ■ — " • ■ C •:::::::: — « ■J I '— I eB 1 3 ! ■ qidaQ S HN«*io»i-xaoHN«tion8C|; si 2 • : : : : : 2 oc is =&gt; © « •* i?4 o a: as ' ■ • • • •♦' « eJ • ; c z z — — — — 3 - </seg>
            <seg id="p103">71 » H i Twenty-third Annual Report OI-MM^-X-"- 1 x -»■ m ~i — c x i- t- -■ -.; ti 2 J!30XCI-t O |s JsssssSs t- x • • ■m ri'M ■ -m ti n as ?&gt; « t- r» — o X •»• ■M — I - x p 5 r-. — x -•■ -: x r- |« :-2U2i^ ;; ;; : ::: - — 6 •».«•• S"*- — x c: — -*■ -&gt;• w ~- a ao p -^ ia gt — ic -*■ 2" S -- »**»-&gt; r^ r- ■^ Tl Tl - ® r • • o ■• ■* s ; ■— 5 r^ i~ -r y. X « ri 3232 u s, i • it ii s«S£ a s i s - i &gt; - -c r: «o — • 5 -. 5C = -. X . = w — &lt; is md*a I -••••♦'••■•••SSHSS </seg>
            <seg id="p104">72 _J u rist--3CMne«rtt-qo»Maioo«n O"0 J* ad od od o ..'i ■* m — -^ d d oi oc ad t-: od t-&lt; ■-&lt; c&gt; i-l i— I rH t— t •—( f-H r- 1 — 4( ■ S«=c=R-*a&gt;« ; ; • • : : : : : mqo : : J* o ad ad »■?]■♦ • ■ ■ . I ' ' loi© • • : :^T1 : S MOio-oonNoos osmoj • J* ad so t^ ao o ■* « — 0 d : •' ' • '• t~ a&gt; 0 • I , . : ; : 3 : i •306 4* il!i:!il!!!l!!!i!i! f 1 : : : : : fT: ~ S -« s a M . w . c ~ : : : ■ : : ■ « - • 3S 2 xasffi 22t5 : : : «^ : : — i r:; = ;;-- .4 Sr-««ai;x : : : (Ma- s'*' fe^2S2H2 : : ::::.: !jJC : : Oh :::::::: : : 3 I « ::::::::: : : vS2£2S2 : : : : I ': : . Ijjg • i T -H S &gt; s :::::::•• ~ . «3 &gt;O IO «O I— 5D • • • • • • " ■ '. id io • • 5"~~^*"»^~* • ■ ftn ::•::::• : : 3 1 ■o — — 1 : : : : : : : : : ~ eNMNItlN ; ; ; • ■ • ■ '• • » • ' lOo'jeioiei^h-' • • ' ' • '• '■ ' to w " • ftn ::••:•: : : — ? : : : . : . ad sO »o iri r~- &lt;?i o • • * • • co * a, : : : : . 1 I m a *&lt; ""■* -"* **•* ni'Tan i s s a s- &amp;• t. i. V (b i&gt; i, £ </seg>
            <seg id="p105">Twenty-third Annual Report 73 ■- |n«« : : *t- ■ ~ '- it w — ■ . ..• • j^hodx ■ * "o; ; »o oo ao ; ; ; © * W^H 8 * sosao'* ■* ; o; ri ?i ; ; ; ■* -- -. 4 s i^22 »t-oao ao ; i« 2 04 ?1 =: § oj ao « : : : oo : m o ** : : • • &lt;: £ : : : : Pg §&lt;ooot- : : ■*• : n-o : : :• • 2 ° a ** : — — iw § ao tc ■* ; : : a&gt; : — • •* ! .' ; ■* -222 • : :s : SSSS : : |5 ; a, : : : : • • • • a : — — : •«» *" S-H»-a&gt; ; ; ■«• ; o onh ■ ; ;» ; £ rH r- 1 * * i— t ' . *-* r* f^ ' p »-• ** • • ■ S •* ~ r- ; '. : 9 " mm»:::— " : "2 : ?i22 : : "2 : * : : : : : : : ■..iriuj-* : -o • 5CO-* : ; :«o : • «-- • . :- : -— . . .- 1 . ~- : : : « : : : : a % &lt;l» da a ■« 0 23 &amp; ss (I II </seg>
            <seg id="p106">74 ft . -, —^ o -o CO iJ is u V • t- "*• —• ' ', '. '. f ar4 !.»••* • • • o 3 o« • ■ •«• 1" a^ "»» o§ 5. a •— ' E I a. a&gt; he tt _• u &gt; &gt; £ 5 ■ ■ • ■ a ... g — im 3c ; ; ; -* ; E a-. «D O '. ' '.o&gt; p-t *— t -* • - • i-H ■ O — • • i, .... —^ ; *** B 22 S '22 So H S &lt;&lt; a, " s v. r^ r-^ o ; ; ; tc *"^ : ! : : - j- X I .... £„ §••• ■■■-.■■ •J cs ai ; ; ; s I s .... 6*-* . jc «? ta ■ • • &gt;a ■ &lt; g-"- 1 I ; i ;• 1 ■ • • &gt;■■ s o o m ■ : : : moo ; : ; — : I x at J • • ■ s ■ — •" &gt;~ ; ; ;a» . 1-9 •_ t^ a&gt; «?'■&gt;&lt;" i- m •£ ic 00--IN ■ : 'o : t-* 1- W • ■ I- ' f— I • ' vH | 3 ■ i I £ g ■ ■3 jj 3: «; &gt;O t£5 M t~ «0 -f_ c » « r: «i r-: od i — •* «o •£&gt; : : : oo • — &lt; ad «c • ■ 'ad ' Nhh ; ; ; — ; -;©&lt;cm o re x i- c-j?5-"^-— — — — X ... . . . . S" S^ 'i^ •■•■*• ~ «io ; ; '5i ! •jt- ?1 i. o ■* • • ■ lO • a; sb &lt;c . . ;~ * „&lt;»« — — : ; :•-&gt; : t _:'-i-"-' : : ■— : 5 : ■ ■ • i : • • </seg>
            <seg id="p107">75 Twenty-third Annual Report 1\bi,k IX.— Soil moUur? &lt;Icter»iination«, 1908. Plat A.— Spring plowed. Corn every year. April April April April Mav Mav Mav 6 lr &gt; '■» 2«&lt; 6 13" ' ].,• Feet eet Percent Perce,U Per eml I'er cent' Per cent PeTce^t \ '•*•' 1-5-1 14.8 14.ii 'i (| i 2 11-1 10.8 U.5 ll.i ,2.3 \h Si? 4 };J 9 -° !(0 !(:i •{ * ! •"&gt; i3.4 ..;.;; ; ;;;■ i : $; 7 8 9 Id 0 . Average to 3 ii.5 lii.it" li.V 11 V "ii's "iVV in Avcrara In « ll a *' '•■? '•'•• t lu.-« 3 11.5 io.» 11.7 11. V ' 14.5 i3.3 M Avt-rage to | 6 ! 11.8 6 ' US 13.5 Plat B.— Fall plowed. Corn every year. (lowed. Corn every year. 1 144 13-2 IJ.S 14.0 at 13.8 | 14.0 M 2 10.4 M&gt;3 11.3 11.6 18 1 H4 11.3 ll.d lo.i ii 4 3 ».i »• ...o 9.3 s... ;;, 3 ».i »• bo »: 3 8 :« ;:s 4 B.3 ! : : :::: :::.:: ■::::■ Si « "■.• :.::;■ :::::: .::::. B:j .;;;;; ;;;;;; ■ H.o :;.:;;;. [^ .;;••; i 8 '.'.'...'. ".'. s ■ 9 n ' in 3 n.3 io.8 i'i.4 ii.4 i:{'.:{ "a.i "\vera££ I 11- IM "•* "* '»•" »•* -werageto 6 11., ,3 Q " U.I ijd Plat C— Summer tilled 1&lt;K)7. Corn 190H. ler tilled 1&lt;K)7. Corn 1908. J ]■&gt;■■} HI 14.7 Ifi.l M.S |t.« H3 14.6 16.1 15.0 14.7 1.V1 1 I £* I HJ I ?i- 7 I »•] »s 1 19.0 4 H.4 . -7 j; fi •- 1 "■ • "• :::::' »:• ::::: 5 i7:« ..::: K-5 • n-2 ::::: :::::. i?:! ;:;;; :.;;:; « 17.2 17.4 8 '.'.'.'... ...[ 8 Q it 0 '.".'.'. 10 1 15.1 14.6 15. V lh.3 17..V "n'M Avln.™^ I'M U - 6 lVl ' "&gt;»•» '".S "lV.0 Average to I ti 15.8 u 15-8 .... lti.e lti.tJ Plat D.— Corn 1907. Summer 1907. Summer tilled 1908. tilled 1908. 1 13.7 IS.3 12.4 12.8 20.1 18.4 1 12.4 I 12.8 I |t.] is. 4 - W.fi 10.0 !».H 9.1 g ■&gt; 10 • !t.l 9.2 HK4 3 9-6 8.8 8.8 U~\ it 1 8.6 8.8 »!l j »il 4 10.8 io 7 10.7 5 14.8 14 ; 5 14.r, 15.4 « ".» 15.4 ::::. ::: « 14.9 8 '.'.'.'.'. '.'.'.'.'.'. 1 H o 9 ' " 9 10 0 Average to 3 10. .V 10.7 Average to | ti 12.4 ... 3 10.3 10.7 10.2 10.2 12. 8 'l2' « 1 (&gt; 12.4 .... 13.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">dtural Experiment Station t J.ABLE 1A.. (C Jontinued) — Soil moisture d terminations, 1908. Plat A.— Spring p lowed. Corn every year. 5 a. •5 May i June June June 27 3 19 24 May | 27 June June June 3 19 24 July July July 2 11 17 O_ Feet 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Average to 3 Average to I Plat B.— Fall plon 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Average to 3 Average to 0 Hlat C— Summer t 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Average to 3 Average to 6 Plat D.— Corn 190" 1 I 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Average to 3 A verage to 6 Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent . 21.1 21.1 23.5 24.4 18.9 18.4 21.7 20.4 12.7 13.2 17.8 17.3 9.4 12.7 13.7 17.6 17.6' 21.0 20.7 14.8 wed. Corn every year. 21.6 20.8 23.1 23.7 18.2 17.3 20.4 19.1 12.1 12.6 14.7 15.5 9.7 13.3 15.6 17.3 16.9 ii'.i' 19.4' 14.9 tilled 1907. Corn 1SW8. 21.1 20.9 21.6 ! 23.4 19.9 19.3 21.2 20.9 18.1 18.1 19.3 18.3 16.3 17.9 18.7 "lit.Y 19.4 '26.7' '20.9 18.5 (7. Summer tilled 1908. 21.2 20.5 I 23.4 22.1 18.0 17.7 20.3 19.6 10.5 11.6 15.4 17.5 11.1 15.2 15.1 16.6 ii'.i' "it.V 19.7' 15.2 Per and Per cent Per cen 21.7 20.8 19.5 18.4 17.8 17.it 17.2 16.7 17.1 13.4 13.4 13.2 19.1 18.4 16.2 21.4 20.2 1U.0 18.1 17.5 17.9 17.0 16.1 17.1 12.7 14.2 15.1 ...•&gt; ...... • "18.8 17.9 18.0 16.4 21.3 20.0 17.7 18.5 18.5 17. rt 16.7 17.2 17 4 17.0 20.1 19.9 18.8 "l8.6 17. ii' 18.9 21.9 2C.2 18.7 18.5 17.7 18.2 17.0 16.4 Hi. 2 14.8 15.0 15.5 19.1 'li'.i' 17.7 17.1 Average to Average to Plat D.— C&lt; Average to \ verage to </seg>
            <seg id="p109">- July July August August August Sept. Sept. t I i 23 27 i 15 21 9 23 3 Feet Per cent Vet cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 1 21.7 19.2 13.2 11.9 10.9 7.3 7.7 7 0 2 17.6 16.9 14.9 11.3 10.6 9.1 - - 3 16.5 16.5 15.8 12.8 11.4 9.1 8.6 Feet 4 14.!* B.I .. H.^ ...... ...... 9.41 l«.« 11.3 5 16. t 11.3 5 6 lti.l 12.2 ti I lti.l 12.2 7 10.2 Hi. 2 8 9.2 8 .... .... 9.2 9 8.6 9 • ... 10 7.9 Av to 3 18.6 17.5 14.6 VIA) 11.0 8.5 9.4 8.1 Av.tol 6 15.2 Plat B. — Fall plowed. Corn every year. I 1 20.9 17.3 11.8 * 12.3 10. 5 8.3 - 7.4 Plat B. — Fall plowed. Corn every year. 10. 5 8.3 B 2 17.5 16.0 13.7 ll.fi •2 17..") 16.0 13.7 11.5 10.2 8.4 i - 8.8 1(1.2 H.4 8.8 3 15.8 16.0 14.9 12.5 11.1 9.1 9.:{ 11.1 i».l 9.3 4 15.5 9.1 4 .. 15.5 .... 9.1 5 14.4 13.2 ... . 5 I 14.4 13.2 ... . ,) 6 14.6 13. i 6 14. B 1S.9 7 11.7 11.7 i 8 10.4 s 10.4 9 9.8 9 .. 9.8 j 10 9.4 Av.to 3 18.1 16.4 13.5 12.1 10. ti 8.6 10.3 Av.to 6 14.2 10 9.4 Av.to 3 18.1 16.4 13.5 12.1 10.6 8.6 10.3 Av.tol 6 14.2 Plat C— Summer tilled 1907. Corn 1908. I 1 20.5 18.2 12.4 10.7 11.0 * 4 7.5 Plat C- Sumraer tilled 1907. Corn 1908. 1 20.5 I 18.2 I 12.4 I 10.7 I 11.0 * 4 7.5 I 7 7.5 I 17.8 17.5 13.9 11.3 10.0 9.5 9.2 9.0 lo.o 9.5 9.2 3 16.6 16. S 14.-1 13.0 11.3 9.3 9.1 9.1 :s 11.3 9.3 9.1 4 .. . 15.7 15.0 9.9 18.5 5 14. S 14.9 .) ti 17.2 16.2 15.0 17.2 13.(1 12.7 8 !l 12.4 10 12.0 Av.to 3 18.3 17.5 13.5 11.7 10.8 9.0 11.6 15.3 I | 12.2 Av. to| 6 Corn 1907 Summer tilled 1908. 1 81. « 19.9 | 16.3 I 17.5 lti.l 15.4 14.0 ■&gt; 19.1 17.4 16.3 15.4 16.3 15.5 :{ lti.4 16.3 16.2 I6.fl 14.5 15.6 15.2 4 14.5 14.6 6 15.8 17.4 ti lli.l 17.4 14.1 B 12.0 I 11.5 10 11.2 18.1 16.6 16.3 19.1 15.3 15.8 14.3 Av.to 6 16.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">78 I! b It: »_ S q) I E &lt;4 •• O • W NHri r^ I— r-"* H, 6 K •» § Nt-fr-&lt;ft in — S'S u icdii- h « S V I be it it it if id t. t. i. i. &lt; i 0 1 ° m:r.naoot-i-s8«;t: 1 i- sec- x 5 i- I »— * r :::::.::: : : j si&gt; ; -- xr-a i-&gt; m • • ° — © — — ' -* m • • ■ ' . '• '■ ' ~ ti '• '. fe '"-"--- :::::::: :~~ : : a. ::::::.:: : : J -hiccc« ?10D • • u ss r- o SO r- iri • • • • • • ■ • ' i- ~ • '■ W i— &lt; I— I -^ i-^ r^ • • •• •. H*4 » ' ::.:::::. : . J rtCMIicr- i-3.. ° r- » etn- • • ' • i- • • w „......._.„„.. 00 o VS o ■ ::::::.:: : : §2° J&gt; as t^ as ice ua '■'■'■'.'.'.'.'. t ~ ~j .' I * :■:::::•: : : E « m O £ -r " r-' «' 3- o «' c-j O T. d m i- i- i~ o i- M — n o "SiO — - .:::::..: : : J XSK- ~. t- t~0O- ° »*'o'»-'-' : • : "• ■ ■ ■ '•■^d Kr-l^^»-^ riH , ■ • -rlrl ■ * :.::•■:: : 1 — ■2 . . . : : : I MlONV^t-f Ml-M • • • r? x — |« J! aas*^**"" 0 " i: ! i 22d : s jfi : : : : be g 05 ssss </seg>
            <seg id="p111">79 ! ~ «oc t ,- — ,— — — 6 £. t i _ . u -. * i- ■k* I e. ■r. 2 I •-.••••■? •::':::: £ 3P. 8 go r-co e»« ■♦ -.i _„ _, — » 6 A. i- " L -I W M 6 S» I 1* •*^ i- s x ■71 I- * Joe O^nxxNM 2 « B, gp ti -f ~i~ "M — • i~ — i - XIXflDM?! ri M i &lt; 5 »v ha 1 •••••••-»• :::::::: !°.^ : : B ° »-r - » Tir^ v. &lt; L6 ft, S§ ? 2zi- : --n2^ r^ t i a \l = ri x ■.= x x c s ~ r, — o — o — •» — •• § -t = « i- r. S ■; i « ; e i a v. ** u*: c-i i" o ~ -♦• *■ t ~ •: ~ »-••*• ♦ © I m.iaa -^ *A *-* U Si ii Si &lt;e s ~ ~ &gt; &gt; &gt; &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p112">80 ta „ - 5 'I "" *s ::::::::: : : | aoMooMO «e w • • (m"5 u t- « o » os ao • •' • • • • • • ■e't- • • j^ 1 V. r^ i— i iNH • ■ - ::::::::: : : "^Sj ° saor-00000 ••!...!• load-- K - ::::::::: : : j • • • : : . : ••*, ; ; t^ #*^ *♦•■ *•■•' ' • • £ ::::•.:• ■ : 50* • — ■ - ::;:.:::: : : § » « ci •- © © o oo • ■ §95 « aoV-w set- io •••'••• •••»-»•• e £■*&gt; ° hOOMN«5+ t-U5 • ■ WC^l'^^^r- l^^f— I MH • • r J t~t rt — X *-* '■'.'..■'.'■'. 'kC «2 • I s i I — i » — i 5 * 2 « g c-i iM » us uiio ©I ac «; M ® t- OD © r- © a&gt; r- -" at ■*. ** .c O — li •* ■* Vi © © ©' 3s ad r- t^ cc •* m ?i — 2 1 ■&lt; *» E O-i-i &lt; . :::.:::.: : : ( ceicxifle ■ • ; as «_ • ■ r : !iii : :ii**!5 Sa « : : : : : : E u; »« e N * 1- « O rt J: r-r-© • i * ao'ad«ioiN^-"o' • • • • •■*«'« • a E o t 6 £ qld»n 8 "-Nn^oei-aoaoiHNHKiiSM".":!^ 0000 •— — — — 09 ce &lt;e 93 — — - — </seg>
            <seg id="p113">81 — I- -Z — X t:ir.t: i-x as -i *■ i ? i * ■.- !IO r^ t Cl ■3«- SlZ^S-?,S i - r s "d B, I X r^ § ►:«» i!&gt; :::::::: :S2 : : 2 as ««i : «Vfi» -5i- u m a x tk, f ".- k 3323 -f. P 9 • 2, i, li i -3 - s! 3 i. i i, 41 i 3 &gt; \6 '£ | 1 t -• * ~ • « it'-", ** tKiMtn 3 #l W — -^ — •-* 4* t_ aj — * ' I - t- 00 ■ § ■ - -*■ i- r- «- | Sac o .-•.-.-"i-r-s 5» ° irtcii--i'«:i- 3 £ Q ( « , J ,-' i- ,-' — — s = -- x x =: 't -r c-i v __ _ _ „ ,- « rt -^ r-lr-&gt;r- — £ = 8 a g ■* -e = « r- —•■:::::.-.-.■: Cms b x = «:■*«- i- : : : : : : : : :22 • "■ ■&lt; 5&gt; ::::::::: «« »-H "S 6 r " ****** e 5* r ! • • • • •"■"'■ '"■ : </seg>
            <seg id="p114">82 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Table XIV. — £ Soil moisture deter miiiatic ns, / . 'lat A. — Spring plowed. Spring wheat every year. | a April April fa May 6 May 21 June 6 nr Feet PercetU PercetU PercetU Percent Percent 1 18.4 15.5 16 7 16.0 20.4 2 16.9 16.4 16.1 15.8 17.3 3 15.8 16 0 14 7 15.8 14 5 4 ! .:::::::! :::::::: ::: : :::i: :::::::::::::::::: 3 16 4 16.0 15 8 15 9 17.4 6 Percent I rerage to erage to 'lat B.— Dii sked after binder and fall plowed. Spring wheat eve 1 16.5 14.1 19.7 15 7 20.5 2 16.4 13.9 15.8 15.6 17.8 3 15.9 16.4 14.7 15.7 15 9 4 5 ti 3 16 3 14.5 16.7 15 7 18.1 6 ring wheat 1906. Summer tilled 1907. 1 15.6 12.3 19.2 17.6 21.9 2 16.6 12.7 16 5 17.1 20.0 3 15.5 12.3 15.5 15.9 17.6 4 6 6 3 15.9 12 4 17.1 16.9 19.8 6 ery year. 12.6 12 2 10.0 19.9 19.4 17.0 n.9 l verage to l verage to 'lat C— Sp average to l verage to •lat D.-Su immer tilled 1906. Spring wheat 1907. 1 15.7 15.0 19.6 17.4 20.1 2 16.9 15.6 17.1 16.6 17.8 3 15.9 15.4 15.2 15.9 15.1 4 5 6 3 16.2 15.3 17.3 16.6 17.7 6 I verage to verage to </seg>
            <seg id="p115">83 Table XV. — Soil moisture determinations, 1908 lat A. — Spring plowed. Spring wheat every year. April May June July August "47375 y i July 7 August 5 =■ T Average to Average to I Plat B.-Di Average to Average to PlatC.-Su Feet Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 14.2 17.6 16.9 14.3 7.2 2 11.0 8 9 12.8 9 3 8.3 3 11.0 8.2 8.7 8.6 8.1 4 10.3 9.1 9 5 9 0 8 4 5 11.6 10.9 11.0 10.6 10.0 6 12.1 12.7 13.2 11.9 11.8 7 8 9 10 Average to 6 , 11.7 112 12.0 10.6 9.0 Average to 10 Plat B. — Disked after binder and fall plowed Spring wheat eve 1 14.0 18.7 17.8 12.1 7.3 2 12.1 11 9 14 6 8.7 7.7 3 8.7 8 6 10.3 8 8 7 7 4 9.3 9.5 9.4 9.6 8.7 5 12.1 11.0 12.2 12.9 11 3 6 14.3 12.2 15.2 15 4 14 1 7 8 9 10 Average to 6 118 12 0 13.3 113 9.5 Average to 10 Plat C— Summer tilled 1907. Spring wheat 1908. 1 15 9 19 4 15.4 12.6 8.1 2 15.7 15.6 14.0 9.7 7.8 3 15.4 14.1 14.9 10.1 7.2 4 14.9 14.5 14 1 10.7 8.0 5 18.9 16.4 17.4 15.7 13.3 6 18.0 16.2 18.0 16.0 15 1 7 8 9 10 Average to 6 16 5 16.0 15 6 12.5 9.9 Average to 10 . Plat D.— Spring wheat 1907. Summer tilled in 1908. 1 14.6 19.7 ' 21.1 22.5 16 1 2 11.8 13.2 18.3 18.4 10.8 3 8 8 9.5 13.5 17.5 16 3 4 10.7 11.7 12.0 16.2 16.0 5 15.5 14.2 16.2 17 8 18.6 6 15.0 14.4 15.3 15.7 18 9 7 . ... 8 9 10 Average to 6 12 7 13.8 16.1 18.0 16.8 Per rent 119 tv year. u!a 10 6 10 1 1U . D 111 H 14 8 ii.4 11 8 14.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">84 8 • • ■ • „ 8 v ; ! * • " : : ! i" 1 : ©aiosos'-o ; ; "© • EC 3 Seao«i-t-«!NBMoiio i.oooxiaJas'M^otaoaoooJ C0OM©t-a0O'M'*Tlr'. Tl — as0OO5©'*'»"N — — O — M 3 ~ ■*j . . . • ■ JOHOBll-S) ; ; • ;&lt;D ; S» — '— 35©©M I " IM " ft( : : : : : isncatoio • • • • • -h ■ S'^OOJO'-c© : ; ; ;« • •5 : : : : : : : I : : ' i H ; ! &gt; « II •&lt; be H .S E o. ■ -2 Dm 2 -_ ..... .....I Eaoooior-H : • ; • e* '• . r-«iaooaai '. • '. - o i. « «ei i «2 eo -h i-h ; ; ; . -^ . 08 "i ■* oj o n '■&amp; ; . : ; « • , : h : — LJ — U QJ .... g '.;;;■.&gt; .■ ; .* ' * 8Nn»NOP ; ; ; ; © ; « «*&lt;tCOW ; ; ; J t" • •, » i- us n o o ; ; ; ;■* ;2 u5 '" 3b *^"'5 . '. '. ."■ ■ W *"^ I"H i"H .... *^ . flj '"^ '"^ f^ . . * v N i-i rt rt H iH . . , i-H .CQ^^»— &lt; f— l-^i— t * ' " *^* * t, : : : • : :::::] &lt; I I __: — : — : — : 1 n-t • • * • * i 2 1 I gr-tcso^o—i^Qot-QO^iao o ao«or-5eto-*t&lt;tor-iN»Q«ao « _% ~z 1 o be _a "E a. w qjdaa — — • • en ! </seg>
            <seg id="p117">85 I. I- i- -f l-lfll- O tf2 **• OO * Ci"t"^ 5 h s 2 =«e*-Hao»® : • : .« : •**«©•. : : : ji • 2 -?' : : : : : : : : : "&lt;&gt;•»&lt; ; • ; ; . . . . • £ o as x&gt; r- to ■* — « i- «5 ■♦ oo ■"! j*?**^?"*"" °&gt; S^i "fl6rf«o«oo6«6K9«-"«»P:'^ ~ * x ~ 2 2 " 72 ~~ ~ — — ■H | h— &gt;55 *"■&lt;&amp;&lt; W • I- r- 3: « -r X ; ■ ■ ; I 1 .5 j "• : ; = i ?i^ a =2= : : ; ;a ; e : ; . . t_ n .'.'.'' * ' • • &lt;d iricKrir-^oo : : j \m ■ r -. t r : : : : a . : | £ . : : . : : : : : : 1 ce* : ■ '■ ■™ : t3£'-iSi2 : : ■ S : | : : ■ • ■ : ■ • | "2 I &gt;, 1 * a» » — r- od : : : 1 •. . " = . 'i = . ". "". : . 3 2 «« 8 ®2»222 : : : 2 [8SSSSSS ■ : ■ : '± ■ ■s 2 2 £ :::::" : : : : Oe •••• 4 i q s «i : ■ : . . ja ' S a s oo»)t-nt- • ■ ■ ••* ■ * us «3 oo » « a&gt; ; • ; : r; ; W Jj;2-« i iSl : : : |S | | ; : .^ • r^ a ' ■ 'f. »^ ci« I *• I : : : : : V ~ 38 r- y. rt r- t- t- •- &gt;Mrt S V .- —- o «S • : : :«2 : -* • oo -r ?i '.t ~ i- C4 . U3 M3 '" '-* X -: I fc l«»»-*:3 : i : H i^SSSS * -i - _« 5 rndan ?- N«* «o« r-oo a&gt; © a= o 2 « as r-oc o&gt; o» o ' S be I- ■ :— : § ' r n . . 5 • • 1 : : = J^ "* II" I </seg>
            <seg id="p118">A.gncu Itural Experv nent Station of Nebraska jleX 1 m.—t loil mo 'sture determinations, 1908. Plat A.-S, rin? p owed a id ham iwed. Barley every year. _ f a April 15 May 9 May June June 22 8 25 August Sept. n 29 Feet 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 6 Percent 9.7 8.7 8.2 Percent 15.4 9.6 8.7 9.8 11.6 15.2 Per cent 15.7 13.6 7.7 Per cent Per cent 13.4 18.6 11.3 12.1 10.0 10.6 10.8 11.7 14.4 Per cent Per cent 7.4 6.6 8.5 8.2 8.5 8.5 9.1 «.2 11.2 11.1 I i| 9.9 19.2 .verage to iverage to lat B.-Di iked a 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 6 ' ' 8.9 :ter bind 12.9 12.5 9.7 11.2 11.7 er and I 16.2 13.7 10.4 11.0 13.6 16.7 12.3' Fall plow 15.5 16.1 10.6 11.6 13.8 11.9 red. Barley ev&lt; 11.6 19.9 10.3 13.8 10.5 11.8 12.5 15.6 16.9 sry year. 12.8 I 11.1 9.9 U.8 8.9 10.2 9.7 11.7 12.8 14.4 15.3 15.8 10.5 11*0 11. « lt.fi Eerage to erage to it C— Sui nmer I 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 6 " ii" V i illed 19( 14.1 15.0 14.6 13.4 13.6 &gt;7. Bar 17.2 15.4 14.1 15.5 18.8 18.5 "n.i ■ley in IS) 13.5 15.8 16.1 10.8 1.V.2' 12.9 908. 11.5 22.5 10.5 13.9 11.7 13.5 14.1 18.3 16.1 11.6 9.2 10.1 9.8 9.9 9.8 11.0 10.5 15.7 15.2 1 Ii 10.2 9.6 12.3 13.3 I ' 14.6 15.9 16.6 15. i' • tilled it 11.2 16.6 13.7 n 1908. Average to Average to Plat D.-Bi I ,rley ii 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 3 6 i 1907. 13.8 14.3 11.8 .. .. Summer 18.6 12.7 8.8 10.7 14.4 16.2 19.4 18.6 14.9 13.4 16.0 16.7 17.7 14.1 17.1 15. ti 15.8 15.1 15.3 14.5 18.4 18.6 19.4 1 "16.9 14 17.3 16.1 Average to Average to ' 13.3 "l3.4 13.6 17.6 I""'. 16.5 I </seg>
            <seg id="p119">87 Table XVIII. — Soil moisture dele rminatwm, 1 w. 'lat A. — Spring plowed and harrowed. Barl ey every year. E April April May May June August 1 IS • 21 ft M May 21 June 6 , T ., Fut Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 15. 6 14.0 19.9 lti.4 20. H 8.1 2 16.4 13.6 16.3 16.2 18.5 8.4 3 15.2 13.8 15.4 15.2 15.8 1.1 Average to 3 " "i5."7* "n'.s" " iY.'i" "ib.it" "is'.i" 8A Average to t 6 10.3 Plat B. — Disked after biDder and fall plowed. Barley every year. 1 15.6 15.8 18.2 16.9 20.8 2 16.5 16.4 15.5 15.6 19.1 3 16.0 15.5 15.9 14.8 16.9 8.8 4 9.6 Average to 3 "ieio" 'is!**" "ih'.h" " ib'.s" "is.s" Average to 6 11.4 Plat C— Barley 1906. Summer tilled 1907. Plat D.— Barley. Summer tilled 1906. Spring 1907. • 1 16.6 15.3 16.9 16.3 22.3 9.6 2 16.9 15.4 16.4 16.1 20.3 ll.fi 3 15.3 15.1 15.4 15.3 18.2 lt.1 4 12 :! 5 Mil ■ VIA Average to 3 16.3 15.3 1H.2 15.9 20.3 10.4 Average to 6 , 12..") </seg>
            <seg id="p120">88 Table XIX. — Soil moisi '?(»•&lt;' detevminatio rminatii m, 190, 'lat A. — Spring plowed. Barley ev ery year. ■ i .a April June £ 19 9 July July 12 22" July 22" August 26 October Average to Average to Average to Average to Fett Per cent \ Per cent 1 18.4 20.5 I 17.1 17.8 I V.i.~ 15.8 4 9.4 11.5 5 11.7 11.1 6 14.8 13.7 7 12.6 8 10.0 9 9.8 10 9.5 11 9.2 12 8.8 .. 13 8.4 14 8.1 15 8.3 3 16.4 18.0 6 14.2 15.1 10 12.7 15 11.6 Per cent Per cent Per cent Percent 22.2 15.2 14. 9 14.6 11.6 11.2 9.9 9.6 ll.fi 12.2 14.1 15.2 13.0 10^ 9.6 9.3 13.3 12.9 11.6 10.3 12.0 15.7 1K7 12^2 I I 16.2 13.7 14.0 13.0 12.0 i2!&lt;5 12.6 ■ I Table XX.— So I moistu ire determinations, 1909, Plat B. —Disked after bind&lt; r and fal 1 plowed. Barley every ye; r. f April 19 June I July 12 July 22 August 26 o^ Average to Average to Average to Average to Feet 1 2 I 4 5 6 7 8 it 10 II 12 13 14 15 3 6 10 15 Per cent Per cent Per cent \ Per cent Per cent Percent 18.6 14.8 11.8 11.3 16.2 16.3 13.1 11.2 10.8 10.2 1.9 9.4 9.3 8.7 8.5 15.0 14.7 13.3 11.9 20.7 18.2 15.1 12..". 14.5 15.5 20.2 12.7 13:2 12.1 16.0 9.8 8.8 9.4 8.7 9.8 9.2 9.0 12.", 11. h 12.4 14.2 14.3 13.3 12.8 10.6 10.4 10.1 . "i^o" lti.7 ::::::::! :::::::• :::::::: 13.7" 12!"7 l6!6 12.9 12.3 11.1 11.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">89 Table XXI. — Soil moisture determinations, 1909. Plat C— Barley in 1908. Summer tilled 1909. April June July July August October &lt;P 19 It 12 23 2ti If 12 It 23 26 Ifl Feet Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent j Per cent 1 17.7 21.8 23.6 19 1 17.3 | 15.5 18.1 21.4 18.3 14.9 3 11.3 13.0 20.1 18.0 15.1 4 14.3 12. ti 19. « 15.4 5 14.7 1H..1 20. ti 23.3 19.1 fl 15.9 15.8 19.2 21.1 tt.fi 7 12.4 17.8 fcft.l 10.9 IV 1 13.5 10.9 I ' 15.1 13.5 it 10.9 13.6 13.2 10 11.1 13.2 12 7 U 10.4 11.1 12 10.3 , 11.8 13 10.2 | 11.7 14 10.0 I 11.2 15 11.1 Average to 3 14.8 17.8 Average to 6 11.6 Hi. 4 21.7 18.4 15.8 1". rt 20.6 19.9 16.2 Averageto 10 13.5 17.9 j M.fl Averageto 15 ! 12.4 | ; | .... I4.fi Table XXII. — Soil moisture determinations, I Plat D.— Summer tilled 1908. Barley 19i&gt;9. April June July July August (X'tober * 19 12 8 23 2H M Feet Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 23.4 14.1 10.8 7.8 14.4 10.2 11.7 13.8 11.7 8.9 11.6 11.9 10.5 8.3 10.4 17.9 15.3 12.7 12 9 18.7 16.9 13.7 15.6 1 18.1 20.1 2 16.5 18.0 3 15.4 16.2 4 15.4 H.9 5 18. H 17.7 (i 18.5 19.0 2 14.3 ; 13.7 7 16.2 8 13.8 9 12.5 10 12.2 129 ! 11 7 13.0 12 .7 11.3 11 12.2 12 11.8 13 11.7 11 4 14 11.0 15 11.2 Averageto 3 16.7 18.1 Averageto 6 '• 17.1 17.7 Averageto 10 15.7 18.5 13.6 9.9 10.4 17.3 13.9 10.8 11. 7 13.5 11.9 Average to 15 14.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">90 Table XXIII. — Soil moisture determinations, 1908-1909. Field I.— In brome grass 1905 to 1909. - — Q March April May June June 16 18 11 12 22 . . i July 20 r verage to verasre to Feet Percent Percent Percent Percent 1 12.2 8.0 12.4 14.3 2 8.6 7.3 7.3 «.5 3 7.9 7.0 6.7 4 7.7 7.0 6.8 H.4 5 8.2 6.5 6.9 6.7 6 8.5 6.7 7.0 6.7 7 8 9 10 6 8.8 7.2 7.9 8.2 10 Percent 14.1 9.7 6.8 6.0 6.0 6.7 Percent Per cent 10.6 5.4 10.7 6.6 9.6 6i8 t!l '8.6 6^2 "8.2 April May I 19 8 May 8 June 14 J 7 July 2« T Average to Average to Feet Per cent Per cent 1 17.5 11.8 2 15.9 14.5 3 12.7 12.0 4 7.1 8.1 5 7.0 6.8 6 7.0 6.9 7 7.4 * 7.3 9 7.7 10 7.4 6 11.1 10.0 10 9.7 Per cent Per cent 17.5* 18.8 18.2 14.8 14.7 11.4 10.7 10.7 9.3 10.8 7.7 10.4 Per cent 19.5 10.8 9.6 8.4 9.4 9.3 6.8 6.1 6.4 7.1 9.7 8.4 i3!6" "i2!8* I •An old irrigation ditch just above this Si field was flooded, which probably accounts (01 :ld broke during a hea the increased water o .TV rain June 9 and this on ten i </seg>
            <seg id="p123">91 Tabu XXIV. — Soil moi»ture determination*, 190S- &lt; Native sod on the table-land. Feet Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent 21.6 19.6 10.8 I 8 7.6 8.3 8.1 I 7.1 10 7.1 Average to « 12.0 16.0 15.7 12.5 8.4 Average to | 10 I 10.1 1 21.2 21.6 19.6 10.8 2 18.5 20.3 19.0 12.3 3 9.9 18.5 16.1 14.2 4 7.7 17.2 14.2 13.9 5 7.4 11.5 14.4 12.4 8.6 6 7.3 6.7 10.9 11.6 9.4 7 7.1 10.0 9.0 ~ April May 2:! 12 June June July Aug. IS 27 11 8 2.5 *" Feet 1 I 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 6 Percent Percent I5.fi 20.3 10.9 9.5 10.2 9.5 9.4 9.2 8.5 8.6 7.7 8.0 I Percent Percent Percent Percent Percem 27.3 18.8 17.2 II. I 22.1 17.3 18.1 13.2 - 1 14.4 13.0 ! 17.2 14.7 9.1 10 2 9.4 15. s 14.0 8.8 8.3 9.5 11.6 11.3 8.0 7.6 8.3 8.4 9.0 7.3 15.b' "l2.9 14.7 12.3 Average to Average to 10.4 10. 9 10 1909 n April 27 June 16 July 19 August 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">92 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Table XXV.— Soil moisture determinations, 1908-1 IH)9. Alfalfa 1903 to 1900 on table-land. Field 44. 1908 J3 April May 2o 15 Ftet Per cent Per cent 1 1.8 23.2 2 8.0 9.6 3 8.0 7.7 4 7.3 8.0 5 8.8 8.7 6 8.6 8.3 7 8 9 10 6 8.0 10.9 10 June Sept. October 29 25 5 Per cent Per cent Per cent 15.4 5.6 6.1 12.1 6.7 7.1 8.1 7.9 7.8 7.7 7.8 8.5 8.1 - 1 8.6 7.6 7.4 6.8 7.0 6.2 1.1 5.8 5.5 5.8 5.7 10.1 7.3 7.4 6.8 6.9 verage to verage to 1909 April Mav X 8 10 f b'ttt 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 6 April 8 Per cent 18.5 10.7 8.3 7.8 8.4 8.2 6.6 6.3 6.2 6.2 10.3 Per cent 12.0 9.9 8.2 7.3 7.9 8.2 Ma.v 10 June August Sept. Per cent Per cent Per cent 21.6 7.0 I I 18.6 7.1 7.0 12.7 6.1 7.2 8.5 6.9 6.8 H.5 I.I 7.7 8.5 7.5 8.2 7.1 7.8 6.6 7.1 6.0 6.6 6.0 6.3 13.1 7.1 7.1 verage to ""8:9" </seg>
            <seg id="p125">Ttii ut ij-lhinl Annual Kepori 93 In Tahl." XXVI we ghre the results of ■ asrMi of determina - tions made to ascertain the maximum water-holding capacity of thi - type of soil. On September 9, 1!N&gt;8, the amount of water present in the soil was determined. After making this determination an excavation 8 feet in diameter and one foot deep was made. A total of 96 inches of water was pal into this to insure saturation, and the dry dirt which had been removed in exravat : nir was put hack as a mulch. About 6 or 8 inches of hay was put over all of this in order to reduce surface evaporation to a minimum. Kamples were taken from time to time as shown in the tali nine the movements of the water. We note that after the inir of September 17. 1906, there is a loss of 3 per or a total of S inches of water to October !*. It is evident that this water moved downward, as the first fool shows conclusively that the water did not escape from the surface as tin of the soil was not sufficiently moist to ton much water, after the sampling on October 9, we had a three inch rain which explains the increased amount of water found October SO. Wt then find a decrease to April 22, 190f, when the upper 6 f« soil have on an average about lb' per cent of moisture. There is an increased amount ajrain when the rains srart during the summer, but it drops later in the Season. It would seem. then. that the maximum water-holding capacity of our soil is bet 16 and 18 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p126">94 :^uraZ I Experiment Station of Nebraska a.™ ■ « ! I ? : : : : : C f eioi»i-o«;i-*i8 • • • .i- cc-x&gt;~icaoc»;3:o&gt;t-x • ■ • • " r- a, : : : : . &gt;. 5* S j £ erirtosi'SNocoO'tt-tacr- " jj » « s&gt; * t- « io •tMci^aio.-' &lt;d V s g- I 1 . Wc aoo»o*« s - O^o J^ osccs '.~ M3 -r o^' c-i «re '• — '• •&amp; &lt;o o S5 s I 5 2 5 3 £»!O«:'»' i- act- :c-f:*: • ' ! := t, « |8 w tSSSSSSSSSS : : : : :S -Z i ■ r^^ £s 5^ m ;c « «O odaVsV • ■ ■ i r- 1 '- g s •i C5 T, •S S I o CO "5 I ? i .1 S S- " 5 c : . : : : « act-a««ioa«f!n &lt;«■ 3 : : : : : { -««t-t-OMH«;a © J* » i— a s: « « «g —^ — ri • " ' o w --iiiiifiri-ifi 5J a, : : : : : 03 ? : : : . : - t^ i- t- x o: c: — r-i ih - i i I ab w „„„ : : ; : : ft, • ■ SI 1 a qidSQ 5&gt; s IC | '5 i^ i »CCCt""QCOtG»~*C*lCO^*iO© i </seg>
            <seg id="p127">Fm nty-third Annual Report 95 The following weather record charts are used to show the character and amount of rainfall during the time the moisture work was in progress, and to show the average rainfall thru a long period of years. . B Table XXVII shows the amount of each rain during the months eh to September inclusive. This is shown for the past three yean, time the moisture studies have been in progress. It will be d that many rains are so small in amount as to be of little value from the standpoint of storing moisture. Other rains are very heavy. If one studies the moisture curves carefully and compares the results with this rainfall chart, a correlation will be found be - teen frequency and amount of rainfall, and an increase of water the soil. E Chart I shows the average relative amount of precipitation each month. These averages are made from the records shown 'able XXVIII. It will be noted from Chart I that January, February, and March have only a light average precipitation. In fact, the late fall and winter months are all dry. The amount of rainfall in - creases in April and reaches its maximum in June. About 80 per cent of the annual precipitation falls during the period of April to September inclusive. This distribution of precipitation drives as much water during the growing season as have many sections with a much higher annual precipitation, and is favorable for the production of crops. ■able XXVIII gives a record of the rainfall by months, the &gt;recipitation, and the amount above or below normal. </seg>
            <seg id="p128">96 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska fa , ,a« .-i — m r- S 3 g : : : • : : ::•.::• :|h :::::: :h : ■•§&lt; ! : : ! :* — • ■ • -o « l *: t~ '.'.'.'.'. .-*n I'.:'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'.:, '.a &lt;?■ '.n&lt;&amp; '.~ S in oo — o -oSB •» os . ■ • • ■ • . ..-..-. — — - • • • • ■ • • cj | SS : : : i^S igg i :'g I :S : : i : H :" : ': : i i :8 I » . ! : _^; . !_j *_^ "^ • '. : : • • • • : • :^ 64 S : : : . : © « : : h * ® © £_, f_, • « • : . : S c c_, o S • • ?» • S I ET IS&lt;-&gt; •••••!• -Wtt- ••01 ••••'•• « "M — — I X) "i" — • ' ••'•■'*•••* -^ ■ • • ■ * ' ' ' • *c4 2 ; .■ '. '. r* \ ct--» .' .' .'ooa . ; ! .' .' ; r- i-H ; ; ao o *+ S : : : : i ~ l '. e-i H n . *~t "^ • ■ ' "* — '• ' • '*-* '• ' ® ® " E-&lt; • *" *~ " 1 SS | :IIS : : : :5t H « Hf4 |»S j :* mt &amp; 1^2 | | : :5 •5 I -5&gt; ! ■ §8 9) ! !e ■* ti — m '. *t* '.'.'.'.'. -h ; im m .'« ! .'to *.-: ! :~.H^EHr =:^ "En 0 . : : : : tE-t* 1 . :H§« . .t* :™ '• -t a = 9E ® ! .'«]««« .'*n .'n-ao* ! 1 • lei- . .' H '. '. .e 6 °. — H • • * ® ' °i * • ■* O ■&gt;* • • • ; OC O ; f^ • £_, O ■ ■ ; O § ;3cS H o HH 2a : : : : : :C^ : : : : : :§ IgS : : : :S o - 4 If a 4 " ~ : : : : ; : . — : : : : — : : — : « S " • I : • '■ • : • • . '• . s . "~ Eh : ™. — . : '■ — E-i "™ • • H c . c ! " o "" • . * * * . ■ rH * * ■ • * *cj « 9£ ! iocs 1 ! 's !■■■ i .').'!! i im o: m .' r- m ; 1 « o o p. — : : -^ • . : : j — :•••;:::::: — •••:••:: -^ | § :r-. = EHE-iEH :o : : -fn : : : •.*&lt;= : h -. &lt;=&gt;. •+. * 9 r : H " "i H t ? ~ • " • : &lt;?* g i I I &gt; x I §• • '•««■•••• •' 5} &lt;n • • • ■ im • • • • m • m • &lt;n £ : -.fn :~'M : : : :fn :o.E-i*1 : "■ "• '•-. • -H : :• -.c.hH :•" § ... .... . .... .. .. . • «j i-^ • !■•••'■• « • • • - — • • • • •* o : : : : : : H : '• "• '• :» : H"* :h : : :o^E-"Eh :h " : '• . g : 5 M • • io • • • • e* -asoo • h • b I : : : :H :» : IH-H : :H :H :h®H :■■ •.E^E-.H®. :E-t® « : • : • — : — 7—r-. — ::.:.: — .:..:....:. * s ••• ©■"»■ « ©■_ g : ; :h-&lt;=Eh ::: :h :::;: :® ::::•::•::: :S { || U ! it : i is i ;§S I ; ; I ; ; ; ; H s i j \\ \ \ I |s 3 &lt;a — — p,-^p^HwH"t-WNWWl?4NWWNWrtWr^ </seg>
            <seg id="p129">Twenty-third Annual Report 97 ClUBT I Average Pracipirarion by Monrhs for 35 Years Ar North Plarre I </seg>
            <seg id="p130">* P 6 HMH»osoi-HMat-ee)oo«:ot-oio«er-Nt-i-N-OHie«isor-i ooeei««oaoN«r;aO'*ai;rHioia^e»iK!r-naoiaTf*ionoi"i-rti- i i + i + i + iqu + i-M + i+fi i i i i mi r+mTi+t rf 1 5 " ... . . .... . . tOH«5«Or-NI-»rt'Nrt-l»ON«OMH^CDr*iO«NCO«OOrttO t-OiOS'M SC &gt;Hi^lNr&lt;lNi-)&amp;lH'NriNi-&lt;lMHe^&lt;-&lt;(I^HiHHHHHriHrHC^HC'l l NC']nF-?l — i 8HOOi-r-nH«t-«30 0«*«0!NO, HHnnMeaooHsi, epoi-'a io«M«nr-i-fNa'fn^iooo**h'-N»cnorit-OH^s«tif: •» » ' ' U ' o io«n*~Nn9«oi-i'HOM«oOHoanaSii:&lt;ao«HNeeon&lt;OMw i-l i-H 1-1 'OQ SSSia53Paa5?2SSSS36SSiS883SSSS5!S!*gS8SSS 2 ■ ***a»u5t«)NOOooMriioiOrtaoSni-i^o6iOiONr4i-int^'wNS3Mt-|^' '©iiOi-H "cs " r-&lt; •* ci ■*»• -■* ■* 'e4c&lt;iffime&lt;i 'eJeisoi-&lt;^-&lt;'r-&lt;cir-&lt;eoe»5r-&lt;ioeqi-&lt;i-;i4 I I rtOio*oooie«-"&gt;eoeoMa«5MnoaB»»ie«!&lt;:ino&gt;5iO"t-rHH a p-i ei « ao M fi ei ■-&lt; e4 n 'maitd 'n'nrieJFHMHn'sJn ' ■• ei ■* e&lt;i w «c « «; ri 0. o*aoo«r^r-ioq»mt-iHcit-osq«ertiOMr-i-ioas^«!vai'&gt;i'CcsO'*W' &gt;. I 5. &lt; 5SS:SSSS3S:!:8833S33S33S383S;3S3S3£83S£|* id I 5 i 'i-5'iji' 'i-h' *"'i-i" 3 I s I </seg>
            <seg id="p131">99 S Chart II </seg>
            <seg id="p132">By F. J. Alway and Stella Hartzell The term "strength" as applied to wheat and wheat flour has been so variously defined that it is necessary to state just what is meant wherever it is used. The various definitions have been discussed by Humphries and Biffen* and will not be dis - cussed here. We use the term as defined by the Homegrown Wheat Committee of the National Association of British and Irish Millers — "a strong flour is one capable of making large, well - piled loaves ; the latter qualification thus excludes flours producing large loaves which do not rise satisfactorily. To estimate the strength of any particular sample of wheat, it is necessary to prind it and make the final tests in the bake house." Wood \ pointed out that the two qualities involved in the above definition, namely, size and shape, should be considered separately. He has presented data in support of the explanation which he has offered of the cause of the size of the loaf which a particular flour can make. "The size of the loaf is shown to de - pend in the first instance on the amount of sugar contained in the flour together with that formed in the dough by diastatic action. It is proposed to measure this by incubating the flour with yeast and water, and collecting the carbon dioxide evolved during 24 hours. Particular attention should be paid to the rate of gas evolution in the later stages of the fermentation, as this is shown to be more directly connected with the size of the loaf." I A preliminary study of the subject of strength of wheat flours n at this Experiment Station in 1907 was interrupted by the &gt;val of the junior author to the Iowa Experiment Station, t is improbable that the investigation can be resumed in the future, we have tabulated the data obtained. The samples of flours used were those which remained from •Journal of Agricultural Science, Vol. I, p. 1, 1907. t Journal of Agricultural Science, Vol. I, p. 139, 1907. </seg>
            <seg id="p133">nty-third Annual Report 101 the study of bleached flour* carried on at this station in 1906 - 1907. All the samples used except Xo. 148 were unbleached. No. 148 was used as a stmidard, it being a fine bread making flour and there being a large amount of it on hand. It had been milled from wheat known to be a good sample of Turkey Red. In the case of many of the flours, the sample remaining after the com - pletion of the bleached flour investigation was too small to per - mit of baking experiments. In no case, as the original samples had weighed only five pounds each, was there enough flour to permit of more than one baking test. The evolution of carbon dioxide was determined as follows: Twenty grams of the flour to be tested was placed in a 500 c. c. flask and mixed with half a gram of compressed yeast and 20 c. distilled water. The contents of the flask were thoroly mixed and the flask at once closed with a one-hole rubber stopper, thru which passed a delivery tube connected with a measuring apparatus. The latter consisted of a 500 c. c. narrow-necked flask filled with dilute hydrochloric acid and provided with a two-hole rub- t stopper. The delivery tube from the flask containing the flour, it and water passed just thru the stopper, while one arm of ght-angle glass tube passed thru the other hole and almost he bottom of the flask. The horizontal arm of the glass tube about ten inches long and ended in a tip bent downward. Be - low the tip a graduated cylinder was placed. As gas was evolved in the first flask it passed into the second, displacing an equal volume of dilute hydrochloric acid, which flowed out into the grad - uated cylinder. A large water bath kept at 35 degrees C. night and day by means of a thermoregulator was fitted up so that six or seven flasks could be incubated at once. The incubating flasks were changed daily, each being kept in the bath 22 hours. The read - ings of the volume of gas evolved were made at the end of each hour up to the end of the seventh hour, and the final reading at the end of the twenty-second hour.t The distilled water was heated to 35 degrees before being mixed with the flour and yeast, and the flask was placed in the warm bath immediately after mixing. •Bui. 102 of this Station, 1907. t In a few cases the reading at tljjv end of the seventh hour was omitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p134">102 It is evident from Table I that the yeast varied In fermentative capacity from day to day, the amount of gas evolved during the first hour ranging from 18 c. c. to 54 c. c. The differences in the rate of evolution of pas due to this initial difference in the yeast were less marked in the second hour and disappeared in the third hour. and a I.K i 'ate o erih utiov O f ijn» from flour Mara M 0 0M i ion of gas, in c. c, per hour Kate of evolut ! i I Total vol- ume of gas evolved, in Experi- Date of experiment 1st hr. __ .. 2d 3d 4th br. br. br. 5th hr. 8th 6ih 7th to hr. hr. 2&gt;d br. c.c. 11 12 13 At. of ] Highest c rawest c Max. dif Aug. 6 " 6 " 6 " 6 " 6 6 " 8 " 8 " 8 " 9 " 9 " 30 " SI Sept. 2 3 " 4 " 5 " 7 " 10 " 11 " 12 " 13 29 21 20 22 21 22 50 54 50 32 24 50 37 32 20 18 58 46 10 42 43 50 34 54 20 ; i 71 70 f&gt;9 58 73 64 68 69 57 62 75 60 61 78 59 02 78 62 80 71 47 84 70 46 85 69 48 68 75 M 59 74 66 76 67 48 77 78 58 70 63 54 51 75 62 50 67 55 71 67 47 70 66 59 42 74 54 60 69 52 74 75 57 79 74 60 67 72 56 85 78 66 51 63 46 71 58 68 62 61 62 80 84 85 68 59 76 77 70 51 50 71 70 42 60 74 79 67 85 51 45 44 45 46 44 46 42 44 42 44 52 28 44 38 48 36 32 43 42 41 48 27 42 52 27 37 39 8 40 42 9 37 39 9 38 38 8 43 39 7 36 39 8 45 45' 8 33 38» 7 48 48' 6 40 38 6 43 39 7 22 32 8 36 43 8 20 | 34 8 45 40 8 34 29 8 27 29 7 43 23 7 37 38 4 30 19 6 57 35 5 2s 56 4 37 37 7 57 56 9 20 23 4 first 7 J° ri hours 350 459 342 452 335 438 341 448 345 453 345 449 380' 465 374- 450 390&gt; 434 363' 447 357 461 323 441 373 507 311 429 341 Ml 289 410 331 434 350 460 297 356 313 397 389 460 374 435 346 483 389 507 311 429 |9 expts »fl9" ... &gt;fl9" ... ferenee, per 170 ' 66 24 I 43 66 83 ' 185 144 I 125 I » » i ti seventh 1 ie rate of e' tour. For olution of gat the sake of t wai mifo s not obse &gt;rmity the rved it t! e end of the tor the sixth num &gt;er hour has been repei .ted, the assu npti on being that :he rate did not </seg>
            <seg id="p135">103 The results from the same flour are, on the whole, fairly eordant. For samples incubated at the same time, the results are very concordant, as shown both by the first part of Table I and by Nos. 1, 3, 13, 22, 23, and 59 in Table II. Where the readings are unusually low, there may in some cases have been leaks in the apparatus. To guard against this error, two or three samples from the flour being investigated and a corresponding number of sam - ples of the standard flour should be incubated at the same time. Six or seven samples were incubated at the same time, and on each day except September 25 one of these was a sample of the standard flour. On this date the samples used were Nos. IS. 4_\ 48, 49, 88, 121, and 140. All of these except the last had previously been tested and the readings on the two dates are concordant. Accordingly it is evident that the conditions on September 25 were normal. In the case of any particular sample the conduct of the standard flour in the same incubation period may be found by comparing the dates of the experiments. On September 10 the amount of gas evolved by the standard was low. During the third hour on this day, part of the flour mixture was forced by the gas from the first flask into the flask containing dilute hy - drochloric acid. </seg>
            <seg id="p136">104 r AB 'iate o) (TO, ution oj gas rom a &gt;i ercnt f ours. I ' Iat( 5 of evolution in c.c. per ho' I 3d 4th 5th 6th hr. hr. hr.]hr. :W 2!» 28 32 3h SI 29 33 12 30 34 SO o3' 39 n n so 41 54 42 47 4ti U 41 44! 42 M 22 20 6* 42 36 30 13 49 41 36 83 f,2 53 48 90 68 56 42 40 16 10 7 415 2 10 9 42 10 6 4 "&gt;4 14 2 I 63 26 14 13 67 33 15 12 72 36 15 1 11 72 37 17 12 54 45 36 18 54 34 16 10 58 41 22 12 66 41 4o| 40 40 22 22 26 84 55 511 40 69 40 39 42 60 50 29 21 46 35 22 23 48 27 26 21 52 41 24 24 62 48 26 17 3i 24 20 16 42 34 25 27 42 27 26 25 I 59 37 34 30 63 44 23 28 62 41) 23 23 of in- ras Total volume of gas evolved, in c.c. I — _ s Grade Date of of experi- Flour ment lst lir. 8tti to 22d hr. t 2d hr. 7th hr. i _ In first In 22 7 hours hours I \ A A A A A Patent Aug. 8 Patent " 8 Straight " 31 Bakers' " 9 Bakers' " 9 Patent Aug. 31 Straight " 31 Bakers' " 31 Patent Aug. 31 Straight " 9 Straight " 9 Bakers' " 31 38 ti4 24 2 40 2.i 36 18 20 36 41 43 82 59 '32 '33 38 35 35 9 I 5 7 7 236 348 245 m 364 434 348 44!» 343 450 i i B B B :*2 4(1 47 47 23 8 10 9 270 Ml 325 4^^ 189 3l';{ I I c c c 66 52 54 70 32 3i 37 43 7 8 9 7 306 409 290 404 327 4&gt;»7 405 516 18 i i) D r&gt; i) _ Patent Sept. 2 Patent " 25 Straight " 25 Bakers' " 25 Straight Aug. 30 Straight " 30 Bakers' " 30 Bakers' " 30 38 28 33 2 54 49 47 45 62 51 64 38 12 9 8 5 2 2 2 1 185 212 162 185 167 l!"2 116 1&gt; s i B E K E 74 76 78 78 20 19 15 17 4 5 4 4 ■I 327 271 H44 273 329 278 341 i i r F F Patent Sept. 2 Straight " 2 Bakers' " 2 32 37 33 851 70 70 23 14 20 10 6 6 273 429 235 324 257 m s n 1 1 1 (; Q Patent Sept. 3 Straight " 3 Bakers' " 3 Straight Sept. 3 Bakers' | " 4 1 3 23 14 22 42 32 52 44 26 35 14 10 7 274 492 170 313 340 446 37 n 1 1 H H 52 48 38 18 10 4 294 444 248 314 i 1 2 1 1 I I I I Patent Sept. 4 Patent ' ' 25 Straight " 4 Bakers' " 4 21 29 23 22 41 58 46 46 21 2i 21 16 4 3 4 5 209 tm 230 231 2*-&lt; 237 302 2 .1 J J Patent Sept 25 Straight " 4 Straight " 25 Patent Sept. 5 Straight " 13 Bakers' " 5 32 24 32 42 51 30 48 40 53 15 24 24 8 8 8 190 317 2iH HO 229 355 s K K K 60 71 77 24 30 24 7 5 4 286 390 310 K»2 278 335 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">Twenty-third Annual Report 105 KkMl IL — (Concluded.) Ride of violation of gas from nt Hours. IB I Grade B of Flour late of in &lt; evi i.e. ilution of { per hour as Nth Total volume of gas evolved, in a Date of experi- ment ' st hr. I ! 2d :w hr.jhr. 5tb 6th 7th hr. hr. hr. 4th hr. tO ' 22&lt;l In tirst I j, r 7 hours hour* I —I 31 30 29 27 20 22 23 17 18 21 18 23 L Patent L Straight L Straight L Bakers' Sept. 5 Aug. 30 '• 30 Sept. 5 41 44 4!i 47 59 41 n 54 74 59 80 59 50 32 56 4.-. 57 59 52 41 73 57 73 74 33 37 41 :«3 264 9 276 411 8 -i-.h m I 2*4 i N Patent N Straight N Bakers' Sept. 5 •• 7 11 7 44 48 M 2T&gt; M 65 22 24 27 M :«&gt; 28 53 M 33 224 SM 8 207 *t» 7 350 4:4 i O Patent O Straight O Bakers' Sept. 7 •• 7 " 7 M 50 :.2 40 51 7!l 33 37 25 41 43 31 62 55 35 12 278 458 11 SM 6 430 i P Patent P Straight P Bakers' Sept. 7 " 10 " 10 M :i2 M ■ 68 92 sa 74 43 37 22 31 21 28 31 22 26 8 324 444 4 304 Ml 4 344 391 I Q Patent Q Straight Q Straight Q Bakers' Sept. 10 " 10 •• ■ " 10 31 30 31 48 57 58 61 61 51 54 67 49 60 64 H2 74 3d 54 57 55 67 15 M 15 16 23 11 14 19 10 10 10 M 22 28 3 221 M 2 214 2 187 211 4 274 Hi 105 1 1&gt;6 1 107 1 K Patent U Straight H Bakers' Sept. 10 • 11 " 11 24 56 K a 40 *4 31 30 30 29 2 &lt; 23 71 23 27 6 M 5 296 :i72 5 424 IN 111 1 11: l 113 1 S Pitent S Straight S Bakers' Sept. 11 " 11 " 11 .".2 5U .-&gt;o M fit 40 41 27 42 32 25 56 39 31 9 334 4-&lt;4 11 314 474 12 344 539 Hi T Patent T Straight T Straight T Bakers' Sept. 11 " 12 " 25 " 12 4^ 36 31 48 45 58 53 66 59 M 32 29 H 29l 37 32 23 21 74 20 14 13 17 24 19 3 277 314 1 236 2 216 1 HI M ■i 130 1 131 1 132 1 U Patent U Straight U Bakers' V Patent V Straight V Bakers' Sept. 12 " 12 " 12 Sept. 12 " 13 " 13 38 31 a 1 M 62 59 66 63 66 77 62 68 66 63 79 83 70 71 57 80 78 81 4:5 4.5 .'.4 M 36 34 25 36 34 i-&gt; 39 36 25 42 49 44 16 17 25 42 36 47 5 297 M 5 305 379 4 334 10 343 4&gt;x 4 223 5 407 501 139 1 I 14ll 1 I X Patent X Straight Sept. 13 11 2 s i»; 54 57 j 43l 42 44 47 43 34 43 4 9 384 HI 17 273 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">106 E There is in general a marked similarity in the conduct of the erent flours from the same mill. An example of this is afford - »y those from mills D and T, where there was an almost com - b cessation in the evolution of gas after the sixth hour. rhere is less variation among the different flours examined Wood found among the eight which he reported. This is probably due to the fact that our samples were all from the same State and also almost entirely from the same variety of wheat, Turkey Red, while those of Wood differed from one another in variety and also, probably, in geographical origin. The data from the baking experiments are given in Tables III and IV. The "sponge," or long, fermentation process was employed. The gas oven used was large enough to bake only four loaves at a time : hence each baking was limited to four loaves, one from each of four samples of flour, of which the standard was one. On October 10 the standard flour was omitted. For c;i&lt;li loaf the fourth of a cake of compressed yeast, 2.5 grams of salt, and 130 c. c. of water were used, while the amount of flour varied slightly from the amount desired, namely, 200 grams. A quantity of the flour was weighed out before beginning the ex - periment and the portion remaining after the making of the dough was weighed. The difference gave the amount used for the loaf. The cake of yeast was mixed thoroly with 40 c. c. of water at 35 degrees C, and one-fourth of this was used for each loaf. The salt was dissolved in 120 c. c. of water, also at 35 degrees C, and the flour stirred in to make the batter. This batter was allowed to fer - ment from two to three hours in a cupboard kept at 35 degrees C, then mixed with more flour and the dough kneeded until smooth. The dough was then returned to the cupboard kept at 35 degrees C, and allowed to rise until it had doubled its bulk. Then it was baked. The time which elapsed between the mixing of the flour with yeast, water and salt and the completion of the </seg>
            <seg id="p139">107 Table HI. — Baking teat* of Hour iin&amp;l an a uttindnnl. Volui. Wpiirht of Volume of lo » f from Hour used lo»f perltt» 100 grams nouruseu grAtna Hour Hour Date of baking Weight of Volume of loaf loaf 'Compared with the average, no bread from standard Hour being baked on this day. V = «K Sept. 9 Sept. 11.... Sept. 13... St-pt. 26.... Oct. 4 Oct. 7 Average (hunts 277 2li0 264 257 260 i"&gt;9 269 280 BM an c c. ti71 Ml 675 633 685 704 680 M 66i ti73 (linntH ISO 203 19s 19H 199 200 •203 IN 211 1!)9 e.c. 372 329 341 320 344 352 3S5 34&lt;i 312 :i39 110 n 101 M 101 104 99 102 Ml Tahi.e IV — Rnlt.innt.PMtM _T\ ible IV. — Baking te.stx. i d ** wt. i I ' baking l~f lAbl.K H, DlllilWJ tt.SW. Kela- K volution of Vnl of live H"v"T^ Vol. of \° *■ , of ; vol. of w.thsiandard Vol of Wtof loaf a^,^r 1(&gt;af t )er I K =* ssi h ~ - 100 hls - Ormtm C.C. (i ram* c.C. c.c. 1115 71 •»:{ a 99 76 M mm 99 101 M 1(0 94 76 72 114 88 IB *1 MM 93 102 lo» 116 91 85 7» 83 --.I 89 N ' 80 100 88 -4 100 76 7- 102 107 I&lt;M 105 8S U 114 M 107 no M loo 109 90 80 102 106 92 85 M 104 113 123 110 101 io_ 97 a n 102 M H 83 125 136 134 108 53 60 4.: 105 65 M 100 119 99 1J0 103 114 111 12» 1 Sept. 9 260 2 " 9 264 3 " 9 260 7 " 13 256 8 "13 261 14 " 26 255 19 "26 255 22 " 5 281 B " 6 281 n " 5 2-6 28 " 7 260 " 1 258 30 " 7 264 31 Oct. 8 2S4 37 Sept. 13 253 52 Oct. 8 275 58 " 8 267 71 " 4 267 78 " 4 280 82 " 10 271 88 " 4 268 105 " 7 280 107 " 7 276 121 " 7 274 131 "10 258 139 " 10 264 141 | " 10 269 755 706 m 650 646 623 648 674 704 670 666 692 769 697 792 TO 665 724 690 752 5J-3 715 562 77*5 664 648 683 211 210 201 201 214 191 202 213 212 225 203 207 218 214 202 202 196 204 198 202 194 203 19i 206 187 192 196 :r&gt;K 336 33&lt;&gt; 323 302 326 321 316 332 328 334 353 32ti 392 333 sra 368 348 372 305 352 288 372 355 xr, 348 341 341 341 344 344 352 352 372 372 372 329 329 329 312 344 312 312 335 335 339' 336 346 346 346 339' 339' 339 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p140">108 tThe size of the loaf ( = volume per 100 grams of flour) varied the case of the standard flour Crcm 8 per tent helow to 10 per it above that of the average of the nine bakings. The size of the loaf obtained from the standard Hour in each baking test is given in Table IV, seventh column. The eighth column gives the size of the loaf obtained from each flour compared with that obtained from the standard flour on the same day (=100). The last three columns show the relative amounts of gas evolved in the incuba - tion experiments (Tables I and II) compared with the amounts evolved by the standard flour in the same incubation experiment. In Table V, in order to show the relation between the size of loaf and the amount of gas evolved in the whole 22 hours, in the first 7 hours, and in the last stages of the bread making, 5th, 6th, and 7th hours, the flours are arranged in the order of the size of the loaves produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p141">109 Table V. — Relation between rolume of loaf and erolution of (jas. Standard=100. There is clearly no direct connection shown between th of the loaf and the volume of gas evolved. The thirteen flours which pave the largest loaves evolved on the average somewhat less irsis than the other thirteen flours. Allowing for all experimental errors, it sccins at least im - probable in view of the above that there is any marked connection, in the case of somewhat s'milar flours, between the size of loaf and the amount of gas evolved in incubation experiments. While we do not wish to imply that there are not valuable results to be derived from an exhaustive study along the lines of Wood's con- Flour No. Vol. of loaf K volution of g*t per 100 gr. ■ flour In 22 hours In 7 hours | la 5ih, &gt;&gt;tb and 7th hours ; 37 ■ 58 121 30 52 71 1 31 131 n 141 ■ 105 2f 139 2 3 7 14 88 2:5 1 22 107 27 Av. of fiiht IS Av. of last 13 114 96 110 101 1U2 109 90 108 53 Hii 1(17 106 Ho 107 90 8« 106 M 85 105 71 t&gt;3 10T. 68 M 105 BT, H 104 IIS 12:s MB 111 107 102 83 H3 102 !)7 88 100 '6 - 7ti 100 110 M W) 76 M M 101 !i4 04 Tti 72 93 102 109 ill II 89 7ti 85 t-8 95 Ho 7« H 125 13« HO 100 106.5 92.0 91.0 91.0 89 70 102 4.{ 93 100 94 72 .".2 139 M 59 7H 43 120 88 103 114 115 38 ,'X) l(»i» .".1 134 84 </seg>
            <seg id="p142">110 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska elusion, any such study requires, in addition to the ordinary laboratory equipment, a skillful baker and a large oven. Most commercial flour- testing laboratories work on a small laboratory scale and in the case of flours from the same variety of wheat the results obtained are often of very doubtful value. </seg>
            <seg id="p143">rTORY OF HOG CHOLERA EXPERIMENTS IN NEBRASKA By A. T. Peters.* During the years 1899 to 1903, experiments were wdurta] this Station with hag cholera to ascertain whether a method of icination could be devised that would at least prevent and if ssible cure hog cholera. The work of 1896, 1S97, and 18M has en reported in the Thirteenth Annual Report and in Bulletin &gt;. 47. The experiments that were of importance were thai iking hog cholera serum by the use of horse serum, — des' Bulletin No. 47. FABLE I.— //03a treated irith how hon cholera KDM E»le I shows the number of hogs treateil in each year and her saved. It is of interest to note that in the year I f far the larger number of hogs treated were well at the treatment, a very creditable showing was made for h&gt;&gt;«; serum. All other yeais show that by far the larger num- •d January 1, 1910. Fhich" tbrvak curred No of out- | breaks HffUll I ' 4.", 54 31 3,K!»2 2,164 1 1,110 3,24:! 1,810 2,432 946 l.TW 4,109 2,8tt4 l.aS 1,272 909 2, "81 1 or 53% 2,964 1,841 1,122 =■ 38 3,O4K I,9t5« J.OSO 1,313 </seg>
            <seg id="p144">112 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska ber of hogs treated were sick when treated, and the per cent saved was not satisfactory. After the year 1903, in which we made such a poor showing, the work with horse serum was sus - pended. During all these years we seldom used more than 10 tant thing should be remembered, and that is that the hog cholera se - rum, whether it had much protective power or not, showed that it had very little if any curative power on sick herds. One impor - tant thing should be remembered, and that is that hog cholera se - rum was used in a large measure on very sick hogs and in the larger per cent of cases after the disease had been in progress for from three to five or more days. In most of the outbreaks a careful post-mortem examination was held to ascertain if the disease was really hog cholera. The important points noted were, whether the kidneys had petechiae, whether the intestinal tract had ulcers. t condition of the glands, and the size and condition of the een. If these characteristic lesions were present it was con - ered beyond a doubt a true case of hog cholera. In only about 35 per cent of the cases were bacteriological examinations possible in addition to the post-mortem. Laboratory Work. — Experiments were conducted in the lab - oratory on the growth and characteristics of hog cholera bacilli. It was hoped that the investigations would reveal some important facts regarding the variation of the hog cholera cultures, for it was well known that a bullion culture would be very destructive in one herd and the same culture would not have any effect on an - other herd even when used the same day. Operators in the field attributed this variation to the difference in the feeding or sus - ceptibility of the animals. For this reason hog cholera cultures were grown on horse blood serum and hog blood serum to see if the media would have any influence on the germ itself and if these blood media would increase it3 virulence. Experiments were conducted as follows: Forty-eight-hour hog cholera cultures were grown at room temperature on horse and hog serum. To these tubes was added a normal sterilized salt solution and the germs washed off the media. Five c.c. of this hog cholera salt solution were injected into three hogs with the following results: </seg>
            <seg id="p145">113 EM ho-rs injected with the serum from the hot; serum died and lti days after the injection. Of the ho«r cholera serum horse blood, only one of the three injected died. This showed no advantages over the method of cultivating hag •Terms in bullion. The standard used in the laboratory to ascertain if a pm was really that of hog cholera was that adopted by the (Jovern - nient in Bulletin No. -\ of the Bureau of Animal Industry, U. 8. Department of Agriculture. All ho«r cholera &lt;rerms had to &lt; &lt;&gt;n - fonn to these laboratory characteristics. It had to stain readily with Loefler's Alkaline Blue and had to show under proper stain the characteristic flauella. The difference between the hojr cholera trerm and the BwilM plague gam was never carefully studied by the writer. lie will admit that the swine plague gem has entirely different labora - tory characteristics and cannot be mistaken when seen under the microscope, but he dees not consider that the swine plague gem is in any way serious in producing swine diseases and that, while it is an associate and can be found in most an ; mals affected with hog cholera, it no doubt can 1r&gt; classed the same as the c»lli bacilli. which is almost always found in a case of typhoid and yet .lues not produce typhoid fever. Post-mortem. — In a post-mortem the writer would not sider it essential that, when the limps are affected and the i tines are practically free other than showing slight hemorrhairie in - fection, this form should be termed swine plapne. Any bacteriolog - ical examination held on animals so affected revealed the hog cholera trerm as well as the swine plague trerm. The writer not believe that symptoms are a very safe truide for the positive diagnosis of hog cholera, but that a post-mortem examination is the surest method of determining hog cholera. The loDowng lesions should he a iruidance: the glands are very much inflamed. the intestinal tract shows the liberations and the hemorrhajric in - farction, the kidnevs are studded with these same blood spots, the spleen is very much enlarged, and the lun&gt;rs more or less solidified. In 1903 Dr. Dorset of the Bureau of Animal Industry, United 0. </seg>
            <seg id="p146">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 114 States Department of Agriculture, discovered that the blood of hogs affected with hog cholera when filtered was still capable of producing the same disease. This brought about an entirely new situation in the hog cholera experiments. Up to this time all the experimenters were using the germs of hog cholera and of swine plague, relying on these as the sole cause of the disease. When it was found that the blood of diseased hogs showing the germs prior to filtration and free of germs after filtration was still capable of producing the disease, new methods for making vaccine had to be employed, and so Dr. Dorset used for the first time the entire blood of a hog that had the disease and injected this in large amounts into a hog that either had recovered from hog cholera or had been previously vaccinated and thereby made these hogs what is known as hyperimmune. The blood of these hyperimmunes when defibrinated and used on healthy hogs produces a limited immunity. If used with diseased blood it gives practically a per - manent immunity. r Laboratory work to ascertain the virulence of filtered diseased blood was started in May, 1904. For this experiment three hogs m conchi vere used and the results are shown in Table II. It proved isively that the filtered blood was capable of producing the '■ juile II.— Experiments in 1904 with filter&amp;l bhiod at tiie Dorset method. &amp;vt % Date 1904 Defibrinated blood Date when taken sick Date of death 1 'ost-mortem " May 6 5 c.c. defibrinated filtered blood o f Allen outbreak. May 14 May 18 Ulcers; very ad- vanced case. - May 8 5 c.c. defibrinated filtered blood of Allen outbreak. May 1!» May 22 HemorrhaL all organs. May 11 5 c.c. defibrinated filtered blood of Pollard outbreak. May 22 May 24 Ulcers. </seg>
            <seg id="p147">Twenty-third Annual Report 115 IMMUNITY OP HOGS RECOVERED PROM CHOLERA. In 1898, 1899, and 1900, experiments were conducted to make hyperimmune hogs and to use the serum in the field, which •M done with gratifying results. Much had Iieon said about hogs that had recovered from hog cholera in a natural way being immune and that they could farrow in diseased pens and nut their offspring. Experiments were conducted to ascertain if ths is true. For this purpose hogs that had recovered from hog chol - era were purchased and placed in the hog cholera pens and there exposed in various ways. Table III will show that these kofi and their litter were immune against hog cholera, which is an im - portant fact to know. It will be noticed that these hogs in Table III were all exposed to dead hogs and that post-mortem and bacteriological examination revealed unquestionable hog cholera, and the results of these exposures show that they had perfect im- </seg>
            <seg id="p148">116 Agricultural Experimt nt Station of Nebraska TAiti.E 111. — Hogs pin chased from, farmer* over t 'ie ifter recovery from a vatu &lt;"dl infection of hog cholera. a? Recovered from hog cholera. Farrowed Exposed Results of exposure 52 February, 1898, white sow. 6 pigs July 4. July 8, dead hog placed in pen. All pigs remained well. One check placed in pen took sick 8 i after and died the third day. February, 1898, Po- land China sow. 5 pigs July 12. July 16, exposed in a herd at Raymond. This was a severe out- break. Out of 110 ani- mals in herd all but 21 died. None of the ex- posed animals died or took sick. Post-mor- tem and cultures show- ed hog cholera bacilli. 1898, grade sow. July 6, dead hog was placed in All remained well. Check died ten da\s atter exposure. 9pigs July 1. Lost 6 before ex- posure. pen. .16 March, 1899, white 5 pigs July 2ft. Aug. 3, placed in pen with sick hogs. Animals showed no signs of sickness. No check in this lot. sow. 57 February, 1898, white sow. 4 pigs July 15. Sow and litter sent to Malcolm and placed in hog cholera out- break. This was a ver.\ vere outbreak. Out of 163 only 42 recovered. Sow ii nd pigs not sick at all. Post-mortem and cultures showed hog cholera bacilli. April, 1899, white sow. 6 pigs Aug. Exposed by plac- ing in hog chol- era pen Aug. 12. Animalsremained well. Small check placed with these animals took sick 8 davs after exposure but recover- ed. March, 18!&gt;9, white sow. Exposed to hog cholera Aug. 21 l\v placing dead hog in pen. Animalsremained well. No check placed iuthis pen. hi 5 pigs Aug. </seg>
            <seg id="p149">117 In tin \t;n- 1898 we purchased a large number of aawi wlrieli were imnnuie by natural cholera or vaccination. They farrowed litters in the spring and summer of 1900. About three u previous to farrowing they were immunized by vaccination at tling virus and the sows and the litt &gt;rs were later sent out and ied in cholera herds as follows: ■ot No. 169 was ■ sow and six little piga, placed Sept. 24 with k hogs bdoapag to .Mr. W. S. of Davey, N'ebr. Sow and did not take disease in sick herd. ■ot No. ltil consisted of two weanling! shipped per express 14 to Mr. W. D. II. of Wayne, Xebr. No report of results. Lot No. l")(i was a sow and 8 little pigs placed Aug. 31 with 47 sick BOga belonging to Mr. S. M. of Saltillo, Nebr. Sow and litter did not sicken in cholera herds. ■i&gt;t No. 14") was a sow and 6 little pigs taken Aug. 29 to Mr. L. of Walton, Nebr., and placed with his 73 head of siek 1k&gt;l's. it all but 7. Sow and pip did not sicken. Lot No. 1:57 consisted of two weanling piga, shipped Am:, li to Mr. ,J. S. A. of Seward, Nebr. They were placed in four cholera herds in succession without sickening. B)t No. 38, two weanling pigs, was shipped July :5 to J. W. re, Nebr., who placed them in several severe outbreaks with - eir taking cholera. ELot NO. 2~&gt;, a sow and six pigs eight days old, was taken on 29 to J. R. of Cheney, Nebr., and placed with his 46 head of hogs and they ate, drank and slept with his until all of his dead but 4. These pigs were then placed in other cholera * without sickening. I,ot No. 17, a sow and 7 little pigs, on May 2 were placed in a iiolera herd of about S15 hogs, all ages, belonging to Mr. &lt;i. K. »st Lincoln, Nebr. They remained in the {H&gt;ns with his un - but 26 of his died and our pigs were well and fat when were removed at 7 weeks old and put in another herd of holera hogs. Lot No. 171, two little pigs, was shipped per express Sep- </seg>
            <seg id="p150">118 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska to Mr. H. D. of Leigh, Nebr., to place in his cholera herd. They were healthy on Oct. 26. Lot No. 159, two weanling pigs, was shipped per express Aug. 20, to Messers. L. &amp; W. of Lyons, Nebr., and they moved them from one sick herd to another and wrote that the pigs were O.K. In addition to this, Table IV shows sows not immune by natural cholera that were vaccinated and then several weeks before farrowing were fed or injected subcutaneously with hog cholera culture. It will be noted that some of the sows died from the vaccination, which consisted in giving them the serum and culture at the same time, and which is known as the Law - rence Method and is described in detail dn the Thirteenth Annual Report. </seg>
            <seg id="p151">119 ■r. 2 S § 1 1 « — u ■^ a a 3 a ■« «• /: it o .5 5 "S " i &gt; "a. a ■ u "a a B OB gg be U — z "2. «".£ to "5. fl "16 ! I '1 1 'i 11 |i *• X m i-a !-» i-s -s »-a * *" *^ H | [_ ! ' I i I i! II -s 5 p C3C3Q3'O'3 g 5 ; * Its I ill s s § , s ' § ~&lt;H. 3g-2 3333 = ? G * « O ». M i ■ ~- s ~ ■ i -3 T. •1 s o^sISs - a • - 1? iil.il- I I jj Sill I I 1 | II Ill ii|I|liiii|i I " £ I I |o U 8 3 9 S |t 9 S &lt; i </seg>
            <seg id="p152">exposed to dead hogs and some of them injected with hog cholera culture and the results show that this litter after five months was not immune to hog cholera. The same is true of the litters of sows Nos. 39, 43, 60, 64, and 67. In the litter of sow No. 60 only one died, showing that this hog had not acquired sufficient im - munity. The litters of sows No. 67 and No. 60 were the only ISO Agt {cultural I 'xperiment Station of Nebraska Table V . — Hogs tht iefore farri it recovered from cholera and irere treated \hree weeks I m'ing. S N°o W Date 1898 Ilecord Date of No. of pigs farrow- and their ing condition Remarks Sept. 10 Fed on hog cholera Oct. 3 5 pigs in fair condi- tion On Oct. 21 this sow and litter was sent to Shel- by, Nebr., and placed on four farms. All lived while 9 out of 14 checks died. carcass S3 Sept. 10 Fed on hog cholera carcass Oct. 6 7 pigs in good con- dition On Oct. 26 this sow and litter was sent to Brai- nard, Nebr., and ex- posed to hog cholera. All lived. No record kept of the checks. Sept. 10 Fed hog cholera culture in swill Sept. 30 8 pigs in good con- dition On Nov. 3 this sow and 6 pigs (all that lived) were placed in four outbreaks. Eleven out of 16 checks died. *z Sept. 10 Injected subcutane- ously5c.c. Oct. 5 6 pig. stunted in growth On Oct. 10 this sow and 5 pigs (all that lived) were placed in the ex- perimental pens and dead hogs fed to them. On Nov. 18 the sow was sent to the Animal Hus- bandry Department and the pigs (Nos. 92, 93, 94, 95, and 96) were kept for further exper- iments. It was suggested th tat it would be im ;eresting to know th&lt; uration of immunity of these litters. Lit ter of sow No. 87 wa: </seg>
            <seg id="p153">121 E rt here losses occurred, showing that they did not have thoro im - ty. It is regretted that more work alonjr this line was not It is one of the most important lines of hog cholera re - h before the investigator. </seg>
            <seg id="p154">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 122 Fable VI. — Experiment to text t laturally infected. 'if engt 'l O immunity o) '"&gt;.'/« too. uke of Litters Nos 52, 56, and 58 of Table III. Remarks. Remarks. 5Sf Date of farrowing. Year 1900. Date of exposure 52 6 pifa July 4. farrowed Dec. 1. In hog cholera pen with a Dumber of sick animals. All sick Deo. 10. of which 3 re- covered. One check placed in pens took sick Dec. 6 and died Dec. 9. 5 pigs Jul.v SB farrowed This litter was placed in the quarantine pens, and fed 10 cc of hog cholera culture in half a gallon of sour milk. Two checks placed in the pens took sick Dec. 17 and died on the 19th and 21st. Two of the litter took sick on the 19th but recovered. Post-mortem and cultures showed hog cholera bacilli. M Dec. 11. Aug. 7. farrowed Jan. 3. Kx posed in quarantine pens and check animals placed with them Jan. 9. All animals includ- ing checks sick on Jan. 12. Two of the litter and one check dead. The other check died on Jan. IS. Two of the litter were killed on Jan. 20 on ac- count of being so poor. The others recovered Feb. 2. 1 ' mortem and cultures showed hog cholera bacilli. Record of Litter of Si W No. 67, C HOLER if Table IV, Exposed to Hog Bar -" Poland China sow farrowed this day fipigs in very bad con- dition. At 5 p. m. one pig dead. _« Two small pigs dead. June 27 One more small pig dead. -" Another small pig dead. The remaining pen in good con- dition and was placed in with sow No. 39. July 30 Sow wag put in fattening pen. </seg>
            <seg id="p155">Twenty-third Annual Report 123 Table VI. — (Continued)— Experiment to text &amp;e length of immunity of Itog* naturally infected. Record of sow No. 87 and Litter. These live pigs were the litter of hog No. 87, Table IV. Number ■ Date Culture Date when of ? avs Date of n , 1900 virus taken sick .^ &amp; _ death Kemarks Record of the Litter of Sow No. 39 of Table IV, Exposed to H&lt;*. Cholera. ssr July 14 This sow and litter was sent to Mr. M. at Stromsburg and placed in hog cholera pens. It was placed on three farms without losing any of the pigs. All check pigs placed with them died. tion _ _ ! : I Feb. 1 5 c.c Feb. 1 5 c.c. Feb. 9 Feb. 14 i 8 13 Feb. 13 The check hogs that were u Feb. 18 the pen all d ied . : Feb. 6 Kx posed in hog cbol- Feb. 6 era pen with two Feb. 6 checks not treated. Feb. 20 Feb. 20 Feb. 20 14 11 14 Mar. 8 Mar. 11 Mar. 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p156">124 Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Tari.k VI — (Continued). — Experiment to text tlte lertytk of immunity of hogs naturally infected. Record of the Litter of Sow No. 60 of Table IV, Exposed to Hog Cholera . II Fed carcass of No. 17 to sow and litter. " One little pig (the smallest in the litter) sick. 9 Sick pig dead. July 30 Sow and litter taken to Department of Animal Husbandry. Record of the Litter of Sow No. 64 of Taule IV, Exposed to Hog Cholera. SB July 1 Fed pig No. 18. Post-mortem showed advanced hog cholera lesions. ■ 2 Pig* Nos. 21 and 22 placed in pen as checks— not treated. 9 Both pigs sick and off feed. ■ 11 No. 21 dead. 13 No. 22 dead. July 30 i Sow and litter gent to Animal Husbandry Department. lEOOKD Oi the liltterof sow no. 43 op tai1l.e iv, exposed to hog Cholera . a Poland China sow farrow* d 6 pigs June 11. Fed carcass of hog No. 92 which was very badly affected with bog cholera. June 23 3 small check pigs from a sow not treated— Nos. 17, 18, and 19 were added to this pen. _„ Nos. 17 and 18 off feed — scouring. June 30 No. 19 sick. ,-,. Nos. 17 and 18 found dead in pen. ■*■ No. 19 — did not think he would live until morning so was killed for post-mortem. Sow and litter, still well, were sent to Animal Husbandry Department. Litter seemed stunted in growth but were never sick with cholera. </seg>
            <seg id="p157">TRANSPIRATION EXPERIMENTS WITH THE CORN PLANT (Preliminary Report.) By T. A. Kiksski.bach. Wlicn we make a study of the conditions prevailing in years of general crop failure or crop shortage in regions that are nor - mally very productive, it is found that the cause can usually be as - cribed to a lack of water available to the plants. This is n all strange, (or the leaves of plants in a dense vegetation act as a jrreat pump, drawing water from the soil at a tremendous rate. An average corn plant in eastern Nebraska has a leaf area of atnuit 1200 square inches. This means that with the normal rate of plant - ing in hills three feet six inches apart and three plants in a hill, the leaf area of corn plants on one acre of land is twice the area of the land. In other words, ea: h acre of corn has two acres of 1&gt; It was found at the Nebraska Experiment Station that a sini_'l" plant with 1250 square inches leaf area lost nine poondi water durin'r 8% hours of August !». l!)0!l. Charging th ; s much transpiration to each corn plant in an acre having a full stand as above indicated, forty-eijfht tons of water were transp ; red by the plants of a single acre during 8% hours of that day. This is nearly 1 L . acre-inch of water, and if it were spread evenly over the surface of all the leaves it would form a layer nearly ' , inch deep. Al the experiments herein reported will indicate, water that is drawn up from the soil is lost from these leaves much as water is lost from a sponjre when exposed to a drying atmosphere. The rate of this water loss in a given plant depends chiefly ti[Min cli- B These experiments were conducted as graduate work in the tment of Experimental Agronomy. Acknowledgment is made )fessor E. G. Montgomery for helpful suggestions and generous obtaining the necessary materials. </seg>
            <seg id="p158">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska 126 matic conditions. If the atmospheric demand for moisture con - tinues and the plants are unable to absorb moisture at the required rate, the plant tissues collapse and ultimately die from drouth. Where an abundance of water is available, corn plants are fully able to absorb all necessary water under the most drying field conditions such as hot, dry winds.. The noticeable relation of water supply to plant growth has led to numerous inquiries and investigations to find if possible some practical means for reducing the amount of water that the plant must absorb for normal growth. It is with this same object in view that the following experiments were undertaken by the writer in a preliminary way. Such a search involves a study of the functioning of the plant itself, and the method used must be such as to permit an accurate determination of the absolute transpiration by the plant, or that quantity of water which is evaporated from the leaves and stems. In order to study the effect of variations in any one particular environic factor, all of the plants should be subjected to otherwise identical condi - tions. Differences in results may then be quite safely ascribed to Esponding differences in the one factor under control. Sev - such factors may be combined in order to study variations several factors under control. EMany results obtained in the past have been accounted for he apparently erroneous supposition that the leaf stomata or thing pores exert a regulatory control over the quantity of &gt;r transpired according to variations in the conditions of th. That there is. no such regulatory control was pointed out tperiments by Lloyd in which he determined the absolute tran - ition from plant cuttings. A similar negative result was ob - ?d by the writer with growing rooted corn plants from which absolute transpiration was determined under the following litions. Eltogether, observations were made with 40 corn plants of an yellow dent variety. Twenty of these were grown for 64 n rich alfalfa sod loam soil watered with well water, while ler 20 were grown for 76 days in sand watered with a com- </seg>
            <seg id="p159">Twenty-third Annual Report 127 plete nutrient solution. Those plants grown in soil have been called the Soil Saturation Series because they were divided into 5 sets of 4 plants each, each set of which was kept at a different degree of saturation. The plants growing in the sand were kept at an almost con - stant saturation of 100 per cent. They have been called the Soil Fertility Series because they were divided into 4 sots of 5 plants each, each set having a different strength of solution added. !The object in view with the soil saturation series was to find possible the relation, if any, between transpiration and the ater content of the soil. It has commonly been held that the total nount of water transpired and the quantity used per gram dry atter produced were in more or less direct relation with the il water content. In this connection the plants in the soil sat- </seg>
            <seg id="p160">128 Agricultural Experiment Station of Xcbraska illation series were studied in regard to the relation of soil water content to changes in the quantity of water transpired as influenced l&gt;y rWngjllg climatic factors. The soil fertility series was intended to throw light upon the relation of soil fertility to the quantity of water transpired in producing a given dry weight. It has l&gt;een quite commonly be - lieved that the quantity of water transpired per gram dry weight increased considerably as the strength of solution decreased. To make these determinations a new apparatus which may nned a transpirometer was devised. Into the bottom of a 4-gallon glazed stone jar was placed an empty inverted 4-inch porous flowerpot. This pot was conn* with the surface of the jar by means of two Vi-ineh glass tubes and (1 both as a water chamber and an aerating device. One-half liter of water could be added at a time thru one tube by means ot a funnel with rubber tubing connection and the displaced air es caped thru the other tube. The jar was nearly filled with air-drv soil, which was firmly packed about the inverted flowerpot. The water added in the pot was quickly ihmrbed by the surrounding soil mass until saturated. By knowing the weight of the apparatus and the total dry weight of the soil contained, and the weight of water required to saturate it, any desired percentage of soil satura - tion could be maintained by frequent weighings and replacement of the water transpired by the plant. Surface evaporation \v;is prevented by three sheets of paraffined parchment paper, lapped over and tied firmly to the jar. A layer of gravel about an inch in depth was placed upon the paraffined paper, both to weigh it down and to prevent evaporation thru the I 1 ■/•&gt; inch space j:bout the corn plant. The plants were grown out of doors in a cornfield. The entrance of rain was guarded against by permanent closely fitting oilcloth covers and a temporary canvas tent covering during all rain storms. Bie type of transpirometer used in these experiments has thi - ng characters: 1. The roots penetrate thoroly thruout the soil mass. 2. The absolute transpiration may be definitely dete^mineJ. </seg>
            <seg id="p161">Twenty-third Annual Report 3. Thoro aeration of the soil is permitted. EL The plant may be grown normally in a soil or sand culture am for a great length of time. 5. The addition of water is easily accomplished, and constant soil saturations may be maintained by weighings. SOIL SATURATION SERIES Kch transpirometer contained 15,680 grams of air-dry soiL ired 6,099 grams water to saturate the air-dry soil which ed 8V2 per cent hygroscopic moisture. five degrees of soil saturation were maintained, based on the y soil, viz., 98, 80, 60, 40, 20 per cent saturation with 5 to ■ cent variation. Each transpirometer W8° weighed separate - grams every 48 hours at 7 P. M. Water was added several during each interval so as to avoid much variation from the desired percentage. The saturation never was greater than the assigned degree, and each 48 hours the exact weight was restored. At the age of six weeks, 200 grams of water were added to the total weight, to partially balance the increased weight of plant. One corn plant was grown in the center of each transpirom - eter. The seed was planted July 3 and harvested September "&gt;. 1907. As the quantity of soil was not sufficient to grow the plants to maturity they were harvested green, shortly after the silking </seg>
            <seg id="p162">130 B These plants were regularly located on the same level on either e of the trench, but for the purpose of taking this picture the plants the soil fertility series have been placed in the trench. Note the at uniformity of the growth of plants in each series. The canvas •kground was temporary for taking the picture. Photo taken gust 13, 1908. The retarded growth of plants in the 20 per cent soil satura - tion (Table I) indicates that in this soil and under these conditions of growth the water supply was deficient. Of all the plants, these alone wilted somewhat when conditions were conducive to heavy transpiration. Regardless of the soil water content, the total amount of water used in all cases was very uniform, except in the 20 per cent sat - uration where it was considerably less. This falling off may doubt - less be accounted for by the rather frequent wilting of the leaves. B Nearly the same amount of water was transpired per gram weight in all saturations, except in the 20 per cent saturation. I somewhat less was used, the dry weight produced being also In general the root development varies inversely as the soil water content. </seg>
            <seg id="p163">Twenty-third Annual Report 131 Is &gt;. — 3 *E ° - - y«|j I*-. 00 ." 3 .-: 0 . . ft * *M s 5 S«o OrtMiOifl — c u 3 I i i £.-3 t. &lt;:3.s • * 5 ll-s s |xsa«a !&gt; T_ t, qj i. 3 a" cfi e «N IM •* m r- I s sis si if 'I 0873 « 3 5 ■Qsao-' S a 3i -^ r^ rj s. ■&lt;»&gt; ta &gt;ra •« ce 6 ri B 1 I ■«• a so r- &gt;o i&gt; JO c9 i T3 £ * O is-sllls. 'sstta JS'- flag §1 l -.3 I ! «- o </seg>
            <seg id="p164">lit cos bi S rJ f i **-. _ « «j ° Ss* - ~ ~~^ v { I =U C X J! S * Q g _ S. no S s be" 5 S ° 3^ : i ; £ aa «iet-HrtooM«-;«5Masi-N3.aoc a. ■* O-S N«iSl"nB«SO00O*«*»ISN-e £^~ , I I 1 5 "a 5 2 aS 5S is. go 5 1 I S S -5 Gu— *it-r-noct--t-«asai-n»oi'MN O * S" - — rt — — -I-H^ — rt-! 8 i ! ik! I 1 5- -.1 2 * lOfloowiaoi-^^eiiecsMoBoicii-M •M | «- be r- r- r— r- r- i— r- r— r- r— r- r— t— r- t— t— t— r- t- . s a s" -"« -a "*• s s tf jfsf s sf a s s »" *f^ j»&gt;j*&gt; &gt;» ti be be tic tic tic bit ti bl i bk ti ti ti bit fti ■§.■§. I </seg>
            <seg id="p165">f«N nty-third Annual Report 133 i — : TT1 | 1 1 1 1 1 | —~- -^^— ■"■*™ — ~ ■" ~~ I T "I 1 r T T 1 1 I aB-c s cr2f -SSC3 1^ "■ •— -^ J^ —M i ~ x ~ 3ESE3 ? — x 3 1 "^^^ d a . Q " i i i, 1 S Si — </seg>
            <seg id="p166">134 x _^ r &gt;r. - O oS as oo — os * — ao t- n -♦ 35 PI * «5 r- g2 "E •So o&gt; «o ori Wio *•!-•' t- *"*&lt;«' ao «o so X- J _ £* C »- . _ § SSMUSM3 •♦©■♦'in-* *&gt;O »'■&gt;*' •♦««!■♦■*«' H- r- I Oi, "- ~ •— *O *»c8O • ~X ?» i » ,,» O^S 00NMS'"Or--C — OP-t'dKC B . g c~ *■ ("S^at-HHftiffxNMts-cntiM^ii *" j^ -^ c o 3~ S r # x S rfS 2 o-^S*'"* ■ ° "3 .- Nn'is'ia« ;c ■&lt;*■ us is » » a&gt; ■♦' ♦' n x&gt; us •♦ ! S § °^ £2* •£•= *~ " * lSlsSSa2a8S85S2SJ8SS5g. os u le •— « n ic « -t » * io «; b &gt;n c ■*' t '^ s o ■!■ v ~ J = ~^r -= o- — *" _. w JO S* es ». 5 &gt;■ S ooxxxxopapopooaoooooxxaoooxa £ s 3 o" a ■» g 0 "^ -S - S~ | 3 -5 | _Jj co -^ s .g : 1 a ** 8» ::::::::• ; ••• : : : : : ~ *i « OQ &gt;■• tx U ti ti ti si ii u. ti ti be u li i ti i </seg>
            <seg id="p167">Twenty-third Annual Report 135 to - a £ »-o - a a-^ 2 g «8^2 $ 3*. i_ — _* ■■ ft ft 55 "Hjl lit r — s &gt; C - «&gt; S.X 4 £ U 2 st.c IlSI &gt; ' £ f ifilljj S 7 S = «?3 ■ M I— — — N </seg>
            <seg id="p168">136 There was a wide variation in the quantities of water tran - spired during different 48-hour intervals. The greatest difference between two consecutive periods will be noted on August 27 and 29, when the variation was 80 per cent. There was a correspond - ing variation in evaporation rate from a free water surface. The method used in determining the evaporation rate was rather out of date, but the data obtained will serve fairly well for compar - ison with the transpiration. P careful study of Tables II and III and Charts I and II that regardless of the soil water content the periodic fluctu - ation in the transpiration rate was nearly the same with few ex - ceptions. (The slight irregularities can to some extent be account - ed for by the fact that in these rapidly growing plants the leaf area was inconstant.) All increased or decreased in quantity of water transpired at about the same relative rate. This would seem to indicate that there is little or no "stomatic regulative control" of transpiration as related to soil water content. That is to say, according to the belief of many investigators, one would ex - pect that on days conducive to excessive transpiration the relative increase in quantity of water transpired would be less where the t liable water supply is small, as a result of stomatic closure in icipation of wilting, but this was not the case. rie causes of these changes in the transpiration rate are found the same as produce changes in evaporation. (Table IV.) The transpiration changes from one interval to the next can be accounted for in most cases by changes in one or more of the climatic factors. Relative humidity of the air is the chief con - trolling factor of both transpiration and evaporation. The change from the interval ending August 29 to that ending August 31 is especially interesting in showing the effect of temperature and wind velocity. The strong tendency to vary with humidity has been demonstrated in most intervals, but on this occasion is shown the great effect of temperature and wind velocity on both transpira - tion and evaporation. Very interesting problems are suggested here on relation of climate to transpiration. </seg>
            <seg id="p169">137 a t* . * -&gt; 3 e^ Zkts £S ee«»Coa g « r- ao x o o o c t-i s i r-N&lt;«ac — * s»'** afni J«K m* : 5^" ! o = E acicio 5C»-^C'it^3;t-r^»c?i?*i^H»— r— 't n ri ?i — 1 1- c- i- r. « »o — a LI'S £ w.i I 3 ill: " 5 us ■ nl — r 3 = 3g -a b oS»g ec-*5C*CW5O: re -M — ■ r~ re rt wr^r -« — — &lt;; "8 » « .1 g»** C &lt;- «? 2 ° "■2 - §■ S - ■ ■! 9 ■« "•», ~ - a u (c * = 1 JS-2 5 S St.** c te 6t-S IT =1 JS-2 o^ 5 S .35 ih t- as oo » ao « «o « «c co s&gt; a&gt; 2 3CX3C3C00XXXXXX0CX3CX3C7 S — — — -«— .M*ieM^S« &gt;. at ti be si »i si si ;i u u it bi si si si. ii 31 P *^33333S3333333333«* •S2 </seg>
            <seg id="p170">138 FERTILITY SKRIKS Four sets of five plants each were grown in pure river sand, watered with a complete nutrient solution • of "arying strengths, viz., .6 per cent, A per cent, .2 per cent and .1 per cent. (Period of growth July 3 to September 17.) Table V. — Showing correlations Water tran- Total water spired per transpired gram dry No. plants Strength Saturation J^ averaged solution maintained diiced weight Gramt 47.8 i 74.9 65.3 73.4 P There was not much difference in the amount of water used gram dry weight with the different strength solutions. How - ever, not including the 0.6 per cent solution which was too strong for normal development, the amount of water required decreased slightly with an increase in the strength of solution. Cie dry weight produced varied but little except with the 0.6 nt solution; here it was rather low, doubtless due to too a solution. INDICATIONS The quantity of water consumed by similar corn plants in pro - ducing a given yield cannot be materially affected by varying the water content of the soil, other things being equal. No more water is transpired by corn plants of the same parentage growing in wet soil than by those growing in much drier soil, provided it is not •Schimper's Normal Nutrient Solution (Concentrated). Formula : 6 gr. calcium nitrate. 1.5 gr. potassium nitrate. t5 gr. neutral potassium phosphate, 5 gr. magnesium sulphate. 1.5 gr. sodium chloride. 600 c.c. distilled HaO. 'er cent Per ceni .6 .4 2 100 100 100 trama 'jrani* 11592 16734 15577 19041 223 </seg>
            <seg id="p171">Twenty-third Annual Report 139 Kthat the plants wilt. With the soil this dry, somewhat less I used in producing a given dry weight, but the yield is also ed. It MM that there is little or no stomatic regulative control which will adjust the rate of transpiration according to the ex - ternal conditions. Ke transpiration rate varies much with the changes in the clmatic factors, relative humidity of the air being the chief these. The transpiration curve is fairly parallel with the ition curve. Ris possible that by knowing the rate of evaporation from a ater surface in any given locality, an approximate idea may of the transpiration requirements. Ea experiment in which similar corn plants were grown for unths in pure river sand watered with a complete nutrient n showed no marked relation between the strength of so - and the quantity of water required to produce a unit of atter. The root development is proportionally much greater in . I ry than in wet soil. Plants which make their early growth in dry soil may then be expected to better withstand a later period of drouth for the reason that they would have a great absorbing sur- </seg>
       
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>