<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth BEATRICE, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">Fifteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth BEATRICE, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">102 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH RESIDENT OFFICERS W. S. Fast, M. D Superintendent Emma J. Lawrence, M. D Louis Werner Assistant Physician Steward Susan H. Raley C. P. Underwood Cora Austin Matron Bookkeeper Stenographer SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Harriet Schaeffer, Principal Martha Dillon Clara Wilson lone Storey Ada M. Glancy Jack O'Donnell Hazel F. Ferrell DEPARTMENT HEADS William Pollock Eada Pollock W. C. Alvord Nellie Alvord Tabitha Greenwell Lon Wait Boys' Supervisor Girls' Supervisor Supervisor Boys' Hospital Supervisor Girls' Hospital In Charge of Laundry Chief Engineer D. J. Dennehy Paul Hohlbein Carpenter Painter </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 103 To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I herewith hand you the fifteenth report of the Nebras - ka Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, covering the bien - nial period from December 1st, 1912, to November 30th, 1914, and with it I beg leave to offer the suggestions per - taining to the operations of the Institution for the next two years. ACKNOWLEDGEMENT If success has been attained in the management of this Institution during the past two years, much of the success has been due to the wholesome advice and generous support given us by the Governor and the members of the Board. We have also been fortunate in being surrounded by loyal assistants. The officers and employees have been faithful and have worked in harmony with the Superintendent. The boys and girls for whom this Institution was built and for whom it is being maintained have been ever ready to assist in the work and have been easily governed by kindness. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">104 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF MOVEMENT OF POPULATION No. present on this date Nov. 30, 1914 No. of officers and employees Nov. 30, 1914 470 47 Total population November 30, 1914 517 The number of children present at the close of the bien - nium shows a material increase in the population during the past two years and the number of applications for ad - mission now in our hands and with the correspondence with people in the various counties relative to feeble-minded children who should have institutional care we are led to believe that with the extra room provided, as will be recom - mended later on in this report, the Institution will, at the end of the biennium just beginning, be again filled to its capacity. We are able with our corps of teachers to do much in the way of mental and physical training for the feeble - minded child. About half of the children are capable of being taught to read and write. They are also taught num - bers, a little geography and some history. The average feeble-minded child is not able to carry on school work beyond the third or fourth grade. However, the average feeble-minded child outside of institutional care is never taught even to read and write and is considered too dull for any school work whatever. Besides the regular school No. enrolled December 1, 1912 429 No. on vacation December 1, 1912 17 No. of inmates present December 1, 1912 No. admitted during the period 161 Wo. discharged (52), died (43), during the period 95 No. enrolled on last day of period, Nov. 30, 1914 495 412 No. on vacation or temporarily at home on this date 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 105 work, we teach our children the various industrial vocations. Boys do brush-making, help with the plumbing, painting, carpenter work, farm and garden work. Girls learn sew - ing, crocheting, basketry, weaving, housework, etc. There have never been at this Institution adequate edu - cational facilities. For many years the school rooms were on the third and fourth floors of the main building and many of the children who were mentally capable of learning were physically unable to go to the upstairs school rooms. In the past two years we have used one of the cottage wards for school purposes and have had all our school work on the ground floor. These quarters are cramped and unsuitable in almost every way for the purpose we are using them, but better than those formerly provided for schoool use. NEW SCHOOL BUILDING In our present school rooms we can accommodate only about one hundred children, while we have at the Institu - tion more than two hundred and fifty who should have school privileges. By far the greatest need of this Institu - tion is a new school building with four large rooms for school purposes and industrial classes, with cloak rooms and toilet rooms all on the ground floor and an auditorium on the second floor with inclines or easy stair-ways to the same. Our assembly meetings, religious services and amusements are now held in a day room of one of the cot - tages. The room is wholly inadequate for our population. We can, in this room, accommodate less than half of our children who are able to and should attend such meetings. By building school rooms and an auditorium as proposed we would be able to reconvert our present school rooms and assembly room into a ward, the purpose for which it was originally built. The present school rooms were good dormitories and without any changes can be again used for sleeping purposes for the children. By having the new building for school and industrial purposes and converting our present school rooms into ward use, we would be able thereby to make room for thirty to forty more children. With the increase of population during the biennium </seg>
            <seg id="p007">106 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF and the probability of a continued increase in the regular way and, considering the fact that there are many feeble - minded children in the State who should receive institutional care and whose presence out in society is a menace to the State and whose parents and guardians are demanding in - stitution care for these defective children, it is my opinion that another cottage should be built so that we would not be compelled to refuse admission on account of lack of room to any feeble-minded person in the State. The high grade feeble-minded child is to the casual ob - server apparently not far from normal. Physically many of them appear normal. Many of the boys and girls are good looking and, but for their mental defects, would get along well in the world. With their mental defects, how - ever, and their pleasant faces and normal bodies, unless segregated by institutional care, they would get out into the world and mingle with society — the mentally defective boy choosing for his mate a mentally defective girl and, by their union, bring into the world a number of mentally defective children. The mentally defective mother and the mentally defec - tive father generally raise a large family. The feeble - minded person ordinarily knows no such word as self - control, having the same desires and same pleasures as the normal person and, left to their own initiative, they would marry one of their kind. Observation teaches us that the mental defectives are prolific in propogating their kind. SEGREGATION For the sake of future generations, I want to make a plea to the Governor and to the Board that adequate pro - visions be made for the segregation of the high grade feeble - minded child. My opinion is that, if for a period of two or three generations mentally defective men and women were absolutely prevented by segregation and otherwise from propogating their kind, feeble-mindedness and insanity would be very materially decreased and, if the mental de - fectives were segregated or otherwise made incapable of propogating their kind, in the period of a hundred years, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 107 feeble-mindedness and insanity would almost wholly be eliminated. We have no right to allow the defects of this generation to be stamped upon the children of coming gen - erations. HEREDITY Heredity is a tremendous factor in the causation of mental defects. Statistics show that at least sixty - five per cent of feeble-minded children come from men - tally defective parents and a very small number, probably two per cent, from traumatism and that possibly five per cent is due to the influence of diseases upon the brain struc - ture, the most prominent of which we would name cerebro - spinal meningitis and infantile paralysis. Other diseases contributing a share are scarlet fever, typhoid fever and whooping cough, dangerous in the order named. HEALTH There has been no epidemic during the past two years. The health of our entire colony has been uniformly good. Early in the period there was a threatened typhoid outbreak, a few cases occurring among inmates and employees. This was an aftermath of an epidemic occurring during the for - mer biennium, and was soon gotten under control. During the past year no true cases of typhoid have appeared. The mortality rate of the Institution has been remarkably low. The cause of death in the majority of instances was either epilepsy or tuberculosis. About fifteen per cent of our pop - ulation are epileptics, some of them are of the most severe type. Tuberculosis has been prevalent among the most helpless children. Some of those who were unable to walk and who were of necessity in the house a great deal of the time have succumbed to the disease. One of our boys who contracted tuberculosis was transferred to the Hospital for Tuberculous at Kearney. Our children have been singularly free from injury and accidents. One boy was injured by slipping on the ice and breaking his leg, another fell from a wagon and broke his arm. Both made good recoveries and show no evidence of </seg>
            <seg id="p009">108 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF having been injured. At this date we have no children sick in bed. MORE LAND NEEDED Many of the boys are able to do work on the farm and in the gardens. In fact, we have more boys who are able to do such work than we have work for the boys to do. We need more farm and pasture land. The boys are better contented if given a reasonable amount of work. The State's holding given over to the Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth consists of 222 acres. The buildings, the orchard, the groves and the lots occupy about 40 acres. We have about 40 acres in pasture, 65 acres in alfalfa, 40 acres ordinarily for garden, sweet corn, potatoes, etc., the balance of the farm, about 40 acres, for corn and oats. We should have and could care very well for 100 acres of corn and half that acreage of oats. We should have also more pasture. I would recommend the purchase of from SO to 160 acres of land near the Institution. OUR DAIRY Our dairy herd consists of 26 cows and 20 heifers, the heifers most of which will become cows within the next year, some of them soon. We have, during the past two years, kept all of our heifer calves and by continuing doing so we expect in another two years to have enough cows to furnish sufficient milk for the needs of the Institution. At the present time we are not getting the quantity of milk we need. The herd at the beginning of this biennium consisted of a mixed sort of cows all of which were eight years old or over. We have added, during the past two years, six pure bred Holstein cows and a pure bred Holstein bull. All of the calves ve are now saving for the dairy are either pure bred Holsteins or high grade Holsteins. HOGS We have on the Institution farm a herd of 65 head of hogs. In 1913 cholera attacked our herd and we lost a num- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">y c q i en n I m ,- C ■j: ■ &lt; | a: IIH"^^ c s 1 g a: </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 109 ber of the young hogs, but fortunately saved all of the brood sows. We now have a herd of 13 aged sows and a male hog that are immune to cholera. They have raised for us during this year about 60 good shoats. They are thriv - ing, no disease having appeared among them. HORSES AND MULES The State owns at this Institution two good spans of mules, one heavy work team of horses, one medium size general purpose team of horses, two fairly good driving horses, and one old farm horse. RAILROAD SWITCH NEEDED The Institution is located three miles from the freight stations. The only mode of transportation of goods from the railroads to the Institution is by wagon route. It costs the State about $.60 per ton to deliver coal, a carload of 50 tons of coal costs the State $30.00 to deliver to the Institution. During the biennium the Institution will use about 3,000 tons of coal, it will consequently cost the State $1,800.00 to deliver this coal to the Institution. A railroad switch could be laid to the Institution from the nearest point of the rail - road yards, which is nearly two miles from the Institution, at an estimated cost of $5,000.00. The saving of drayage expenses during one biennium, I believe, would pay for the track. This is one of the Institution's greatest needs. ICE PLANT NEEDED The Institution is in need of an ice manufacturing plant with a circulating refrigerating system sufficient to keep the cold storage plant cool and also with a capacity of making about 1000 pounds of ice per day. For cold storage purposes the Institution has been depending upon ice cut from the small stream running through the Institution grounds. Bacteriological tests in the past have shown this stream to be contaminated with typhoid germs. We have endeavored to guard our food supply from direct contact with the creek ice, this being a task that requires most care- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">110 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ful attention and, even then, there is great danger of food contamination. We have, during the past year, bought manufactured ice for kitchen use during very hot weather. I believe that it would be a wise procedure for the State to abandon harvesting ice from the polluted creek, the quality of which is always questionable and the quantity uncertain. At an expense of $5,000.00 it is my opinion that an ice plant could be installed, doing away with the dangers as above stated and giving the Institution a more wholesome supply of ice and manufactured as needed. CHICKENS During the past year this Institution became fairly well established in the chicken industry. We have hatched and raised about 2,000 chickens. The Institution has con - sumed and sold about half of those raised. We are keeping about 1,000 young hens and expect soon to be getting all of the eggs necessary for use at the Institution. FINANCES A record of the financial affairs of the Institution is in the hands of the Board, therefore we are not including it in this report. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 111 The following work was done during the biennium by the sewing room and the needle work department of the industrial classes: SEWING DEPARTMENT MADE NEW 216 Sunday dresses 840 Everyday dresses 432 Aprons 180 Underskirts 1008 pi Elastics 72 Waists 150 doz Sanitary napkins 264 Gowns 240 Night shirts 100 pr Drawers 60 pr Combination drawers 9480 pr Overalls 150 pr Rompers 13992 Shirts, r 1 doz Men's shirts 210 doz Diapers 40 doz Bibs 12 doz Work aprons 3 doz Bakers' caps 312 doz Sheets 210 doz Pillow cases 280 doz Towels 3 doz Table cloths 12 doz Napkins 350 pr Curtains 4 doz Sofa pillows 5 doz Laundry bags 1 Mangle cover 12 Bread covers 6 Throw covers 3 doz Husking mittens 14 Hall runners 12600 4176 13560 3696 11040 2640 3312 pr 9504 pr 1200 96 9480 pr 13992 2928 504 504 744 pr 102 96 20 pr 100 pr 14 24 doz 5 doz 10 doz 6 Dresses Aprons Gowns Underskirts Undershirts Waists Drawers Combination drawers Sweaters Corset covers . Overalls Shirts, men's and boy's Nifrht shirts Jackets, men's and boys' Coats, men's and boys' Pants, men's and boys' Vests, men's and boys' Caps, men's and boys' Gloves, men's and boys' Rompers, boys' Overcoats Sheets Comforts Blankets Rugrs TI7I-J _1 1 U- -J 30 Window shades hemmed he: NEEDLE WOR IK DEPA1 lRTMENT 17 17 13 pr 2 2 pr 36 5 1 1 12 10 1 IS Sofa Pillows Emb. sheets Eml). pillow slips Drawn work sheets Drawn work pillow cases Fancy towels Emb. shelf pieces Emb. table cover Emb. sideboard piece Emb. centerpieces Emb. doilies Emb. white waist Emb. dresser scarfs I 25 2 7 1 2 19 35 29 lbs 12 450 19 Emb. corset covers Crocheted curtain holders Fancy aprons Lunch cloths Crocheted spread Crocheted table runners Raffia baskets Raff rugs and 5 yd. runner Rags sewed to be woven Pennants Tea Towels Miscellaneous articles </seg>
            <seg id="p014">112 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF FARM AND GARDEN Following is a list of farm products raised on the In - stitution farm during the year 1913 and 1914, the same be - ing consumed at the Institution : 1913 1914 Apples 100 bu. Apples 100 bu. Alfalfa 125 ton Alfalfa 150 ton Beets 300 bu. Beets 400 bu. Beans 50 bu. Beans 50 bu. Carrots 100 bu. Carrots 100 bu. Cucumbers 50 bu. Cucumbers 10 bu. Cabbage ~ 400 head Cabbage 500 head Cherries "ZZZZZZZZ. 200 bu. Cherries 200 bu. Corn " " 400 bu. Corn 800 bu. Com (sweet) TZZZZZZ.'. 200 bu. Corn (sweet) 500 bu. Fodder ZZZZZZ.. 35 ton Fodder 40 ton Lettuce 100 bu. Lettuce 100 bu. Onions 100 bu. Onions 200 bu. Oats 550 bu. Oats 720 bu. Potatoes 800 bu. Potatoes 1500 bu. Potatoes (sweet) 200 bu. Potatoes (sweet) 400 bu. Peas (green) _____ 20 bu. Peas (green) 20 bu. Parsnips 50 bu. Parsnips 20 bu. Radishes ZZZZ 150 bu. Radishes 200 bu. Rhubarb 100 bu. Rhubarb 100 bu. Squash Z ZZZZZZZZ. 100 bu. Squash loO bu. 100 bu. Spinach '.'. 100 bu. Spinach _. 7 ■* /\ _- _ _ O*. __ ... Straw ______ 10 ton Straw 8 ton Tomatoes ZZZZZZ 300 bu. Tomatoes 400 bu. MEAT AND MILK There have been produced on the farm and slaughtered, cattle and hogs, as f ollows : Dressed beef : 6217 pounds Dressed pork 9258 pounds Milk produced 19568 gallons Respectfully submitted, W. S. Fast, Superintendent. Beatrice, Nebraska, November 30, 191i. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">.-*" ~4 ■ .- 4 i i s i' -• &lt;H I c &lt; CD P ■I d 5 1 1 j 5 •^ . </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 113 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year to to Nov. 30, Bienmun Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Present at beginning of of period 14 198 412 21* 198 11: Admitted: For first time Readmitted* 27 10 37 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 H5 160 Transferred from other Institutions Returned from parole granted before com - mencement of per - iod Returned from escape made before com - mencement of period Totals Discharged: No longer requiring institutional care Transferred to other institutions Died ''aroled or on visit home and not returned dur - ing period Escaped and not return - ed during period Totals Remaining at end of per - iod 246 224 470 230 195 425 Average number in Inst Absent on parole or es - cape at commencement of or during period and later discharged without returning to institution •Includes those who have been previously admitted to this Institution or to similar institutions elsewhere. Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for </seg>
            <seg id="p017">114 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE II. AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE III. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 to to Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 For year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium AGES Under 5 5 and under 10 10 and under 15 15 and under 18.. 18 and under 25 25 and under 35. 35 and under 45 .. Over 45 M. F. ', 6 6 2 2 3 6 5 6 1 1 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 11 11 6 5 4 9 10 3 13 21 7 28 8 5 3 8 13 11 24 24 16 40 5 2 13 8 6 14 12 10 22 11 5 3 8 6 7 13 17 15 32 7 4 4 6 6 12 16 7 23 1 1114 5 2 5 7 112 5 7 2 6 8 Totals Totals 27 11 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 66 161 For year ending For year ending Nov. 30. 1913 CIVIL STATUS Nov. 30. 1913 For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium M. F. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Single Married Widowed Divorced Separated Unknown ... 27 11 38 22 13 35 45 39 84 94 12 3 1 1 1, 63 157 2 3 1 1 Totals 27 11 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 66 161 For year ending: Nov. 30. 1913 EDUCATION For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. Able to read and write Unable to read and write 3 24 2 9 5 3 3 6 5 4 9 33 19 10 29 41 38 79 11 84 9 20 57 141 Totals 27 11 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 6&lt;5 161 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 115 TABLE V. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VI. PARENTAGE OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending: For year ending: Nov. 30, 1913 Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium NATIVITY M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Nebraska United States, other than Nebraska 21 S 29 17 8 25 39 36 75 77 52 129 I 8 8 5 4 9 7 5 12 17 12 29 Total native born 2tf 11 37 22 12 34 46 41 87 94 64 158 Austria Dominion of Canada Russia 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Total foreign born 1 1 11 11 1 2 3 Totals 27 11 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 66 161 For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1, 13 ending Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Noy.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium PARENTAGE M F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Both native born Both foreiim born Mixed Unknown 15 9 2 1 :s l l 21 16 10 26 28 25 53 12 5 2 7 13 10 23 3 3 6 9 2 112 2 13 59 27 5 4 41 100 15 42 7 12 3 7 Totals 27 11 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 95 66 161 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 116 TABLE VII. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,1 ending Total Remaining Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, COUNTY Nov. 30, to to lia.30.-13 Nov.30,13 1914 biennum 1914 M. F. T. M. F. T. '. T. M. F. T. M. P. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Adams 1 1 2 12 1 1213268 2 2 11213628 1 114 4 1 1 1 1 2 6 8 6 2 8 Antelope 2 2 Boone 1 1 4 4 1 2 3 2 2 4 Brown 1 1 11 • 2 :&gt; 3 3 12 3 2 :) Burt 1 1 11 1 11 112224 1 1 2 Butler 2 113 3 « 3 9 ■1 1 1 1 1 9 Buffalo 1 1112 11121 1314K39 3 14 H 3 9 ri Box Butte 2 2 2 I Cass 3 3 3 3 8 3 11 3 3 ■&gt;. 8 3 11 1 113 4 7 i i a 4 7 Cedar 1 1 Cherry 11 11 2 2112 1 1 1 1 2 2 112 Cheyenne 1 1 ! 1 1 223 3426 2 2 ■! 3 4 2 6 Clay 1 1 3 3 Colfax •&gt; Cuming. 11 11 2 2 12 3 1 1 1 1 2 2 Custer 1 1 1 112 2 4 3 7 1 1 2 2 4 3 11 112 13 11 2 13 Dakota 1 ! 11 1112 3 Dawes ] 1 1 Dawson 11 112 3 5 1 1 1 1 a 11 1 1 :i 4 7 1 1 :i 4 iJixon 1 1 1 11 ! 2 :; 5 Oodge I Douglas 4 7 6 6 12 10 22 21 14 35 4S :}o 8." 21 14 35 4b :!.'. 8" Dundy 1 1 11 1 1112 112 112 11 11 114 18 Fillmore 1 Franklin •' 2 2 3 3 5 5 5 1 •; Frontier 1 4 1 1 1 1 2 :S 2 5 Furnas 1 1 2 ] 3 12 12 24 Gage 2 1 Garfield 1 2 3 Gosper 1 1 1 11 1 11112 Greeley 1 1 Hall 1 11 1112 1 1 1 4 Hamilton 1 2 3 2 2 1 2 •&gt; Harlan 1 1 Hayes 1 1 Hitchcock 1 1 Holt 1 1 1 12 4 6 3 6 Howard Jefferson 2 2 1 1 2 13 2 5 7 Johnson 1 1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 117 Total 28 10 38 22 13 35 46 42 88 96 65 161 260 235 495 I) AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM— (Continued) For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 -» For year Dec.1.12 Jul. 1,13 endinjr to to Nov. 30, lun.30,13 Nov,30.'13 1914 Total for Biennium All Remaining Nov. 30, 1914 COUNTY M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T Kearney Keath Keya Paha Knox Lancaster Lincoln ..._ Madison Merrick McPherson Morrill Nance Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe Pawnee Phelps Pierce Platte Polk Perkins ... _ Red Willow Richardson .... Saline Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sherman Sioux Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston Valley Washington .. Wayne Webster York State 1 1 2 2 4 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 3 3 11 3 3 1 1 2 2 1 11 1 1 1 i i i 1 12 2 112 2 1 2 111 11 2 3 4 7 5 6 11 13 2 2 2 2 1 12 13 1 113 111 11 1 11 13 4 4 4 8 5 11 3 14 7 112 112 7 4 1 11 114 1 11 4 113 3 4 13 4 3 3 6 2 4 4 4 4 4 2 1 2 112 2 2 11 111 2 13 2 13 3 3 1 ' , i ' ' \ 3 114 4 6 1 1 2 1 S 1 1 3 20 33 8 8 4 4 3 6 1 1 1 1 7 12 5 12 6 13 2 6 1 2 2 2 6 1 4 4 8 6 8 6 10 1 3 4 5 1 3 1 3 2 3 1 4 7 2 5 1 1 1 1 4 1 5 1 3 6 7 13 1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 118 TABLE VIII. HEREDITARY INFLUENCE TABLE IX. CONDITION OF THOSE DISCHARGED For year ending Nov. 30. 1913 For year CONDITION AT Dec 1.12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for DISCHARGE to to Hov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30. 13, Nov.30,13 1914 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Much improved 628 628 12 4 16 Moderately improved 11 11 Slightly improved 224 415639 1 1 Unimproved 9 5 14 5 3 8 14 8 22 Insane 1 1 12 3 2 2 4 Totals 18 10 28 16 8 24 34 18 52 For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 HEREDITARY INFLUENCE For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30. Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium Hereditary taint denied Father or mother feeble- minded Father or mother insane. Father or mother epilep- tic Father or mother intem- perate Parents blood relations Grandfather or grand- mother feeble-minded • Grandfather or grand- mother insane Grandfather or grand- mother epileptic Aunts, uncles or cousins feeble-minded Aunts, uncles or cousins insane Aunts, uncles or cousins epileptic Brother or sister feeble- minded Brother or sister insane. Brother or sister epilep- tic Unknown i_ M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. 3 1 4213549 10 11 4 15 8 4 12 17 15 32 36 2 13 1 1112 4 1 1 2 112 13 4 3 1 1 2 112 2 4 6 4 1 1112 12 3 3 3 3 2 2 4 4 8 9 1 1 ! Ill 12 1 1 2 2 112 4 2 6 7 11 11 2 2 2 2 1 13 4 7 6 8 3 Hi 7 4 11 12 15 27 1 27 F. 6 n i .i I I 4 1 1 I 4 4 22 F. T. 16 M I I H) I 13 :s 1 in 4 10 49 T. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 119 TABLE XI. PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN INSTITUTION OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING BIENNIUM For year ending For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 ! Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium CAUSE M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Apoplexy Dysentery Epilepsy Erysipelas Exhaustion from heat Gastritis Inanition .'. Intermittent fever Malnutrition Meningeal inflamation Pneumonia Tuberculosis of the bow- els Tuberculosis (Miliary).... Tuberculosis (Pulmonary) Typhoid fever 11 11 111 1 459 22467 13 11 11 111 1 112 111 1 112 112 11 11 11 11 11 11 2 2 2 2 2 2 113 3 11 11 527 41593 12 11 11 Totals 16 8 24 1 4 5 10 4 14, 27 16 43 p m« For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year ending njn.r in i ai •! Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Less than one month From one to six months From six to twelve mos From one to two years. From two to five years.. From five to ten years. ... From ten to twenty years From twenty to thirty years Over thirty years M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 1 ~T | 1 1 2 2 112 2 2 5 16 11 11 3 14 113 2 5 123 12 3246 224 11415 64 10 617 223 3 93 12 2 2 2 2 Totals Totals i 16 8 24 1 4 5 10 4 14 27 16 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 120 TABLE XIII. AVERAGE NUMBER OF PATIENTS EMPLOYED Average number employed Average Per Cent Population Employed In Outside Ward Ward Aggregate For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 AGE Under 10 10 and under 15 15 and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 35 and under 40 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 50 and under 55 55 an] under 60 00 and under 65 H5 and under 70 Over 70 AGE For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30,13, Nov.30,13 1914 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. i ~T~ i i 2 21121 1415 314 62893 12 224 22123 369 6 6 117 7 2 2 1112 3 112 11 123 112 112 11 11 Totals 16 s 24 1 4 5 10 4 14 27 IK 4:- During year ending Nov 30, 1913 39 50 89 75 30 105 114 80 194 228 193 421 50 39 *■*; During year ending Nov 30, 1914 50 60 110 75 30 105 125 90 215 247 224 471 50 40 45 Averages .. for bienni- um 45 55 100 75 30 105 119 85 204 237 207 446 50 78» 44* </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 121 TABLE XIV. RATIO OF EMPLOYEES TO PATIENTS M. F. T 1 1 2 Number of physicians, including superintendent Ratio of physicians to patients 1:212 Number of day nurses and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients ! 13 18 1:24 Number of night nurses and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients 1 5 6 1:71 Total day and night nurses and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients 6 18 24 1:17 Total officers and employees. Ratio of same to patients 18 2&lt;) 47 1:9 </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026">s -•% "^ | n s r 5 as cr. Q J I =^- £«J = I S 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Twelfth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Girls' Industrial School Geneva, Nebraska To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE B1ENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 124 OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES Lyda J. McMahon Superintendent Minnie A. McMahon Matron Alice E. Becker A Family Manager Mary E. Donohue B Family Manager Anna R. MacKenzie C Family Manager Hazel D. Harvey Assistant Teacher J. M. Aeschlimann Secretary Lucile Tennebaum Music Teacher and Librarian Bertha Heald Sewing Teacher Ida Clark Domestic Science Teacher Clara Barnes Laundry Teacher A. A. Le Roy Band and Orchestra Director Cashen C. Murray Farmer and General Helper A. D. Huston Engineer James Cuzick Assistant Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 125 To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I have the honor, herewith, to present the twelfth bien - nial report of the Girls' Industrial School, covering the per - iod from November 30, 1912, to November 30, 1914. Our task being ever the same, to receive neglected, delinquent, and too often morally defective girls, to provide for them a home whose atmosphere shall be as nearly like the normal home as institutional life can make it, compels us as fast as financial circumstances allow to make such improvements as will tend to the physical well-being, moral and mental development of our wards. In the past ten years we have made a difficult but con - tinual climb. It has always been hard for the present man - agement to convince those in whose power it lay to make adequate appropriations for our maintenance. Comparison with other institutions is odious; girls cannot go into the field and plow, cultivate the land, or do manual labor which tends materially to lessen the per capita in other institutions of our State where such help may be utilized. Our girls average in age 13 years; come too often wholly untrained, uneducated and physically unsound; we must begin at the very foundation. Four and a half hours each day are de - voted to school work, four hours to industrial training, and the rest in beneficial and varied recreation. No more could be expected and I earnestly invite the closest investigation of our work and ask that investigation precede censure. The most important event of the last two years was the creating of a Board of Commissioners by an act of the 33rd Session of the Legislature. The duty of this Board was to assume charge and man - agement of all State Institutions after July 1, 1913. New life and ambition was awakened by the support and earnest co-operation of this Board, they giving special attention to </seg>
            <seg id="p030">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 126 the methods of care and treatment, education and improve - ment of our children and we feel that we no longer are struggling alone with our difficult and perplexing problems. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS We have about ready for occupancy a new building 48 ft. x 119 ft. It comprizes four floors, and furnishes us with a large auditorium to be used as an assembly room, library and music hall, a dormitory that will accommodate 80 beds, a hospital, girls' dining hall, and teachers' dining room, four private suites for teachers, modern general kitchen, brick Dutch bake oven, storage room, and a three-department refrigerating room that will hold two tons of ice. The building was designed by architect Joseph W. Sal - mon and built by W. J. Assenmacher Co., Lincoln. It was completed at a cost of about $45,000.00, is a reinforced con - crete fire-proof structure built of red brick trimmed with cut stone, has five large steel trusses on which the slate roof is carried, and third floor ceiling is of concrete. The dormitory floor or auditorium ceiling is suspended from roof trusses by steel rods eliminating columns in assembly room which is 46 ft. x 72 ft. There are steel stair balus - trades, composition floors, and tile entrance. The building is heated by vapor vacuum system and first class plumbing on every floor gives perfect sanitation throughout. Tele - phone and electric wires are all carried through conduit and a tunnel 8 ft. wide, 60 ft. long and 9 ft. high connects the two buildings ; this tunnel is also heated and lighted. We repaired the administration building, removing the old lime plastering on walls and ceilings of three main floors, replastered and painted; put new flooring on three main halls, hospital C dormitory, and superintendent's din - ing room ; built a commodious kitchenette on second floor and superintendent's private office ; installed four best flush valve toilets in girls' recreation rooms ; and temporarily fitted out a department for our new family; erected four iron standards with electric lights on the grounds ; laid 2,000 feet of cement walks; built cistern 12 ft. x 20 ft., a new poultry house and addition to coal shed; partitioned </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 127 boiler room with brick walls and built a storm shed on east side; put vegetable cave in good repair with cement steps, good doors, and two ceiling ventilators ; put in a 4 in. Crown water meter ; planted a small plum and peach orchard ; and fenced four acres of alfalfa hog tight. Every dollar has been made to go as far as possible and there are many im - provements to show for the expenditures. NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION To sucessf ully carry out our work, to suitably and prop - erly furnish our departments with necessary machinery and equipment, I submit, herewith, the following conservative estimate for the coming two year* • Maintenance (which includes clothing, food, shoes fuel, electric current, water supply, furn - iture, bedding, placing children in homes, med - ical attendance, dentistry, chaplain service, feed, stock, carriages, harness, horse, musical instruments, school equipment and supplies, amusement and entertainment, dishes, ice OUR WORK AND ADVANCEMENT Until 1892 the delinquent boys and girls of Nebraska were cared for in one institution at Kearney, but by a wise act of the Legislature of 1891 a separate school for girls was established and the small population at Kearney was transferred to Geneva. Two divisions comprized the classification from this time until 1912; now we have a better defined classification and segregation according to character has been secured by the addition of another class or "family" as they are called. In this division are placed the girls of excellent record who supply) _1 $45000.00 Lepair and improvements 14000.00 iuperintendent latron 3000.00 960.00 'amily managers 4560.00 Employees' wages 8040.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">128 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF are free from infection and perfectly normal m every res - pect. Excellent reports are received from girls who have been paroled and discharged; we keep in touch with them regu - larly and it is gratifying to hear of their filling responsible positions as nurses, stenographers, dressmakers, milliners, domestics, and high school pupils, entering the 10th grade after leaving our institution. Our aim is to place the girls in homes where the in - fluence and surroundings will be of the best ; where they will not only be kindly treated but have real help toward leading useful lives. We are not living in an ideal world and dis - appointments sometimes occur. When homesick or dis - couraged the girl turns to the institution for which she has only the kindest feeling ; her little visit rekindles fresh courage and she goes back to her duties and the world where she has now proven herself a helpful and honest woman. Our work is so arranged that each girl receives during the year training in laundry for three months, kitchen three months, sewing three months, and general housework three months. She is obliged to attend school four and a half hours five days in the week. In connection with this, she has musical advantages — piano, horn, reed instrument, vio - lin and voice. Our class rooms are noticeable for their cheerful and busy atmosphere, for the spirit of helpfulness and self-con - trol. Our girls come from city schools, rural schools, and from the streets. Their previous training has been in no two cases the same; most of them have had very little, if any, interest in school, have been irregular in attendance and their advancement has not been uniform. Our problem is to meet the most urgent need of each one and our aim is, not alone to impart knowledge, but rather to develop char - acter. In this the personal influence of the teacher counts for much. In class room, kitchen, laundry, sewing room, music hall, or on recreation grounds, pride and interest must be aroused, ideals developed, evil habits and thoughts eliminated, cleanness of thought and action made desirable. Strength of character, earnestness, sympathetic under- </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
            <seg id="p034">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 129 standing and unlimited patience are needed for this work and the demands on the teacher are many. During the past biennium, as in other years, my corps of teachers have devoted strength, interest, skill and time to their work, have made their various departments a potent influence in the reformation of the girls, and, to me, have given loyal and intelligent co-operation. One fact, however, remains, — and I should like to im - press this upon the minds of our legislators, — that while physical and mental response is readily observable after a few months' experience in the well-regulated life of the school, moral growth is perforce a slower process. Time for the development of character cannot be reckoned in weeks or months; our training loses its effect if a girl leaves the school too young. A year or two more in the institution for many a girl is often the saving grace for her. There is less to be feared of her becoming "institutionalized" than of her being too weak to stand the temptations that beset a young girl at every turn in the outside world from the ages of 16 to 20 years. I ask that our jurisdiction be extended to twenty-one and the age of majority made the same as in the case of the boy. This is especially fair in the event that Nebraska will give woman the right of franchise. FARM AND GARDEN PRODUCE From November 30, 1912, to November 30, 1914 2,677 ftal. milk 900 lbs. butter 440 bu. potatoes 250 bu. tomatoes 300 heads cabbage 26 bu. beets 200 bu. sweet corn 14 tonff alfalfa 6 tons timothy 1,098 bu. oats @ .20 $2535.41 .. ..© .30 270.0( @ .75 330.01 Q 1.00 250.W @ .05 15.W @ .40 10.41 ....© .50. 100.W i © 15.00 210.01 e 13.50. 81.W ..@ .50 549.W Total $4350.81 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">130 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK To the Superintendent, Girls' Industrial School Madam : Starting as I did less than two years ago with a small band of ten pieces at the Girls' Industrial School, Geneva, we have grown to a band of twenty-two and an orchestra of nineteen, playing a good grade of music correctly. The instruction is general and the opportunity open to all. Many pupils have made remarkable progress and our band and orchestra are now recognized as first class organ - izations. We have played at the State Fair, County Fairs and other popular assemblages before noted musicians who are all enthusiastic in their praises. The only drawback to our ambitions has been the limited fund at our disposal. It was through the most careful management and generous assistance of our friends that we have accomplished what we have. The girls have cared for tneir instruments and music in such a manner that draws from me the hierhest commen - dation. Respectfully yours, A. Albin Le Roy, Director of Music. Geneva, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. To the Superintendent, Girls' Industrial School. Madam : Preventative medicine and sanitation are the main fac - tors in maintaining the health of the inmates of any insti - tution ; a healthy body is the first aid to a healthy mind ; the two taken together make possible the reformation and train - ing of those who have been abnormal in their tendencies. At the Girls' Industrial School, since I have been in charge of the medical department, there have been no epi - demics or contagious diseases of any kind and no sickness or accidents except of very minor importance such as slight burns, sprains and an occasional off-day. Those who are contaminated with specific diseases when received are given careful and reerular treatment and are soon cured. The most excellent system of classification </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 131 arranged by the superintendent divides the population into three grades or classes, thereby segregating these specific cases. This, not only institutes a more moral measure, but also a sanitary and hygienic control of those inmates and diseases which might be contageous. The new building now nearing completion which was badly needed will facilitate the handling of these cases and make it possible for the management to more readily carry out this classification, also, when the new hospital rooms are at our disposal we will be able to carry out aseptic meth - ods. The most important need of the institution is the dis - posal of the sewerage. This is imperative and should be im - mediate. Respectfully yours, J. Bixby, M. D. Geneva, Nebraska, November 30, 191 U. I conclude my report with thanks for your cordial sup - port of my administration, and for the splendid encourage - ment and helpfulness received from the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions. Respectfully submitted, Lyda J. McMahon, Superintendent. Geneva, Nebraska, November 30, 191 U. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">132 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1, 12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,13 1914 M F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Present at beginning of period 86 82 86 86 Admitted: For first time Readmitted* 11 11 1 38 &lt;il 1 Transferred from other institutions 2 2 Returned from parole granted before com - mencement of period 9 s 22 5 Returned from escape made before com - mencement of period Totals 106 100 133 172 Discharged : Expiration of fixed term Reached majority 9 1 IE 25 Transferred to other in - stitutions -. 1 3 4 Released to parents or friends I a 20 5 Died Paroled and not returned during period 10 • 23 7 Escaped and not returned during period Totals 24 15 33 72 Remaining at end of per - iod 82 85 100 100 Average number under care 94 92 116 151 Absent on parole or es - cape at commencement of or during period and later discharged with- out returning to school 3 13 I •Includes those who have been previously admitted to this or similar institution. </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 133 TABLE II. AGES AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE III. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 IJul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, 13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium AGE W C WC T W C T W C Under 10 10 and under 12 12 and under 14. 14 and under 16 16 and under 18 1 4 1 2 K 4 1 1 5 6 4 1 1 1 2 5 14 6 13 1 5 1 2 1 3 2 16 13 ■4 2 4 25 23 1 1 2 2 5 27 23 Totals 12 12 IS 39 M 58 58 6 6 64 6-1 For year ending: For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 Jill. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium EDUCATION T r T F T F None Below 3rd grade 4th grade 5th grade ' 6th grade 7th grade 8th grade I High school ; College j Unknown 1 2 1 1 1 : 2 2 1 1 1 12 I 2 10 4 2 1 15 15 5 18 5 3 2 Totals. 12 13 :S9 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">134 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 Dsc. 1,'12 Jul. 1, '13 ending Total for NATIVITY OF PARENTS For year to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,'13 1914 to For year ending For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 NATIVITY Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1/13 ending to to Nov. 30, Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,'13 1914 Total for Biennium T F Nebraska _ United States, other than Nebraska Total -native born Germany, total foreign born Unknown 7 4 11 ] I 7 21 14 12 1 ■ 1 3 33 25 ■ t ■ I 4 Totals. 12 13 39 United States, both par- ents j Foreijm. both parents Mixed j Unknown I 11 1 13 31 1 4 3 56 2 4 3 Totals... u 13 39 fU J </seg>
            <seg id="p041">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 135 TABLE VI. PARENTAL CONDITIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year PARENTAL CONDITIONS Dec. 1,12 'Jul. 1, '13 ending Total for ti to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,'13 1914 F T F T F T F T Both parents dead 1 4 5 Father dead 1 2 6 9 4 "&gt; Mother dead 1 4 5 10 Parents living together... 9 !t 1» TABLE VII. AGES AT DEATH OF PARENTS 'arents separated las stepmother Jnknown 'arents divorced ... las stepfa^e- Totais ... 1 2 2 3 3 5 9 2 3 7 2 1 3 4 7 13 4 9 16 Mi' 5T~ 49 * For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending Total for to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, '13, Nov.30,13 1914 AGE OF CHILD Age at death of father Under 10 years 10 and under 15 years.. 15 years and over Unknown , Age at death of mother Under 10 years 10 and under 15 years.. 15 years and over _. , Unknown 1 1 1 1 1 1 4 7 2 6 1 1 x 4 1 11 1 2 Totals. 17. n </seg>
            <seg id="p042">136 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII. ADMISSIONS FROM DEFECTIVE OR DELINQUENT HOMES For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,'13 ending j Total for CLASS to to Nov. 30, 1 Biennium Jun. 30, '13 Nov.30,'13 1914 F T jF I IF T F T Feeble minded: Father Mother 1 1 Both parents Brother 1 1 2 Sister Insane: Father Mother Both parents Brother Sister Intemperate: Father 6 3 10 18 Mother - 1 1 2 Both parents Brother _ 8 3 Sister - _ 1 1 Delinquent: Father . Mother 1 1 4 6 Both parents Brother 1 Brother 1 1 Sister 1 1 Unknown Totals , 8 6 21 i 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 137 AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 "I COUNTIES For year Dec. 1,12 Jul. 1,13 ending to to Nov. 30, lun.30,'13 Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium All Remaining Nov. 30, 1914 F F F r r Adams , Brown Buffalo Butler Cass ' C&lt;sdar j Custer i Dakota Dodge Douglas Fillmore Furnas Gage Garden Grant Hall Harlan Holt — Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Lancaster Lincoln Nance _ Nemaha Phelps Platte Polk Bed Willow Saline Scotts Bluff - Thayer Washington .... Wayne I ■ ■ 1 1 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 -1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 l!i 1 1 I 4 2 1 I ■ i i i i 2 1 2 27 1 1 2 1 3 1 1 4 1 1 1 3 1 2 1 3 1 2 i i i i 2 2 3 M 1 2 2 1 1 5 1 I 1 1 1 9 1 2 1 2 6 3 1 1 1 3 1 1 Totals.. 12 u 39 ti-1 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">138 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE X. CAUSES FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year CAUSE FOR Dee. 1. '12 Jul. 1,13 ending Dee. 1, 'IS Jul. 1,13 ending Total for ADMISSION to to Nov. 30, Biennium Jun. 30, '13, Wlt/ia 1914 TABLE XI. STATISTICS OF PAROLED PUPILS On parole Nov. 30, 1912 Paroled during biennium Returned from parole: 12 2:; For cause VI 10 IS Without fault Escaped from parole and not retaken Discharged from parole Died while on parole On parole Nov. 30, 1914 •; TABLE XII. DIVISION OF LABOR OF ALL PUPILS NOV. 30, 19U School, 4\i hours per day 100 Domestic Science, 6% hours per day Laundry, 4% hours per day 16 U :&gt;i Sewing, 4% hours per day Total. 100 Dependency or neglect Delinquency: Unclassified Assault Breaking and entering Immorality Larceny 1 ;» 2 1 8 1 3 10 27 12 4 4 I 3 Total Delinquents.. 11 12 n r,2 Grand total 12 13 39 64 </seg>
          
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>