<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Bacillary White Diarrhea in Chicks</title>
               <date value="1920-07">1920-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 58 July, 1920 Bacillary White Diarrhea in Chicks L. VanEs, M.D., V. S. Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BACILLARY WHITE DIARRHEA IN CHICKS The term white diarrhea is rather loosely applied to certain dis - eases marked by abnormal intestinal discharges. Some of those diseases are not now understood, but of the one responsible for the greater part of the losses, we have learned at least enough to be able to devise preventive measures. This disease at present is more particularly known as bacillary white diarrhea because it is caused by a specific bacillus, namely the Bacillus Pullorum, discovered by some of the New England experiment stations. HOW IT ACTS As the disease is commonly observed it is the most ruinous one to recently hatched chicks. Affected chicks as a rule die within a day or so after leaving the egg. The symptoms may be very misleading, as affected chicks may die without diarrhea being present. There may be weakness, dullness and death resulting merely from lack of vitality. In such cases the infection may kill without giving time for the development of abnormal bowel discharges. The greater number of outbreaks are, however, marked by the occurrence of a number of cases of diarrhea. This diarrhea fs char - acterized by a whitish, creamy and sticky bowel discharge in which from time to time brownish streaks may be observed. The discharged substance may be quite abundant, but not uncommonly the evacuations are rather scant. The stickiness of the discharge causes it to adhere to the down about the vent and not rarely the latter may become effectually sealed in this manner. It is also noticed in not a few of the cases that the evacua - tions are quite painful to the chick as shown by the sounds it produces. Affected chicks lose their appetite, act drowsy and prefer to remain quietly under the hover. The wings droup, the eyes are closed, the down is more or less staring and it seems that they take no further Interest in life. If such chicks do not die within the course of the day they become extremely poor and weak enough to compel them to remain lying in one spot. In some of the cases death does not occur for a number of days and then the chicks concerned will often assume a very peculiar appearance. They anpear to become "short backed" on account of the becom - ing enlarged and protruding backward. In this condition the chicks may live for several days. A few may even survive as scrawny looking cripples. Most of the affected chicks die before they reach the age of three weeks. THE CHICKS AFTER DEATH The after-death appearance in white diarrhea cases vary and we can only attempt to give an average picture of what may be observed at the autopsy. It is common to find the crop either empty or filled with a sticky, stringy fluid, which may also be present in the gizzard and the intestines. The latter are usually quite empty altho grayish or brownish contents may be observed. In the ceca or blind guts a more or less solid, cheesy sub - stance may be found. The liver is of a pale or dull ochre color and often has its surface marked by reddish streaks or patches. The substance of the or^an is soft and friable and in the more strongly developed cases the gall bladder is quite often overfilled. All internal organs are pale in color. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Within the abdominal cavity there is nearly always found to be present an unabsorbed yolk. Several investigators having extensive experience with the disease regard this feature as quite characteristic of the disease. The yolks present range in size from that of a pea to a normal-sized egg yolk and vary in color from yellow to brownish green or almost black. In consistency they may be gelatinous, watery or cheesy. NATURAL HISTORY OF THE DISEASE The natural history of the disease is interesting and contains valuable indications as to how the disease may be managed. Investigation of the disease soon showed that the young chicks become infected during their formative stage within the egg, and it was further discovered that the egg becomes infected before it is laid and that the hen herself is the real source of infection. OLD HENS AS INFECTION CARRIERS How this comes about cannot always be traced out, but two ways are open. In the first case, the hen as a chick may have survived the dis - ease and have remained a germ carrier ever since. It has been repeatedly shown that such surviving birds are apt to remain infected for the rest of their lives. It is also well within the range of possibility that perfectly normal birds take in the germ of the disease with food or drink con - taminated thru the droppings of sick chicks or infection-carrying older birds. Another very important feature in the natural history of the disease is found in the fact that the white diarrhea bacillus once introduced into the older fowls, will become localized, especially in the ovaries and testicles. In this connection the sexual organs of the female are especially im - portant because, even if diseased, they will continue to form eggs, to some extent at least, and those eggs are always infected. They have, however, a noiu.al &lt;ti&gt;pea.aiiee and thus become th3 usual means by which the disease is spread. The infected ovaries show some characteristic features which should be known to all poultry raisers. In such an ovary, both normal and abnormal ova (eggs) are present. The normal eggs are like those of an uninfected bird and as a rule show considerable variation in size. In the diseased ovary the eggs are more apt to be of equal size and in a given ovary we find at least many of the same volume. In the case of the larger eggs we always recognize the tendency to become irregular in outline and angular in shape. The surfaces become flattened and show a somewhat mottled coloring, while the substance of the yolk itself ranges from a light yellow to a dark, greenish brown. Such eggs are firmer than normal ones and often contain a solid, cheesy substance and a clear, yellowish fluid. In such ovaries the germs of the disease can always be found. SUGGESTIONS FOR CONTROL OF THE WHITE DIARRHEA In the handling of the disease we have nothing to depend on but preventive measures. These may be of a general nature and consist of the practice of cleanliness, the disinfection of incubators, brooders and utensils, proper feeding, the selection of vigorous breeding stock, pro - tection against cold and dampness. Of more specific character are the preventive measures which are </seg>
            <seg id="p004">directed against the introduction of the infection and toward its suppression after this should have occurred. THE IMPORTANCE OF INFECTION-FREE EGGS The principal vehicle by which infection is introduced into a flock is by the infected egg used for hatching purposes. It is, therefore, extremely important that only eggs be selected which originated from flocks or poultry yards having a well- established freedom from disease. In addition we should keep a constant watch over the condition of the hens composing the flock and to accomplish this thoroly we should make it a regular prac - tice to examine the ovaries of all birds used for the table or which die of various causes. When diseased ovaries are found we should go to other sources for our hatching eggs. It may even be quite advisable, in flocks where many diseased ovaries are found, to kill off all the remaining birds and to mak&lt;* a fresh start after a lapse of two or more months. As fowls with dis - eased ovaries are perfectly fit for table use, the loss will not be too great. By bacteriological tests of the blood of the fowls it is often possible to pick out the ones most likely to be the carriers of infection, but it is doubtful if the cost of this method, when applied on a large scale, would not render it rather impracticable. On farms where the disease has gained a firm foothold it seems wise to suspend hatching for a time, altho when a thoro cleaning up has been done this may not be absolutely necessary. A complete disinfection of all utensils with which infected chicks have been in contact is imperative. The brooders used for chicks which were exposed to the infection must be disinfected every day. Tbe floor should be sprinkled with such a sub - stance as fine sawdust or al' Ufa meal, in order to render thoro cleansing more easy. It is also wise to divide the chicks into as many separately kept groups as possible and whenever a chick shows any evidence of indisposi - tion, it should be removed before its droppings can increase the danger of infection. Judicious feeding of sour milk has been known to exercise a favorable influence upon the mortality rate, altho it would be rash to attribute to this any specific influence. In the case of incubator chicks more than ordinary care should be given to maintain a clean water and food supply and especially should the latter be guarded from contamination by the droppings. Fresh, clean water should always be used and no medicines should be added to it or given otherwise. (10M&gt; Distributed in furtherance of cooperative agricultural extension work. Acts of May 8, 1914, and June 30, 1914. Extension Service of The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture and U. S. Department of Agriculture cooperating. W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>