<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  HANDLING SILAGE.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 145. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. VoLuiut XXVII, Article II. HANDLING SILAGE. By L. W. Chase and Ivan D. Wood. Distributed September 1, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. I'MI RIMNTt OF TNI UNIVERSITY HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. HONORABLE QEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, Pretident, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYPORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICER8. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. B. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. C. W. PTJGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service. J. 8. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. R,D Wacox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. TJpson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. Bliss. B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. H. C. Fiixey, A. H., Farm Management. Kr. Mormll, M. For., Forestry. A. Emerson, D. Sc., Horticulture. . Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent of Experimental Substation. North Platte. C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Botany. J. W. Calvin, B. Sc., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Boils). Eswnr Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). J. A. R ati -lift, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. Howard J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M.. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz Knorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. •S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nye, Foreman Demonstration Farm. Cuibertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Equipment and help required : The large commercial outfit R The cooperatively owned smaller outfit 5 The small individually owned and operated outfit 5 Cutting the corn 6 Corn cutters 7 Corn knives 7 Sled harvesters .- 7 Corn binders 7 Table 1. — Cost of cutting and loading 8 Field loading 8 Hauling in green corn 9 Unloading green corn 10 Types of silage cutters 10 Table 2. — Capacities and horse power requirements of machines using blowers 11 Machines using carriers 12 Table 3. — Capacities and horse power requirements of machines using carriers 13 Tramping the silage 13 Sealing the silo 13 Watering the silage 13 U Removing silage from silos : Above-ground silos 14 Pit and semi-pit silos 15 Hand hoists 16 Horse power hoists 18 Hoisting with a gasoline engine 21 Cost of silage 21 Table 4. — Cost of various operations in filling silos. . .22,23 '• A simple hand hoist 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BY L. W. CHASE AND IVAN D. WOOD.* Green corn such as is generally used for silage is very heavy. The moisture content ranges from 60 to 85 per cent of the total weight of the corn. For this reason every means should be util - ized to simplify the process of filling the silo and to reduce the labor and cost of handling the corn. Three general classes of equipment and methods of handling the corn are utilized to produce this result. They are: the large commercial outfit, the cooperatively owned large or small outfit, and the small indi- EQUIPMENT AND HELP REQUIRED. THE LARGE COMMERCIAL OUTFIT. Khere the large commercial outfit is hired and a cutter having acity of 18 or 20 tons is used the following method is gen - carried out : Eie corn is cut with two corn binders; hauled in with five or teams, depending on the length of haul; four men are used I field to hand up the bundles; one man is used at the silo to unload; one man to care for the cutter; and two or three sed in the silo to distribute and pack the silage. THK COOPERATIVELY OWNED SMALLER OUTFIT It is now a common practice for farmers to buy a 12- or 14 - cutter cooperatively and use it on five or six jobs per season. i an outfit would have a capacity of 8 or 10 tons per hour, one corn binder cutting steadily would be required to keep it i-ork ; two men could do the loading in the field, while three us would do the hauling. In most cases the drivers would do unloading. THE SMALL INDIVIDUALLY OWNED AND OPERATED OUTFIT. ■ Since the pit silo has come into use there has been a demand a small drag carrier outfit which can be operated with a four •Mr. Wood was formerly Instructor in Agricultural Engineering and is now Agricultural Engineering Adviser to County Demonstrators. BUL. 145. AGE. EXP. STATION OF NEBB. VOL. XXVII, AKT II </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Handling Silage or five hone power gas engine, and which will cut 5 or 6 tons of silage per hour. Two or three teams will do the hauling, the drivers loading and unloading their own wagons. The corn may be cut by a harvester in the morning and the filling operations carried on in the afternoon ; or a sled harvester may be used. In the latter case the hauling wagon is driven alongside the harvester to make it convenient for the men who are doing the cutting to lay their armfuls of corn on the wagon as fast a« they are gathered. Another method is to cut the corn by hand and lay Pis. 1. — One form of sled harvester. Ipon the wagons as fast as cut. When only two or three men available to operate one of these small outfits, a few acres of i may be cut, then loaded and hauled, and cut into ailaee by same men, only one of the processes being carried on at one CUTTING THE CORN. Ijorn intended for silage is at the proper state of maturity n the kernels are denting and glazing. If it is cut before this e is reached, part of the feeding value will be lost. Also, when too green, it makes a looser, more washy feed and contains e acid than if cut just at the proper time. If left until too , the corn will make a drier feed and stock will not always n it up so well. Il fairly good grade of silage may be made by cutting corn • it is apparently dry, but plenty of water must then be ied as it is being put into the silo. Many farmers feel that are repaid by cutting stover and making silage in this man - especially in refilling silos which have been emptied once • filling in the fall. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Handling Silage 7 COKS CITTERS. Corn can he cut for silage with common corn knives, the sled harvester, or the corn binder. I'orn Knivks. — The use of corn knives is advisable only on very II jobs and then only when sled harvesters or corn binders an - available. When hand knives are used, the corn may be tem - irily shocked, thrown onto the ground, or laid directly upon wagons to be hauled to the silo. I&lt;i.i:ii Habvesters. — The sled harvester is probably the cheapest he three methods mentioned for cutting corn, but because it nch hard work for the men on the sled to catch the corn, the hod is not popular. Bulletin 173, Office of Experiment Sta - s. United States Department of Agriculture, states that it 8 $1.18 to cut corn with the sled harvester. A short test at University Farm showed the cost was f 1.28 per acre for cut - and loading. Two men were able to harvest and load a ton y 10 minutes at a cost of about 17 cents, but since they worked • about two-thirds of the time, 40 tons or about 5 acres was &gt;od day's work. in using this machine most efficiently, the wagons nsed in ing must be driven alongside the cutter and keep pace with the cutters can lay the corn directly on the wagons; other - the corn must be picked off the ground. It has been found it costs about 10 cents per ton to lift the bundles from the nd to the wagons. Cobn Binders. — Altho it is fully as expensive and probably more so to cut corn for silage with a corn binder than by anv other method, it no doubt is the most satisfactory, and the method to be most highly recommended. |&lt;ince 7J acres ]&gt;er day is about the average amount cut with com binder, the farmer who is planning his work for filling &lt;ilo should estimate the tonnage per acre his corn will yi-ld. if he finds that one harvester will not keep the silage cutter &gt;lied he should cut a day or so in advance, or have two or thr&lt; e i binders in the field at once. The cost of cutting corn on 10 Nebraska farms was found to l&gt;e $1.52 per acre, and the cost of twine about $0.25 per acre on • 'in! yielding a little over 7i tons. The total cost of delivering I to rora on the ground cut and bound was about $1.77 per acre. \\ -Inch is approximately *0.236 per ton. I Should it be desirable to shock the corn and make silage from dry feed the cost will be ;;hout $0.47 per acre to do the shock- This would make the total cost of cutting, binding, and •king $2.24 per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ." .v When the corn is cut by hand or wilh a sled it should seldom be laid on the ground, and if possible a bundle loading device should be used with the corn binders, as it has been found that it costs about $0.10 per ton to pick the corn from the ground and lay it on the wagons for loading. Table 1. — Cont of cutting and loading.* * Taken from 16 farms In 1911. Khe cost of cutting by hand and by sled harvester in the above sed on results from United States Department of Agricnl- Bulletin No. 173. IVt the Nebraska Experiment Station the cost of cutting with sled harvester and laying the corn directly upon the wagons found to be fl.98 per acre or $ 0.259 per ton. FIELD LOADING. Field loading of either loose or bound corn can best be accom - plished by allowing two men to hand up and one to arrange the bundles on the wagon. A careful test at the University Farm showed it to cost more per ton to use three men on the ground for each wagon than it did to use two. but that it cost much less Fig. 2. — Method of loading bundles onto rack wagons. to load by having two men on the ground for each wagon than it did to have only one. Tn the first case the men are in each other's way or waiting for the man on the wagon, while in the second case the man on the wagon waits for the man on the ground. Cutting Twine Handing up Total Method Per acre Per ton Per acre Per ton Per Per ton Per UL acre acre .'uttiug by band Cutting with sled Cutting with binder. ■ . $1.50 1.18 1.52 $0,196 0.155 0.199 $0 252 $0,978 0.978 0.978 0.121 0.121 12.478 2.158 2.498 \B $0^033 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Handling silage 9 The bundles should Dot be promiscuously thrown upon the wagon, as it has been found that by careful loading the total time spent in unloading may be reduced nearly 40 per cent. The loading should be planned in conjunction with the setting of the cutter. If the cutter can be set in a manner which will permit the teams to stand with their heads at the elevator end. the load - ing should commence at the rear of the wagon with the butts on the right of the rack, if the wagon stands at the right of the cutter; and vice versa, if the wagon stands on the opposite side of the cutter. Ef the horses must face the feeder end of the cutter, the load - should commence at the front end of the rack and the nn ing begin at the rear. Eone man unloads the bundles they should all be laid on the in the order -4. B, C, D, and E, Figure 2, and the unloading place in the opposite order E, D, C, B, and A. When two unload, the ends of the rack are loaded first as explained • "Unloading Green Corn." HAULING IN GREEN CORN. I figure :i shows a convenient rack for hauling in green corn, rack is made by hanging two bed pieces under tke axle of wagon and building a platform on these pieces. The frame ung by a long kingbolt in front and stirrups over the bolster nd. When two or three teams are doing the hauling to ■ 11 cutter, one man will drive each team and load his owi on. Fig. 3.— A convenient rack for hauling silage corn. I Whet huge capacity cutters are used and it is not possible to the special silage racks, the flat topped racks and low wagons found to be the most convenient. Tests at the University in have shown that low wagons considerably lessen the cost of I loading. On 16 Nebraska farms, the average cost of hauling was found to be |3.37 per acre or $0,443 per ton for an average haul of 148 rods. The cost per ton of producing silage will depend consider </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ably u|&gt;on the distance the green corn has to be hauled. It is inv portant that the fields be as close as possible to the silo. In one instance, it was found that it cost J0.39 more per ton to haul from a field a mile away than it did to haul from a field adjacent to the silo. In filling a 100-ton silo this would amount to $39. UNLOADING GREEN CORN One or two men may be used to unload the em at the cutter. If two be used one starts the unloading near the middle of the rack, and when an opening is made sufficiently largo to allow room, a second man may assist. Figure 4 shows the wagon stand ing at the cutter. Tt also shows how the butts of the corn on the front end of the load are turned opposite from those at the rear. when wagons are to be unloaded from the center toward the Fig. 4. — Method of placing long corn on wagon where two men are to unload, starting at the center of the rack. Ki. This saves one man considerable time which would other - f be spent in turning bundles to allow the butt ends to enter cutter first. In short corn where two tiers of bundles can be ■ed end to end across the rack, the butts are turned out TYPES OF SILAGE CUTTERS. ii'ower cutters with fan blowers are much used for filling re-ground silos, and are always advisable where many large » are to be filled. This type of cutter consists of a revolving of knives which cut the stalks into short lengths as they are vered by the feed rollers and which in turn are fed by the apron. The length of cut is regulated by changing the speed he feed rolls. After being cut. the pulp is drawn into the f;\n </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Klelivered thru the blower pipe into the silo. By using a di» - tor, considerable time may be saved the men in the silo. Egnre 5 shows a blower outfit fitted with a distributor. Thi« butor is made in sections and is flexible, allowing silage to &gt;wn to all parts of the silo. The blower pipe should be ran irly vertical as possible, otherwise more power will be eon - i due to friction on the sides of the tube. Fig. 5. — One type of modern silage cutter fitted with blower and distributor. K lower machines are made in capacities ninjjing from 5 to 40 per hour. In most instances the number of the machine ex - es the width of throat or length of feed rolls. The capacities of the cutter will depend upon the speed, the lfu&lt;;th of cut. and condition of the corn. The following table giVM the |TRI|( capacity and power requirements as given by nine of the leading manufacturers of silage machinery : Table 2. — Capacithx &lt;m&lt;l hurxc pmoer reqnircm«mtt of machine* itxiny bloicCrs. WidUiufthro.it (in inohesj 10.0 ! 12.0 | 14.0 MM) | 20.0 22.0 &gt; &gt;WgB f ipritv (to s per hciiir ) . . 4.5 I t&gt;7 i S.X 12.0 i 19.7 24.5 II P required (stc:iin tr.inon M •&gt; ■'&gt; \ %J0 t).") I 12") 14.0 H P rmiinri'.l i ir-i-u iliiw ' l'&gt;-lti 1 T-2T) I 21 Y-IH ''"-'it) llViff 40-4^ n. r. m|iim *i ' i ■ ■ \ * — *** ' *"^— *' *• ~" ~ "' tr " »^ »^&gt; »" </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Hailing Silage MACHINES USING ' AHRIER8. The drag carrier operates much like the old type of straw • arrier used on threshing machines. It may be used successfully :n filling pit and semi-pit silos, but is not successful where a long • arrier is required or in windy countries unless the carrier is nvcred. The single chain inclosed tube carrier shown in Figure 6 is a -...id type for use with both pit and above-ground silos. Most Fig. 6. — Modern silage cutter fitted with inclosed drag tube carrier. fanies provide a swivel i fig. 0, a), by means of which the &gt;r may be turned in all directions from the cutter. This re would be an advantage on commercial outfits where all of conditions have to be met. The inclosed tube gives very trouble, since it is light, compact, and has but one chain, carrier should be inclosed, or trouble will be had with the scattering the cut corn as it is being elevated. (Tie drag tube carriers are generally preferable where a farmer aying his own outfit, since the first cost of both outfit and er is less, and the carrier requires only about one-third the er that is required by the blower. The blower outfit is better commercial work, since it will operate under more varied litions. is more quickly set up. and has larger capacity. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Handling Silage 13 Table 3. — Capacities and horse power requirements of machines using carriers. Width of throat (in inches) 10.0 12.0 I 14.0 16.0 I 18.0 I 20.0 I 22 0 Capacity (tons per hour) 4.5 6.7 8.8 12.0 16.0 19.7 I 1 i 7, H. P. required (steam stationary). 3.5 5.0 6.5 8.0 9.5 11.0 12.5 H. P. required (gasoline) | 3.5 I 5.0 | 6.5 1 8.0 | 9.5 I lllo | 12J5 TRAMPING THE SILAGE. fit least two men should be kept tramping while the silo is !* filled, and if the silo is of a large diameter, three or four recommended. In some cases, concrete tampers have been with splendid results. Keep the outside the highest and ip it the most. This will prevent spoiling along the outer s of the silo. If a silo is filled quickly and is poorly tramped, there will be a large amount of settling. Where a farmer owns his own out - fit, it will pay in many cases to allow the settling to take place for a day or two and then refill the silo. SEALING THE SILO. I ■several tons of silage could lie saved each year if the top of silo could be sealed. Many schemes have been suggested, such overing it with earth, or planks, or sowing oats on the surface tie silage. The best practice seems to be to build silos smaller iameter and deeper, so that a small amount of spoiled silage s a large amount of feed. Then, by snapping the ears from last few loads of corn, there is very little loss of feed by using jje as a seal. WATERING THE SILAGE. Dry, semi-dry, or frosted corn should always be dampened as it enters the silo. Ordinarily it re - quires from one to three tons of water for each ton of such corn. It is always better to get too much water rather than not enough. The water should be added to the corn on the wagon before it enters the cutter head, and as it enters the blower or elevator, for it must be thoroly Miixed in order to keep the silage from moulding. pjg. 7. 1 1 does very little good to put water on top of the silage fork. *ilage after the silo has been filled. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REMOVING SILAGE FROM SILOS. AKOVE-GROUND SILOS. I'^roui two to three inches of silage should be removed from entire surface of the silo daily during the summer months at least half of this amount in the winter. In the above - ind silos the silage may l»e dug loose with a silage fork (fig. ind allowed to Ml down thru the chute to the ground, where K). — An adaptation of a feeding arrangement as used by Peter R&gt;&gt;rg - uist, Atlanta, Nebr. Can be used as well for above-ground silos aa )r bank silos. Ky be loaded into the can or carrier and fed where desired; may be dropped directly into a cart, currier, or wagon, and to the stock. If the silo is adjacent to the barn and there is a smooth way i silo to feed manger. ■ simple silage cart such as is shown by ire 11 is the most convenient device for taking the silage to stock. The cart can l&gt;e left l&gt;eneath the silo chute and tilled 11 above without reshoveling the silage. Loose silage weighs it 18.5 pounds per cubic foot, and this should be given con - ration when building a cart for a definite capacity. More often than otherwise in Nebraska the silo stands either in or adjacent to the feed yard, in which case there is very seldom </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Handling Silage 15 a smooth way from silo to hunks. An overhead feed carrier is then generally advisable. This defends upon the number of stock to be fed. Such a carrier can be arranged as shown by Figure 8. If the yards are small the arrangement shown by Figure 0 is advisable. Fig. 9. — Illustrating bow a swing track may be attached to a strong silo and the silage distributed to several feed bunks. Ehen several carloads of stock are being fed silage the most nient scheme is to throw the feed into a wagon and dis - :e it to the bunks with a team. Figure 10 shows how to pe the chutes for filling a wagon when there are two silo*. PIT AND SEMI-PIT SILOS. f'Oine sort of hoisting device should be used in pit and wmipit . where the pit part is more than 10 feet deep. Hand hoists power hoists are l^ing used for this purj^ose. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Hand Hoists. — The simplest hoist is that of the bucket raised hand over hand, but this requires one person in the pit and an - other above ground. A bet - ter scheme .and one which is practical where the silo is located in the barn between the mangers, is to obtain several baskets and equip them with stiff bails, then use them as follows: Fill the baskets and place them in the silo con venient for raising, climb »iit of the silo, and hv Fig. 10. — The arrangement of the chute for filling the wagon with silage when two wagons are ad - jacent Fig. 11. — Homemade hoist for semi-pit and pit siloe. See Pig. 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Es of a hook on a rope hook a basket of silage and hoist it After the basket is emptied drop it back into the silo, re - the hook, and hook another basket ; then proceed as before. Figure 11 shows a homemade hoisting device for semi pit silos. which can be adapted to pit silos as shown by Figure 12. It con - sists of a 3-inch pipe carrying a wooden wheel at a and two wooden drums at ft and c. At d is shown the counterweight which may be an old milk can filled with scrap iron. It should be slightly lighter than the weight of the cart and the silage. The Fig. 12.— Homemade hoist for pit silos. cart is shown in the raised position with the counterweight down in the silo. A chain is shown at g on the rope to the counterweight. This is to allow adjustment of length so t«c weigi c will just set on the silage when the hook at f is in a position to allow the cart to hook onto the 3-inch pipe. The operator steps into the cart and by pulling on the end - less rope raises himself and the cart sufficiently to release the hook. He then pulls on the opposite side of the rope and lowers himself into the silo. This operation raises the counterweight id) which must be held aloft, while the box is being filled, by the weight (h) which is hooked to the endless rope. After the box is filled the operator can either pull up the load and then climb up a </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Handling Silafe loose ladder or he can step into the cart and hoist himself with cart and feed. When the cart reaches the door the hook (0) slips over the pipe, the operator steps out. releases the hook (f), and attaches it to a convenient loop; then by means of a quick pull. Fig. 13.— Hook shown at t. Fi~. 11. Fig. 14.— Wheel shown at a. Fig. 11. runs the cart out onto the grounds, and release* hook le). The silage is now ready to be taken to the stock. E'hen the silo is being filled, the 3-inch sloping pipe should moved and replaced when the silage has been fed down to ce where the hoist is again needed. Fig. 15. — Bearing used to support 3-inch pipe on hoist shown in Fig. 11. Horse Power Bourn. — Figure 1&lt;&gt; shows a hoisting device in use on the farm of W. I*. Bennett at Cambridge. Xebr. This silo is entirely below ground with an opening in the roof thru which silage is hoisted. The silage carrier is a box about 4 feet </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Handling Silage 19 and pulled over to the dump chute by means of one horse. A trip rope allows the operator to dump the silage thru the chute and return the carrier. An ordinary hayfork cable and carrier are used. This same arrangement might be used for feeding into several bunks. E commercial silage hoist is shown in Figure 17. When the 1 is fed down below the ground line, a strong timber is hunp e supports at a ;ind b. An ordinary hay carrier runs on Fig. 16 16. — Method of hoisting silage from a pit silo and dropping it into feed bunk as used on farm of W. P. Bennett, Cambridge, Nebr. a section of track attached to this timber. The feed carrier box is 5 feet long by 2 feet wide and 20 inches deep. The carrier nnd carrier box are pushed into the silo. Aft:T being tripped, the carrier box lowers into the pit. When full it is pulled up by a horse on the rope at c. If the carrier has to be pushed any considerable distance to reach the feed bunk, the rojic is unfastened from the carrier. Figure 18 shows a convenient hoist for use where two pit silos are built close together. One of these hoists has been Mr cessfully operated by Mr. Junkin and his sons at Bertrand. Nebr., for a number of years. The construction is simple, con - sisting of a framework set upon the edge of the silo and firmly </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Handling Silage 20 Fig. 17. — Commercial hoist for u«e in pit silos. Ied in position. A length of hay carrier track leading to each is supported by a piece of 4 by C inch timber. These timber* laid upon the two 2 by 8 inch crosspieces which are supported he two 18-foot lengths of telephone poles. Fig. 18. — Hoist which may be used where two pit silos are built close to - gether. Mr. Junkin and sons, of Bertrand, Nebr., designed and have successfully operated this type of hoist for several years. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Prope unwinds from the drum one carrier may be run *I, and the box allowed to lower, while the other box is ra out. The pulleys shown in the cut keep the ropes up mud and guide them as they wind on the drum. Eoisting With a Gasoline Engine. — By making or purchas - hoisting device such as is used for hoisting hay into barns to stacks, a gasoline engine may be connected up to a silage and do away with the use of the team and the bother of fing the rope thru the mud or snow. COST OF SILAGE. In 1911, the Department of Agricultural Engineering gathered statistics from 16 farms regarding the cost of silage and the labor required for the various operations. The data are assembled in detail in the following table. irhe table is compiled by assuming the corn to be worth 50 ts per bushel and the stalks 50 cents per acre. The amount nterest and depreciation charged to the various machines has i obtained by taking the standard rate of interest or amount lepreciation and proportioning it to the amount of work done these machines each year. For instance, the interest on the ge cutter has been taken as 1.2 per cent. Probably the stand rate of interest on such machinery is 6 per cent, but each ter will fill about five silos, making the interest on the cutter each silo one-fifth of 6 per cent, which is 1.2 per cent. mi j *rt + "^v * a 1 In 4-nji !*» n a' n * 1 n *» o </seg>
            <seg id="p022">2 Tabli 4. — Coat of various Data gathered by the Departme ent of . pricultural Engineer 1 ;i I 7 location Lincoln Lincoln Walton Bethany Palmyra Lincoln Franklin Lincoln Number and type of siloj 2— stave 1 — stave 1— stage 1— stave 1— stave 1 — stave 1— sUve 1— stave tited tons silage ' corn required ited tons per acre ited bushels per &amp;ted bushels per silage to field er of teams hauling er of men tramping 211 16 13.2 81 11.6 118 20 5.95 152 25 6.1 181 28 6.5 lie 12 9.9 75 11 6.8 66 14 4.7 40 40 l 25 40 l 40 45 30 . 3.03 80 4 1 3.46 40 4 1 4.20 100 6 2 6.57 100 6 I 6.15 40 6 2 4.55 120 5 2 442 80 5 3 10.63 80 5 2 Value of corn and stalks $264.00 I $115.50 $210.00 $412.50 1462.00 $222.00 $137.50 $287.00 Coat of cutting corn Per acre Per ton 39.74 2.48 0.188 14.10 2.01 0.174 23.70 1.19 0.199 18.73 0.75 0.123 45.20 1.61 0.250 22.10 1.84 1.86 14.80 1.35 0.197 22.50 1.61 0.341 Cost of hauling.. Per acre Per ton 83.05 5.18 0.394 31.20 4.46 0.386 H7.05 3.35 0.563 73.25 2.93 0.432 74.65 2.65 0 412 57.20 4.77 0.480 27.15 2.47 0.361 30.95 2.21 mm Coat of putting in silo Per acre Per ton 87.60 5.47 0.415 36.30 5.19 0.448 50.40 2.52 0.423 69.15 2.77 0.450 57.10 2.04 0.315 53.60 4.47 4.500 42.83 3.89 0.570 0.450 Coat of twine _ Per acre Per ton 5.40 0.338 0.026 2.25 0.320 0 028 2.56 0.128 0.022 4.13 0.165 0.027 7.20 0.257 0.040 3.60 0.300 0.032 4.00 0.364 0.053 3.20 0228 0.049 Cost of housing P«»cre Per ton 48.70 3.11 0.236 28.00 4.00 0.346 49.00 2.45 0.412 35.00 1.40 0.230 70.00 2.50 0.386 42.00 3.50 0.352 28.00 2.55 0.373 46.90 3.25 0.710 To-, cot Per acre Per ton 524.09 B.7f 2.48 225.10 32.16 2.78 400.21 20.01 3.36 608.63 24.30 4.00 708.95 25.25 3.92 396.90 SUM 3.33 250.28 22.75 3.34 417.10 29 80 6.32 ?O8t Of fill I'ost of hoi si — 17 above-grot 2 pit silos, ising — 16 wood stavi 2 pit silos, 1 masonry si iling — all silos. inc! silos, 315 acres. 2,308 tons. 14 acre». 82 tons. i silos. 29$ acres. 2.301 tons. 14 acres. 82 tons, ilo, 17 acres, 87 tons. I^oat of ha i 'Interest on investment is calculated. Cutter 2 per cent, binder 4 per cent, engii , per silo, ne 1 per &lt; as follows: Cutter rent, wood stare silt </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Handling Silage H operations in filling silos.* lee &gt;yt ie Department of Farm Management. 10 11 12 13 14 u 10 1 Water- loo 3— stave 875 85 10.3 Cam- bridge 2— sUve 277 40 6.9 Lincoln 1— nave 87 12 7.3 Exeter 1— stare 91 20 4.6 Exeter 1— stave 86 20 4.3 Lincoln 1— pit 36 8 4.5 Exeter 1— pit 46 6 7.7 Tout Per acre Average Per ton 2.599 341 ~i.ea " 20 30 I 30 25 15 20 20 f 1.94 320 4 1 4.35 180 4.12 160 6 2—3 5.44 480 8 1 3.49 60 6 3 4.45 400 6 3 2.6 40 2 1 I — $722.50 (500.00 $150.00 $210.00 $130.00 $68.00 $51.00 $12.28 - a 133.59 1.57 0.153 55.40 1.38 0.200 24.02 2.00 0.276 32.70 1.64 0.359 31.75 1.59 0.369 10.05 1.26 0.280 9.00 1.50 1.96 i.a - ii 387.25 4.55 0.442 91.00 2.28 0.328 38.87 3.24 0.447 91.15 4.56 1.00 38.25 1.91 0.445 19.80 2.48 0.550 17.00 2.83 0.370 137 " 4 292.66 3.44 0.334 01.33 2.28 0.330 36.57 3.05 0.420 54.50 2.73 0.599 49.30 2.47 0.573 25.33 3.17 0.703 21.06 3.51 0.458 107 - Mi S2S 22.50 0.265 0.028 10.00 0.250 0.036 2.75 0.230 0.032 6.65 0.330 0.073 5.70 0.285 0.066 1.44 0.180 0.040 2.10 0.350 0.46 0.242 - m 224.00 2.64 0.256 71.54 1.79 0.258 49.00 4.08 0.563 49.00 2.45 0.539 49.00 2.45 0.570 8.05 1.01 0.222 6.75 1.13 0.147 ' 67344 m 21.55 3.78 176TP.O0 20.7S 2.01 809.27 20.23 2.92 298.46 24.87 3.44 437.35 21.87 4.80 298.30 14.92 3.47 131.23 16.40 3.65 104.81 17.47 2.28 2iW m average per acre. $0,481; average per ton, $0,063 average per acre, 0.257; average per ton, 0.044 average per acre, 2.51 1 ; average per ton, 0.326 average per acre, 1.060; average per ton, 0.181 average per acre, 1.540; average per ton, 0.271 average per acre rod, 0.01443, average per ton rod, 0.00182 average per acre mile, 4.620; average per ton mile, 0.582 cent, engine 0.6 per cent, silo 6 per cent. Repairs and depreciation are ealeulatej, per silo, a&gt; follows per cent, masonry 1 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Handling Silage APPENDIX. A SIMPLE HAND HOIST* Spire 19 illustrates a very simple yet practical hand hoist. oist can be built as shown for pit silos, or it can be used in •it silos by placing the crossbeam in place and setting the jd chute into the door after the silage has been fed down ently to need being hoisted. Fig. 19. — A simple homemade hand hoist for pit and semi-pit silos. Ee method of operating the hoist is to fill the box, which I be made of thin wood or galvanized iron, pull down on the which will hoist the box with silage until the rod attached i front end of the box catches under the hooks at the side •The idea of this hoist was proposed by Mr. C. W. Crouse of Thompson, Nebr., but It was worked out and made practical by Glen Chase, Pawnee City Nebr </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 ■he chute, then by continuing the pull on the rope the box tip up and the silage will run out. down the chute and into cart, wagon, or onto the ground. Irhe blocks which hold the upper pulley are made to slide on crossbeam so the box can be adjusted to the proper distance a the chute. The end of the rope which is attached to the sbeam is set back 15 to 20 inches behind the block. This &gt;s the ropes from twisting, thus insuring the box rising in proper position for the rod to catch" beneath the hooks on the Bt is essential that the lower pulley be rigidly attached to the of the box, but that the bail be free to swing as the box tip*. |[f the silage is inclined to stick to the chute at the point re the box strikes it, the tipping rod can be lowered about inches below the edge of the box so the lip of the latter will over the chute, thus insuring a smooth passage for the silage. With this hoist, one man will easily raise 75 pounds of silage (4 cubic feet) at a time, and because it automatically dumps itself, he will have to climb into the silo only once each feeding, no matter how many times the box needs to be filled and emptied. </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>