<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00063.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00063.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Statement of the Auditor of Public Accounts of the State of Nebraska showing the appropriations made and moneys expended by the forty-fifth session of the legislature</title>
               <date value="1929">1929</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATEMENT OF THE AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA SHOWING THE APPROPRIATIONS MADE AND MONEYS EXPENDED BY THE FORTY-FIFTH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE Convened January 1, 1029 and Adjourned April 24, 1929. legislative Expenditures Shown UP to May 21, 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OP CONTENTS Page State Board of Equalization 4 Statement No. 1 — Appropriation Bills 5 1-A — Emergency Appropriations available during the Fiscal Year ending June 30, 1929.... 6 1-B — Biennial Appriations for the biennium July 1, 1929 to June 30, 1931 7 Analysis of Biennial Appropriations 20 1-C — Nominal Appropriations 22 Statement No 2 — Appropriations and Expenditures for the Legislature 24 2-A — Salaries and Mileage Members of the Senate 25 2-B — Salaries of Officers of Senate 26 2-C — Salaries of Employees of Senate 26 2-D — Salaries and Mileage Members of the House 27 2-E — Salaries Officers of the House 29 2-F — Salaries Employees of the House 29 2-G — Expense — Postage 30 2-H — Expense — Telephone &amp; Telegraph 31 2-1 — Expense — Printing 32 2-K — Expense — Supplies and Miscellaneous 34 2-L — Printing House and Senate Journals 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">4 STATEMENT OP THE DEPARTMENT OP AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS L. B. Johnson Auditot Donald Smith Deputy Auditor Auditing Division C. A. Sommer State Accountant Frank B. Honza County Treasurer Examiner Oscar G. Peterson County Treasurer Examiner Margaret McCalpin Fund Bookkeeper Viola R. Mayborn Stenographer Warrant Division Lucille Robinson Appropriation Bookkeeper Margaret Marsh Warrant Recorder Nadine Wassell Warrant Writer Naomi F. Schenck Voucher Clerk Bond Division Ralph C. Lawrence Bond Examiner STATE BOARD OF EQUALIZATION AND ASSESSMENT Arthur J. Weaver Governor Frank Marsh Secretary of State L. B. Johnson State Auditor W. M. Stebbins State Treasurer Harry Scott State Tax Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p004">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 5 STATEMENT NO. 1 APPROPRIATIONS MADE BY THE 45TH LEGISLATURE A — EMERGENCY APPROPRIATIONS Re- Amount H. R. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Appropriated 1 Legislative Expense $102,500.00 2 Salaries of Members 125,000.00 163 Sub-station for Box Butte Co 10,000.00 203 Relief of A. M. Bartlett $ 150.00 204 Relief of Kirk Rodgers 155.00 205 Relief of Perry C. Bell 80.00 220 Relief of City of Chadron (State Highway Fund) 8,091.00 282 Geneva Girls' Training School 15,000.00 283 Main Building Hastings State Hospital 27,000.00 284 Lincoln State Hospital 15,000.00 340 Relief of Claude E. Winters 500.00 585 Guaranty Fund Investigation 150,000.00 586 Claims &amp; Deficiencies 36,559.91 362,621.21 280 Eradication of Corn Borer 25,000.00 Total $807,621.21 B — BIENNIAL, APPROPRIATIONS 280 Maintenance General Government $38,337,593.06 281 Salaries General Government 777,140.00 324 Salaries, etc., Supreme Court Judges 133,800.00 325 Salaries, etc., Supreme Court Commissioners 142,700.00 Total Biennial Appropriations $39,391,233.06 Grand Total $40,198,854.27 RECAPITULATION BY FUNDS PROPERTY TAX FUNDS General Fund $15,861,400.01 Capitol Building Fund 1,975,376.00 Total Property Tax Funds. $17,836,776.01 CASH FUNDS Gas Tax Fund $12,318,000.00 Motor Vehicle Fund 2,420,000.00 Game, Parks and Forestry 391,000.00 Normal School Cash 207,000.00 Institution Cash 698,900.00 Miscellaneous Cash 574,100.00 Federal Cash 5,753,078.26 Total $40,198,854.27 For Nominal Appropriations See Statement 1-c. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">6 STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT NO. 1-A EMERGENCY APPROPRIATIONS Appropriations made by the 45th Session of the Legislature passed with the Emergency Clause, and thus available during the biennium ending June 30, 1929. H. K. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Legislative Departments $227,500.00 2 E- 2 Salaries to Members &amp; Officers..! 125,000.00 1 E- 3-5 Incidental Expense 85,000.00 1 E- 6 Printing House and Senate Journals 17,500.00 Under Direction of Governor.... 150,000.00 585 E- 58 Investigation of Banks 150,000.00 Lieutenant Governor 95.00 586 E- 95 Premium on Officers' Bonds 95.00 State Treasurer 5,360.00 586 E- 95 Premium on Officers' Bonds 5.360.00. Guaranty Fund Commission .... 260,111.34 586 E-204 Reimbursement 260,111.34 Tax Commissioner 2,000.00 586 E-223 Administration of Tax Laws 2,000.00 Miscellaneous Appropriations 42,845.51 586 E-32S Real Estate Taxes and Assessments 21,558.40 586 E-329 Refund of Corporation Taxes.... 21,057.81 586 E-330 Miscellaneous Claims 229.30 University of Nebraska 163 E-404 Experiment Sub-station — 10,000.00 Experiment Sub-station — Alliance 10,000.00 Board of Control 109,709.36 Geneva Girls' Training School: 282 E-523 Construction of Building 15,000.00 Ingleside State Hospital 586 E-545 Replacement of Fire Loss 25,999.38 283 E-546 Repairs on Main Building 27,000.00 586 E-680 Relief of Eunice T. Deering 542.50 Lincoln State Hospital 284 E-575 Repairs on Heating Plant 15,000.00 State Penitentiary, Lincoln 586 E-595 Maintenance of State Prisoners in county jails 16,070.48 340 E-59 6 Relief of Claude Winters 500.00 586 E-680 Relief of Hugh Thompson 2,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 7 H. K. Acct No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount Total Home of Dependent Children 586 E-680 Tuition of Children 7,097.00 Total Emergency Appropriations SS07.621.21 STATEMENT 1-B BIENNIAL APPROPRIATIONS Appropriations made by the Nebraska Legislature, 45th Session, to cover Governmental Cost Expenditures for the Biennium July 1, 1929, to June 30, 1931: H.R. Acct. Amount No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total $ 4,500.00 LEGISLATIVE DEPARTMENT 280 1 Incidental Expense of Next General Session $ 2,000.00 280 2 Expenses of Capitol Investiga tion Committee 2,500.00 JUDICIARY DEPARTMENTS Supreme Court 324 20 Salary of 7 Judges $105,000.00 199,700.00 324 21 Salary of Clerk 10,000.00 324 22 Salary of Deputy Clerk 6,000.00 324 23 Salary of Reporter 8,000.00 325 24 Salaries of Employes of Supreme Court 62,200.00 325 25 Maintenance Clerk's Office 8,000.00 325 26 Maintenance of Reporter's Office 500.00 State Library 30,300.00 324 30 Salary Deputy Librarian $ 4,800.00 325 31 Maintenance Library 5,500.00 325 32 Printing Supreme Court Reports 8,000.00 325 33 Purchase of Books for State Library 12,000.00 Supreme Court Commission 46,500.00 325 36 Salaries of 3 Commissioners ....% 30,000.00 325 36b Salaries of 6 Commissioners to Sept. 15, 1929 6.250.00 325 37 Salaries of 3 Secretaries to Commission 9,000.00 325 37b Salaries of 4 Secretaries to Sept. 15, 1929 1,250.00 District Court 562,500.00 281 40 Salaries of 35 District Judges ..$350,000.00 281 41 Salaries of 35 Reporters 192,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATEMENT OF THE 8 H.R. Acct. No. No. ] Amount Xo For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total 280 42 Traveling Expenses of District Judges (Expenses to be allow - ed only while in the perform - ance of official duties away from home, unexpended bal - ance for any district can be used at end of biennium to meet expense in any other dis- trict) 20,000.00 Total for Judiciary Department $ 839,000.00 EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS Governor % 37,880.00 281 60 Salary of Governor $ 15,000.00 281 51 Salary of Secretary to Governor 5,280.00 280 52 Salaries and Wages 7,900.00 280 53 Maintenance 4,500.00 280 54 Membership Governor's Conference 200.00 280 55 Improvements and Maintenance Governor's Mansion 5,000.00 Under Direction of Governor... $ 166,500.00 280 56 Rewards $ 500.00 280 58 State Sheriff 90,000.00 280 59 State Fire Marshal. For the State Fire Marshal, all fees col - lected during the biennium ending June 30, 1931, and any unexpended balance on hand June 30,— Estimated 76,000.00 Secretary of State $ 48,980.00 281 60 Salary of Secretary of State ....$ 10,000.00 281 61 Salary of Deputy Secretary 5,280.00 280 62 Salaries and Wages 12,200.00 280 63 Maintenance 6,000.00 280 66 Administration of Initiative and Referendum Laws 10,000.00 280 69 Stock Brand Fund, all moneys collected during the biennium ending June 30, 1931, or so much theerof as may be need - ed, together with any unex - pended balance on hand June 30, 1929, Estimated 5,500.00 State Auditor $ 63,830.00 281 70 Salary of State Auditor $10,000.00 281 71 Salary of Deputy Auditor 5,280.00 280 72 Salaries and Wages 35,000.00 280 73 Maintenance 11,000.00 280 74 All moneys received by Auditor of Public Accounts for the an- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 9 H.R. Arct. No. No. ] Amount Xo, For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total nual audit of the Metropolitan Water District of Omaha, be, and the same are hereby appro - priated for the purpose of de - fraying the expenses of ac - countants and examiners, esti- mated 1,300.00 280 Check signing machine 1,250.00 State Treasurer $ 52,645.00 281 80 Salary of State Treasurer $ 10,000.00 281 81 Salary of Deputy Treasurer 5,280.00 280 82 Salaries and Wages 17,640.00 280 83 Maintenance 3.000.00 280 84 Check signing machine and perforating machine 1,725.00 280 85 Administration of Gas Tax (from Gas Tax) 15,000.00 Attorney General $ 97,375.00 281 90 Salary Attorney General $ 10,000.00 280 91 Salaries and Wages 49,875.00 280 92 Maintenance (Office) 2,500.00 280 93 Litigation 30,000.00 280 94 Costs and Judgments 5,000.00 State Superintendent $ 91,880.00 281 100 Salary of State Superintendent..! 10,000.00 281 101 Salary of Deputy Superintendent 5,280.00 280 102 Salaries and Wages 38,600.00 280 103 Readers of Examinations and extra help; from Examination and certificate fees. Estimated fees to June 30, 1931, Not to Exceed 18,000.00 280 104 Maintenance 20,000.00 Under Direction of State Superintendent $ 344,200.00 280 105 Fixed Charges, Aid to Schools ..$100,000.00 Fixed Charges, Aid to Normal Training (Sec. 6407-6413 Inc.) 195,000.00 280 106 280 107 (Including expense of inspec- tion not to exceed $5,000.00) 280 108 Inspection of High Schools 20,000.00 280 109 Instruction of Deaf Children .... 10,000.00 Division of Adult Immigrant Education 280 109A Salaries and Wages , $13,600.00 280 109B Maintenance 5,600.00 Commissioner of Public Lands &amp; Buildings $ 33,930.00 281 110 Salary of Land Commissioner ..$ 10,000.00 281 111 Salary of Deputy Commissioner 5,280.00 280 112 Salaries and Wages 17,150.00 280 113 Maintenance 1,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">10 STATEMENT OP THE H.R. Acct. No. No. 1 Amount For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings as Custodian of Capitol $ 140,000.00 280 115 Wages for Capitol Employees ....$ 50,000.00 280 116 Fuel, light and power 40,000.00 280 119 Contingency Fund 50,000.00 Total for Executive Departments $ 1,077,220.00 CODE DEPARTMENTS Department of Agriculture $ 683,300.00 281 120 Salary of Secretary $ 10,000.00 280 121 Bureau of Foods, Drugs and Oil, Bureau of Markets. All moneys collected by said Bu - reaus during the biennium end - ing June 30, 1931, or so much thereof as may be needed for the maintenance and support of said Bureaus, not to exceed 275,000.00 Bureau of Animal Industry ?so 122 Salaries and Wages $ 30,000.00 280 123 Maintenance 22.000.00 92.000.00 280 124 Eradication of Bovine Tuber- culosis and Glanders 300,000.00 280 125 Eradication of Scabies 22,500.00 280 126 Eradication of Swine and Chicken Diseases 9,000.00 280 127 Eradication of Bovine Tuber- culosis — All reimbursements for counties — No estimate. 280 133 Bee Inspection (Loan from Gen - eral Fund — $1,000.00) 280 134 Bee Inspection. All fees under provision of S. F. No. 88. Pro - vided that the General Fund be reimbursed for the $1,000.00 appropriated at such time as the inspection fees are avail - able for Reimbursement — Estimated 4,000.00 280 135 Eradication of Insect Pests. Bal - ance and Estimated Fees to June 30, 1931 7,800.00 280 136 Potato Inspection. Fees collect - ed from the inspection of pota- toes, estimated 3,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 11 No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated H.H. Acct. Amount Total Amount Department of Labor $ 35,000.00 280 151 Salaries and Wages $ 26,000.00 280 152 Maintenance 9,000.00 Department of Public Welfare.. $ 210,700.00 281 161 Salary of Secretary $ 10,000.00 Bureau of Health 280 162 Salaries and Wages (including not less than $4,000.00 for child hygiene) $ 40,000.00 280 163 Maintenance (including not less than $2,000.00 for State Child Hygiene) 22,000.00 280 168 Federal Child Hygiene. All moneys received from the Fed eral Government No Estimate Bureau of Child Welfare 280 171 Salaries and Wages $ 14,400.00 280 172 Maintenance 5,000.00 Bureau of Examining Boards 280 173 Bureau of Examining Boards for pay of examiners, salaries and maintenance of the Bureau all moneys collected by said Bu - reau, or so much thereof as may be needed for maintenance and support of said Bureau. Balance and Estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 $ 65,000.00 280 174 For the use of the Division of Athletics, from moneys collect - ed during the biennium ending June 30, 1931, together with any unexpended balance on hand June 30, 1929, not to ex- ceed 13,500.00 280 176 Salary and expense. Scottsbluff Laboratory 5,800.00 280 177 State Barber Board. All money collected by said board or so much thereof as may be re - quired for maintenance and support of said board. Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931, Not to exceed 35,000.00 Department of r«Mic Works .... $ 675,580.00 281 180 Salary of Secretary | 10,000.00 280 18 0B Provision for Additional Suiary to Secretary 5,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">12 STATEMENT OF THE H.R No. Acct. Amount No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total 280 181 Salaries and Wages (From Gasoline Tax) 283,000.00 280 182 Maintenance (From Gasoline Tax) 70,000.00 280 183 Salaries and Wages (Bureau of Irrigation) 37,380.00 280 184 Maintenance (Bureau of Irrigation) 25,200.00 280 185 Special Survey (Bureau of Irrigation) 25,000.00 280 186 State Highway Administration from 2 Vz % of total registra - tion fees, Balance and esti- mated receipts to June 30, 1931 190,000.00 280 186B For enforcement of Motor Vehi - cle Laws (from 30% of motor vehicle license fees) 30,000.00 Public Improvements $19,350,000.00 280 187 Road Maintenance — 30% of Road Maintenance — 30% of Motor Vehicle Registration of State. Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 $2,200,000.00 280 188 Road Maintenance from Gaso - line Tax, Estimated 3,550,000.00 280 189 All funds derived from a 4c per gallon Gasoline Tax, not otherwise appropriated for road purposes, to be distri - buted as provided by law, in accordance with House Roll 242, Session Laws of 1929. Provided: That the Depart - ment of Public Works is au - thorized and empowered to construct highways, connect - ing state and Federal Institu - tions and Parks with State Highways, when such Insti - tutions and Parks are not on State Highways such expendi - ture not to exceed $40,000. - 00 for any one year. Bal - ance and Estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 $8,400,000.00 280 193 State Aid Bridges $ 200,000.00 280 194 Federal Aid Road. Cash re- Federal Aid Road. Cash re - ceived from Federal Govern - ment. Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 — 5,000,000.00 Department of Trad" and Commerce $ 307,000.00 281 200 Saiorj or secretary $ 10,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 13 H.R. Acct. Amount No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total 280 200B Provision for Additional Salary to Secretary 5,000.00 280 201 Salaries and Wages 25,000.00 80 202 Maintenance 15,000.00 Bureau of Banking 280 203 Salaries and Wages 30,000.00 280 204 Maintenance 15,000.00 280 204B Expense of organization and administration of state re - ceivership as successor of Guaranty Fund Commission, including checking all assets in transfer and administra - tion of assets and property after transfer $ 100,000.00 280 204C The proceeds of assessments on banks, trust companies, building and loan associa - tions, installment investment companies, co-operative cred - it associations and agricul - tural loan associations levied and collected under House Roll 249, Laws of 1929, for salaries and expenses as in said act authorized No Estimate Bureau of Insurance 280 205 Salaries and Wages $ 21,000.00 280 206 Maintenance 16,000.00 280 207 Salaries and Expenses of In surance Examiners, actuaries and accountants, the fees col - lected from insurance com - panies for such examinations. Balance and Estimated re- ceipts to June 30, 1931 45,000.00 280 208 Support, Bureau of Insurance and Wages Salaries and Wages in Isurance Depart - ment. All moneys received from Filing and Miscellan - eous Fees. Estimated Fees to June 30, 1931 25,000.00 Total Code Departments , $ 1,911,580.00 Total Public Improvements .... $19,350,000.00 SUNDRY DEPARTMENTS Tax Commissioner and Budget Control $ 60,000.00 281 220 Salary of Tax Commissioner....! 10,000.00 280 221 Salaries and Wages 40,000.00 280 222 Maintenance 10,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">14 STATEMENT OF THE H.R. Acct. Amount No. For AVbat Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total Xo. Military Department $ 193,400.00 281 230 Salary of Adjutant General....! 8,000.00 281 231 Salary of Assistant Adjutant 5 400.00 280 232 Support 175,000.00 280 233 For the completion of the Memorial Building 5,000.00 Railway Commission $ 139,880.00 281 240 Salary of Three Railway Commissioners $ 30,000.00 281 241 Salary of Secretary 5,280.00 280 242 Salaries and Wages 61,600.00 280 243 Maintenance 10,000.00 280 244 Extra Help, Traveling Ex - pense and Rate Investigation 33,000.00 Board of Educational Lands and Funds $ 56,720.00 280 250 Expense serving school land notices, supplies to County Treasurer and State Survey - or, repairs of building on state school land $ 2,000.00 280 251 Expense re-appraising school land 2,000.00 280 259 Relief of Spanish War Vet- erans and Dependents 30,000.00 280 260 Publishers Reports 750.00 280 261 State Fund Relief, Rehabilitation 7,770.00 280 261B Administration for Emergency Relief 11,700.00 280 262 Special Drainage Assessments 2,500.00 Capitol Commission 280 270 Special levy for Capitol for $ 1,975,376.00 Special levy for Capitol for 1929-1931 together with any unexpended balance on hand June 30, 1929, to be expend - ed under the provision of Sec - tions 5253-5257, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and House Roll 534, Forty-fifth Session Legisla- ture of Nebraska. Estimated $1,975,376.00 Public Library Commission ...... 280 280 Salaries and Wages { 14,800.00 ? 29,800.00 280 281 Maintenance 3,000.00 280 282 Binding 1,000.00 280 283 Books 280 283 Books 6,000.00 280 284 Institutional Libraries 5,000.00 Board of Vocational Education % 400,046.52 280 290 Salaries and Wages $ 28,500.00 280 291 Maintenance 8,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 15 Acct. No. ] Amount H.R. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total 280 292 State Aid Vocational Education 140,000.00 280 293 All moneys received from the Federal Government for voca - tional education. Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 173,789.00 280 294 Industrial re-education 24,628.76 280 295 Federal Industrial Re-educa - tion, all moneys received from the Federal Govern - ment, Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 .... 24,628.76 Board of Pardons and Paroles $ 14,000.00 280 300 Salaries and Wages $ 10,000.00 280 302 Maintenance 4,000.00 Administration of Game Laws State Parks and Forestry .... $ 391,000.00 310 For propagation, preservation and distribution of game and fish; for salaries and main - ance of office; for necessary equipment for activities of the commission; for purchas - ing and improving lakes and swamps; for sinking wells ill lakes not owned by State — unexpended balance on hand heretofore appropriated to the Department of Agricul - ture for these activities, and 90% of all moneys received from sale of hunting and fish - ing permits. Estimated re - ceipts to June 30, 1931 $ 350,000.00 280 280 315 For maintenance of all State Parks — 10% of amount re - ceived from sale of hunting and fishing permits estimated to June 30, 1931 37,000.00 280 316 — 19 — For each park respective - ly, all cash receipts, balance and estimated receipts, esti - mated 4,000.00 Total Sundry Departments... $ 3,260.222.52 MISCELLANEOUS APPROPRIATIONS State Board of Agriculture .... % 232,270.04 280 320 Premiums $ 4,000.00 280 321 Meetings of Organized Agriculture 3,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">16 STATEMENT OF THE H.R. Acct. Amount Total No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated 280 322 Maintenance 75,000.00 280 323 Promotion of Agricultural Activities 30,300.00 280 324 Development of Boys' and Girls' Club Work 10,000.00 280 325 For advertising the State of Nebraska 20,000.00 280 326 Removal of dirt from Capitol grounds to fair grounds. amount due 5,977.04 280 327 Boys' and Girls' Club Building 75,000.00 280 328 Superintendent's Residence on Fair Grounds 6,000.00 280 329 Purchase of land and filling.... 3,000.00 State Historical Society $ 27,000.00 280 335 Salaries and Wages $ 13,000.00 280 336 Maintenance 8,000.00 280 337 Publishing Historical Volume 2,000.00 280 338 Binding 500.00 280 339 D. C. Bristol Collection 3,000.00 280 340 Expense of moving offices to State Capitol Building 500.00 Grand Army of the Republic $ 4,000.00 280 345 Maintenance and Clerical Assistance $ 4,000.00 State Irrigation Association .. $ 600.00 280 350 State Aid $ 600.00 Revision and Printing the Statutes $ 60,000.00 280 355 Editing, Compiling and pub- lishing Statutes for Nebraska $ 60,000.00 Total Miscellaneous Appropriations $ 323,870.04 EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS University of Nebraska f 5,221,160.50 All expenditures for education - al purposes unless otherwise herein specified $4,644,500. - including the following: 280 400 General Appropriation $3,562,500.00 280 401 Agricultural Extension 187,000.0 280 402 Division of Conservation and Survey, not less than 80,000.00 280 403 College of Medicine, Hospital Maintenance 300,000.00 280 405 Joint heating, lighting and power plant (under auth - orization of House Roll 534) </seg>
            <seg id="p016">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 17 H.R. Acct. Amount For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated No. Xo. Total not to exceed 315,000.00 280 406 Purchase of land and partial construction of Dormitories, not less than 200,000.00 Cash and Federal Funds 407 University Cash No appropriation 280 409 Agricultural and Mechanical Arts, Estimated - $ 100,000.00 280 410 Smith Lever Fund, Estimated 216,778.50 280 411 Agricultural Experiment Sta- tion, Estimated 60,000.00 280 412 Purnell Fund, Estimated 120,000.00 280 413 Capper Ketcham Fund, Estimated 57,882.00 Legislative Reference Bureau 280 415 Salaries, Wages and Maintenance $ 19,000.00 280 416 Printing and editing Blue Book and Legislative Manuals 3,000.00 Normal Schools and Board ... All expenditures unless other I 1 816 800.00 wise herein specified: 280 420 Normal School Board $ 5,000.00 280 430 Chadron State Normal 358,754.00 280 440 Kearney State Normal 426,146.00 280 450 Peru State Normal 374,352.00 280 460 Wayne State Normal 405,548.00 Cash or other miscellaneous receipts from miscellaneous sources during the biennium ending June 30, 1931, to - gether with any unexpended balance on hand June 30, 1929, for the current ex - penses of the respective Nor- mal Schools. 280 431 Chadron Normal Cash Fund.... 33,000.00 280 441 Kearney Normal Cash Fund.— 42,000.00 280 451 Peru Normal Cash Fund 63,000.00 280 461 Wayne Normal Cash Fund .... 45,000.00 280 432 Chadron Normal Library 3,000.00 280 442 Kearney Normal Library 9,000.00 280 452 Peru Normal Library 6,000.00 280 462 Wayne Normal Library 6,000.00 280 453 Peru Normal Equipment for Science Building 10,000.00 280 462 Wayne Normal enlarging Heating Plant and repairing buildings 30,000.00 Total Educational Institutions $ 7,037,960.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATEMENT OP THE H.R. Acct. Amount No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total PENAL AND CHARITABLE INSTITUTIONS $ 5,586 880 00 18 500 General Maintenance Appro - priation for Board of Control and all institutions, all ex - penditures unless otherwise herein specified $3,712,500.00 281 502 Salary for three members of Board of Control 24,000.00 281 280 503 Salary of Secretary to Board.. 5,280.00 504 Salaries and Wages (Office).. 14,200.00 For each institution respective - ly all institutional or other cash receipts. Balance and estimated receipts to June 30, 1931 $ 698,900.00 NEW BUILDINGS, REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS Nebraska Institution for Fee- ble Minded Youth, Beatrice 280 280 512 New Building and Equipment $ 125,000.00 513 General Repairs and Re- placements 40,000.00 Girls Industrial School, Geneva 280 522 General Repairs and Re- placements 15,000.00 Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors Home, Burkett 280 532 General Repairs and Re- placements 20,000.00 280 533 Administration Building 60,000.00 Hustings State Hospital, Iugleside 280 542 General Repairs and Re- placements 25,000.00 280 543 Power Plant Building 40,000.00 State Industrial School, Kearney 280 552 General Repairs and Re- placements 12,000.00 Hospital for Tuberculosis, Kearney 280 562 General Repairs and Re- placements 8,000.00 280 563 Hospital Wing on Sun Room.. 60,000.00 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln 280 572 General Repairs and Re- placements 15,000.00 280 573 Connecting sewer with sanit - ary sewer system 9,500.00 280 574 "L" on one end of Receiving Building 35,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 19 H.R. Acct. Amount .No No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln 280 582 General Repairs and Re- placements 10,000.00 280 583 New Hospital Unit and Equipment 100,000.00 State Penitentiary, Lincoln 280 592 General Repairs and Re- placements 12,500.00 280 593 Chapel and Cells 100,000.00 280 594 Dining Room, Kitchen and Equipment 30,000.00 280 595 New Unit to Power Plant 58,000.00 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford 280 602 General Repairs and Re- placements 6,000.00 280 603 Hospital Building and Equipment 45,000.00 Soldiers and Sailors Home, Milford 280 612 General Repairs and Re- placements 6,000.00 Nebraska School for Blind, Nebraska City 280 622 General Repairs and Re- placements $ 17,000.00 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk 280 632 General Repairs and Re- placements 60,000.00 280 363 One New Building 100,000.00 Nebraska School for Deaf, Omaha 280 642 General Repairs and Decorat- ing Auditorium 5,000.00 280 643 Walks, drives, gutters 12,500.00 280 644 Furnishing new school 7,500.00 280 645 Power Plant and Equipment.. 40,000.00 State Reformatory for Women, York 280 652 General Repairs and Re- placements 5,000.00 280 653 Tile Dairy Barn 6,000.00 Nebraska Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln 280 662 General Repairs and Re- placements 5,000.00 280 663 Education of Dependent Children : 9,000.00 State Reformatory for Men, Lincoln 280 672 General Repairs and Re- placements 5,000.00 280 673 Superintendent's Residence .... 8,000.00 280 674 Employee's Building and Equipment 12,500.00 280 675 New Boiler 7,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATEMENT OP THE g.? £• I ! ! |8 ! ■ 22 ; 1 Illllil ! I j i ! j j i ! ! ~~8 M88 ; M 8 Vt- •#■ i I I I 4* 8 |8 8 8 1388 3 R 28R S «■ i m- MM! I : : ■ : : I ! I ! ! : •0 ■ IB Hie 1 a - 8 ;8 ! 8 x" S . S . = 8S ; ; 8 SS : ' 3 8g ! 8 8 ! ;83 g § Mil § III 8 of SS |8 8 S8888S8 8 188 8 88888 j 8 2 -&lt; 5 g O 2 111 3SSS 8 O c*J in 8888888 8 sasisssaKS" § i*S 8 J3Sf 3 88888 | 8 SSSgs I a M&gt; • **■ «» » Vr «- ■«» IP mi - it 8888 |8 8888 1 8 c\ »c &gt;o I £5 8 8 S 8 8 8 8 g S g § « R 8 8 S 888 8 '/&gt; ! «* 88888 3 asggfe a Q 5 1 ■z I I a 5 I |ll! I IIIIIH I |M ! MM! ! i Mil = ! ! I ! ! ! I i i i ! i mm! \ \ | M I • i i i ! j j i ! j | ' | : I j | : ! I ! ] n ! j ! I j j ■ j I j ! i'o I „ | j j 8 I in I 111 iillliyi I l|J I ii|il I \\ i \Q i 2 I I -22 I j -'I 3 5 I-S g 3 a &lt;3^ a S? ! o T ; o ; . re = o o « : Fo o • *&gt;"" °° o I It 'eg H | a sgss H $\ti H h-s==^ H Q C. 5 »*i — — U: m 3 *■•",£ ♦'■CM C O I- » ~ "^ m$ io|j|| ||| i-jai illsll sggss=B= ilsl 1&amp;s-?&amp;&amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p020">111 cog' Kb ~ I i88.8 I I 1 18 8 \ JL I I ! ! &lt;• I 18 I I 8 II II • 88 S| -r — V9- s s a «■ «■ 53- I ■sS|g 8 |8 ;888 Mi 8 O S "* : Os *n &gt;O i : '■ m a ; - «" 53 | ! | S «■ ! ! ! ** 88 8 8 |$ • I &lt; ! | ; ! ] iSK ! j Sj I I ! i Mil i i i j M M ft || s 8.8. iS8 8. 8 8 8 i K u i = I i 8 :S8 j8S88 8 88111 8. R»* j j j 5 8 I 18 | a &lt; I s 111 c/5 i 888 j ;333 I 8 \ Vt ■ i '» |8 j i : r«i j : i «■ ! ■ i 8 . ! 'A- «i I «$- 8 8 I i 4 ■r- s *~- &amp; -g"8 S 88S888S?88 K r-j •— i O\ *V «*3 M -' — * r^ 55- «■ «■ SS8S8 S S3 S is s 8 S i a s s S3 E I i | | || | | I ! j I ! I 1 i I Ml i! I M 1 1 1 1 1 1 MUM I i t i ! i ! So ! ! i i ! ! Ml "3 j jS i j j I I ! j j | j | I i [ | i j til] 1*11] IjJlli I 1 111 1 Is MuiA i mh % m i it i lislliliiM iiiiil 111 ii i.xH~ — — ■- — = — — Ex.x.»u:u IU3Z 0.&amp; Q 1 I Is - a z a &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">22 STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT NO. 1-C NOMINAL APPROPRIATIONS Listed in accordance with Article 3, Sections 22 and 25 of the in- Constitution and Statute 315T, being appropriations which do not crease the expenses of the State or the amount of revenue to be provided. H.R. Acct. Amount No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total REVOLVING FUNDS Department of Public Works 280 710 State Equipment and material Fund No Estimate Cash and Road 280 715 All moneys donated or reimburse - ments by counties during the bi - ennium ending June 30, 1931, together with any unexpended balance on hand June 30, 1929, Estimated $250,000.00 Board of Control 280 720 Handcraft Furniture Co. (Cash Fund) of manufacturing end of State Penitentiary, Estimated No Estimate TRUST FUNDS Department of Trade and Commerce 280 820 The receipts during the biennium ending June 30, 1931, together with any unexpended balance on hand on June 30, 1929, in the State Hail Insurance Fund are hereby appropriated for expendi - ture under the provision of Chap- ter 310, Session Laws of 1921 No Estimate Department of Public Lands and Buildings 280 830 The income from the bonds for Soldiers' Relief during the bi - ennium ending June 30, 1931, together with any unexpended balance on hand on June 30, 1929, is appropriated for ex - penditure under the provisions of Chapter 40, Session Laws of 1921 No Estimate RE-APPROPRIATIONS From State Aid Bridge Fund 586 193 Boyd County $ 3,074.90 586 193 General Construction Co 6,455.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 23 H.R. Acct. Amount No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Appropriated Total From State Highway Fond 220 187 City of Chadron 8,270.34 No person receiving compensation from a "Salaries and Wages" appropriation shall receive additional compensation from any "Main - tenance" appropriation, or from any appropriation of fees. And fur - ther provided where there is a "Salaries and Wages Appropriation" no office salaries and wages can be paid from "Maintenance". Appropriation — When Available — No appropriation from any fund except the General Fund shall become available for expenditure for any expending agency until such department shall submit to the Gov - ernor estimates of the amount required for each activity to be carried on, and such estimates shall have been approved by the Governor. A statement of the estimates as allowed shall be promptly furnished the Auditor of Public Accounts for his guidance. (H. R. 425) Expenditures to Be Pro-Rata — No expending agency shall be en - titled to expend more than one-eighth of its appropriation from the General Fund during any one quarter of a year, and the State Auditor is hereby prohibited from issuing warrants during any one quarter in amounts exceeding the quarterly quota. Provided, that where an emergency may exist or a special need arise for greater expenditures, the expending agency shall submit to the State Auditor, its request in writing. The State Auditor shall present this to the Governor, and if such request be approved by the Governor, then the State Auditor shall have authority to disregard the pro rata provision. But in no case shall the amount of warrants issued during the biennium exceed the amount of the appropriation. Unexpended balance of any quarter may be expended during any subsequent quarter. Provided, that the foregoing restrictions shall not apply to appropriations contained in bills passed with the emergency clause. (H. R. 425) 86 189 03 189 04 189 05 189 From Gas Tax Fund Phelan-Shirley Co Relief of A. M. Bartlett Relief of Kirk Rogers Relief of Perry C. Bell 27,029.97 150.00 155.00 80.00 80 128 From General Fund Eradication of Cornborer 25,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">24 STATEMENT OP THE STATEMENT NO. 2 EXPENDITURES OF THE LEGISLATURE Showing the expenditures of the 45th Session of the Nebraska State Legislature (up to and including May 21, 1929.) Expenditures Senate House Salaries of Officers _ $ 6,347.00 $ 7,312.50 Salaries of Employes , 15,019.10 20,134.50 Salaries of Members 26,400.00 80,000.00 Mileage of Members 921.20 2,728.90 Postage 735.50 2,797.20 Telephone and Telegraph 115.05 175.45 Printing and Printed Matter 2,675.78 4,162.19 Supplies and Miscellaneous 3,400.46 3,799.79 Printing House and Senate Journal 2,569.56 3,132.36 Expended by Senate $ 58,183.65 J124.242.89 Expended by House 124,242.89 Total Expenditures $182,426.54 APPROPRIATIONS TO COVER EXPENSE OP LEGISLATURE H. R. Acct. No. No. For What Purpose Appropriated Amount (1927) 1 Expenses of Beginning of Legislature $ 2,000.00 2 E-2 Members and Officers' Salaries 125,000.00 1 E-3-5 Mileage of Members, Salaries of Employees, and Incidental Expense 85,000.00 1 E-6 Printing House and Senate Journal 17,500.00 Total Appropriation $2 29,500.00 Expended up to May 21, 1929 182,426.54 Balance unexpended $ 47,073.46 As Follows: Acct. No. 1 — Unexpended $ 1,195.70 Acct. No. 2 — Unexpended 6,290.50 Acct. No. 3-5 — Unexpended 27,789.18 Acct. No. 6 — Unexpended 11,798.08 $ 47,073.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 25 SCHEDUIiE NO. 2-A MEMBERS OP THE SENATE Amount Per diem Xo of MUes Amount of Mileage To Whom Paid Total Paid Amspoker, Rosa Springview. $ 800.00 580 $ 5S 00 ? 858.00 809.60 831.40 817.80 814.20 811.00 811.00 811.00 806.00 882.20 800.00 885.40 830.00 836.00 833.00 817.60 835.40 817.00 811.00 811.00 827.20 830.00 811.00 824.00 846.80 846.00 820.40 802.40 804.20 820.00 816.20 853.00 891.40 Banning, W. B Union... 800.00 96 9 CO Bowman, John E Loup City. 800.00 314 31 40 Brazda, Rudolph .West Point. 800.00 178 17 80 Clark, O. G Columbus. 800.00 142 14 20 Cooper, John W Omaha. 800.00 no 11 0 0 Dworak, Gus A .Omaha. 800.00 110 11 00 Easton, Harry K Omaha. 800.00 110 11 00 Frush, George F .Wahoo. 800.00 60 822 6 00 Griswold, Dwight P Gordon. 800.00 S2 20 Jeary, Clark Lincoln. 800.00 Johnson, C. W Potter. 800.00 854 85 40 Johnson, Harry Holdrege. 800.00 300 30 00 Kennedy, Horace F Broken Bow.. 800.00 360 36 00 Kryger, Ralph M .Neligh... 800.00 330 33 00 McFarland, E. W Ohiowa. 800.00 176 17 60 McGowan, J. C Norfolk. 800.00 354 35 40 Neuman, Arthur L .Oakland. 800.00 170 17 00 Patton, J. A -Fremont. 800.00 110 11 00 Randall, William L .Omaha. 800.00 110 11 0 0 Reed, Perry -Henderson.. 800.00 272 27 20 Rickard, M. F Guide Rock. 800.00 300 30 00 Rodman, James A Omaha. 800.00 110 11 00 Schepman, Henry F Falls City. 800.00 240 2 4 00 Scott, P. W McCook. 800.00 46S 46 so Stinson, Allen S Niobrara. 800.00 460 46 00 Vance, R. R Hastings. 800.00 204 20 40 Warner, Charles J Waverly. 800.00 24 2 40 "Welch, Andy J Milford. 800.00 42 4 20 Wellensiek, H. G -Grand Island 800.00 200 20 00 Wherry, Kenneth S Pawnee City. 800.00 162 16 20 Wilcox, Wesley T North Platte.. 800.00 530 53 00 Wood, A. B XJering. 800.00 914 91 40 $26,400.00 9,212 $921.20 $27,321.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">26 STATEMENT OF THE SCHEDULE 2-B OFFICERS OF SENATE To Whom Paid No. of Days Amount Williams, George A., President $1,600.00 Snow, George C 98 days @ $10.00 $980.00 Preparing Senate Journal for Publication, etc 1100.00 2,080.00 Bailey, Arthur J., First Asst. Sec'y. 98 days @ $ 8.00 784.00 Preparing Senate Journal for Publication, etc 200.00 984.00 Linn, Frank, Second Asst. Sec'y. 98 days @ $ 8.00.... 784.00 Preparing Senate Journal for Publication, etc 200.00 984.00 Taylor, Buck, Sergeant-at-Arms 108 days @ $ 5.50 594.00 Morris, L. A., Asst. Sergeant-at-Arms 98 days @ $ 5.50 539.00 Cressman, A. A. Chaplain, 98 days @ $ 5.50 539.00 Wilhelm, Jerry, Postmaster 114 days @ $ 5.50 627.00 Total $7,947.00 SCHEDULE 2-C EMPLOYES OF SENATE To Whom Paid No of Days Amount Bagley, Rex A., Messenger 92 days @ $ 5.00 $ 460.00 Bell, Bruce, Page 96 days @ 3.50 336.00 Berkhemer, Mary, Stenographer lOOi days @ 5.00 502.50 Binder, Hattie, Journal Clerk 129 days &lt;g&gt; 6.50 838.50 Blount, A. J., Asst. in Bill Room 96 days @ 5.00 480.00 Bradley, Harry, Custodian 124 days @ 5.50 682.00 Brooks, Richard, Page 96 days @ 3.50 336.00 Burkhardt, O. J.. Janitor 108 days @ 5.00 540.00 Bush, Sam, Janitor 100 days @ 5.00 500.00 Cooper, Frank, Chief Bill Clerk 104 days @ 5.50 572.00 Douglas, Mabeth, Bookkeeper 96 days @ 6.50 624.00 Dwyer, Theresa, Stenographer 96J days @ 5.00 482.50 Fisher, Esther, Sec'y. to Lieut. Gov. 98 days @ 6.00 588.00 Gibson, Mayme, Mimeo. Operator 93 days @ 5.50 511.50 Gross, Theoda, Engrossing Clerk 82 days @ 5.00 410.00 Helvey, D. R., Asst. in Bill Room 87 days @ 5.00 435.00 Kelly, Edna, Stenographer 9 8 days @ 5.00 490.00 Konkel, Blanche, Asst. Journal Clerk 109 days @ 6.00 654.00 Krusen, M. P., Asst. in Bill Room 81 days @ 5.00 405.00 Marks, Maynetta, Chief Engrossing Clerk 99 days @ 6.00 594.00 Miskel, Berna, Stenographer 97 days @ 5.00 485.00 Oaks, EBtella, Stenographer 80 days @ 5.00 400.00 Peterson, Madonna, Stenographer 75i days @ 5.00 377.50 Prall, M. H., Proof Reader 86 days @ 5.50 473.00 Schwarting, Norma, Stenographer 74 days @ 5.00 370.00 St. Clair, J. C. Janitor 94 days @ 5.00 470.00 Tudor, M. C, Mail Carrier 114 days @ 5.00 570.00 Young, Richard, Janitor 94 days @ 5.00 470.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">27 AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS To Whom Paid To Whom Paid No of Days Amount No of Days Amount Zellars, C. B., Second Asst. Zellars, C. B., Second Asst. Sergeant-at-Arma 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 Sergeant-at-Arma. Curry, Nola, Stenographer Curry, Nola, Stenographer Boggs, Allen M., Legal Adviser 22 days &lt;§&gt; 5.00 110.00 2 Mos. @ 125.00 250.00 3 days @ 5.00 15.00 22 days &lt;§&gt; 5.00 110.00 Boggs, Allen M., Legal Adviser to Engrossing Dept to Engrossing Dept. 2 Mos. @ 125.00 250.00 Burden, John J., Janitor Jones, Merle S. Proof Reader. Rugg, Harry, Janitor Burden, John J., Janitor 3 days @ 5.00 15.00 118 hrs. @ .70 82.60 Jones, Merle S. Proof Reader 118 hrs. @ .70 82.60 Rugg, Harry, Janitor Total, Senate Employes. 3 days @ 5.00 15.00 $15,019.10 3 days @ 5.00 15.00 Total, Senate Employes. $15,019.10 SCHEDULE 2-D MEMBERS OP THE HOUSE Amount No Amount Amount No Amount Per of of Total diem Miles Mileage Paid To Whom Paid To Whom Paid Per of of Total diem Miles Mileage Paid Adams, Max Dannebrog $ Adams, Max Dannebrog $ 800.00 252 $ 25.20 $ 825.20 800.00 252 $ 25.20 $ 825.20 800.00 194 19.40 819.40 800.00 194 19.40 819.40 Allyn, A. E Hastings Allyn, A. E Hastings Amsberry, J. A Mason City.... Amsberry, J. A Mason City.... 800.00 308 30.80 830.80 800.00 308 30.80 830.80 Andrews, Vernon D....College View... Andrews, Vernon D....College View... 800.00 10 1.00 801.00 800.00 10 1.00 801.00 800.00 56 5.60 805.60 800.00 56 5.60 805.60 Ashton, Harry L Reward Ashton, Harry L Reward Aurand, L. H Chapman Aurand, L. H Chapman 800.00 240 24.00 824.00 800.00 240 24.00 824.00 Bailey, E. Preston Carleton Bailey, E. Preston Carleton 800.00 196 19.60 819.60 800.00 196 19.60 819.60 Barbour, W. M Scottsbluff Barbour, W. M Scottsbluff 800.00 840 84.00 884.00 800.00 840 84.00 884.00 Binfield, E. E Prosser Binfield, E. E Prosser 800.00 224 22.40 822.40 800.00 224 22.40 822.40 Bishop, John S Lincoln Bishop, John S Lincoln 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 Bowring, Arthur Merriman Bowring, Arthur Merriman 800.00 768 76.80 876.80 800.00 768 76.80 876.80 Brown, Guy A Geneva Brown, Guy A Geneva 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 Brown, O. B Lyman Brown, O. B Lyman 800.00 900 90.00 890.00 800.00 900 90.00 890.00 Buck, Ralph J Sutton Buck, Ralph J Sutton 800.00 142 14.20 814.20 800.00 142 14.20 814.20 Buckendort, W. E Bassett Buckendort, W. E Bassett 800.00 500 50.00 850.00 800.00 500 50.00 850.00 Burke, Allen G Bancroft Burke, Allen G Bancroft 800.00 252 25.20 825.20 800.00 252 25.20 825.20 Burr, Walter M Juniata Burr, Walter M Juniata 800.00 212 21.20 821.20 800.00 212 21.20 821.20 Campbell, C. G Walthill Campbell, C. G Walthill 800.00 210 21.00 821.00 800.00 210 21.00 821.00 Cone, Trenmor Valley Cone, Trenmor Valley 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Coulter, Bern R Bridgeport Coulter, Bern R Bridgeport 800.00 802 80.20 880.20 800.00 802 80.20 880.20 Curry, G. R .Arapahoe Curry, G. R .Arapahoe 800.00 390 39.00 839.00 800.00 390 39.00 839.00 Cushing, Marion J Ord. Cushing, Marion J Ord 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 Daddow, Fred Loup City Daddow, Fred Loup City 800.00 306 30.60 830.60 800.00 306 30.60 830.60 Davis, Troy L Weeping Water Davis, Troy L Weeping Water 800.00 70 7.00 807.00 800.00 70 7.00 807.00 Druesedow, Robt. C. Omaha Druesedow, Robt. C. Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Essam, Harvey R Beatrice Essam, Harvey R Beatrice 800.00 90 9.00 809.00 800.00 90 9.00 809.00 Fickler, Albert Stanton Fickler, Albert Stanton 800.00 254 25.40 825.40 800.00 254 25.40 825.40 Foster, Harry A Omaha Foster, Harry A Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Frahm, William C Blue Hill Frahm, William C Blue Hill 800.00 236 23.60 823.60 800.00 236 23.60 823.60 Freeouf, Frank Wilber Freeouf, Frank Wilber 800.00 62 6.20 806.20 800.00 62 6.20 806.20 Gardiner, M. J Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Gardiner, M. J Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Gillespie, Mabel Gretna Gillespie, Mabel Gretna 800.00 76 7.60 807.60 800.00 76 7.60 807.60 Hansen, Henry P North Platte... Hansen, Henry P North Platte... 800.00 510 51.00 851.00 800.00 510 51.00 851.00 Harritt, R. F Nelson Harritt, R. F Nelson 800.00 210 21.00 821.00 800.00 210 21.00 821.00 Hasselbalch, Earl St. Edward Hasselbalch, Earl St. Edward 800.00 310 31.00 831.00 800.00 310 31.00 831.00 Havekost, John Hooper Havekost, John Hooper 800.00 142 14.20 814.20 800.00 142 14.20 814.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">28 STATEMENT OF THE Amount No Amount Amount No Amount Per of of Total diem Miles Mileage Paid To Whom Paid To Whom Paid Per of of diem Miles Mileage Total Paid Havens, C. E Atkinson Havens, C. E Atkinson 800.00 460 46.00 846.00 800.00 460 46.00 846.00 Hovis, Victor M Lexington Hovis, Victor M Lexington 800.00 396 39.60 839.60 800.00 396 39.60 839.60 Howard, Jerry Omaha Howard, Jerry Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Hunt, Edward L Syracuse Hunt, Edward L Syracuse 800.00 88 8.80 808.80 800.00 88 8.80 808.80 Jackman, E. E Grant Jackman, E. E Grant 800.00 320 32.00 832.00 800.00 320 32.00 832.00 Jelen, Oldrich J Omaha Jelen, Oldrich J Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Johnson, O. O Gordon Johnson, O. O Gordon 800.00 858 85.80 885.80 800.00 858 85.80 885.80 Johnson, Richard O.— Havelock Johnson, Richard O.— Havelock 800.00 14 1.40 801.40 800.00 14 1.40 801.40 Johnston, El well Orchard Johnston, El well Orchard 800.00 458 45.80 845.80 800.00 458 45.80 845.80 Jones, Charles L Schuyler Jones, Charles L Schuyler 800.00 158 15.80 815.80 800.00 158 15.80 815.80 Kelim, Karl Omaha Kelim, Karl Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Keister, E. C Auburn Keister, E. C Auburn 800.00 173 17.30 817.30 800.00 173 17.30 817.30 Kendall, J. F Ponca Kendall, J. F Ponca 800.00 322 32.20 832.20 800.00 322 32.20 832.20 Kier, Max Lincoln Kier, Max Lincoln 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 Lowry, Vincent J Omaha Lowry, Vincent J Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Lukens, Mark Bloomfield... Lukens, Mark Bloomfield 800.00 422 42.20 842 20 800.00 422 42.20 842.20 McBride, J. G Lincoln McBride, J. G Lincoln 800.00 800.00 800.00 800.00 McGaffln, W. H David City McGaffln, W. H David City 800.00 104 10.40 810.40 800.00 104 10.40 810.40 McKay, C. R Omaha McKay, C. R Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 McLellan, John Grand Island... McLellan, John Grand Island... 800.00 196 19.60 819.60 800.00 196 19.60 819.60 McMahon, P. J Omaha McMahon, P. J Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 McMillan, Aaron M Omaha McMillan, Aaron M Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811 00 McQuistan, W. E Spencer McQuistan, W. E Spencer 800.00 570 57.00 857.00 800.00 570 57.00 857.00 Minnick, R. L Stromsburg Minnick, R. L Stromsburg 800.00 146 14.60 814.60 800.00 146 14.60 814.60 Moyer, George H Madison Moyer, George H Madison 800.00 244 24.40 824.40 800.00 244 24.40 824 40 Mueller, Fred A .Kearney Mueller, Fred A .Kearney 800.00 280 28.00 828.00 800.00 280 28.00 828.00 Neubauer, E. M Orleans Neubauer, E. M Orleans 800.00 388 38.80 838.80 800.00 388 38.80 838 80 Newton, Robert Franklin Newton, Robert Franklin 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 Norris, D. C Brewster Norris, D. C Brewster 800.00 468 46.80 846.80 800.00 468 46.80 846.80 Oelkers, Henry Eustis Oelkers, Henry Eustis 800.00 400 40.00 840.00 800.00 400 40.00 840 00 O'Gara, W. H Laurel O'Gara, W. H Laurel 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 Olesen, Julius Ashland Olesen, Julius Ashland 800.00 50 5.00 805 00 800.00 50 5.00 805.00 O'Malley, Geo. W Greeley O'Malley, Geo. W Greeley 800.00 300 30.00 830 00 800.00 300 30.00 830.00 Ough, Dan L Benkelman Ough, Dan L Benkelman 800.00 560 56.00 856.00 800.00 560 56.00 856.00 Parkinson, W. T Pawnee City.... Parkinson, W. T Pawnee City... 800.00 140 14.00 814.00 800.00 140 14.00 814.00 Pedrett, J JCiinball Pedrett, J JCiinball 800.00 840 84.00 884.00 800.00 840 84.00 884.00 Peterson, Ernest Axtell Peterson, Ernest Axtell 800.00 276 27.60 827 60 800.00 276 27.60 827^60 Price, F. O Thayer Price, F. O Thayer 800.00 126 12.60 812.60 800.00 126 12.60 812.60 Putney, W. G Cedar Bluffs... Putney, W. G Cedar Bluffs.... 800.00 94 9.40 809.40 800.00 94 9.40 809.40 Raasch, Obed .Norfolk Raasch, Obed .Norfolk 800.00 276 27.60 827.60 800.00 276 27.60 827.60 Randall, O. C— -'- Holdrege Randall, O. C— .'- Holdrege 800.00 310 31.00 831.00 800.00 310 31.00 831.00 Regan, R. C Columbus Regan, R. C Columbus 800.00 136 13.60 813.60 800.00 136 13.60 813.60 Reneker, Dr. Geo. W..Falls City Reneker, Dr. Geo. W..Falls City. 800.00 226 22.60 822 60 800.00 226 22.60 822.60 Rockwell, Will H So. Sioux City. Rockwell, Will H So. Sioux City. 800.00 280 28.00 828.00 800.00 280 28.00 828.00 Rundle, F. C Aurora Rundle, F. C Aurora 800.00 154 15.40 815.40 800.00 154 15.40 815.40 Russell, Carson McCook Russell, Carson McCook... Saunders, John D Kearney. 800.00 456 45.60 845.60 800.00 456 45.60 845.60 Saunders, John D Kearney 800.00 276 27.60 827 60 800.00 276 27.60 827.60 Sloup, Adam Omaha Sloup, Adam Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 Sniallwood, Jas. W North Platte... Sniallwood, Jas. W North Platte.... 800.00 510 51.00 851.00 800.00 510 51.00 851.00 Spence, L. D Crab Orchard. Spence, L. D Crab Orchard- 800.00 116 11.60 811.60 800.00 116 11.60 811 60 Spencer, A. D Barneston Spencer, A. D Barneston 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 Sprick, A. W Fontanelle Sprick, A. W Fontanelle 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 800.00 130 13.00 813.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 29 Amount No Amount Per of of Total diem Miles Mileage Paid Staats, Geo. F Fremont 800.00 104 10.40 810.40 Story, George M Plainview 800.00 330 33.00 833.00 Turner, S. B Jullerton 800.00 260 26.00 826.00 Valder, C. A Tekamah 800.00 200 20.00 820.00 Van Kirk, Rolla C Lincoln 800.00 800.00 Waldron, S. C Callaway 800.00 446 44.60 844.60 Wells, Frank S Fairbury 800.00 158 15.80 815.80 Whitney, F. L Big Springs 800.00 640 64.00 864.00 Wilson, E. P Chadron 800.00 914 91.40 891.40 Wittier, August Wayne 800.00 326 32.60 832.60 Wright, Stanley Alliance 800.00 748 74.80 874.80 Wynne, Chet Omaha 800.00 110 11.00 811.00 $80,000.00 27,289 $2,728.90 $82,728.90 SCHEDULE 2-E OFFICERS OF THE HOUSE To Whom Paid Corrick, Frank P., Chief Clerk, 109 days @ $10.00 $1090.00 Preparing House Journal for Publication, etc... 1250.00 $2,340.00 McAllister, J. M., First Asst. Clerk, 109 days @ $8.00 872.00 Stanley, W. L., Second Asst. Clerk, 109 days @ $8.00 872.00 Lundy, James W., Sergeant-at-Arms, 99 days @ $6.00 594.00 Brunzell, W. O., Asst. Sergeant- at-Arms, 99 days @ $5.50 544.50 Chadwick, Rev. A. E., Chaplain, 98 days @ $5.00 490.00 Total $5,712.50 SCHEDULE 2-F EMPLOYES OF HOUSE To Whom Paid \i&gt;. of Days Amount Allen, George, Clerk 88 days @ $ 5.00 $ 440.00 Beaumont, Fred, Page 22 days @ 3.50 77.00 Boggs, Allen, Legal Adviser 2 mos. @ 125.00 250.00 Brinkman, Karl, Mail Carrier 114 days @ 5.00 570.00 Brinkman, Maurine, Stenographer.... 5 days @ 6.00 30.00 Brown, Frank, Jr., Page 99 days @ 5.00 495.00 Burks, J. S., Janitor 99 days ® 5.00 495.00 Carey, John, Postmaster 98 days @ 5.50 539.00 Clark, Royal, Messenger 24 days @ 5.00 120.00 Crawford, C. A., Custodian 125 days @ 5.00 625.00 Currie, C. A., Clerk in Bill Room 88 days @ 5.00 440.00 Curry, Nola, Clerk 71 days @ 3.50 248.50 5 days @ 5.00 25.00 273.50 Curtis, T. D., Cloak Room Custodian 96 days @ 5.00 480.00 Dawson, Margaret, Stenographer 57 days @ 6.00 342.00 Decker, Frances, Stenographer 109 days @ 6.00 654.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">30 STATEMENT OF THE To Whom Paid No. of Days Amount East, Nelle, Chief Clerk in Engrossing Room 94 days @ 6.50 611.00 Farley, George, Committee Clerk 87 days @ 4.00 348.00 Perneau, John, Page 99 days @ 3.50 346.50 Fillinger, Virginia, Stenographer 101 days @ 6.00 606.00 Fleming, Geraldine, Bookkeeper 99 days @ 6.50 643.50 Frederick, Goldie, Stenographer 59 days @ 6.00 354.00 Frederickson, Ida, Docket Clerk 122 days @ 6.00 732.00 Harrenstein, Nelle, Stenographer 109 days @ 6.00 654.00 Hemenway, Carl, Chief Clerk In Bill Room 108 days @ 6.50 702.00 Holt, Jack, Clerk In Bill Room 87 days @ 5.00 435.00 Hutchinson, T. B., Proof Reader 105 days @ 5.00 525.00 Johnson, Robert, Janitor 109 days @ 5.00 545.00 Latrom, R. J., Messenger 109 days @ 5.00 545.00 Liston, Meda, Stenographer 98 days &lt;g&gt; 6.00 588.00 McMaster, A. F., Custodian 92 days @ 5.00 460.00 Martin, G. F., Clerk in Bill Room.... 97 days @ 5.00 485.00 Milliken, Thos., Cloak Room Custodian 89 days @ 5.00 445.00 Mitera, Marie, Stenographer 104 days @ 6.00 624.00 Morrow, W. H., Proof Reader for House Journal. 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 Back Pay 60.00 550.00 Nelson, Edna, Committee Clerk 87 days @ 4.00 348.00 Overton, Goldie, Stenographer 38 days @ 6.00 228.00 Pinkerton, Clyde, Clerk in Bill Room 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 Salak, A. M., Main Floor Custodian.. 99 days @ 5.00 495.00 Van Kirk, C. B., Gallery Custodian.... 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 White, Mildred, Stenographer 99 days @ 6.00 594.00 Wehner, Henry, Clerk in Bill Room 97 days @ 5.00 485.00 Whitelaw, S. S., Janitor 97 days @ 5.00 485.00 Whitney, Grace, Clerk 98 days @ 5.00 490.00 Total House Employes $20,134.50 SCHEDULE 2-G POSTAGE Date of No. of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued 1929 Senate House Jan. 3 J86572 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M $ $ 244.00 Postage Jan. 7 J86661 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 50.00 Postage 11 J86984 Jerry Wilhelm 54.00 Stamps 14 J87100 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 100.00 Stamps 14 J87101 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 388.00 Stamps 24 J87563 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 50.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 31 Date of No. of Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant 1029 Senate House Stamps 24 J87576 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 50.00 Stamps Febr. 1 J.88073 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 100.00 Stamps 4 J88076 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 100.00 Stamps 8 J88385 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 485.00 Stamps 11 J88431 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 100.00 Stamps 21 J88813 Trev. E. Giilaspie, P. M 50.00 Stamps Mar. 4 J89250 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 50.00 Stamps 8 J89414 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 50.00 Stamps 11 J89564 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 487.00 Stamps 11 J89567 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 50.00 Stamps 20 J90001 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 50.00 Stamps 23 J90133 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 9.00 Stamps 27 J90488 Jerry Wilhelm, P. M 54.00 Stamps 27 J90489 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 60.00 Stamps Apr. 3 J90709 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 485.00 Stamps 8 J90779 Jerry Wilhelm, S. P. M 100.00 Stamps 16 J91085 Trev. Gillaspie, P. M 172.20 Stamps Apr. 23 J91228 Trev. E. Gillaspie, P. M 167.00 Stamps 24 J91363 Jerry Wilhelm, S. P. M 15.00 Stamps May 7 J91872 Geo. C. Snow 12.50 Stamps ¥ 735.50 $2,797.20 SCHEDULE 2H TELEPHONE AND TELEGRAPH Date of No. of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued 1929 Senate House Febr. 8 J88326 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co $ 62.19 % Telephone 8 J88335 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 80.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">32 STATEMENT OF THE Date of No. of Warrant Warrant To Whom and for What Account Issued 1920 Senate House Telephone 16 J 88465 Western Union Tel. Co 4.56 Telegrams Mar. 8 J89404 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 23.25 Telephone 8 J89415 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 41.15 Telephone Apr. 5 J90768 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 36.00 Telephone 10 J90866 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 23.60 Telephone May 2 J91774 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 1.45 Telephone 7 J91883 Lin. Tel. &amp; Tel. Co 18.25 Telephone % 115.05 $ 175.45 SCHEDULE 2-1 SUNDRY PRIMING Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House Jan. 18 J87213 Warren C. Wood, Printing Cards for Desks ? 19.60 $ 23 J87286 Warren C. Wood, Printing Cards for Doors 12.50 11 J86987 Marshall Press, Printing Roll Calls 25.00 18 J87110 Amer. Printing Co. Printing Senate Roll Calls.... 6.25 18 J87111 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 154.96 23 J87413 Claflin Ptg. Co., Engrossing Blanks and Identification Cards 22.25 23 J87416 State Printing Co., Printing Legislative Rosters 18.00 23 J87417 Claflin Ptg. Co. Printing Committee Blanks.. 7.00 K. B. Ptg. Co., Printing 33 23 J87418 sets, Legislative changes 198.68 25 J87666 State Ptg. Co., Printing Legislative Rosters 58.00 25 J87667 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 312.89 25 J87668 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 461.90 25 J87670 State Printing Co., Printing Senate Rosters 16.00 Feb. 4 J88078 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 1,088.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 33 Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House 5 J88122 Warren C. Wood, Printing Cards 37.50 8 J88328 Amer. Ptg. Co., Printing and Engrossing Committee Re- ports 9.75 8 J88331 Warren C. Wood, Printing Signs 20.00 8 J88332 Warren C. Wood, Printing Signs 19.50 8 J88383 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 1,001.30 16 J88462 Golden Rod Printing Co. Printing Report Blanks, etc. 56.00 16 J88468 State Journal Co., Printing Senate Files 1,842.30 20 J88717 State Journal Co., Printing Senate Pamphlets.... 123.70 21 J88810 E. R. Purcell, Printing Synopsis of Bills 262.50 8 J89412 Mar Burr Pub. Co., Printing Bills 86.42 23 J90134 Warren C. Wood, Printing Cards for Chairs and Desks.. 50.80 27 J90490 Golden Rod Printing Co., Printing Reports and Stationery 15.00 Apr. 3 J90705 State Journal Co., Printing 148 Page Pamphlet 680.47 5 J90773 Brown Ptg. Co., Printing Roll Calls 4.00 12 J90951 State Journal Co., Printing Senate Piles 114.00 15 J91012 Burr Pub. Co., Printing House Rolls 101.32 23 J91237 Brown Print Shop, Printing Senate Roll Calls 4.00 25 J91598 Claflin Ptg. Co., Engrossing Bill Sheets 7.50 $2,675.78 $4,162.19 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">34 STATEMENT OP THE SCHEDULE 2-K SUPPLIES AND MISCELLANEOUS Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House 1929 Jan. 11 J86951 Geraldine Fleming, Notary Public Commission....? $ 9.00 11 J86956 Buck Taylor, Preparing Senate Chamber.... 90.00 11 J86957 Harry Bradley, Preparing Senate Chamber.... 90.00 11 J86958 O. J. Burckhardt, Preparing Senate Chamber.... 90.00 18 J87105 Van Sickle Glass &amp; Paint Co., Varnish, Brushes etc 19.50 18 J87106 Lin. Stamp &amp; Seal Co. Supplies 13.70 18 J87107 C. A. Crawford, Preparing House Chamber.... 115.00 11 J86952 C. A. Crawford, Cheese Cloth etc 14.14 11 J86984 Jerry Wilhelm, Box Rent 4.00 18 J87109 A. G. Chapman, Two Line-a-times 39.10 18 J87211 Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 10.40 23 J87414 H. R. Kelso Co., Soap 6.25 23 J87415 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Repairs on Mimeograph 24.25 23 J87419 H. R. Kelso Co., Janitor Supplies 2.35 23 J87420 Schwarz Paper Co., Supplies.. 5.15 25 J87669 Keystone Press, Stationery.... 39.25 25 J87671 Beatrice Creamery Co., Ice.... 7.60 1 J88066 Golden Rod Ptg. Co., Feb. Stationery 12.50 1 J88072 Revolving Fund, Supplies 482.87 5 JSS11S Nebr. Typewriter Co. Typewriter Rental 24.40 5 J88119 Hardy Furn. Co., One Stool.. 3.25 5 J88120 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Two Flags 7.00 5 J88121 Frank P. Corrick Box Rent 4.40 8 J88323 George Bros., Supplies 611.91 8 J88324 Revolving Fund, Supplies 108.74 8 J88325 Huffman Gen. Supply House, Stationery 5.50 8 J88327 A. G. Huffman, One Line-a-time 19.55 8 JSS329 Revolving Fund, Supplies 455.09 8 J88330 Latch Bros., Supplies 396.28 8 J88333 Lin. Novelty Co., Supplies 3.25 8 J88334 Huffman Gen. Supply House, Supplies 110.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 35 Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House 1029 8 J88336 Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 13.12 8 J88337 George Bros., Supplies 816.43 8 J88382 Frank P. Corrick, Typewriter Rental 10.00 8 J88384 Tucker Shean, Supplies 2.00 8 J88386 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Typewriter Rental 25.60 8 J88387 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, Janitor Supplies 37.85 16 J88461 H. R. Kelso Co., Janitor Supplies 2.00 16 J88463 Hall Hdw. Co., Janitor Supplies 63.75 16 J88464 Lin. Stamp &amp; Seal Co., Notary Seal, Badges etc 30.45 16 J88466 Brown's Arcade, Coat Hangers 2.16 16 J88467 Van Sickle Gl. &amp; -Pt. Co. Varnish 7.70 18 J88604 F. W. Woolworth Co., Ash Trays 1.20 18 J88605 Wekesser-Brinkman Co., In- dex and References of House Rolls 98.40 21 J88811 T. J. Thorp Mch. Co- Lock on Desk 8.50 21 J88812 Schwarz Paper Co., Drinking Cups 5.15 Mar. 6 J89287 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., Supplies 5.65 6 J89288 Thomas and Vail, Atty's. Attorney Service 100.00 6 J89289 Beatrice Creamery Co., Ice 7.60 6 J89290 Latsch Bros., Supplies 326.80 6 J89291 Schwarz Paper Co., Drinking Cups 10.30 8 J89405 Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 30.85 8 J89406 Uni. Pub. Co., Supplies 2.80 8 J89407 George Bros., Supplies 40.55 8 J89408 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Type - writer and Stands Rental 43.50 J89409 Revolving Fund, Supplies 167.22 8 J89410 Huffman Gen. Supply House, Supplies 44.55 8 J89411 Latsch Bros., Supplies 17.53 8 J89413 Donley Stahl Co., Crutch Tips 3.00 8 J89416 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Typewriter Rentals 29.55 8 J89417 Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 2.00 8 J89418 Revolving Fund, Supplies 287.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATEMENT OF THE Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House 36 8 J89506 Remington Rand Business Co., Line-a-times 37.26 11 J89566 Minor S. Bacon, Stenographic Service 29.05 15 J89688 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Cleaning Mimeograph 15 J89689 Chicago &amp; N. W. Railroad Co., Inspection State Institutions.. 20 J90080 L. C. Smith &amp; Corona Type - writer Inc., Rent on Type- 9.55 158.75 writer 4.00 20 J90081 Lin. Stamp &amp; Seal Co., Supplies 1.50 23 J90135 H. R. Kelso Co., Mops 2.00 15 J89687 C. A. Crawford, Preparing House Chambers.. 60.00 Mar. 23 J90136 Schwarz Paper Co., Drinking Cups 15.00 26 J90156 John Wilts.e, Expense in Capitol Investigation 9.76 Apr. 1 J90574 San. Towel &amp; Ldry. Co., Laundry 2.00 2 J90594 C. B. &amp; Q. R. R. Co., Inspec - tion of State Institutions 54.00 2 J90650 Revolving Fund, Supplies 103.48 3 J90703 Huffman Gen. Sup. House, Supplies 3 J90704 Lin. Stamp &amp; Seal Co., Supplies 3 J90706 Donley Stahl Co., Crutch Tips 3 J90707 H. Herpolsheimer Co., Supplies 3 J90708 Nebr. Typewriter Co., Rent on Typewriter 3 J90710 Fenton B. Fleming, Pencil Supplies (Ever-Sharp) 3 J90711 Latsch Bros., Supplies 4 J90713 Queen City Coach Line, In- spection of State Institutions 4 J90714 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., 50.00 Janitor Supplies 2.00 4 J90715 Nebraska Typewriter Co. Rent of Typewriters .... 43.50 16.80 5 J90742 George Bros., Supplies 5 J90743 H. R. Kelso Co., Janitor Supplies .S5 5 J90744 Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 10.00 5 J90769 Interstate Transit Co., In - spection of State Institutions 150.00 188.78 5 J90770 Revolving Fund, Supplies... 9 J90791 San. Towel &amp; Ldry. Co., Laundry 3.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 37 Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate House 1030 17 J91142 Schwarz Paper Co., Drinking Cups 15.45 17 J91143 Chas. B. Letton Clk. Sudi-. Chas. B. Letton Clk. Supr. Ct. Reimbursement for re- moving Telephone 14 00 Apr. 18 J91158 L. C. Smith &amp; Corona Type- L. C. Smith &amp; Corona Type - writer Co., Rent on Type- writers 23 J91229 Golden Rod Ptg. Co- 4.00 Golden Rod Ptg. Co., Envelopes 23 J91230 Huffman Gen. Sup. House. 18.25 Huffman Gen. Sup. House, Supplies 23 J91231 H. Herpolsheimer, 38.00 H. Herpolsheimer, Cheese Cloth 23 J91232 George Bros., Supplies 23 J91233 Latsch Bros., Supplies 23 J91235 Tucker Shean, Supplies 23 J91236 Beatrice Creamery Co., Ice.... 7.60 .90 1.63 24.50 23.70 23 J91238 Latsch Bros., Supplies 40.00 24 J91442 George Bros., Supplies 121.43 25 J91560 C. A. Crawford, Ice Cream Dishes and Flag Staff 25 J91561 J. W. Lundy, Flowers. 2.40 J. W. Lundy, Flowers, Individual Purchases 18.50 25 J91562 Nebr. Type Co., Rental of Typewriters and Tables 34.50 25 J91597 Sanitary Towel &amp; Ldry. Co., Laundry May 2 J91768 George Bros., Supplies 268.75 2 J91769 Remington Rand Bus. Serv.. .75 Remington Rand Bus. Serv., Supplies 18 oo 2 J91770 Latch Bros., Supplies 11 90 2 J91771 Danielson Floral Co.. Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 5.00 2 J91772 San. Towel &amp; Ldry. Co.. San. Towel &amp; Ldry. Co., Laundry 6. 65 2 J91773 Harry Bradley, Boxes 8 75 2 J91775 Danielson Floral Co.. Danielson Floral Co., Flowers 2 J91776 Rudge &amp; Guenzel. Flae"" 7.00 2 J91776 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, Flag May 7 J91870 Revolving Fund, Supplies 143.65 4.25 7 J91871 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, Supplies.. 1.65 7 J91873 James E. Beltzer, Cushions.... 11.00 7 J91882 George Bros., Supplies 7.65 14 J92064 Revolving Fund, Supplies '.'. 156!40 14 J92257 Nebr. Type Co., Typewriter Rental 39.70 16 J92258 Geraldine Fleming, Strings for Session Laws. 7.50 Totals $3,400.46 $3,799.79 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">38 STATEMENT OF THE STATEMENT 2-L PRINTING HOUSE AND SENATE JOURNALS Warrant Warrant Senate House Jan. 12 J86988 Kline Pub. Co. $ $ 94 08 12 J86989 Kline Pub. Co. ' ' 21540 12 J86990 Kline Pub. Co 198 76 18 J87212 Kline Pub. Co 95^8 19 J87217 Kline Pub. Co .!!! 108.48 25 J87672 Kline Pub. Co _ 42.84 25 J87673 Kline Pub. Co 111.36 25 J87675 Kline Pub. Co. 17400 28 J87946 Kline Pub. Co. 71 10 Feb. 1 J88067 Kline Pub. Co. .. 187 99 2 J88074 Kline Pub. Co., I.™."™""™.™ 27.60 vwwu .^ *».wug i uu. \ju. f ZV.bu 2 J88075 Kline Pub. Co 199.68 8 J88281 Kline Pub. Co. 114 84 J88388 Kline Pub. Co ."' 9744 97.44 J88389 Kline Pub. Co! _..Z~Z.__™ 109.20 w WUUUV ■»niin J * uv. \s\j. . j.uy zu 16 J88559 Kline Pub. Co. . 149 64 J88560 Kline Pub. Co. *"' 152 88 23 J88816 Kline Pub. Co ion or. " JBSBib K.nne Pub. Co ion 9fi 23 J88817 Kline Pub. Co. .. "" 131 04 Mar. 1 J89247 Kline Pub. Co 1 ? K 00 J89247 Kline Pub. Co J89248 Kline Pub. Co 109.20 125.28 6 J89292 Kline Pub. Co __.!!Z™ 31^20 J89293 Kline Pub. Co ...ZZZ 48.72 8 J89505 Kline Pub. Co __......." 76.56 11 J89508 Kline Pub. Co ..^.ZZZ.'. 90.48 J89565 Kline Pub. Co. " 40 7, 16 J89779 Kline Pub. Co. ill'™ Ton Ton Tj-u « » « XXX. JO 48.72 J89780 Kline Pub. Co. .....ZI™"~Z"! 184.08 20 J90082 Kline Pub! Co! !!!!!!!!! 87.00 23 J90137 Kline Pub! Co! !!!!!!!!!! 73.08 J90138 Kline Pub! Co! 17479 27 J90491 Kline Pub! Co. Apr. 1 J90575 Kline Pub. Co 62.64 jauDia mine rut), (Jo. . 0,744 J90576 Kline Pub. Co !!!!!!!"!!!! 156.00 2 J90595 Kline Pub! Co! !!!!!!!!!!!! 34.80 _ „ . „ M.m.**Mj.\, &amp; uu. \j\j. 'j a on J90651 Kline Pub. Co. ... B6 16 5 J90771 Kline Pub. Co. .. ,0700 J90772 Kline Pub. Co. 7 s 00 lu '- 88 9 J90780 Kline Pub. Co. „ ns J90781 Kline Pub. Co 4q «e 12 J90952 Kline Pub. Co. o, „ J90952 Kline Pub. Co. J90953 Kline Pub. Co. 109 20 15 J91013 Kline Pub. Co. !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!"!!" 83.52 18 J91155 Kline Pub. Co. !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 170.52 J91156 Kline Pub. Co 141,19 20 J91223 Kline Pub. Co! ,„«. Apr. 20 J91224 Kline Pub. Co. on 40 J4 23 J91234 Kline Pub! Co! !!!!!!!!! 69.60 J91239 Kline Pub! Co 102 Q« 25 J91563 Kline Pub! Co! ZZZ'ZZZ." 104.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">AUDITOR OP PUBLIC ACCOUNTS 39 Date of No. of To Whom and for What Account Issued Warrant Warrant Senate Senate House May 2 J91777 Kline Pub. Co 96.72 2 J91778 Kline Pub. Co 74.88 2 J91779 Kline Pub. Co 107.88 Totals $2,569.56 $3,132.36 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>