<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00012.00014">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00012.00014</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA For the Quarter Ending November 30, 1904.  TO THE HON. JOHN H. MICKEY, GOVERNOR.</title>
			            <date value="1904">1904</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-20</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-28</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
BIENNIAL REPORT 

OP THE 

HOME FOB THE FEIENDLESS 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 

For the Quarter Ending Noyember 30, 1904. 

TO THB 

HON. JOHN H. MICKEY, GOVERNOR. </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
Hon. J. H. Mickey Goyernor 

BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS. 

Hon. George D. Follmer, Land Commissioner Chairman 

Hon. G. W. Marsh, Secretary of State Secretary 

Hod. F. N. Prout Attorney General 

Hon. Peter Mortensen Treasurer 

VISITING AND ADVISORY BOARD. 

Mrs. H. J. W. Seamark, 1030 G Street Chairman 

Mrs. H. H. Wheeler, 1517 H Street Secretary 

Mrs. A. H. Weir 1120 C Street 

Mrs. E. C. Hemsworth Ninth and South Streets 

Mrs. R. D. Stearns 1343 L Street 

RESIDENT OFFICERS. 

Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus Superintendent 

Dr. May L. Flanagan Physician 

Mrs. William Faulkner Matron 

APPOINTIVE OFFICERS 

Otto Geschwender Engineer 

Mrs. Katherine Bregstone Head Nurse 

Hattie A. Moulton Teacher </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
REPORT. 

State Home for the Friendlbw, 
Lincoln, Neb., November 30, 1904. 

To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Board of Public 

Lands and Buildings: 

Gentlemen — In accordance with the Compiled Statutes of 
the State of Nebraska of 1899, p. 644, chap. 35, I have the 
honor, as superintendent of the Home for the Friendless, to 
submit to you herewith the third biennial report 

Very respectfully, 

Mas. Sarah B. Sohus. 

DESCRIPTION. 

The Home for the Friendless property consists of 2.87 
acres of ground. On this there are five buildings, main, and 
school buildings, laundry, cottage or hospital, and ban. The 
three first named are brick, the other two are bUMt The 
Bain and school buildings are two stories and basement; 
e laundry two stories with boiler underneath. 

The home is situated on the corner of Eleventh and South 
streets and may be reached from the city by any one of three 
car lines, cars running every ten minutes. Visitors are always 
welcome and the Home is opened to them six days of 
each week, except legal holidays, between the hours of 10 :00 
and 5 :00. 

HISTORY. 

The home has been a state institution for the period of 
years, and yet we feel that the people throughout the I 
do not know of it and of the work done by it as we wish they 
might. 

We endeavor in every way possible to make it truly a home 
for our dependent children of the state, girls under fourteen 
and boys under thirteen being admitted. Efficient help has 
been employed so that not only a home has been provi </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
296 


but also their morals, mental training, and physical needs 
all received as close attention as though they WCR with 
parents in the average home in the state. 

te have continued the work along the same lines as we 
during the former ported. As each child comes to us 
i home his physical needs are the first to be looked after, 
4 cleanliness taught him, and good wholesome food 
ided. Their morals we raise to a higher standard, showthem 
the benefits to themselves and to all those with 
in they associate. We have found that kindly methods 
¦al to the reason MR than corjMual punishment, and 
tave very little troublein governing our children. 

S IX DAY PRIVILEGES. 

Every Sunday morning from 10:00 to 11 :00 we have Sunday 
school in our chapel, using the same lessons as are used 
in the city churches, the helpers in the home l&gt;eing teachers. 
as none other than Christians are employed. In the afternoon 
we have Christian Endeavor from 3:00 to 4:00. This 
nducted by members of the Christian Endeavor societies 
of the different churches in the city, and great good is being 
done. Our children in that way receive benefit by coming in 
contact with others than those in the home, the change proving 
beneficial. 1 do not doubt that those coining to us from 
K different societies also receive a benefit. Quite often 
our older children, accompanied by a teacher or governess, 
•nd a nearby church in the evening. We feel confident 
tliat any children going away from our home, no matter 
where, will always remember the teachings they have had 
while with us. 

REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS MADE. 

Of the repairs and improvements suggested as needed in 
the last biennial report we have l&gt;een able to accomplish the 
following: Tearing out the old floors in the basement of the 
oi building and replacing same with cement floors. The 
in pipes in the basement of this building have been placid 
above the ground, not only making them more accessible in </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

297 

caae of needed repairs but has better facilitated the heating 
of the school building. On the first floor alx&gt;ve we have liail 
the old wash-room torn out in the main hall and &lt;miv&gt; 
the said hall that was of no use into two bathrooms, one for 
the second nurserv children, and the other for the nr.it run, 
who had no conveniences on this floor. These little OBM in 
this nurserv had heretofore to go to the larger boys' dormilory 
on the floor al&gt;ove to take their baths. The main hall is 
now in much better shape and is well lighted. We have had 
the bathroom in our hospital cottage and the girls' bathroom 
in the main building each thoroughly equipped with new 
necessary arrangements. Also in the toilet for the old ladies 
new closet and bowl. 

Ee have had new iron fences where needed, and they have 
a great improvement in the appearance of the hist it u- 

Aside from these improvements we have had one of the 
lM&gt;ilers thoroughly repaired, had all the tubes taken out. 
cleaned, and replaced, and new tubes where needed, making 
it in good condition to give us better service than heretofore. 

Eiring a wind storm of a year ago our smokestack was 
a down, and while down we had it painted, and it wtm 
ace inside of thirty-six hours. 

Ee inside of the institution was gone through with paint. 
", varnish, calsomine, and carpets, and linoleum wli 

The beds in each dormitory, as also throughout the entire 
institution, are in excellent condition, being well supplied 
with all the necessaries to make them such, each bed Mag 
supplied with sufficient bedding and linen to make them very 
comfortable. 

Ke had new tables made for the children's dining room, 
ig more seating capacity and more substantial tables. 

IMPROVEMENTS NEEDED. 

Of the improvements needed for the home at the present 
time I would mention first more land. We have only that 
that our buildings are on and none at all for garden pur- </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
298 


poses. We ought to at least have the property lying west of 
the home in the same block. 

E addition should be built on the south of the main build•r 
two bathrooms and a toilet. One bathroom for the 
dormitory, the other for the old ladies, and a toilet 
in the basement. The bathroom for the girls is at presi 
the basement, and the children have to travel two 
t of stairs to reach it. The old ladies do not have a 

By having the suggested bathroom for the girls it would 
give a chance to enlarge our storeroom, something we need 
very much. Our present storeroom is 12 x 14, and not at 
all large enough for our needs. The bathroom for the girls 
is divided by a partition from the storeroom, and by removing 
same it could easily be thrown into one room and give 
us the opportunity to store more than we can now. We can 
not buy goods in large quantities as we have not the room 
to keep them. 

Over the laundry we have six employees rooming, and no 
sanitary convenience of any kind. There should be a toilet 
arranged for that building. 

inew coal- and wood-house is needed to take the place of 
! now in use as they are almost past repair, having been 
e for several years. 

The porch at our cottage needs a new roof and a thorough 
repairing. 

A new water connection with the main is needed, the one 
we have being too small. It is only 1J inch. The pressure 
is not sufficient to carry the water to the second floor when 
the washing is being done in the laundry. In case of fire we 
would not have pressure enough to help ourselves very much. 

Ke need a new steam washer in the laundry. The one in 
has been there for fifteen years and is practically worn 

Kt the present time the Home is in very fair condition, 
have kept up as far as we have been able all the different 
irtments, and especially have we paid attention to the </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

299 

plumbing and the sanitary condition throughout. There are 
some changes that could be made to good advantage, especially 
in the toilet room for the children. The coming spring 
it will be necessary to go over the whole institution with 
papering, painting, kalsomining, and varnishing. This we 
try to have done every two years. In doing so we can keep 
the institution in a clean and healthy condition. 

APPROPRIATION OF 1903. 

Total disbursements — repairs and improvements. 3,074 61 

Total disbursements — cash fund 1,066 01 

Grand total $18,873 51 

Average number of inmates for first year 77 

tper capita based on maintenance, salaries, 
and wages f 191 33 

Cost per capita based on all expenditures 245 11 

r Lin* 

ii-H\«l/\lv XS.CI KJ1 

L . 

APPR&lt; 

IPRIATION OF 1' 

II. 

Maintenance 

Salaries 

Waives 

Repair, 

rit in treasury Dec, 1902. . 
ded from these funds 

$ 3,493 21 
3,490 22 

11,274 16 
1,088 33 

$1,475 87 
1,475 63 

•2,091 0; 
2,084 2J 

Lapsed 

2 99 

I 185 83 

I 

024 

9 

6 T 

Maintenance 

Salaries 

Wages 

Repairs 

.mount appropriated 
Expended to December 1, 1903 . 

$14,000 00 
4,531 48 

$6,560 00 
2,188 67 

$7,000 &lt;M 
1,960 56 

990 ! 

Ixpended to December 1, 1904 . 

$ 9,468 52 
7,475 15 

$4,373 33 
3,280 00 

$5,039 44 
3,501 17 

12,009 64 
815 73 

Remainder in treasury 

$ 1,993 37 

$1,093 33 

$1,538 27 

$1,193 91 

FIRST YEAR. 

l otal disbursements — mi 

untenance, salaries, and 

wages , 

|14,73l' m </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
300 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 

SECOND YEAR 

tl disbursements — maintenance, salaries, and 
wages |14,25&lt;&gt; 32 

Total disbursements — repairs and improvements. 81 5 i:*&gt; 

Total disbursements — cash fund 989 07 

Grand total |16,061 12 

Average number of inmates for second year TS 

tper capita based on maintenance, salaries, 
and wages f 182 77 

!&gt;er capita based on all expenditures 205 !&gt;1 

Our cash fund is derived from the sale of old iron, cinders. 

and from board paid by the parents who wish to main- 

tain the custody of their children. This has been reduced 

more than half since our former report. 

b on hand at time of last report $ 101 12 

•ived first year 1,078 63 

Total |1,179 7.") 

Expended first year 1,066 01 

Cash on hand December 1, 1903 f 113 74 

ived during second year 921 60 

Total |l,035 34 

Expended during second year 989 07 

Cash on hand December 1, 1904 f 45 27 

MAINTENANCE. 

With our limited appropriation for maintenance, we have 

been required to practice most rigid economy every place 

possible. With most watchful care we have had nothing go 

to waste and have considered it economy to buy the best in 

both food and clothing. 

Owing to the advanced price of coal, because of the strikes. 

it has required close figuring, as the coal, water and light are 

included in this fund </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
301 

Our cash fund being so much less than the former two 
years, because of the low rate charged for the children 
1" 'aided, we have not had the aid from this fuud, aud may 
have a deficiency in the maintenance fund. 

MATRON'S KEPORT. 

Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus, Superintendent Uonie for the Friend- 

less: 

iline is a gospel of work, cleanliness, and economy, and 
the nearly four years of my stay in the Home I have 
nuously sought to exemplify this gaapeL We have tried 
each first that work is man's heritage, thai "Us work is 
duty to which he is born," and that all work is honorable, 
is not the deed a man does, but the way that he do 
nld plead for the man's comj&gt;ensation in doing it 

In the kitchen we have tried, and I think the round, bright, 
healthy faces of our children are proof that we have not entirely 
failed, to servo plenty of good, appetizing and wholesome 
food, and at the same time we have used the the stri 
economy, always gathering up the fragments, that nothing 
be lost, and we think that our kitchen is as clean and sanitary 
as the kitchens in the best homes of our land. 

Our laundry work will compare favorably with the work 
of the In'st laundries, and yet we work at great disadvani 
because of the worn-out condition of our machinery, but we 
hope to have a new washing machine soon, and that other 
Machinery may follow. 

I r e have tried in every department to keep the standard of 
work high and to encourage cleanliness, and economy, 
matron could give a summary of the work done in an 
itution; the little daily duties are innumerable. But the 
?wing tables show a very few of the things accomplished : </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
302 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

ring done at the Home from December 1, 1902, to 
December 1, 1904. 

Sheets. 221 

Baby blankets 

Baby blankets 6 

6 

Napkins 375 

Napkins 375 

Baby bands 12 

Baby bands 12 

Girls' dresses 63 

Girls' dresses 63 

Pillow cases.. 185 

Pillow cases.. 185 

Gowns 129 

Neckties 29 

Neckties 29 

Ladies' dresses 13 

Ladies' dresses 13 

Baby hoods 2 

Baby hoods. 

o 

Skull caps. 20 

Skull caps. 20 

Baby cloaks 3 

Baby cloaks 3 

Sleeve aprons 17 

Sleeve aprons 17 

Stocking supporters 6 

Stocking supporters 6 

Wash cloths 115 

Wash cloths 115 

Rabbit suit 1 

Rabbit suit 1 

Spreads 42 

Short towels 72 

Short towels 72 

Comforts 40 

Tomforts 40 

Boys' waists 121 

Boys' waists 121 

Roller towels 148 

Roller towels 148 

Diapers 228 

Diapers 228 

Broad cloths 5 

Broad cloths 5 

Underwaists ." I 

Underwaists 54 

Iron holders 73 

Iron holders 73 

Cushion covers 10 

Cushion covers 10 

Cotton pads, for protec 

on pads, for protec- 

Box covers 2 

Box covers. 

«&gt; 

tion of beds 67 

tion of beds 67 

Lounge covers 3 

Lounge covers 3 

Pants. 

9 

Laundry bags 2 

Laundry bags. 

o 

_ 

Table cloths 23 

Table cloths 23 

Mattresses 22 

Mattresses. 

9O 

Dressing sacks 3 

Dressing sacks 3 

Long curtains 52 

Long curtains 52 

Short curtains §1 

Long baby dresses 17 

Long baby dresses 17 

Short curtains 82 

Short baby dresses 37 

Short baby dresses 37 

Drawers for girls 26 

Drawers for girls 26 

Long baby skirts 13 

Long baby skirts 13 

Drawers for babies 1 " 

Drawers for babies 15 

Short baby skirts 27 

Short baby skirts 27 

Tea towels hemmed 337 

Tea towels hemmed 337 

Girls' skirts 48 

Girls' skirts 48 

1, 1902, to December 1, 1904. 

1, 1902, to December 1, 1904. 
Fruit juices — Qts. 
Peach 6 

Fruit Canned from December 

Fruit Canned from December 

Canned fruit — Qts. 
Peaches 276 

Canned fruit— Qts. 
Peaches 276 

Fruit juices — Qts. 
Peach 6 

Apples 148 

Apples 148 

Cherry 4 

Cherry 4 

Grape 20 

Grape 20 

Cherries. 56 

Cherries. 56 

Fruit jelly 87 

Fruit jelly 87 

Pears 15 

Pears 15 

Grapes 31 

Grapes 31 

Butters — 

Butters — 
Peach 81 

Cranberries. 59 

Cranberriea 59 

Peach 81 

Plum 12 

Plum 12 

Preserved and pickled 
frnit. ft 22 

Preserved and pickled 
frnit. ft 22 

Cucumber pickles canned.228 

Cucumber pickles canned.228 </seg>



            <seg id="p011">
303 

Vegetables from December 1, 1902, to December 1, 1903. 
§ dozen bunches onions at 10c per dozen . . f 5 60 
dozen bunches onions at 5c per dozen. . . 1 95 

45 dozen bunches lettuce at 15c i&gt;er dozen. 6 75 
« dozen bunches lettuce at 5c per dozen. . 1 70 
dozen bunches radishes, 7c per 3 dozen. 7 35 
dozen bunches radishes, 4c per dozen ... 13 32 

~-i quarts of peas at 4c per quart — 8 96 

256 quarts of beans at 2^c per quart 6 40 

235 heads cabbage at 2}c per head 5 87£ 

150 dozen tomatoes at 7c per dozen 6 75 

140 dozen ears corn at 7c per dozen 9 80 

15 bushels beets at 25c per bushel 3 75 

Total $7^ 

Vegetables from December 1, 1903, to December 1, 1904. 

30 dozen bunches radishes at 25c per doz.f 7 50 
22 dozen heads lettuce at 15c per dozen. . 3 30 
41 dozen heads lettuce at 10c per dozen. . 4 10 
57 dozen bunches onions, at 15c per dozen 8 55 

3^ bushels onions at 50c 1 50 

11 dozen bunches beets at 25c per dozen. . 2 75 
1£ bushels beets for greens at 35c per half- 

bushel 1 05 

4 bushels beets at 50c 2 00 

13 bushels peas at 75c 9 75 

6 bushels beans at fl.25 7 50 

22 dozen heads cabbage at 25c per dozen. 5 50 
t dozen heads cabbage at 30c per dozen. 1 50 
bushels cucumbers at 50c 4 00 

14 bushels tomatoes at 60c 8 40 

188 dozen ears corn at 5c 9 40 

12 bushels corn at 25c 3 00 

Total 1 79 80 

Total |158 00 

Respectfully submitted, Mrs. Wm. Faulkner. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
304 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

PHYSICIAN'S KEI'OKT. 

Mrs. Sarah B. Soli us, Superintendent Home for the Friend- 

less: 

The records of the past two years show much illness of a 
serious nature, including diphtheria, scarlet fever, pneumonia, 
and an epidemic of measles, and yet with the lowest 
death-rate in the history of the institution. When we coni 
that the ages of the inmates have ranged from a few 
hours to eighty-four years; that there were admitted fifteen 
under the age of one month, and forty-one under two years; 
that the majority of these came into the world under most 
unfavorable conditions, poorly nourished or with inherited 
rasia, we feel that we have just cause for congratulations. 
Of the eight babies we have lost in two years one 
was eight months old, one three months, the remainder less 
than two months; one died shortly after admittance of endocarditis, 
another of syphilis at the age of one month, three 
of malnutrition, and three of gastro-enteritis. Two other 
deaths occurred, an old lady eighty-four and a little colored 
girl of eleven who had never been well from the time of 
entering the Home, dying from heart failure. 

Ine who has had any experience with artificially fed bawill 
understand the difficulty we have in finding food 
will agree, and also the fact that such little ones have 
h less resistance against disease. We have had some 
8 of malnutrition in which we could find no food that 
could assimilate, though no expense was spared in our 
•ts, an item, however, that adds to our per capita rate 
h more than if it were an adult to be fed. For instance, 
food that we found valuable cost at the least estimate |2 
;ek for one child. 

Ei an institution of this kind we expect and we find chilcoming 
with skin affections, ring-worm, pediculosis, 
throats, etc., and it requires constant watchfulness to 
ent the spreading to other children, and we feel that the 
te is particularly free from such case*. 

Wo were unable to trace the source of diphtheria an&lt;i 
scarlet-fever, but by adopting strict measures but three had </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
305 

HOME FOR THE FRIENDLB88. 

either disease. Measles, however, went through the entire 
institution, so that every dormitory was a hospital, but in 
no instance were there any bad results. Pneumonia CMMd 
us much anxiety, but all made good recoveries. Two of the 
old ladies were seriously ill, requiring special care for many 
I'cs. I have not hesitated in serious cases to have 
ition, and feel that everything has been done for the 
are of the inmates. The small appropriation permits 
ut most rigid economy so that there is no extra nurs&gt; 
for the sick, but this must be done by the regular atauts, 
and I wish to show my thorough appreciation of 
untiring efforts of the superintendent, matron, and imiiees 
working night and day when necessary, and I know 
in the best homes in the city a sick child could receive 

setter care than has been j 

iven to our children. 

HOSPITAL CASES TREATED 
NOVEMB 

'ROM NOVEMBER 30, 1902, TO 
R 30, 1904. 

Children Adults 

Total 

l~" 

IBiSnA • ... ¦¦••¦¦¦¦¦•¦•••*••••••¦•¦ • 
Ceasle* 
Yactnre of radius 
AGrippe 

3 
3 
4 
11 
1 
37 
1 

i " 
5 
"i " 
""i" 

3 
3 
5 
16 
1 
38 
1 
6 

Recovery 

umber of visits 

AUSES OP DEATH. 

Children 

Age 

Adult Age 

Total 

Hdage 
lalnutrition 
iyphili. 
Valvular heart disease 
leart failure 

3 
1 
1 
1 

Under 2 months 
I month 
II years 
3 months 
f 1 6 months \ 
\ 2 under 2 mos. j 

1 84yrs 

! 

Castro-enteritis 

3 

3 

Total 

10 

I 

Respectfully, 

May L. Flanag. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
306 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

TEACHERS' RErORT. 

Mrs. Sarah B. Sohus, Superintendent Home for the Friend- 

less: 

I here is no work more pleasant than that associated with 
children. To watch the daily struggle with problems bei 
unknown; to see the look of pleasure that comes over 
face when these problems are mastered ; to see the efforte 
Le to put into practice the lessons that have been learned ; 
now that in the child, day by day, slowly it may be, but 
sly, is developing traits of character that will give to the 
Id a noble man or woman, these alone repay all the efs 
one may put forth. 

Our children are not below the average intellectually or 
morally, but we feel that in many cases all the instruction 
they will receive along either line will be received during 
the few months or years they may be here, and ours is the 
responsibility of turning the young minds and hearts in the 
right direction. 

The school was found in excellent condition, and it has 
been our aim to in no way lower the standard. 

te common branches are taught, and although the school 
&gt;t large there are six grades, making the number of 
es twenty- three. The grades taught are the first, secthird, 
fourth, fifth, and seventh. Nearly all special ocas 
have been celebrated with suitable programs. Every 
Friday the children write to their friends. A part of 
Friday afternoon is given up to exercises of a general 
re, reading aloud, drill in the multiplication tables, givl 
program prepared entirely by the children, or some; 
of the sort. 

Eteen minutes of each day is devoted to calisthenics, and 
casionallv use the dumb-bells. Lack of time alone pretheir 
daily use. 

That part of the daily exercises most heartily engaged in 
and most thoroughly enjoyed by the children is the singing. 
We have no instruction books, but use the Sunday school </seg>


            <seg id="p015">
307 

Kiere is a small but well-selected library, and a number of 
older children are learning to appreciate some of the 
authors through reading them for themselves. 

In the kindergarten we try to prepare the children to love 
and to enjoy their future school work. 

Eiebel has said that the entire object of true education 
make people not merely do the right things but to eniem, 
and not merely industrious but to love industry. 

Eery morning we have the morning circle. In this we 
up a different subject every week and study it thor- 
Iy by means of talks, stories, songs, and games. The 
half-hour in the afternoon is spent in playing games 
ti they all heartily enjoy. 

The rest of the day is mainly devoted to the primary recitations 
and the kindergarten table work. The children take 
great delight and pride in decorating the kindergarten with 
their work, and each tries his best to do his work nicely so 
that it can be placed upon the wall. 

At Christmas time last year there were sixteen children 
promoted to the other room and after a brief review this 
fall four more were ready to be promoted. And at present 
there is a class of ten who will soon be ready for the more 
advanced work, but will probably be retained in the kindergarten 
as we are not as yet crowded. 

The average attendance in the kindergarten is twentyfive; 
ten of the little ones are in the kindergarten work and 
the rest entered the primary in September. 

The total enrollment in the grades from December 1, 1902, 
to November 30, 1903, was 61, and from December 1, 1903, 
to November 30, 1904, was 65. The average daily attendance 
for the first year was 27, and for the second year was 
31. Number of days taught the first year, 192, with two 
days' vacation at Thanksgiving and five days at Christmas. 

Eiys taught the second year 194, with two days' vacation 
hanksgiving, two at Christmas, one at New Year's, and 
nforced suspension of thirteen days during an epidemic 
teasles. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
308 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

The above is a report for the year beginning December 1, 
1902, and ending November 30, 1903, and for the year beginning 
December 1, 1903, and ending November 30, 1904. 

Yours respectfully, 

Hattie A. Moulton, Te 
Mary 8. Barnett, Kin&lt; 

¦acher. 

lergarten Teacher. 

REPORT OP INMATES 

Boys 

Girls 

Adult- 

Number present December 1, 1902 

4.1 

18 

72 

Bber received to December 1, 1903 — 
ioarded 
Relinquished 
leturned from homes 
"emporary shelter 

M 
a 
I 
17 

3G 
6 
5 
14 

3 

"28' 

71 

61 

Iier dismissed to December 1, 1903 — 
aken by parent or friend 
n trial 
ther institutions 
an away 
ound work 

53 
9 

..... 

37 
9 
1 

20 

1 

"i 

"i". 

"k 
1 

48 

1» 

umber present December 1, 1903 

51 

31 

: umber received to December 1, 1904 
Boarded 
Relinquished 
Returned from homes 
Temporary shelter 

31 
12 
7 
3 

17 
1 
4 
7 

I 

"¦9' 

53 

3-i 

|&gt;er dismissed to December 1, 1904 — 
aken by parent or friend 
ther institution* 
ound work 

45 
11 

31 
8 

"T" 

5 

s 

1 

"V 

'"%' 

5 

Gl 

42 

1(1 

:nt December 1, 1904 

7 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

309 

MI 

ED. 

1904 

Boys 

Girls 

Boys 

Girl. 

Under one month 
Between one month and six monliis 
Between six months and one year 
Between one an 1 two years 
Between two and three years 
Between three and four years 
Between four and five years 
Between five and six years 
Between six and seven years 
Between seven and eight years 
Between eight and nine years 
Between nine and ten years 
Between ten and eleven years 
Between eleven and t *elve years 
Between twelve and thirteen years 
Rween thirteen and fourteen years 
ween fourteen an i fifteen years 
ween fifteen and sixteen years 

2 

3 
2 
1 
6 
5 
1 
6 
d 
5 
5 
2 
5 
1 
5 
5 
1 
1 
1 

4 
3 
2 
2 
1 
1 
7 
7 
5 
5 
4 
5 
4 
3 

I 

3 
5 
3 
2 
4 
7 
6 
8 
8 
4 
8 
7 
3 
1 

• 

T 

Total 

71 

OL 

53 

x 

Average age in years 

o.a 

li.G 

13 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
110 LAND COMMIE 

ISIONER'S REPO 

ABLE SHO WI J'JG COUNTIES 
AD 

FROM WHICH 
MITTED. 

COUNTIES 

i 

X 
T. 
5 

&lt; 

I 

1 

S3 
5 

9. 

Clay 

2 

3 

1 

6 

3 
1 

1 
1 
1 

» 

.... 

.... 

.... 

"2" 

"2 " 

" i' 

1 
1 
1 
1 
1 
6 
1 
2 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

... 

.... 

fc=EE 

2 
1 
2 
3 
2 

1 
3 
1 
2 
1 
1 
31 

"3" 

6 
4 
3 
6 
4 
1 
85 
1 
7 
3 
8 
1 
5 
4 

"l" 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

... 

1 
1 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

41 
1 
3 
1 
2 
1 

"is" 

'25" 

ie 

¦¦•¦ 

«• 

3 
2 
3 

1 

"l 
2 

... 

.... 

... 

i 

¦3" 

"4" 
1 

... 

"5" 
2 

.... 

.... 

.... 

"2" 

.... 

.... 

"l" 

.... 

¦f 

.... 

2 

.... 

"l" 

.... 

" i 

.... 

.... 

.... 

1 
2 

.... 

.... 

v 

' 4" 

"l" 

"2" 

¦¦ Y 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

— 

— ' 

- 

STATES 

Colorado 

3 
1 

... 

2 

1 

&amp;=E= 

"l " 

.... 

I 
1 

.... 

¦: 

.... 

.... 

.... 

.... 

... 

.... 

— 

I 

I 

— 

Total 71 

61 

2S 

160 

53 I 

36 

9 

Total number admitted during the two years, 258. 

Of the nine children who were in homes awaitin 

\ action 

at tiie time of our report two years ago four were t 

lien on 

B agreement plan and five were adopted, 
uring the past two years there have been 37 
ed out on trial. Ten of them have been retun 

*¦*. 

ied, five 
lakes it 

of these being past ten years of age, whioh always i 
harder for them to fit into a home. The other fi </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

311 

babies under two years of age and were, in each case, returned 
through no fault of the child. Four of the 37 children 
have been taken on the agreement plan, eight have htm 
adopted, two frail little ones have died, and thirteen are 

now awaiting further developments. 

About, a year ago the Board for the Home decided that 

E superintendent should visit each child in the home bei 
the final papers were made out. Heretofore this had 
not been done because of the lack of funds. But during the 
past year we have used our cash fund for this expense, and 
all but two of the homes have been visited and each child 
has been found to be pleasantly and happily situated, and 

will, no doubt, finally become a member of the family. 
The cases of the three children running away were chil- 

8 here in the city who had been allowed to have their own 
most too much to want to settle down to a life of obedi. 
They each bad a parent who would not require their 

return to the Home. 

Of the adults in the home at the beginning of the biennium 

I was temporary shelter and eight had no other home. 
this number, the eldest, eighty-four years of age, has 
jed on to the Home not made with hands. The others 
with us and will probably make this their home Two 
hese require a special attendant, two are almost entirely 
&gt;less, and the others more or less so. Aside from these 
¦e have been 37 given temporary shelter during the two 
re, some remaining only one night and others longer, 
le we have given work, and some have needed only a little 
stance to be able to go on to friends. All have been 

deserving. 

BTJLES AND REGULATIONS FOR TAKING CHILDREN. 
On trial. 

It is hereby agreed by and between 

• 

superintendent of the Home for the Friendless, of the first 

part, and , of the second part, that said 
, party of the second part, shall take 

, a , child of the age of years, </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
312 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

from the said Home for the Friendless for the purpose of 

adopting said child, and if, after four months' trial, it shall 

be satisfactory to both of said parties hereto that said child 

shall be adopted by , party of the second 

part, then said first party agrees to relinquish to said second 

party and said second party agrees to adopt said child at 


Relinquishnient. 

I, , do solemnly swear that I am the 

&gt; 

Superintendent of the Home for the Friendless, and one, 

, a child, .... years of age, . . . 

and said child 

has been surrendered to said Home in writing by its guar- 

dian, , for the purpose of adoption to 

the Home for the Friendless and has been under the care of 

said Home for .... weeks; that I give my consent in writing 

to the adoption of said child by and 

voluntarily relinquish all right to the custody of and power 

over said child, and all claim or interest in the same. 

Agreement Plan. 

This agreement made and entered into this .... day of 

, 190. ., by and between the State of Nebraska 

by , Superintendent of the Home for the 

Friendless, an institution of said State, party of the first 

part, and of , in the county 

of , State of Nebraska, party of the second 


Witnesseth : That the said party of the second part shall 

take one , child born , 

and name , to keep and treat as their 

own child until . .he shall have arrived at the age of twentv- 

one years, said child to render what assistance is required 

of in the home of the party of the second part, pro- 

vided such requirements are not deemed unreasonable. For </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
313 

ROME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

these services the said is to receive suit- 

able and proper care, attention, clothing, and a common 
school education, including one year in some recognized Mgfc 
school. At the age of twenty-one years the said party of the 

second part is to pay to the said th«&gt; 

sum of f in cash or its equivalent, as the 

may desire at that time. 

It is further understood and agreed by and between the 

fes hereto that the said child has been properly relinted 
to the said Home for the Friendless and will \&gt;y 
Home be relinquished to the said party of the second 
hereto subject to the following conditions: That in 
the said party of the second part shall in any manner 

fail in duty as guardian of said child to give said 

II proper care, attention, education, clothing, or etherneglect 
said child, then the party of the first part or 
successor in office or other person in authority repreng 
said Home for the Friendless, shall have the ri^ht 
authority at any time before said child reaches the age 
mrteen years, at her option to rescind this agreement 

and take and remove said child from the care and custody 

of the party of the second part. 

In testimony whereof, the said parties have hereunto set 

their hands the day and year first above written. 

Superintendent. 

RULES FOR ADMISSION TO HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

1. Children in order to become inmates of the home must 
belong to one of the following classes: 1st Surrender to 
the home and thus become its ward; 2d, orphans or half 
orphans. All applications under these two classes shall be 
investigated by the advisory board and Superintendent and 
none shall be admitted without such investigation shows destitution 
enough to require, the shelter of the home. </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
314 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

children said person shall pay to the home for care and 
board a sum not to exceed two dollars ($2) per month, 
smaller amount may be charged according to circumstances, 
at the discretion of the superintendent and visiting and advisory 
board. 

Parents or guardians wishing to place children temporarily 
in the home must sign an agreement that if no compensation 
is paid for six consecutive months, the children 
will be considered wards of the state, and as such may be 
placed in homes for adoption. 

3. No children will be admitted whose parents or guardians 
reside in states other than that of Nebraska, Applications 
must be accompanied by written statements from 
reliable persons, stating that conditions are as applicant 
sets forth. 

4. Boys under thirteen and girls under fourteen years of 
age may be admitted in accordance with sections 1 and 2 or 
rule 1, and any rule governing admission to said home, 

5. Any person desiring to take a child from the home for 
adoption or to bring up to maturity must communicate in 
person or by writing to the superintendent, giving a full 
statement of the circumstances in which the child will be 
placed, if transferred from the home to his or her care, what 
position in the family such child will hold, what labor will 
be required, what advantages for education will be given, 
what will be the religious privileges and training. Also assurance 
of temperate habits. These facts must be accompanied 
with good and satisfactory recommendations or the 
request can receive no attention. 

DUTIES OP OFFICERS. 

Superintendent. — The superintendent shall reside at the 
Home and have general supervision and control of both the 
internal and external management subject to rules and regulations 
provided by advisory board and Board of Public 
Lands and Buildings. She shall have the power to engage 
and discharge employees, except those provided for in chap. </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS. 

315 

37, of Session Laws 1897. She shall keep a record of names 
of all inmates with the date of their admission and dismissill. 
This record shall contain as far as possible the name, 
age, nativity, where from, when received, when dismissed, 
how disposed of, and in case of death state cause, which last 
should be certificate of the Home physician. She shall make 
a written report of all actions in connection with inmates 
and employees, every three months from promulgation of 
these rules, to visiting and advisory board. In no case shall 
the superintendent and matron be absent from the home at 
the same time. 

i[ATBON. — The matron shall reside at the home and have 
?ral supervision of the domestic arrangements of the inltion 
sewing and dining rooms, table linen, kitchen and 
ldry, and have charge of all stores. She shall see that 
institution be in perfect order, all work be done in pro]&gt;er 
iner, and be responsible for the good conduct of the help 
ler departments. In the absence of the superintendent 
shall assume the duties of that officer. 

Physician. — The physician shall have general supervision 
of the health of the inmates. She shall make daily visits to 
the Home and oftener if necessary and shall attend all inmates 
during sickness. Shall have provided for her a room 
furnished with hospital and medical supplies, and a 1h«&lt;1 
when obliged to remain at the Home. Shall make out all 
requisitions for medical department, and in her absence the 
superintendent shall see that nurses comply with physician's 
instructions. She shall keep a record of all patients attended 
and report each month through the superintendent 
to visiting and advisory board. She shall thoroughly examine 
all children before being taken into the home and use all 
precautions to prevent contagious diseases. 

Eo nurses for either sick or well shall be employed at the 
e who are under twenty years of age. 

ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. 

In submitting this report I wish to thank the Governor 
and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings for the deep </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
316 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

interest they have taken at all times in the affairs of this 
home. For the hearty cooperation they have shown in all 
that pertained to its best interest. 

wish also to thank the Ladies' Advisory Board for the 
faithful performance of their duties and the helpful advice 
and willingness to do all in their power to aid us in this work 
and for the encouragement given. They have at all times 
faithfully endeavored to help us carry out the rules for this 
institution. 

We wish to thank all those — and there have been many — 
who have contributed to the pleasure and profit of the children 
and old ladies in bringing gifts at holiday times, for 
books, magazines, toys, fruit, candy, etc., all of which has 
been duly appreciated by the children and also the grown 
people. Especially do we wish to extend our thanks to l&gt;r. 
Green for the cucumbers and to Dr. Paine for the peaches 
which they so liberally gave us this past summer. 

EWe extend a cordial invitation to the taxpayers of this 
te and all interested in the charitable work of the state 
visit us and see the results of our efforts in the workings 
the institution. 

Respectfully submitted, 

Mas. Sarah B. Sohus, 

Superintendent. 

Lincoln, Neb., December 1, 1904. 

To the Governor and Board of the Home for the Friendless: 

Bour advisory board respectfully submit the following 
,rt: 

In their judgment the administration of this home is commendable 
In the various duties pertaining to the management 
of this large household, common sense, good judgment, 
and scrupulous cleanliness with careful attention to a 
healthful dietary have prevailed. This Board endorses the 
suggestions contained in the report of the superintendent. 

The placing of these children in good private homes is one 
of the most valuable features of this work. A state agent </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
317 


able to devote the whole time to this work would be desirable. 
A personal inspection of proposed homes before ad&lt;»j&gt;tion 
is desirable. The duties of the superintendent mak 
difficult for her to attend to this feature of the work. 

No provision is made for those children belonging to the 
home after they are fourteen. It is necessary to fit all these 
children for self-support. It is especially necessary if they 
are to be self-dependent at so early an age that the industrial 
features of education be emphasized. This is done in 
a measure. They are taught the simple household tasks. 
If the home had sufficient land for farming purposes much 
more in this line could be accomplished. For this reason 
the plan of uniting this institution with the one at Milford, 
where there is land owned by the state, commends itself to 
us as well as for reasons of economy for the state. The 
school work of this institution would be better adapted to 
the needs of these children if it provided for a thorough 
manual training department. 

I is not practical for this home with its present resources 
Lre for crippled and defective children. Justice can not 
one either to normal children or the afflicted when the 
npt is made under present conditions. This institution 
&gt;w caring for such a case. To do so the dispensary was 
eited into a bed-room and the home's quarantine arements 
almost destroyed. Nor do we feel that justice 
be done to these cases which need special nursing for 
h we have no provision. 

1&gt;endent old ladies form a class in the community apig 
strongly to our sympathies. No doubt the state or 
;e charity should make provisions for them. It is exigly 
difficult to care for them in the place that is deto 
the care of children. They can not be housed, manor 
cared for under the same rules or in the same man- 
The plan for housing and feeding as well as plans for 
occupation and comfort must needs differ widely from 
for the best good of children. The effort to care for 
three classes of dependents under the same manage- </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
318 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

ment has increased the difficulties and decreased the efficiency 
for the management of this institution. 

Eovision should be made for different departments for 
lal children, defective children, and dependent old laif 
the state cares for all these dependent classes in this 
tution. 

Grace M. Wheeleb, Secretary. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>