<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00031.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00031.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1914 His Excellency, J. H. Morehead, Governor of the State of Nebraska ar Sir: — I have the honor to present herewith my biennial report retary of State, for the biennium ending November 30, 1914, i contains a statement of all fees received by this office. is report contains appropriations for, and the expenditur fice, also list of corporations filing articles during the last bi- 1 ne report of municipal and school bonds approved by me is tt rl as t same appears in the report of the Auditor of Public have also omitted certificates of approved banks, as this nt report of the Banking Board. List of notary com- l&lt; ars ;d has also been omitted missi n In this r port I have endeavored to include only such matters as pertain to this office Respectfully submitted. ADDISON WAIT. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">death resigna TERRITORIAL 1. Thomas B. Cuming, Aug. 23, 1854, to Mar. 12, 1858. 2- J. Sterling Morton. July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. 3. Algernon S. Paddock. May 6, 1861, to Feb. 21. 186". STATE 4. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871 5. Win. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. 6. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. 7. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. 8. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879, to Jan. 4, 1883. 9 Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1883, to Jan. 6, 1887 10. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889 Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by U of James Laird. 11. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891 Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by tion of Gilbert L. Laws. [John C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891, to Jan. 3, 1895. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895, to Jan. 7, 1897. F. Porter, from Jan. 7. 1897. to Jan. 3. 1901. *George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905- A- Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. Geo. C Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907, to Jan. 5, 1911. Addison Watt, from Jan. 5, 1911, to Jan. 7, 1915. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">t HISTORY THE TERRITORY T Perritory of Nebraska was organized May 30tl tska v Phe Territory was a part of the Louisiana Purchs Louisiana Purchase ceded by tory was a part of the ce to the United States in 180:!. First T. rritorial L3{ held D ISOii. F rst Territorial Ligislatu uaha, commencing January loth, Qg of 1 ting of 13 Count linen it Omaha, commencing .lanua )i Oma- 25 Representatives and the 12th and la D conv t • ssion convened at nd 25 Representatn id anuary 19th, 1867. la Ja rhe seat of Government was permanently located I anently located at Lan t w 1867. The Territory sent 3,157 present site of Lincoln, July :!«.&gt;th. INT. The Territc to the Union army during the Civil War. Lint ol sent site of Lincoln, Ju t vil War. Lincoln statue ai 1 during th c t d Sept. 2nd, 1912. orial erected on State House grounds — unveiled Sept. orial erected on State House grt THE STVIl THE 8TATI Nebraska was admitted to the Union as a State Marti Nebraska was admitted to the Union as a State March 1st, 1867, by act of Consress passed February and by Proclamation issued )f Congress passed February and by Procla t of ( Andrew Johnson and attested by Hon. William H. Sewtrd resident Andrew Johnson and attested by Hon. Willia etary of State, and dated March 1st of that year. e first State Legislature was held in Lincoln January 7th, 1869 e present Constitution was adopted November 1st. Ml The first State Legislature was held in Lincoln Janu The present Constitution was adopted November 1st The extreme length of the State east and west is 412 The extreme length of the State east and west is 412 rr Its greatest breadth north and south is 208 miles. Its greatest breadth north and south is 208 miles. Its area is 76.895 square miles, or 49,212.000 acres. Its area is 76.895 square miles, or 49. 212.000 acre Number of votes cast in 1868— 15.C01. Number of votes cast in 1868— 15.C01. Number of votes cast in 1907—271,491. Number of votes cast in 1907—271,491 Population in 1900 was 1.066,300. Population in 1900 was 1.066,300. Nebraska's population in 1910, 1,192.214. Nebraska's population in 1910, 1,192.214 Gain in last decade. 125,914. Gain in last decade. 125,914. Gain percentage, 11.8. Counties showing net loss, 21. Counties showing net gain. 71 Counties losing in First district, 6 of 7. Counties losing in Second district, 1 of 3. Counties losing in Third district. 3 of 15. Counties losing in Fourth d'strirt. 5 of 12 Counties losing in Fifth district, 6 of 18. Counties losing in Sixth district, none. Repr </seg>
            <seg id="p006">SKOM 1868-1914 1868 15,291 1889 167,2 167,268 1901 203.1&amp;2 1872 15,250 1890 214.072 1902 198,574 1876 49,387 1891 145,131 1903 2M.58 1879 61,682 1892 195.2!m 1904 232,457 2,45 181.606 1905 102,152 1880. 87,452 1893 1881 75,527 1894 81S,«I 213,652 1906 194,692 1882 86,259 1895 141,412 1907 203,93 S.934 1883 '1,409 1*H.. 224,174 1908 271.491 1884 134,193 1897 194,128 1909 207,57; 1885. 126,840 1898 190,657 1910 24 ism; 138.209 1899 :'4H 1911 225,380 145.708 1900 251,005 11U2 124 202.291 1914 246.941 24 Secretary of Addison Walt </seg>
            <seg id="p007">b OFFICE FORCE OF DEPARTMENT OF STATE AdiUson Wait, Syrac Geo. W. Marsh, University PI . .T. W. Smith, University Pll </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA STATE GOVERNMENT THE KOLLOWIX; ARK THK OFEH EKS OK THE STATE AS SHOW* BY THE RECORDS OF THIS OFFICE. THE TERMS OF THE EXKCITIYE OFFICERS EXPIRE ON JAM AKY 7th, 1915 Governor Jno. H. Morehead Lieutenant Governor S. R McKelvie Secretary of State Addison Wait Treasurer Walter A. Georg Auditor of Public Accounts W. B. Howard Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Fred Beckmann Attorney General Grant G. Martin Superintendent of Public Instruction James E. Delzel Clarke. Jr.. H. T.. Omaha. 1917 Railway Commissioner Hall, T. Lm, Lincoln, 1915 Railway Commissioner H. G. Taylor, 1919 Railway Commissioner OFFICERS-ELECT WHOSE TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRES JANTARY. 1917. Governor Jno. H. Morehead Lieutenant Governor James Pearson Secretary of State Chas. W. Pool Treasurer Geo E. Hall Auditor of Public Accounts W. H. Smith Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings Fre-^ Beckmann Attorney General Willis K. Reed Superintendent of Public Instruction A. O. Thomas Clarke. Jr., H T, Omaha, 1917 Railway Commissioner Hall, T. L.. Lincoln, 1921 Railway Commissioner Taylor. H. G., Central City, 1918 Railway Commissioner FEDERAL DEPARTMENT I'nited States Senator Gilbert M. Hitchcock, 1917 United States Senator-elect George W. Xorris, 1919 CONGRESSMEX WHOSE TERMS EXPIRE MARCH 4. 1915 First District John A. Maguire Second District C O. Lobeck Third District Dan V. Stephens Fourth District Chas. H. Sloan Fifth District Silas R. Barton Sixth District Moses P. Kincaid </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 First Distric r. Reavis Second District Third District. Fourth District Fifth District. . Snxth District ! P. Kinkaid CONCESSION VI, DIST Kl( IS BY COUVI I KS District S'emat d [ &gt;y. Dougla ilngtor let Rurt. Thurston, Dal rta, Dixon. Cuming. Dodge, Colfax, tanton. Wayne. Cedar. Knox Pierce iso \ and Merrick aunders. Butlf ward ■ ( xth District -Sioux. Bcotts Rhiff. Banner. Kimball. Dawps. Box Butt rhpyf Lincoln. McPher«on. Hooker, Thomas. Tx&gt;Kan. Dawson. Ciister Blaine. Brown. Keya Paha. Ro-k. Loup. Holt. Oarfield. Valley. Sherman. Buffalo, Howard. Greelpy, Wlieeler and Boyd. Rlaine. I JUDICIARY SII'KEME COURT Chief Justice— Manoah B. Reese, Lincoln, 1M15 Conrad Hollenbeck. 1921 Justices— John B. Barnes, Norfolk. 1916 Jacob Fawcett, Omaha, 1916 Samuel H. Sedgwick. Lincoln. 1916 Charles B. Letton, Fairbury. 1918 William B. Rose, Lincoln, 1918 Francis G. Hamer. Kearney, 1918 DISTRICT JUDGES Term expires 1JH4 tBt District— John B. Ra-per, Pawnee City ond District— Jas. T. Regley. Papillion rird District— Albert J. Cornish, Lincoln: P. James Cosgrave. Lin coin: Willard E. Stewart. Lincoln. Fourth District— George A. Day, Omaha: Lee B. Estelle, Omaha: James &lt; O\I.RKSSMK&gt;-M.KCT WHOSE TERM OF OFPICI IXHH8 MARCH 4, 1917 C O. Lobeck Dan V. Stephens Chas. H- Sloan .\shton C. Shallenberger Ui hardson, Pawnee, Johnson and . Fillmore. York, Polk and Hamilton. ( t Hall. Adams, Webster. Franklin. Kearney. Phelps. Har- sper. Furnas. Red Willow. Frontier. Hitehcoc Per- Dundy, Xuekolls and Clay heridan, Deuel. Cherry. Grant. Morrill. Garden. Keith. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 James P. English. Omaha: Charles Leslie, Omaha: Willis G Sears, Tekamah; Abraham L. Sutton, South Omaha: Alexander C. Troup, Omaha. Fifth District — George F Corcoran, York; Edward E. Good. Wahoo Sixth District — Conrad Hollenbeck. Fremont: George H. Thomas, Schuyler. nth District— Leslie G. Hurd, Harvard Eighth IMstrict — Guy T. Graves, Pender Ninth District— Anson A. Welch, Wayne T nth District — Harry S. Dungan, Hastings Eleventh District — James R. Hanna. Greeley; James X. Paul, St- Paul Twelfth District— Bruno O. Hostetler, Kearney.' Thirteenth District— Hanson M. Grimes. North Platte Fourteenth District — Edward B. Perrv. Cambridge Fifteenth District— R. R. Dixon. O' Neill reenth District — Wm. H. Westover, Ruahvllle. enteenth District — Ralph W. Hobart. Mitchell Eighteenth Dirtrict — Leander M. Pemberton. Beatrice STENOGRAPHERS Supreme Court Stenographers Nettie M. Dortch Norfolk C L. Hobbs Lincoln O E. Johnson Lincoln .1 E. Ferris Lincoln Winifred Kaup Western Florence Wilson Lincoln Evelyn Hanna Lincoln District Jndsres' Stenographers First District J A. OTCeefe. Beatr Second Dictrict Earl R. Travis. Plattsmouth Third District Myron E. Wheeler. Lincoln E. R. Mockett. Lincoln C. A. Emerv, Lincoln Fourth District W. S. Heller. Omaha Thomas P. Wilson. Omaha W. J. Fawsett. Omaha Geo. W. Meec&gt;iam. Omaha W. T. Speice. Columbus Seventh District Daisy Williams Cattle. Geneva Eighth District J. B. Rossister. Walthlll Ninth District W. R. Ellis, Wayne Tenth District G M Baird. Wllcox Eleventh District O. A. Abbott Grand Island H. J Paul. St Paul Twelfth District W. M. Cook, Kearnev </seg>
            <seg id="p011">e\ f*&lt;* a y.j t\ i v_j r iii f*j f*j v. t\ ij i «"\ li 1 \ i r l - \ l I* 11 Erteenth District, irteenth District eenth District teenth District P. J. Barron, North Platte V. R. Schober, Cambridge C. B. Scott, O'Neill J. I). Scott, Rushville Liston L. Hall, Ger \ . Johnson, Beatrice Eenteenth District hteenth District SUBORDINATE STATE OFFICERS UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BOA Kit OF REOKVr&gt; [~&gt;rge Coupland. Elgin B. Anderson, Lincoln L. Hall. Sr.. Lin-oln. . G. Whitmore. Valley ink L. Haller. Omaha G. Lyford. Falls City P. Brown, Elect .Jam Jam January. 1916 .January. 1916 .January. 1918 .January, 1918 .January. 1921 ..Tanuarv, 1921 J. E. Miller. Elect I Stuart Dales, Lincoln muel Avery. Lincoln . Secretary Chancellor STATE XORWAL SCHOOLS Peru Daniel W. Haves. President Kearney Gpo S Dick. Pn Adjutant General, X X. G ....P. L. Hall, Jr. banking Board . . . . K. Royse, Secretary Board of Irrigation . . . . D. D. Price. Secretary Board of Charities and Corrections. ....J. W. Shahan Deputy Labor Commissioner \V Pool Deputy Game and Fish Warden . . . .Gust Reutenbeck Deputy State Food Commissioner.. . . . .C. E. Harm an Deputy State Veterinarian. L C. Kigan Printing Board N. .1. Ludi. Dep. Comr. ultural Society . . . . W. R. Mellor. Secretary Horticultural Society .' C. G. Marshall Board of Equalization ... Secretary Dairymen's Association R. W. McGinn Poultry Association A. H. Smith. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OP STATE Wayne L T . S. Conn, President Chadron Joseph Sparks, President STATE INSTITUTIONS The following officers are appointed, their terms expiring at the re of the appointive power, the officers being as follow Nebraska Hospital for Insane, Lincoln.. Dr- B. F. Williams, Sirpt. Hastings Insane Asylum, Ingleside. . . . Dr. M. W. Baxter, Supt. Norfolk Asylum for Insane, Norfolk Dr. W. D. Guttery, Supt. Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home, Grand Island. Fred Zimmerman, Com'nd't. Soldiers' &amp; Sailors' Home, Milford David Rowden. Commandent State Penitentiary, Lancaster W. T. Fenton, Warden Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln Dr. H. Winnett Orr, Supt Tuberculosis Hospital, Kearney Mrs. Pearl Barker, Head Xurse and Supt Institute for Feeble Minded Youths, Beatrice Dr. W. S- Fast, Supt Boys' Industrial School, Kearney R. V. Clark. Supt Girls' Industrial School, Geneva Lydia J. McMahon. Supt Industrial Home, Milford Lena E. Ward, Supt School for the Deaf. Omaha Dr. F. W. Booth, Supt School for the Blind, Nebraska City X C. Abbott, Supt BOARDS The Secretary of State, by virtue of his office, is a member of the following boards: Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Edueational Lands and Funds Board of Pharmacy. Board of Canvassers Board to Approve Depository Bonds. Board of Prison Inspectors. Voting Machine Commission. Board of Veterinary Medicine. Following is a list of the various State Boards and the members thereof: </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 HOARD OF C0MMI§8I0XNM OK MA IK 1NM1I1 T1ONS Office in Capital Building Silas A. Holcomb Chairman Henry Gerdes Howard Kennedy- Leo Mathews Secretary BOARD OK EDK ATIONAL LANDS AMI KI \ DN M ••♦•!•. second Tuesday of each month Jno. H. Morehead, Governc Chairman Fred Beckman, Commissioner Public Lands and Building retary Walter A. George, State Treasurer \ddison Wait. Secretary of State Grant G Martin. Attorney General BOARD Or PHARMACY Meets second Wednesday of Kehruary, May. Anini-t and November W. B. Howard, State Auditor Chairman Fred Beckman, Commissioner Publi Lands and Buildings. . . .Secretary Eison Wait. Secretary of State . nt G. Martin, Attorney General ter A. Georg. -urer DKPOSIIORY BOND BOARD (ailed Heetinars Eo. H. Morehead, Governor dison Wait. S.-crctary of State ant G. Martin. Attorney Genera BOARD OK ASSESSMENT AND KQIAI.IZATION Meets for Assessment first Monday in May Meets for Equalization third Monday in July Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Chairman Addison Wait, Secretary of State Walter A. George, State Treasurer W. B. Howard, State Auditor Fred Beckman, Commissioner Public Lands and Buildings Henry Seymour Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 PRINTING COMMISSION Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Commissioner X- J. Ludi Deputy Commissioner BOARD OF « AWASSERS »er&lt;»nd Tuesday in September and fourth Monday in N«&gt; ember Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Chairman Walter A. George, State Treasurer \V. B. Howard, State Auditor Addison Wait, Secietary of State Grant G. Martin, Attorney General BOARD OF EDUCATION A. H. Viele, President, term expires 1915 Norfolk J. R. Gettys, Vice-President. term expires 1916 Lincoln D. Morris. Secretary, term expires 1914 Kearney T. J. Majors, term expires 1913 Peru A L. Caviness, term expires 1!U7 Fairbury James E. Delzell. Superintendent of Public Instruction Lincoln Walter A. George, State Treasurer Lincoln VOTING MACHINE COMMISSION (ailed Meeting Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Chairman Addison Wait. Secretary of State W. B. Howard. State Auditor. BOARD OF VETERINARY MEDICINE (ailed Meeting Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Chairman Addison Wait. Secretary of State W. B. Howard, State Auditor. A. Bostrom State Veterinarian BOARD OF HEALTH (ailed Meetings Jno. H. Morehead, Governor Chairman James E. Delzell, State Superintendent Grant G. Martin, Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p015">RKPORT OK THK SECRETARY OF STATE 15 BOARD OK ( HARITIKS AM) ( nitKM MO\s Meets third Tuesday of January. April, July and Oetolter G( Chairman James E. I Secretary Fred Beck sioner Public Lands and Buildin J W Chief Clerk fRANSACriONS OF BOARDS the Board of Educational Lands and Funds will bt Comrr o Public Lands and Bu rd of V.q f t r \ Jno. H. M&lt; SuptTintenden rtu alization and Public \ccounts, which will to Appro 'ory Bonds will be included in the repor </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ESTIMATED EXPENSES FOR THE OFFICE OF SECRETARY OF STATE FOR THE BIENNIUM COMMENCING APRIL I, 1913 OFFICE EXPENSES For preparing session laws for printer, copying, comparing and indexing same, stationery, b~oks, blanks, printing binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, tele - phone, shipment of laws rnd journals, furniture, repairs postage, such clerical and stenographical help as may b necessary for the recording and licensing of corporations and other office expenses $4,5( For registering letters, blank applications, blank records and issuing licenses for automobiles, 2,100.00 Total appropriation for the biennium $6,600.00 For carrying into effect the Initiative and Referendum Law. .. .6,000.00 SALARIES Secretary of State, salary, two thousand dollars $2,000.00 Four thousand dollars for the biennium $4,000.00 Salary for Deputy, eighteen hundred dollars $1,800.00 Three thousand six hundred dollars for the biennium $3,600.00 Salary of Bookkeeper, sixteen hundred dollars $1,60000 Thirty-two hundred dollars for the biennium $3,200.00 Salary of Corporation Clerk, fifteen hundred dollars $1,500.00 Three thousand dollars for the biennium $3,000.00 Salary of Recorder, one thousand dollars $1,000.00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2,000. 0q Salary of one clerk, one thousand dollars $1,000.00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2,000. 0q Salary of Stenographer and Copyist $1,000.00 Two thousand dollars for the biennium $2,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 FEES The fees received by this office for services performed during the past two years, from December 1st, 1912, to November 30th, 1914, in- clusive are as follows For filing and recording Article of Incorporation, and Certificates of Agents $ 38,310. 65 For affixir Great Seal of State, and forwarding No- tarial Commissions 1 For filing and allowing Live Stock Brand For Motor Vehicle license 511.04 For Certificates, Transcripts, Trade Marks and Labels For Corporation Permits For Corporation Penalties From all ■ M Tota VPI'ROI'KIUMOS \Mi EXPENDITURES Legislature of 1913 made the following appropriations for ce for the purposes named below : Serrettrj of State Kary (per ann &gt;ended Balance November Balu' -nber t rary (per annum, $ pended Rary (per annum $1,500.00) &gt;ended </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 .nnuni 11,600-04) $3,000.00 uded 2,375.00 OO Balance November 30th, 1914 Balance November 30th, 1914 $ 625.00 Recorder Recorder Salary (per annum $1,000.00) |2,000.00 Salary (per annum $1." 12,000.00 1.583. 3S 1.583.33 Balance November 30th, 1914 Balance November 30th, 1914 $ 416.67 Stenographer and Copyist Stenographer and Copyist Salary (per annum $1,000.00) $2,000.00 ■idetl 1,583.33 Salary (per annum $1,000.00) $2,000 Kxpended 1,58 Balance November 30th, 1914 Balance November 30th, 1914 $ 416.67 For session laws for printing, copying, comparing and indexing same, stationery, books, blanks, printing, binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, telephone, shipment of laws and jour - nals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographic help as may be necessary for the recording and licensing corporations and other office expense $4,500.00 For session laws for printing, copy ng, comparing and indexing same, stationery, books, blank printing, binding, lithographing xpress, freight telegraph, telephone, shipment of laws and jour - nals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographic help as may be necessary for the recording and licensing corporations and other office expense $4,500.00 Expended 3,713.67 Expended 3,713.67 Ealance November 30th, 1914 Balance November 30th, 1914 $ 786.33 For registering letters, blank applications, blank •rd books, seals, issuing licenses for auto - mobiles $2,100.00 rtering letters, blank applicntions, blanl record books, seals, issuing licenses for auto- mobiles $2,100.00 Expended 1,608-33 Balance November 30th, 1914 $ 491.67 Initiative and Referendum Account Appropriation $5,000.00 rected for printing arguments in pamphlet form, at $62.50 per page: May 23rd, 1914, Mr. Bigelow, Omaha, 2 pages,.. $ 125.00 June 17th, 1914, Regents University, 1 page.... 62.50 July 11th, 1914, George Coupland, In pages 625.00 July 11th, 1914, Frank Ringer, 3 pages 187.50 July 13th, 1914, Mrs. H. W. Hardy, 2 pages 125.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 July rersity Campus Ex., 25 pages. 1,5- C'rumpacker, Omaha, 2 page;;, 125.00 .Mr i nip any for printing the panvpln $ 1- 187. 50 625.00 July 21st, 1914 July 21st, 1914 July 21st. 1914 12 62.50 1* 1. 4 $2,812.50 t :e and expense in mail! M in mailing pamphlet amp! $4,891-98 . 108.02 in 812.50 Statement Areount of Account of Reri^d Statute-, tttt, Revised Statutes, 1 ■• i:s 1914, received of State Jour- jf State Jour- Binding Binding, ding 4,000 copies ing 1,000 copies 5,00&lt; ot DISTRIBUTION ISTRIBl'TION s Buckram binding, at $5. "0. .8.340.00 ather binding, at $600. .2,292.00 .&lt; ',4') mi bind nding, a $1" ' llectiona remitted to State reasurer to November 30th, 1914 ovember 30th, 1914 |l»,l id not yet paid for, 33 copies, vered to Counties and not yet paid for, 33 coj vered to State Library for Exchange, 60 cor ary for Exchange, 60 copies, t the 33rd Session of the Leg- rd Session of the L« U lature, Judges of the Courts, State Departments and mrts. State Departments and Institutions, State University, Normal and High Schools, Libraries, etc., Federal Courts, Congrr versity, Normal and High Federal Courts, Congression- itary of State at Washington, a •y of State at Washington, as )ies. law, 493 cop RECAPITULATION RECAPITULATION 2.083 copies State Library »0 copies </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 On Hand 2,364 copies Total number copies 5,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS Author- Kind of Place of Business ized when CORPORATE NAME Instru- Capn Filed Stock ment None Dec. 14 American Salvationists (The) Articles Neb. City Omaha $100,000 Jan- 1913 Atlas Investment Co. (The) Articles Alliance Creamery &amp; Pro 1913 50,000 Jan duoe Co Amend't Alliance 1913 Adams &amp; Kelly Co Articles Omaha 200,000 Jan. 1913 Atlanta State Bank Amend't Atlanta Jan. Alvo Hall Association Dissolu- 30 1913 tion Alvo Jan. American V Barrel Ma chine Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Feb. 6 Albright Institute of Social rvice Articles So. Omaha 6 Feb. Automobile Mutual Insurance 191 of Nebraska Articles Omaha 13 Feb 10,000 Feb. 1913 Aurora Printing Company irora American Lai Companj Laun dry Company Lincoln 20.000 Feb An te B erly Feb. 25 1913 Pfoples State Bank) Amend't Arn Austin-Western Rtad Machin- '"•"Mar 000 Mar es Albion Milling Company A \ Anderson. C. I,.. Tailoring C (formerlv Dresner, the Lin 1913 t ol Ailinerton Light, Heat &amp; ' Apr. 10, 1913 Power Company Art ingtt 1913 Ainsworth Light &amp; Power Co. Amend't 150.ii Automatic Time Irrigating 1913 Dam Co., Articles Mor 50,000 May American Savings Cc Loan 1913 Association Amend't Lincoln lay Amusement Park Co Articles Long Pir 13 1913 Arcadia State Bank (former- ly State Bank of Arcadia). Amend't 'Arcadia 14 May Abbott &amp; Linn Lumber Com- nissoiu tion Genoa </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 M1S( KLLAXEOl/S CORPORATIONS— (CoBtinoed) Author- Kind of place Qf ized When CORPORATE NAME i Instru- Business Capital Filed ment Stock Advance Printirg Company.. Articles 'Lincoln 10,000 Juue 100,000 June 16 m Aurora Electric Company. . . Amend't Aurora 24 mj Axtell Grain &amp; Elevator Co.. ! Amend't Axtell 50,000 Juut 10,000 Junt 191. Armitage-Olson Drug Co 'Articles ,Kearn€ American Hog Cholera Rem- edy Co (Articles Fremont 25,000 July 25.0UO Ji Arndt Blaugus Company. ... Articles Blair American Salvation Army . . Articles Beatrice July 21 1913 Antelope Telephone Co Articles Hay Spr'g 12,500 J Albion Hall Company (The) Articles Albion 4,940 Aug 21 191 Associated Retailers of Oma ha Articles Omaha 6,000 Sep 8 1913 Aspegren-Tanner &amp; Co Articles Lincoln 365,0i 25,000 Oct Allison Realty Company lArticles Omaha 17 191 Ashland Mills lArticles [Ashland 5,000 Oct Addison Telephone Company LArticIes Bloomfield 24 1913 American Hand Sewed Shoe Company Articles Omaha 150,000 Oct. 21 19 Austin (The) Irrigation Ditch Co. of Sherman County. . . . Articles Austin 10,000 Nov 10 19 Allen Bros. Co DIssolu- . tion Omaha I Nov. 10 1913 Aetna (The) Fire Extinguish- er Co lArticles Lincoln 10,00') No-. 29 1913 American BroUierhood Articles .Martell Dec. 12 1913 Axtell Investment Company. iDissolu- tion lAxtell Dec. 12 1913 Articles Amend't Dissolu - tion 40,000 Dec Eln Investment Company n-Forney Company ; Gas Construction Co. . Lincoln Harvard 12, 1913 18 1913 Der Adams Co Dec. 15 1913 American Naval Stores Co... Dissolu tion Savannah, Ga. Dec 26 1913 Alexandria Light &amp; Water Co Dissolu tion Alexandria Jan. 6 1914 Advance Printing Company (Now) Atlas Publishing Company Amend't </seg>
            <seg id="p023">i Author K AME Ii.stru- g^ Alb Pi Alb J 1 4 H Axtt And And UlU Arcs y Feb. 11 1914 1 U Feb 11 1914 F i Arti . Aim l At 1914 Artit )U! AH As Art \ rante i Acme m Dis Li! I 1 v Art I. 4 Angora State Bank Art Ang ■ Al Art May Jun« Jun« Alden M 1914 An Co. 4 15 A v. . . A An Wit) July 24 r : Amos T Kimb any. . . Artit 4 Abbf nd Grain Company Artie Abb 6,000 Aug 1 Alfalfa Land Live Stock Conrpany Articles He 150,00n Auk 50,0" 4 IS Anderson Brake Adjuster Co. Articles Watertown Auto Speedway Company (The Article Omaha 100,00. hi Oct. X American Invt ment Co Article Lincoln o? Arnstein Guar Clothing Co. (S) (for lerly Arnstein Mayer Guar Clo. Co.).... Amend't </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 MIM 'El.LA&gt;EOl'S CORPORATIONS (( imtinued) Kind of Author " CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock Anzeiger &amp; Herold Publish- nzeiger &amp; Herold Publish - ing Company Articles Grd. Islam 5,000 Oct. 28 ing Company j Articles Grd. Islant 5,000 Oct 28 1914 can Civic League (The) 'Articles Lincoln merican Civic League (The) Articles Lincoln Oi t. 27 Oct 27 1914 Auto Speedway Company uto Speedway Company (The) Amend't Omaha -Nov. 24 (The) ! Amend't Omaha Nov. 24 1914 Barber, P. T., Dental Supply wber, P. T., Dental Supply Company Articles Omaha 15,000 Dec. 7 Company Articles Omaha 15,001' Belles of the Benevolent and elles of the Benevolent and Protective Order of Camels Articles Lincoln Dec. 7 ctive Order of Camels Articles Lincoln Dec Beaton &amp; Laier Co Articles Omaha eaton &amp; Laier Co Articles Omaha 200,000 Dec. 16 200,000: Dec. 16 1912 inkers Realty Investment Bankers Realty Investment Company, General Agency Articles Omaha 10,000 Dec. 17 Company, General Agency'Articles Omaha 10,000 D-c irtlett &amp; Kling Articles Cedar Rap. Bartlett &amp; Kling Articles Cedar Rap. Iowa 40,000 Jan. 3 Iowa 40,000 Jan. 10,000 Jan. -tock Powder Co. (The) Artieta ! \&gt;b. City 10,000 Jan. 4 Stock Powder Co. (Tl Veb. City 4 1913 Becher, Hockenberger &amp; echer, Hockenberger Chambers Co An lumbus 100,000 Jan. 6 Chambers Co Article* Columbus 100,000 Jan 50,000 Jan y Garage fcfttelM Omaha 50,000 Jan. 21 ehy Garage Articles Omaha Tli.&gt; Four Live Stock ig (The) Four Live Stock on Company Articles So. Omaha " Jan. 29 Commission Company \rticles So. Omaha Jan 1 ton State Bank Amend't iBrayton rayton State Bank Amend't &gt;Brayton in. 29 eatrice Steel Tank Mfg. Co. Amend't Beatrice 'eb. 1 Fob Beatrice Steel Tank Mfg. Co.lAme&amp;d't Beatric 191 Banner Telephone Company uiner Telephone Company of Thomas County, Nebr.. . Articlf. Seneca 2,000 Feb. 1 2,000 Pet 1 1 Kuran Lumber &amp; Coal Company | Amend't Omaha hi Fel 25,000 Pel Benson Ice &amp; Coal Company . | Amend't Bens-on 17 191 Bar-Five Ranch Dissolu- tion [Valentine Feb 24 1913 Brownville State Bank i Articles Brownvillf -' Bank of Logan County Articles Candy I Mar. 25,00i 20.000 Mar. 50,0nn Mar - 10,000 Mar - 25.000 Mar - 10,000 Mar. 25,000 Mar. B. &amp; L. Company \rticles Fafrbury Byrnes Shoe Company Articles Lincoln -Christensen Realty Co. ;Amend't Omaha Brown Land &amp; Loan Company Articles Superior e, W. W.. Company .... Articles No. Platte Boyd Engraving Company. . Articles Lincoln Blanchard Aerial Works .... Articles jOmaha Boelus Mercantile Company Dissolu- tion Boelus Mar. 25 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 MISCELLANEOUS CORPOR\TIO&gt;iS— (Continued) Kind of j AUth " r - CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed men • st. Belmont &amp; Northern Trac - tion Company Articles Lincoln Mar. 26 1 Belmont &amp; Northern Trac tion Arti Arti Mar Company Bennet Opera House Company Art nnet Apr. 8 ] Hi Opera House Company 1 Apr met Bums, Jay Baking Company (The) uiha Apr. 9 : Bums Jay Baking Company maha Bourgeois Company (The) . . Amend't Omaha 50,000 Apr. 14 : ny (The).. \n Omaha 50,uou Apr 14 VjU Brunswick (The) Hotel Co. .'Articles Brunswick 10,000 Apr. 28 1 ISr Brunswick 10,000 Apr Bone-McLucas Lumber Co., (formerly D. C. Bone Co.) Amendt Fairbury j Ma: B. Fairburj May Bank of Union Amend't Union &gt; 14: Amend't Union May 14 1913 Burns, Jay The, Baking Co. .'Amend't Omaha May 16 ] av The, Baking Co. . 'Amend't |Omaha 15( 1913 Hankers' Realty Investment; Company i Amend't Omaha Ba ompany 'Amend't lOmaha Ma Burton State Bank Burton Byron-Clow &amp; Company... Omaha "June 3 Burton State Bank Articles Burton Byron-Clow &amp; Company. .. JArt Omah June Boyd Engraving Company mpany tion Lincoln Juip ti Line Jin 1 u A Thorne Company.. Amend't loi&gt; Thorne Company. .Amend't i t »1 I! lvhlere Coal &amp; Lumber Co. A lvidere » June 11 &amp; Lumber Co )Ji Kw Lumber Company Lumber Company tion June 11 Jur Jur tion I'Jshaw }u Telephone Company.. Articles l)ix Artie any x Burt County Agricultural B ciety Vrtic •'. Im. r Co., (The) al So- V 1 \ Baker Construction Company Amend ; traction Company A Beatrice Burial Vault Co Artie! \r trice j Bi-nell-.Tones Concrete !' ing Co Articles Lincoln lOO.OOn July Jones Concrete Pll- Art ncoln i &gt; July B gelow Manufacturing Co. . Artie &gt;ln y 2 ring Co. . Art Blue Springs Drug &amp; M&gt; cantile Co Article • July 14 B!m&gt; Springs Drug &amp; Mer- . . . jArtli * July 100,000 July 14 1013 Burlington Investment Co. . .Articles Dodge 100,000 July 14 Artie Dodge B n Investment Co. e Be r River Lumber Company Disso! Be r River Lumber Company Dissolu- tion Lincoln 'July 16 tion Lincoln 'Julv 1 f Agricultural Fair Articles Fremont 10,000 July 18 Big 4 Agricultural Fair Articles ;Fremont 0 July B il'antyne. Cleland &amp; Percy Articles Norfolk 25,000 July 30 Norfolk ■ July 30 1913 Blaee Company (The) Articles Sholes 25,000 July 31 ' July 31 1913 Sholes Bman. Sturge* Shoe Co.. Articles Omaha 10.000 Aug. 7 Articles Omaha 10.000 Aug nell Grain Company Articles |Bushnell 10,000 Aug. 12 Articles Bushnell </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 MISCELLANEOUS ( OKl'OKA II O» -(( ontinaed) Author Kind of Place of ized Business Capital Wher CORPORATE NAME Instru- n inent Stock Burns. Jay The, Baking Company i Amend t Omaha 17&gt;,0O0Aug. 23 1 Belmont Water Users' As- sociation Articles Bridgeport 20,000 Aug. 25 191i Bodman-McConaughy Co. ... Articles Holdrege 100,000 Sept. 22 191 Bradbrook-Saunders Co. ...Dissolu- tion 7 191 Britt Lyceum and Chautau- qua System Articles Lincoln 25,000 O Bey Clothing Company. . Articles Omaha 15,000 Oct 18 1913 d-Rancho Company ...Articles Omaha 40,000 Oct. 27 1913 Buffalo bounty Agricultural Association ! Articles [Kearney 25,000 Oct. 29 lii 1 Bullock Machine &amp; Supply CoArticIes Norfolk 25,000 Oct. 29 1!&lt; lau State Bank Articles Breslau 25,000 N&lt; Basket Stores Investment Co. Articles |Lincoln 100,000 Nov. 18 Beaton &amp; Laier Co Amend't iOmaha Nov. 20 191 Ben way A. D- Co Amend't Lincoln 200,000 Dec. 2 191 Bemis, Geo. P., Inc Articles Omaha 25,000 Dec. 4 191 Brodegaard Jewelry Stores Inc Articles Omaha 200,000 Dec 22 1H1 Burgess &amp; Woodward Thea- tre Co lAmpnd't Omaha Brainard-Carpenter Co llMssoh t:on Omaha Jan. I Bheit-O'Loughlin Co. (for rly Sondermann Furni ture and Undertaking Co.) Amend't Gr. Island Jan. 3 1914 10,000 Jar ian Insurance Agency. . 'Articles Omaha 1914 Barr C. C. Lumber Co iDissolu tion Benkelman Jan. 10 1914 Bank of Bromfield Amend't Gtltner Jan 26 1914 Bennet Farmers Elevator Co. De-Co-Op Bennet Feb. 10 1914 Bourgeois (The) Company. J Amend't Omaha Feb. 16 1914 Buck Printing &amp; Publishing Coiwpany Articles : Newman Grove 10,000 Feb Bilz-Schneider-Baum Co- . . Articles Omaha 25.000 Feb 19 1914 200,000 Feb 27 1914 Brodegaard Jewelry Stores. . Amend't Omaha Bias Construction Company. Articles Chicago 5,000 Mar 5 1914 I </seg>
            <seg id="p027">iior- k' CORPORATE NAME Instru- f*"j" of en \\ ment us Dess Filed y Stock Billings Dental Supply Co., BM Supply Co »rmerly Billings Marshall ital Supply Co Amend't Omaha Place Mercantile Co. . . Dissolu- apply Co Amend't Omaha Place Mercantile Co... D tion Farman ' Mai Ma Bethphage Inner Mission As - sociation Ar \tell Bethphage Inner Mission As- ArticU M Bohemian Catholic Gymnastic and Benevolent sokol Articles Omaha | Mar- 24 Ho nastu Art Mar Apr Black Ranch Company Articles Thedford ; 1,000,000 Apr. 7 Black Ranch Company Articles Thedford ; 1 y Baker Manufacturing Co Amendt Omaha .... Apr Baker Manufacturing Co.... Amend't Omaha -t \p Big Springs Mercantile Co. . . An Apr. II Big Springs Mercantile Co. .. Amend Apr. 1 Bolstein Company (The J. H.) Articles So. Sioux Bolstein Company (The J. H.) City 10,0' Brown Fruit Company (The) Art nd Is'd Brown Fruit Company (Th&gt; ( Beaver Valley Telephone Co. Ai i Beaver Valley Telephone Co. Art Baum and Company &gt;lu- Baum and Company D tion I-'-n I May I !) May Bank of Unadilla lilla Bank k of Unadilla Bruner (T. J.) Company. ... Art .aha Bniner (T. J.) Company. ... Articles Omaha par Bank of Burchard Amend't I.urchard ' June II Bank of I Amend rd ' June 16 Business Men's Protect: Assn of Omaha (The) Articles Oi Protective Bus M A-s \rt Bank of Prague Amend't Trasrue rraeue 4 Am« Brock Mercantile Company. . Dissolu- Brock ft any. . Di tion Brock Bro&lt; tior Bergers Investment Co Articles On Bereers I Art Or Blue Taxi Company (former - ly Her Grand Taxi Co.)... Amend't Omaha Blue Taxi Company (former- Omaha ly Her Grand Taxi Co.)... Amend .1 Bloomington Equity Exchange Articles F.looni July II Bloomington Equity Exchange Art July 15 Bank of Henderson (The) . . . Articles Henderson ; Bank of Henderson (The) . . . Articles Henderson ; 20.0 Aue Bank of Henderson Amend't Henderson Au- Bank of Henderson Amend't Henderson Ai. Burr Incubator Co Articles Omaha 5,0ft" Aug. Burr Incubator Co. Art Omaha Aug. 8 1 Bignell Piling Company (for - merly Bignell — Jones Con - crete Piling Co.) Amend't Lincoln Aug. 1 ! Bignell Piling Company (for - merly Bignell — Jones Con- crete Piling Co.) Amend't Lincoln Aue- 1 7 Butler County State Bank . . Amend't David City Aug. 1 Butler County State Bank .. Amend't David City Aug. 12 1&lt;M4 Burkett and Leslie Company Dissolu- Burkett and Leslie Company Dissolu- tion Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- CORPORATE NAME Klnd ol Place of Business ized When Instru- Capital Filed Stock Bankers Realty Investment Company Amend't Omaha ept 14 iyi4 Burton Lumber and Grain Co. (The) pissolu- tion Burton Oct. Bank of Danbury Amend't Danbury Oct. 12 1914 Beatrice Egg Tester &amp; Pack- ing Co Articles Beatrice 10,00 Oct. 17 1914 Benevolent Turners Tyrs No 1 of Omaha Ai tides Omaha Nov. 14 1914 Beatrice Baler Company .... Ai tides Eeatrice Co-operative Orchard Co Amend't Omaha 15,0 Nov 1M4 ■0 10 Dec. 5 1H12 Colling, W. G. Company ... .|Ai tides iOmaha 25,0Ud Die. 10 1912 11.1 Carlson Review Company (The) Articles 'Norfolk Dec 21 1 Catlin, W. J. Company Articles Omaha 10,00 ns State Bank lAmend't Wahoo Feb j l Capital (The) Tent &amp; Awn ing Co. of Lincoln lArticles Lincoln H Fel i Citizons State Bank nd't Butte i Conservative Trust Company Dissolu- tion Lincoln l I Campbell Soil Culture Pub- lishing Co 'Articles Lincoln H !Hi:s Carter Lake Club (formerly Omaha Rod &amp; Gun Club. .Amend't Omaha M &amp; McKenzie Printing Company Articles Omaha M «hton Lumber Company Articles Creighton Apr 9 Columbus Fuel &amp; Storage Company Articles j Columbus "t Apr i Consumer's Syndicate (The) Articles Omaha 500,000'Apr. 19 Coit G. Campbell, *nc Articles Omaha 5,000 Apr. 22 Coakley Overall Laundry and Supply Company Articles Omaha ,000 Apr. JM May 2K ltl Clowry Court Grocery Co. .. Articles Omaha Cartercar Nebraska Company Articles .Omaha SI 25,000 May Crystal Lake Park Company Articles So. Sioux C 50,000 June 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS- (Continued) Kind of Aulhor - Author- Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- PlaCe of Ued When Instru- Placeof Ued When CORPORATE NAME ment : Business Capital pa , u Business Capital nan j ment v v*\\&amp; Stock Stock Columbus Commercial Col - lege A r ticl» ■ "J 191&lt;s al Col- Columbus Commer lege 14 191 A»"ticl Central National Life Insur - ance Co. (formerly Central National Life Association) A Tin . t Liijcoln Central National L ance Co. (former National Life As Insur- y Central ociation) Amen Lincoln Covina Land &amp; Improvement Co 1 ' Ills u tion Lincoln Jui Lincoln June tion Citizens State Bank A; '.val 15,000 July Citizens State Bank 15,000JJuly 75,000 lu.y Central Investment Company Artie. &gt;ln 10,090 July ! Central Investment Company Article 11 Country Club, or Lincoln .... Amen, it Lincoln 75,000 Ju.y i Country Club, of Lincoln .... Ai ncoln Colclesser Mercantile Com - pany Article 10,000 July . in, mm July 1 Chesapeake Restaurant Com - pany Dissolu- I p: tion [Omaha . July II July it; tior ■ton Blaugas Company... Artie Blauiras Company. . . Article Crosby Company IUssulu- , Cro pany i tion Lincoln (ulj I L.IK t Contractors Construction Company 10.ni&gt;.. July l\ Columbia Life Insurance Company Anund't Fn mont Chase E. M Conn&gt;aii'&gt; Lincoln ir Bank Farm . . Dis.-olu- tion Yort \ tion Co-operative Stor n ' Co- (formerly Int Land &amp; Development &lt; nd t Ob 14 lvl Co-operative St( Inters Land &amp; Development Co... Amend! \ I Capital Tent A Awnii, pany u- tion Lincoln Clark. Zoro D., Incorporateri Articles Omaha Clark. Zoro D.. Incorporat' Carson. J. C. Cattle Company Dissolu- Carson. J. C. Cattle Company Dissoli on Irwin Irwin tion Clarkson Milling and Grain Co Articles Clark- Clarkson Milling and Grain Clarkson Co SArtic Cathroe (H. J.) Co. . Articles Ommha Cathroe (H. J.I Co Artie Citizens Hotel Co \metri t Commercial State Bank . . . Article </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS- (Continued CORPORATE NAME Tnstru- P ' ac f of * zed , **" Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru Business Capital Filed ment ment Stock atctel Club of Omaha. Amend't Omaha 150,000 Nov. 1 ercial Club of Omaha. Aniendt Umaha 150 .\ ty State Bank (Articles Sutton Mate Bank Articles ,Sutton 30,00u Nov. 14 li»13 Reynolds Company Articles iFrimont m Nov. 1. r Constructiou Co... aha 100,000 Nov. 24 )v No Reynolds Company Article hi Nov. J. .instruction Co Artiel Omaha K.tou, John A., Home tor r Working Girls .,, Jolin A., Home I r Working Girls &gt;aha ... 4 191o Articl Omaha 4 ■ Trust Company (iormer- City Trust *i Safe Depos- Trust Company (torui' ■ ,, Aiut-nd't Omaha l.uou.ooo Dec. II it Co Amend't Omaha t 1,01 Dec (D. F.) Furuit ire Co. • U. F.) Furuit ire Co. - Omaha Art Oniah Dec- Jan Telephone. Company . . Amend't ( rete 160.000 Jan. 9 li»14 phone Company 1 t Cr« ms (The) Creamery Co.lDisBoll ius (The) Creamery Co. Di^solu- Cadams Jan. 14 lyl4 J;u tioi :on W. J. Co iArticles Omaha on W. J. Co aha &amp; Northwestern Railway Equipment Trust .■go &amp; Northwest* •; Railway Equipment Tri. of 191C Chicago Jan. 14 Ial4 of 191C Ji 14 l'J14 cago Chalco Elevator Company... Amend't CLalco ©Jan. 22 1914 Amen i Chalco - 1914 Chalco Elevator Company t Crawford Telephone Co Articles Copenhagen 1,000 Jan. 26 1914 1,000 Jan. 26 It Crawford Telephone Co Articles jCopenhag 6 1L&lt;14 Capital Fire Insurance Com - . Amend't Lincoln Feb. 2 1914 ] Drug Company Articles Omaha 10,000 Feb. 4 1914 1 Saving Institute of tlia Amend't Omaha Feb. 13 1914 .■ns (The) State Bank . . Articles Superior Bank Amend't Wood Lake Hank Amend't Cashing Feb. 1 Capital Fire Insurance Com- . Amend't iLincoln F. :ss Articles Omaha 1 lol Drug Company t Child Saving Institute of 14 1914 1 Mill Ft .. Fe Amend't Cushing as Lumber &amp; Supply Co :mber &amp; Supply C . - Chester 10" Articles 10 tie, Roper &amp; Matthews .. Articles Lincoln 100,000 Feb. 20 1914 ing Farm &amp; Cattle Co... Articles Kearney 50,000 Mar. 4 1914 Articles Linct Articles ing Farm &amp; Cattle Co Kearney M o Crounse preamery Company. Articles Crounse r. 25 1914 Crounse preamery Company Articles Crounst r 25 1914 Coleson (The) Swanson Com - pany Articles Concord ir. 28 1914 (The) Center Gr;. Company jArticles Clay Center 20,000 Apr. 1 1914 Coleson (The) Swanson Com pany Articles Concord Clay (The) Center Grain Company [Articles Clay Center 20,ono Apr. 1 1914 Carlson Review Company ..i Dissolu- tion ''Norfolk ADr 7 Apr Collins (S. L.) Oil Company of Nebr 'Articles I Neb City 100.00ft Apr- 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 MIM Kl.l.WhOI S (ORPOKVII"\s I &lt;m tinned i \ Kir M 1 Ail I M c 14 Ma I Lin tio t 4 « T V ( Centi ti ly \t f 14 Dis Or Ar Omaha W nd't On t. Ar panj RPORA Instru- Incort </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Business Place of ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME Instru ment Stock Cavers - Sturtevant Company (formerly Cavers Elevator Co.) Omaha July Amend't Articles Articles ns State Bank Citizens State Bank Ce.ar Rap Diller 25,000 July 50,000 July Co-operative Co. (The) of Pilger Articles Articles Pilger Omaha I',",, Kill) Aug 100,000 Aug Corn-Falfa Mills (Central National Life Ins. Co- Lincoln, Nebr Lincoln Chadron All.;. 24 1914 M l,li Amend't Articles Chadron Garage Company Cottonwood Farm and Cattle Company Dissolu - tion V. olbacli St»pt Chaney-Hunter-Royer Com- P»ny Dissolu - tion Omaha Oct Coates Lumber and Coal Articles Dissolu - tion No. Platte Company Cloverdale Realty Company Omaha Pierce Oct. Oct. 14 Articles Citizens State Bank fsrence Claimants the Nebr. Conf of the M Church Amend't Oct. Colored Progressive Republi - can Club (The) Nov Articles Articles Omaha On^aha 4 ago Liquor House 10.004 Nov Dissolu - tion Colling Company (W. G.) Omaha Nov 1 Duncan-Hesseltine Fruit and Nursery Company Articles Peru ii Dec 10 191 Douglas Manufacturing Corn- 10,00 Articles Crete 1 David City Artificial Ice Co. . Articles David City 1)( iini 3 1»13 Douglas Hotel Company ... Articles Omaha '00 Jan Drexel Shoe Company Amend't Oiraha 0 Jan Dawes County Alfalfa Growers Association Articles Chadron Jan 23 191 Dillehay. M K. Luii 1 Jan pany Waterloo 31 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">&gt;II*( K1.L WfcOl &gt; ( OKI'OKVHO&gt;&gt; &lt;&lt; ill IATE -\ A ■:i« ctr t &amp; I tion Om t'or Co ) Ibc Formerly Formerly athaway. Omaha mbins Company Articles Omaha J pstment Company Omaha Ff 'il Company Articles McCook Club Artiolps Omaha 1914 Oouslas Shoe Store Articles Omaha Apr. II </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 rtr-irUrC F (Jr ixit SKCKETARi OF isTA.Tfe* MlSCELLASEOl'S CORPORA TIOSS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME ment Stock KR.) Deputy Company irmerly Deputy-Ester - ok Co Amend't Lincoln li»14 IU1 Uentnan Grain and Lumber Articles Articles Den in an Gibbon 10 Juin iyi4 DeWolf Mercantile Company 10,000 JUiu 1914 Drainage District No. One of Frontier County. Nebraska Amend't Stockville Junt 16 1M4 Dierks Lumber A; Coal Com- P»ny Amend't dissolu - tion Lincoln 0 July 15*14 I&gt;or8ey Grain Co. (J. E.) Cordova July Kage District No. 4. of lardson County, Nebras- Articles Humbolt . July 4 1914 En-Spelts Lumber Com - y (Formerly Worten - e Lbr. Co.) Amend't Ulysses July 15 1914 Ers Cattle Loan Com - y (Formerly The Atlas Company) Amend't Omaha Aug. 15 1914 Dixon County Agricultural Society Articles Articles Concord Omaha 5,000 Aug. 10,000 Oct. II 1914 Druid Hall Company Detroit Automatic Scale Com- Articles Detroit ,Mch 100,000 Nov. 2% 1914 pany Elmick (The) Realty Com - pany Articles Omaha 50,000 Jan. 15 1913 Eddy Standard Mirror Glass Company Articles Lincoln 50.000 Mar. 8 Eva Lang Theatrical Com- Articles Dissolu - tion Omaha 10,000 Mar. 27 Eagle Hall Co. Neb. City June 7 1913 Korn Valley Irrigation mpany Dissolu - tion O'Neill June 23 1913 Eldorado State Bank Articles Eldorado 10,000 June 23 1913 Empress Garden (Incorporat ed) Articles Omaha 80,000 July 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 35 Mlttt'ELLAJflOUH lOKl'OKVlIO.NS— (toatinued) Author Kairt of ot ized Bush ipital When CORPORATE NAME Instru led iuent Stock -n Omnibus a Transfe ompany Lincoln i July Is Ewing Live Stock Sales Coru- Articles Ewing &gt;00 July m (The) Nebraska 1 Fruit Growei uioii Articles Neb. City "" Aug. Jo 1913 Ic Garage Company Articles Fremont - 1»13 Building Association. Articles Beatrix ■&gt; Sept. 18 1H1J - Mercantile ( Articles Eustis ion Oct. 9 191J Klkhorn Valley State Bank Articles Stanton W)0 Nov. 12 1913 Manufacturing Company Articles David City OHO Nov. ;■ Hddyville Garage Assn Articles Eddyville iOO Nov. 29 1913 Eclipse Realty Compan Dissolu- tion Omaha Jan. 10 Electric Garage Co. of Lin- coln, Nebr Articles Lincoln 0 Jan. 10 Electrical Specialties Mfg Dissolu- tion Omaha Jan. 12 :;;: Erton (J. W.i &amp; Company Articles Eeatrice 10,000 Jan. 29 El (ana Land &amp; Plantation Dtaaoln tlon Grand Is Feb 21 s Kim wood State Bank Articles Elm wood 0 Apr. 50,000 May I 13 Eagles Building Company Articles Lincoln 7 Endicott Equity Exchange Articles Endicott 23 Edward E. Gustin 6 Co Dissolu tion Lincoln June Elwood Shipping Association (The) Articles Elwocd ' June 19 Eldridge Brokerage Company (O. W.) Articles Omaha 10,000 July 28 Ernst Fischer Lumber Com- pany Articles Platte Cen 21 Elmer E. Thomas Company (The) Articles Omaha Oct. 5 Enevoldsen Land Company . . Dissolu tlon St. Paul Not. 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">MiM ELLANEOl'S ( UKl'OKA TH»S -(( ontinued) uthor Kind of CORPORATE NAME &lt;ru- Place ol J Wli Dissc u Eldor UU tioi; Farmers Farms Company . Articles Omal Hickm liana Art if Bruni ,1), .v Merchants Bank \i t Fostt • in Hi- Building ( onipan Aniei j't Floren I)( (The) of Nebraska Art Farmers' Grain Association Kin Jan i (i Jan d ants Ban ('•i Impf Ja PI aim v. N. \ni( Fen Fe\ Schuv 191 Feb Articles Omaha 4 191 rs' State Bank Newcastle F( 1 :er Accident Insurance Company An Lincoln 100,000 Feb 000 Feb 19 131 Kltvator Company Articles UK Trust Company Articles in Feb Farmers' Mercantile Com Articles Lew pany Farmers. Creamery Company Articles • !apiti Kldorado Lumber k Ura First Slate Bank Artk Flatiron (The) I'ompam Artk 40,01 Farmers k Merchants Bank ity Life drain A: Live StOC (Thei Ait BLuml .rain o (Formerly : *■ umber and Supph iny Grain ifc Stock ( i: Union r Grain Fraternal (The) Five Hun- dred Arti&lt; Lmip ( </seg>
            <seg id="p037">At w Art Arti.l. 11 \\ Jut Till Ar npany An h D P: Fa Company tlon Li July II K SECRETARY Ol MIS( Kl.l.WMM S &lt; ORI'OKU1O&gt;S ( oBtii n. 1913 l.inor </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS (Continued) Author- Place of ized When Business j Capital Filed Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru ment Stock 16 Pillmore Blaugas Company . Articles Geneva 25,000 July Farmers' State Bank of "^ Union Articles Union 50,000 July 19 Farmers' Grain Company ..Dissolu- tion Wann July 30 1913 25,000 July 30 First State Bank Articles Lodge Pole Farmers' National Co-oper- ative League Articles Joplin, Mo. Aug. 4 1913 Farmers' Elevator Company Articles Silv'r Creek 25,000 Aug. 13 1913 8,000 Aug. 14 1913 Eers' Union Elevator Co. Articles Abdal ers' Exchange of Homer Articles Homer ers' Co-operative Union Articles Verdel 50,000 Aug. 14 1913 25,000 Aug. 21 1913 Farmers' State Bank Articles Marquette 80,000 Auk 23 I'M Kess Caster Company merly of Nebraska City, Nebr.) Amend't Evansvtlle, Ind- Aug. 30 1913 Farmers' State Bank Articles Stockham 15,000 sept. 15 1913 Fremont Kennel Club Articles Fremont 100 Sept. 20 1913 Kers' Mutual Insurance . of Scotts Bluffs Coun- ty Articles Scotts Bluff Sept 24 Fillmore County Telephone Co resolu- tion Bept 24 •&gt; i First State Savings Bank . . Articles York Farmers' (The) Elevator Co. Articles Sholes 25,000 Oct. 25.000 Oct. R Farmers' (The) Union Co- operative Association. .... Articles Verdi gre 10.000 Oct U Farmers' &amp; Merchants' State 25,000 Oct Bank Articles Salem fi Farmers' Union Co-operative 20,000 Oct. 28 Assn Articles Yutan Farmers' State Bank of Sil ver Creek Articles Silv'r Creek 100.000 Nov. 14 Farmers' Co-operative Cream ery Co. Articles Wolbach 10.000 Nov. 15 Fanners' Co-operative Mer cantile Co Articles Scribner 25,000 Nov. 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 39 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Place of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME Instru- ment Parmer8' (The) Elevator Co. of Nebraska City, Nebras- Articles I issolu - tion Fremont Canal &amp; Power Co Farmers' Mutual Telephont IMssolu tion. Fidelity Investm Pissolu - tion Francitas Canning a. I serving Cc Articles Articles resolu - tion Frogan Investment Company Farmers' Plow Company . . . Farmers' Grain &amp; Stock ( tion Fontenelle Forest Associatior Fry-Rosenzweig Company . . . Articles tion '1 Farmers' &amp; Merchants' State Bank Amend Declar; tion Farmers' Grain Company Co-op. Declar tion. Farmers Bus Co-op Farmers' Elevator &amp; Shipping Article Farmers' Independent Ship ping Assn Declar tion Kers 1 Hog &amp; Cattle Pow- Co Amend't Kers' Co-operative Hail urance Co. Article </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 VIMCELLANEOUS I OKFOKATJONS-M onti Kind of Am RPORATE NAME lnstru- Place ot vV!ien , n ,, nt Business Capr File! Fi Farmers' Co-operativ,- Assn. of Brule Articles Brule 10,000 Feb. 2 1914 Farmers' Co-operativ, Feb 1914 Firmer*' Inion Elevator Co. a &gt; &gt; Feb. 3 1914 Feb. 1914 Fawn Lake Ranch Co Amend t Kushville Feb. 4 1914 Feb 4 1914 Farmers' Lumber and II Farmers' Lumber and Hav Armies Stuart Hi Feb. 14 1914 p Feb 14 1914 Fr"inont Ladies' Relief So- &gt; .nt . . i:&lt;14 Union .Milling :l Co Ar: &gt;0 .Mar. 9 1914 m ii Co, lliiiM &lt;v ii Ma 14 tile (. Pany (The i Mercaotlle Cob- P ;l »y kri 10 Mar I Ma h'ar: Artie: ir. 1" l!»14 Articl Artk-1 Bank Article* Hender 15,( Mar. ! Henderw Investment I Mar. 13 1914 Artie Artie Mar. 13 1914 O kts' Grain Co ArttelM Qaninofl '"Mar. 1 Mar. 20 1M14 Garr Farmers' (The) Union I tion Article! i i Mar. 24 1H14 \rt Mar 24 1914 ■otir Tire .'v: Rubber I Foral Brothers &lt; Formerly Foral &amp; Kuncl) Far: te Bi Amen ■ vnd't Omaha 1!U4 it ( 4 IBank . Imendi Wynot . &gt;r. 27 1914 \i Wvi U I M:tr H 1HU tile Assn. (Formerl; \ssii i Formerly :d't DebllnR Apr. 4 1914 A ("o-opeiat ion of Page. . on of Pag&gt; Paep I Apr \ rt Pne Apr TM4 n' rnion Co-op«rat i- of Tals unty. Xebr. Articles Talmaee 10 ADr. 13 1914 Articles Talma Apr 13 1914 Farmers' I'nion Association Bloomfield Articles Bloomfield Articles [nman 900 Apr 1914 Farmers' smte Bank (The) 20 1914 Kont Creamery Company Amend't Omah Apr 1914 Article! </seg>
            <seg id="p041">K Farmers' Co-operative C pany of Fullerton. Net </seg>
            <seg id="p042">x\tti UKT Of I HL oE/L/XvEi lAKi Vr 31 Alh 42 MISt'ELLA.MEOI/S COKPOKATHhNS— (Continued) Author- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Kind of CORPORATE NAME InBtru- ment Stock Fanners' Educational and Co-operative State Union of Nebraska Articles Ot Neb. July 13 1914 Fremont State Bank (Form erly Fremont Savings Bank) Amend't Fremont July 13 1914 Farmers' State Bank, Polk Xebr Articles Polk 3o,iMio July IT »14 Farmers' Union Co-operative Company of North Bend, Nebraska Articles North Bend 25,000 July 1914 Farmers' Co-operative Mer - cantile Company of Leigh Nebraska Articles Leigh 25,000 July 1914 Farmers' State Bank of Sunol (The) Articles Sunol 16.000 July Farmers' Elevator Assoria tion Articles Stamford in. unit Aug. M, &gt; Aug. 11 r. Farmers' State Bank Articles Clarks 11 Farmers' Co-operative Com pany Articles Eldorado 2(i. mm Sept ;::: Farmers' Society (The) . . . Articles Shelby 500 Sept Fred Underwood Stoker Company Articles Omaha lo. 01111 Sept Farmers' Grain and Live Stock Co. (The) Articles Glenw'd P'k in. 000 Sept Farmers' Co-operative Asso- ciation Articles Vallev 0 Sept z Farmers' Grain &amp; Supply Co. Amend't Atlanta Sept g Farmers' Lumber &amp; Grain Company Amend't Kimball Sept. 12 1914 Ferguson Land and Live- stock Co Articles Wood Lake 250,000 Sept 25.000 Sept 28 2S ;::: Farmers' State Bank Articles Overton Farmers' Union Co-opera - tive Assn. of Memphis, Ne- braska (The) Articles Memphis 20.000 Oct. 2 Farmers' Union Co-operative Assn Plssolu tion VerdiRTP , . . Oct. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 43 WMKMULUamm &lt; 'UftPOKATIOXS (CoatiBw*) Author - ized Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- PlaCe of ized VVhen Place of Business When CORPORATE NAME Instru- ™* n . Business Capital Filed Capital Filed Stock ment Stock Frank Underwood Car - buretor Co Articles Omaha 10,00" Oct 15 1914 Kk Underwood Car - etor Co Articles Articles Omaha First State Bank Articles North Bend 60,000 Oct 24 1914 First State Bank North Bend Farmers' Union Elevator Assn. (The) Articles Hardy "Nov. 3 1914 Hardy 500 Nov. Biers' Union Exchange of rtington. Nebraska Articles Articles Hartington Hoskins ,000 Nov 16 1914 Fanners' State Bank E Pentecostal Church of • Nazarene of Hastings, braska Hasting Omaha 27 1914 37 1912 10 1913 Articles Articles Nov Gate City Furniture Company 60,00* 10,000 Jan Garvin Bros. &amp; Bollard Articles Omaha Garden County Produce As - sociation (The) Leweller Omaha 10,000 Ian 10,000 Jan 14 1913 15 1913 16 1913 Articles Articles Articles Gate City Wall Paper Co Grand Island Brewing Co Gr. Island 100,000 Jan German Savings &amp; Loan As - sociation Articles Beatrice Feb. 8 1913 Garfield Cattle Company .... Dlseolu tion Superior Feb 10 1913 Grand Island Business Col- lege ... Articles Gr. Island 300.00 10 1913 Grand Lodge of the Benevo- lent Or&amp;tr of Beavers Articles Gal- 111 Mar Good Samaritans of the World Articles Lincoln Mar Gilinsky Fruit Company .... Articles Omaha 75,000 Mar Guarantee Fund Life Assn.. Amend't Omaha Mar 10 1913 Grand View Orchards &amp; Vine- yards Company Amend't Lincoln Mar 17 1913 Gate City Tent &amp; Awning Co. (formerly Nebraska Tent &amp; Awning Co.) Amend't Omaha Mar Guarantee Fund Life Assn.. Amend't On aha Mav Globe Van &amp; Storage Co.... Articles Omaha 10.000 May Gordon Fire Proof Ware- house &amp; Van Company... Amend't Omaha 75.000 May 50.000 May 15 1913 15 1913 21 1913 Gordon -McDowell Company — Articles Omaha Grand Island Brewing Co... Amend't Gr. Island 200.000 May </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 MISCELLANEOUS COBPORA.TIOM8 — (Continued) .Authcr- Kiud of CORPORATE NAME Instru- Fhl \\ Cfc| ni en t • Construction Company Articles Omaha 10,000 Ma Uuthrit; &amp; Company Amend't Superii 30,000 July 7 191 Lin-American Bank Build on Articles York 50,000 July 14 191 Gage County Blaugas. Com- pany Articles Beatric 25,000 July 16 lai Grand Island Blaugas Com- Articles Ur. Island 50,000 Julj 16 Glenville - Inland Telephone ation Dissolu tion Hasting July 17 191J Gray Mercantile Company. . Articles Columbi 000 Aug 191 nburg Light &amp; Power Conrpany i . tion Got 130,000 July 26 191 Gothenburg Irrigation Com- Dissolu Pany tion Gothenbur Pt an Samaritan Hospital ■'tion Articles Omaha Germantown Light &amp; Pow C° Articles Germant'n 191 Bd Isla.:d Furniture &amp; dertaking Co Dissolu tion Qr. Islai i)t i 25,000 Oct Grant County State Bank.... Articles Ashbv 1913 in American Printing and Publishing Co Articles N'ebr. City 10.000 Nov. 8 1913 (The) Tire &amp; Rubber Co-&gt; Articles Omaha 20.000 I)« 15 1913 Galbraith Nurseries Dif solu tion Fairburv Dec 16 1913 Garffeld «• Red Cloud Tel Co., Articles Rei Cloud 2,500 Dec 50,000 Jan 22 1913 15 1914 • n American Bank Articles Deshler Gruettli Telephone Company Dissolu tion ;ncan Jan. 19 1914 Oaly Sons Company \rticles Gordon 25,000 Jan. 24 1914 Gorman Supply Company... Articles Lincoln 100,000 Jan 26 1914 Ooehner Elevator Co. on </seg>
            <seg id="p045">\ pply t A \r At H. On l.Of Flint Company .... Vrticles Omt Jan v Hein Brothers Tonvpanv .... Vrticles f« I! -lome Investment and Ton Jan. 14 19 JUMKI.I. \\H»l * ( t»KI &gt; OKAH(»NN &lt; in nueih ste Bank Articles Oma struction Company V 'in. 14 of David ird Rpalty Company.. \ r ;:aha 50,00i' Jan. 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Place of ized When Business Capital Fiied CORPORATE NAME Instru- ment Stock Harry's Shoe Shop Articles Lincoln Omaha &gt; Jan. 25,000 Jan. 50,000 Feb. 20,000 Feb. 25,000 18 I Hopper Bros- Company Articles is He nsen Products Company.. Articles St. Louis Lakeside West Point 12 Harris-Crowther Company.. Articles 24 Home Lumber Co. (The) . . . Articles Hippodrome Amusement Com- pany Articles Omaha Lincoln 50.000 Mar. 18 1913 House ct David of the World Articles Apr. 9 1913 Herman Telephone Company I (The) Articles Herman Fairbury No. Platte Kalston 10.M0 Apr. 100,000 A-pr. 14 H. W. M. Company Articles 17 Howe &amp; Maloney Articles 12,000 Apr. 300,000 May 24 Howard Stove Works Amend't 1 H&amp;ger Candy Company Amend't Hastings 0 May 24 Harris, The Sarah Fisk Me- morial Home Association.. Articles Lincoln DeWitt Omaha 700 May 29 1913 Home State Bank Amend't June 4 1913 Hayward Brothers Shoe Co. Amend't June 7 1913 Howells (The) Milling Com- pany Articles Howells June 7 1913 i Hornaday, The C. W., Mer - chandise and Grain Com- pany Articles Sidney 100,000 June 20,000 June 13 iii! Hildreth Mercantile Co Amend't Hildreth Omaha 18 Hudson &amp; Thurber Company Articles 400,000 June 24 Hastings Independent Tele- phone Company Dissolu- tion Hastings July 15 1913 Harris-Sartor Jewelry Co, (formerly Sartor - Harris Company Amend't Lincoln 25,000 Jul* 28 Harrison Oil &amp; Development Company) Articles Harrison Omaha 20,000 Sept. 60,000 Sept. 10,000 Sept. 12 s Hoffman, Leo- A Articles 23 Harwood-Pope Company. . . . \rticles Omaha 23 High-Line (The) Telephone Company Articles Eustis 1,500 Oct. I 17 5 Hardy Furniture Company. . \mend't Lincoln 250,000 Oct. 25,000 Oct. Haig State Bank Articles Hatg 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 47 MIHCELLASEOl'g I'UKPOKATIOSS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Place &lt;&gt;t i/t'd When ess Capital Kile I nild'OKATK NAME Instru- ment • r I^and *fc Investment Articles Amend't Hooper Nov ngs &amp; Heyden Amend't Omaha 00 I&gt;et 00 Det - Elevator Company. ... Articles Omaha IS ls»13 Home Investment Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Dec 10,000 Jan 25,000 Jan Home Savings &amp; I&gt;oan Assn. Articles Lincoln Harrison (The W. H.) Co.... Articles Gr. Island 10 1914 attle Co. tion Ellsworth 15 1*14 Spring* Commercial ompany A menu ' Hay Sprn 0 Jan 25,000 Jan 17 1.14 24 1914 17 1914 Hiatt - Fairfield Company. . . Articles Omaha Hatcher (J. S.) &amp; Co Amend't Mc'Cook "• Feb Holt County Telephone Co. . Di&gt; tion O'Neill Feb Hastings. .&amp; .Northwestern Railroad Co By-laws Omaha Feb 20 1914 21 1914 25 1914 Howard Street Stables Co.. Articles Omaha 0 Feb 20.000 Feb. 40,000 Mar. Hastings &amp; Hatcher Co Articles Venango Harlm County Bank Amend't Alma 5 1914 Herald Publishing Company Dissolu- tion Wayne Mar. 5 1914 Hall Bros. Co- Amend't Lincoln Mar- 7 1914 Haase - Morris - Bailey Com- pany Articles Kearney 20.000 Mar. 13 1914 25 1914 Hampton Elevator Company Amend't Hampton Mar Hershey Hook Company .... Dissolu- tion Lincoln Mar. 31 1914 Hathaway (H. C.) Ice Cream Co Articles Lincoln 15.000 Apr 20,000 Apr ; ;;:: Hardware (O. K) Company. . Articles So. Omaha Hopper Investment Co Dissolu- tion Omaha . . . . Apr. 16 1914 Harkert Cigar Co. of Nebras- ka Dissolu tion Gr. Island Apr 16 1914 Horacek Brothers Company. . Articles Brainard 10.000 Apr 22 1914 Holstein Mercantile Company Articles Holstein 7,500 April 28 Haveiock Mercantile Com- 50,000 Apr. 30 1914 pany Articles Havelock </seg>
            <seg id="p048">ii 1 VJf 1 I 1 tj Ptl . t\ rj X -. * l\ L V_/ J* kd A -A. X t* J 48 i MlSt ELLANKOI S CORPORA HONSHU ontinued) Kind of Cupi Hackberry Club (The) Article Omaha May 1 M Ma Am Dla J't H oi hit ion Lint Li ik foi Old Folks and Or- Hank Articlt 3 Hoh Hahn-Hoyer Electric Heater pany Article^ Lincoln ( Mark i Amend't Omaha ■ 'n-Hra Company Pi tion Hasting Havens Rridee Company .... Articles Havens lO.nnoSept 1914 Honey Furniture and Carpet Co Article Sutton s Womei ry Articles Omaha Company Artleh ■ Omaha ..■ORATE KAMI Insmi- Place ot n.ent 1Ilest Kr Liquor Company Articlts Oinaiia ard Manufacturing Oom- ■pany Article E Tailoring I'ompany, coin. Neb Article ly i:i^soli Ktior :uiis Building iv Loan Milling Company (T Articles 1 i Henry \- A 1 i • Hard- i formerly Omaha Hvy. Hardware Co.) Amend' Holmepvillp Farm. ;or (The) - Ho Han ttion orial Hoi e Sarah Fisk) tion pr Iviuiiy Kxchange . . . . Arti phans Lincc nlr»r«&gt;txo Stato Ronii Artir&gt;U= HnlH ilty Company I Sept. 23 1914 KOct 30 1914 00 Nov. 17 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">RKPORT OK T'H K SfcX'RKTAR\ OK STA'l h. 49 MIS&lt; KLLAM-OI S (ORI'OKA LIONS iimt-.l Authc ed When RPORATK NAME Business Capital meut County Grain Company.. A-ticles Omaha 12,500 Ju- 23 1914 an d East India Tea Co. (Thf dia Tea Company (formerly India and East India Tea Company) Kind of Instru- Pla « Nov. ! : Amend t Omaha inpany. . . . Articles Omaha A r 1 1 c ] * lAug. 11 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 M1SCELLANK01S CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author " Author- Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- business j ized When RATE NAME Instru- Business ™« When ment Place of Capital Filed Stock Interlocking Cement Stave Silo Company of Omaha. . . ; Cement Stave lany of Omaha... Articles Omaha 10,000 Sept. 21 1914 Articles Omaha 1914 K national Spiritualists ion (The) il Spiritualists he) Articles Omaha Sept. 30 1:&lt;14 Articles Omaha Sept Iwanca Manufacturing Com uufacturing Com- Dissol tion Lincoln Oct 2*. pany Dissolu tion Lincoln Oct 1M County Soldiers' nument Association "oun&lt;y Soldi' sociation. ... Articles Fairbury Dec. 1!' Articl Fairbury 1 KU Lumber Company (for - rly Joslin-Axtell L-br. »er Company (for- jslin-Axtell Ll&gt;r. Amend't Fairbury Feb. 1!&gt; Amend't Dissolu - tion Fairbury . . Feb. It drain Company i Company. ... iu - tion ii.. City !Apr. 28 1913 Neb-. City Omaha Apr \l\ Jaeger. A. G. Company J. Company Articles Omaha v 21191?, Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Dissolu - tion »1 sphone Company. Articli-s Jacinto 400 July 28 Eto Telephone Company, n Realty Company ■n Mercantile Company lal Publishing Co Jaclnti Blair Ity Company Articles Blair 70,000 Aug. 18 1913 70,000 Aug 8,000 IS 191 •cantile Company Articles Big Sprcs. 8,000|Aug. 23 1913 Big Sprf Columbu Wishing Co Articles Columbus 10,090 Dec. 17 1913 10,000 Dec 1 191 i Company Dis.solu- | tion ook Feb Land and Cattle Articles piattsm'th , ir. 25 1914 Jones Farm Company McCo Feb 1 Jean (The) Land and Cattle Articles 000 Mar Brewing Company Limited ewing Company, Articles Bo. Omaha lOO.nnoApr. 10 1914 Articles Articles tion So. Omaha 1 Johnson Grocery Co •ocery Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 May 4 1914 Lincoln 4 191 Joy Freytag Company (The) ; Company (The! Dissolu- I tion Odill 'June 17 1914 Odell Jur 17 James Coal Company (The) Company (Thet . . Dissolu - tion aha July 20 1914 Dtaaoln tion July Omaha Jansen Light and Power Co (Th. tit and Power Co- Articles Jansen in. 000 Sept. 2 1914 Articles 10.000 Sept .Tansf Ery Omaha Company (for rly Rambler Motor Com ay) iha Company (for- mbler Motor Com- Amend't Omaha Sept- 7 1914 Amend't Articles Omaha Lincoln Sept- 7 1914 ne (The) Club. rhet Club Articles Lincoln Jan. 31 1913 Co. (formerly Jan 51 191 K-Peck Co. (formerly lg-Swanson Co.) nson Co.) Amend't Omaha Feb. 5 191" Amend't I Omaha Feb ituehrk Articles Cedar Biffs 30.000 Feb. 11 1913 Articles Cedar Biff: Amend't Norfolk Killian &amp; Stuehrk 0 Feb. ) Mar. Killian. A. L. Company L. Company Amend't Norfolk '0 Mar. 1 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS ( •&gt;ntinui .1 1 Author- CORPORATE NAME , Kind of Place of I ized I Instru- Business Capita When Fil Stock Lincoln lar. 4 Kappa Sigma Building Assn. Artie] Knox Weed Company ' Articl Omaha .., Mar. I 1 KMT, Wm. Co. of Spencer Articl r Pottery Company. ... Articl (The i Lumber Coal Company ! Articl K rotter, Wm. ( Kahler I . ille ley (The i Lumber &amp; Coal Company Art Mir Pal Kemp Merchandise Com-panyiArtid Kemp Merchandise Com-pan Knox County HI, pany . \rtiel \nox m&lt; Kleyla faun I Kley .Co Articl \r Koutsky-Pavlik Company. . . . Articl Karbaeh Realty Company Keil-Dedlow Manufacturing Co- Articl Keil-TWlow M{ Phi Kenesaw (The) Drug Co. ... ! Articl Art Kant-Slip (The) Heel Pi: Co | Articl Plate Kl.opp &amp; Bartlett Co Articl Art \ v K F. .T O wid Ha Om Art Kohn Br Brokerage Co. A (V. D.) Manufacturing B 14 ( Ar Art f- T.ir &amp; S K. lb &lt;T\ \rti So. On Llpht &amp; Power M Art Kit Knights of Columbus i y id' New Ha Am( </seg>
            <seg id="p052">RKi'ORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS ( OHPORA TIONS (( ontinued) Autho Kind of Place of Business ized Capital CORPORATE NAME I Instru- led ment 5toc Mjr Ladies OuU'ittin :iipany Dissolu- tion 'Kearney Al.lN May iy 1^14 28 li»14 r Company (The) . .Amend't Lincoln mi Manufacturing Com pany (The! Articles Omaha • r Company (Henry H tion [Omaha Lutheran High School and Business College * ,000 I)t II. 1'. Company Ameni't ILincol -1 Dec |)ln (The) No-Air Tire: (i lArt; ,, aln &gt;reaux Brothers Com-' iy Art Jan j, N. C. Company (for - rly Kotera &amp; Leary Co.) Ajw alia ilty Co An .aha y Land &amp; Power Co. .. Arti coin Mar. r Temple Amend't Lincoln o Apr. ■ te Bank Articles | Lincoln 100,000 Apr. &gt;ln Packing Company. . Amend't Lincoln •. 000 Apr. iln Suburban Homes ■npany Arti i oln '0 Apr. Filling Co I Art u oln oreaux Broth m- Articlf li .! 191 v Kotera &amp; Leary Co.) Ami ■r" 1 8 IS I Co Articles ' Omaha 14 1913 Lundy Land &amp; Power Co. . . Artie! i - Labor Temple Amend't Lincoln Apr. In State Bank Articles , Lincoln Apr Apr lbl In Packing Company. . Amend't Lincoln i In Suburban Homes ompany Artici' 19 191 iln Tpnt &amp; Awning Co (The* Artli .oln \l 28 1913 nd Company Amend't Oinah May 12 lx&gt;ng Pine Land &amp; Live Stock Co Dissolu- tion May 20 191 Lincoln Symphony Orchestra Articles Lin 10.000 May 28 191 L^ahy Manufacturing Com- pany Dissolu- tion North Be May 31 1913 23 i913 I-arson Auto Company Articles Fremont .000 June Lyman-Warner Company . . . Dissolu- tion Lincoln June 30 1913 Lincoln Amusement Company Articles Lincoln 10.000 Jul Lindell Hotel Company Dissolu- tion Lincoln July 15 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATION'S— (Continued) Author- Kind of CORPOR. TE NAME Instru- 1 P ' ace of ized W»« CORPOR. TE NAME Instru- • ment Busln ess Capital Kiled ment | «ock Business College Col Building Co ,. . Lincoln "in July 16 li&gt; Company Articles N Platte "i July - Artie Lincoln erk-Sandall Company 'Articles N 1'latte "i July - Leoa'a, Incorporated aha Incorporated naha .incoln Mills Lincoln Articles Lincoln Lincoln Sign Works Article! Lincoln :u Hospital Associa - tion Artie!' n Works Articles Linco 1 ocia- Arti Lyric Theatre Co Artiohs Fremont irrigation Co.... Art: nball eatre Co Article* Fremont Ige Pole irrigation Co Articles Kimbal Lincoln Pure Butter Company Ami coin .Amen.i UtchfieM A South Loup Tel. Co. Articles Litchfieki A. Arti tc Lincoln Mining Company.... Art utna coin Mining Company. .. .Articles Omaha Lakeside Ice Company Art \ Lincoln Building &amp; Supply Company Lincoln ipply At Lincoln Overland Company. . (Articles Lincoln 1 1 npany i R-olu- tion ion I the Cross. . Arti \r Loup Valley State Bank... \ Llreeey Brick Company Pisso' r Pis tior tion Land&gt; Linco Landy Clark Company. Art Lincoln Highway Automobile Co. of Omaha Ar lit Arti Omat O Lee-Glass- Andreeson Hdw Co. (\'ow) Lee-Coit-An - dreeson Hdw v 'aha Lee-Glass- Andreeson Hdw (V T.pp-Coit-An 6 1914 dreeson Hdw Am i Le'sy Brewine Company \rtielps Omaha 8 I*. y Brewine Companv... Artie Omaha Lawrence Lumber Co. (for - merly A. H. Bowman Lu: ber Col Amend't Lawrei f Lawrence T A. H. F ber ( Amp d t T^pwr Loveland Farms Company (Thel Article- Loveland F Company (The) ArticH Lakeside Comrpany (TheV .. Articles Doim' (The 1 ) . . . Article Lincoln Pure Butter Company In T fThf I't I.in&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 MIMKLLANEOIS tORPOKATIONS i ( ontinued) CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of | ized When m Business ' Capital Filed m Business ' Capital Filed Stock Stock Linch Shock Loader Manu - facturing Company (for - merly Shock Loader Mfg. ■I Amend't Lincoln Apr. L'T l:&lt;14 Ei Shock Loader Manu - turing Company (for - rly Shock Loader Mfg Ob. i Amend't Lincoln 'Apr. M 1M4 Lawn Social Club Articles ;DouglasCo. MM May 16 1914 ngton State Bank (for - merly The Lexington Bank) Amend't Lexington May 28 1914 Lawn Social Club Articles Douglas Cc 16 1914 aton State Bank (for merly The Lexington Bank Amend t Lexington May 28 1914 Lincoln Transfer and Stor - ompany Amend't Lincoln i June 2 1914 Lincoln Transfer and Stor age Company Amend't Lincoln June 2 1914 Lamoreux - Peterson - Noyes ustr Co Dissolu- Lamoreux - Peterson - Noye istr Co Dissolu - tion tion Omaha I 1914 Omaha June Lakeside State Bank (The) -ide State Bank (The) . . Articles Lakeside 25,000 June 5 1914 Articles Articles Lakeside 25,000 June Laverty Brothers Articles So. Omaha ,ne 12 1914 Laverty Brothers So. Omaha :5.00u!june 12 1914 Lincoln Cleaning &amp; Dye Works Amend't Lincoln June 19 1914 Kin Cleaning &amp; Dye rks Amend't Lincoln Junf 19 1914 Lamoreux &amp; Peterson Com - pany Dissolu- Lamoreux &amp; Peterson Com- Pany Dissolu - tion tion Omaha I July 1 1 -'1 4 Omaha July Lincoln Stove Repair Co. ... Amend't Lincoln |july 1 1914 In Stove Repair Co. ...] Amend't Lincoln July 11914 IS 1914 Loval Power Company Articles Omaha 0 July I ly I^ano &amp; Power Cos pany Dtaaol Loval Power Company Articles lOmaha n julv Lundy I^anc &amp; Power Com- pany iDissolu- tion Lincoln [July It tion Lincoln (July 16 Liberty Gun Club of Dakota rty Gun Club of Dak. County, Nebraska. (The).. Articles jDakotaCity MNiW * 191* County, .Nebraska. (The) . . Articles Dakota City Omaha o.OOC'Aug "Auk 4 1914 Lodge Supply Company (The) Articles Omaha lO.ftM Autr 2 Lodge Supply Company (The) Articles Loomis Farmers Co-operative txioniis Farmers Co-operati Company Articles Loomis pt. 11 1914 Company Articles Loomis I Sept 0 Oct. Lincoln Inn Company Articles Omaha 10 Oct. 22 1914 Lowe Pure Foods Company (The) Articles Omaha 25.000 Nov. 10 1914 Club, Omaha Lodge 90. L- O. O. M Articles Omaha ",Dec 0 Dec McCann. C. A. Company Articles Omaha Mutual Land Company Articles Omaha Morehouse. R. H. Company. . Dissolu tlon Omaha Dec Moose Club. Magic City Lodge No. 308, L. O. O. M Articles So. Omaha lo.nnn Dec 28 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 U8CELLANE0U8 (ORPORATIO&gt;&gt; &lt; &lt;&gt;ntinu*&gt;d) Kind of I Author - CORPORATE NAME Instru- ! Place of ized XN hen When ment Business Capital Filed Filed Stock achine Manufacturing &amp; richine Manufacturing &amp; Engineering Company (for - merly Positive Print Ma- Engineering Company (for- merly Positive Print Ma- chine Paper Company) Amend't Omaha It iiuhu (inson, A. O. Company Articles Osceola M Feb. arsh Lake Hunting &amp; Fish- ing Association Articles Plainview | Feb. IS 181- Plain view i) Keb. 19 anufacturers' Auto Tire Co i Omaha Omaha 191 utual Film Corporation of .Nebraska (formerly Pro- gressive Film Kxchange lan Company) Amend't Omaha ! Feb. 1 IMS Ami «i Omaha Omaha par lid West Serum Company. . naha West Serum Company. Merchants Mortgage Loan Company saha 100,000 Ma: par Omaha Omaha lotorist Publishing Company Amend't Omaha ,;. 11111 Apr [cCook Electric Company... Amend't Dmn Apr. 4 Apr. 4 l'-'l II Vt lasonic Temple Craft South Omaha (The) Article* So. Omaha • mie Temple Craft of Flor - ence Article* Flora r&lt; \r M T.M Flc Flora Arti Apr. 11 19 lerohants Advertisin - of America Articles Lincoln M \ An Morsman Drug Company... Dissolu- tion Falls City Falls Ci Mosby. H. E. Company (for - merly Mosby &amp; Young Co.) Amend't Sioux City June 1 Uosbv. H. E. Company (for- June 18 191 June 18 191 Mosby &amp; Co.) Ane Martin Bros. Furniture Co.. Article* Centra! ("y Martin Brn^ F Arti Meyers Land &amp; Cattle Co.... Articles Omaha' ine 18 191: Mevers Land &amp; ( \r Merrick-Johnson Co Dissolu- Merrick in Jlu- tion 1 Manhattan (Thp&gt; Tnvpstment Company Dissolu- lu- tion iha June 27 191 tlon June 27 191 July 8 191 Omaha Madrid Madrid Town Site Company Articles Madrid "July 8 191 Madrid Town Site Company Articles Missouri River Freight &amp; For - warding Company Articles Omaha 5,000 July 9 191 rissouri River Freight &amp; For - warding Companv Omaha 5.000 July 9 191 Masonic Temple Craft of Hastings Articles Hastings ly 11191 Articles Amend't Hasting Lincoln iO July 1 Uy 14 191 Marsh-Burke Company </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 MISCELLANEOUS COEPOBATIOSS— (t ontinued) Author- Kind of! place Qf CORPORATE NAME Instru- 1 Busine8S ment Stock Merchants Grocery Syndicate Dissolu tlon {Omaha July 15 191 Morton's Express Company. . Articles Benson 10,000 July 18 191 Millard Auditorium Assn IDissolu tion Millard 'july 1 Magee &amp; Deemer Amend't Lincoln 100,000'july 29 191 McCabe. The, Aviation Com- pany 'Articles Lexington | 100, n 1 Melcher Drug Company ;Dissolu tion So. Omaha ! Sept. 22 191 I&gt;t Meneray Omaha Nursery Co. Articles Omaha 25,000 Sept 19 191 Moritz Meyer Cigar Co Dissolu- tion Omaha 20,000 Oct. 9 191 iri Valley Oil Co Articles Omaha Oct. 13 1 Miller - Winship Investment 25." Co Articles Lincoln Oct. 27 1 Miller - Winship Investment Co I Articles Lincoln Oct. 27 191 McCabe Aviation Company. . I Amend't Lexington | 100,000 Nov. 6 191 McCabe Aviation Company. . Amend't Lexington 100,000 Nov. 6 1 Mutual Rating &amp; Adjustment Mutual Rating &amp; Adjustment Assn j Articles Omaha 10,000 Nov. 10 191 Articles Omaha M,M«Noy. 10 1 Mayes Serum Co. Articles So. Omaha 10,000 Dec. 1191 Mayes Serum Co. Articles So. Omaha lO.Omi p P( . 11 Marshlake Hunting &amp; Fishing Aasn Dissolu- Marshlake Hunting &amp; Fishing Assn Dissolu- tion Marshlake Dec. 2 1 tion Marshlake ' Deo. 2 191 Morrill County Abstract Co. Articles Milier-Welgand Company. . . . Dissolu- Morrill County Abstract Co. Articles Bridgeport 10,000 Dec. 4 1 Bridgeport 10,000 Der 4 191 Miller-Welgand Company. . . . Dissolu- tion tion Craig Dec. 5 1 Craig Dec. 5 191 Merchants Advertising Assn Merchants Advertising Assn of America Dissolu- of America Dissolu- tion tion Lincoln iDee. 10 1 Lincoln iDee. 10 191 Midwest Iron Works Convpany Articles Omaha 9,000 p ec . 11 1 Midwest Iron Works Company Articles Omaha 9.000 Dec 11 191 Marion Automobile Co 'Amend't Omaha Dec. 16 1 Marion Automobile Co 'Amend't Omaha 16 191 Dec Mayle, J. W. Co- ! Dissolu- Mayle, J. W. Co- i Dissolu- tion Blair Dec. 18 1 tion Blair Dec. 18 191 Maurer, G. W. Co Dissolu- Maurer, G. W. Co Dissolu- tion tion Beatrice iDee. 20 1 Beatrice iDec. 20 191 Monarch Film Company Articles Monarch Film Company Articles Omaha 10,000 Dec. 20 1 Mills, (V. T.) Co Dissolu- tion Platte Co Dec. 30 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">MISCELLANEOUS i ORPOK VTIONS 1 1 ontinaed) Author- Kind of Place of ized CORPORATE NAME Instru- Business Capital XN en ment Stock Filed Michigan A pany Omaha tiot Uis Jan *orth t Jan. Jan. Malcolm State Bank Amend t Malcolm I! • ileum Burial Associa- Lincoln \rt t^ M V Amer (1 entral tchell Mercantile &lt; l&gt;is N tio Marv J fn Iv *: irt ( An • Anu-i Order of M )ma Ft y Ma gee £ Deenier) Am Lint -nerly M;il Am Omaha Feb Mar M Nurserv &lt; inaha Metropolitan Conservator Arts m Arti Omaha Mar Mary (The) Lanning Mot al Hospital Art Mar Malone-Armip Co. (The) Riverton ■ne-Averv Amend't (TY Red Mithen Company (J. H.) (for- ly Mithen-Drew Co.) I Omaha McGregor Engraving and Seal Article* (Lincoln ■ Marsh Burke Supply Corn- incoln ioo.oo 10.01 50.0' 1 11 1914 24 1914 pan Model Laundry Company. .. .Article Or. Island Mendenhall Ice Co Articles iFairbury Murdock Mercantile Company/ !e;:f-! (The) Articles Murdock ' May Valley Historical hum Arti'l- - Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF TOE SECRETARY OF STATE MlStELLANEOlS COBPOKATIO-NS— (Continued) I Author- Place of ! ized When Business I Capital Filed Kind of Instru- CORPORATE NAME ment Stock Masonic Temple Craft Assn 18 1914 of Bloomfield, Nebr. Articles Bloomfield 10,000 June Millard I'lattdutclien Vereen of Millard, Nebraska. Articles Millard July 11 1K14 Mullen 24 1914 Mullen Telephone Company Articles 15,000 July Minden State Bank Articles Minden 40,000 Aug. 21 1914 Morrill Target Company Omaha 1 1914 Articles 30,000 Sept. .er's Bank Amend't Shelton Sept. 14 1914 Lincoln 24 1914 r Brothers Company. . . Amend't Sept. Maxwell Lumber &amp; Grain Company Dissolu- tion Maxwell Oct Murphy - O'Brien Auto Co (The) Articles Omah 25,000 (W 29 1914 ok Cement Stone Com pany Dissolu - tion McCook JNov Midwest Ranch Company Articles Atkinson lmi.imo Nov. Mutual Live Stock Commis sion Co- Articles So. Omaha Xov Midwest Iron Works Com pany Dissolu- tion Omaha Xov 28 1914 Naponee Joint Stock Hall Building Company 'Articles Naponee 1.500 Jan. II 1»1J National Oil &amp; Paint Manu- facturing Company lArticles Omaha '"'Jan. 27 1: Nebraska Branch No. 22 of the Motion Picture Exhib- itors League of America. .. 'Articles Omaha I Jan. 31 1913 Nebraska Homesteaders' Assn Articles Whitman 10,000 Feb. Nebraska (The) Tent &amp; Awn- ing Co. of Omaha. Nebraska Articles Omaha 10,000 Feb. 5 1913 Feb. 15 1913 umana Omaha Omaha Nebraska Clothing Company Amend't National Detective Service. . Articles Feb. 20 1913 Neidhart Monumental Works (The) Articles jBeatrice 10,000 Feb 25,000 Mar 4,000 Mar 21 1913 17 1913 26 1913 Nichols Roofing Company. .. Articles Lincoln Helena Hall Association'Articles I New Helena </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 MISCELLANEOUS COKPOKATIOYS 1 1 ontlntd) I Kind of aor " ! CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized U hen Kind of Place of Business CORPORATE NAME Instru ment Business Capital Filed ment Stock ell (The) Investment The) Investment Company Arf .itrice mpany Articles Beatrice i Mar 28 m Norfolk Packing Co A niend't Norfolk nlk Packing Co Ani.nd't -Norfolk r. 4 \pr 4 lal uska Central Building &amp; iska Central Building &amp; tan Association Amend't Lincoln Lincoln ui l't las. The I olas. The L. V. Oil Com- 1 Com- ny Articles Omaha -i A(pr. 12 I Articles Omaha pany h German Rural Tele- North German Rural T phone Co Articles Pierce Apr. 13 Pierce North Salem Telephone Assn. Articles Dakota ("y iska Automobile Deale i Articles Hooper M Dakota C" 000 May North Bend Grain Company. . Amend't North Bend North Bingham Telephone Co. (The) Articles Bingham Ideal Laundry Company Dissolu- Co. (The) Articles Binghar Ideal Laundry Company Pi- tion Lincoln Lincoln Omaha Omaha Norfolk M tion a Oil &amp; Gas Company. . Articles Omaha | ta Oil &amp; Gas Company. . Articles National Box Company Articles 1 Junf National Box Company Articles Omaha 18 191 Norfolk Investment Conrpany Articles Norfolk ijune 21 1 June mal Automobile Training ■ iation Amend't Omaha \«sociation Amend't Omaha " Jun "i Jun 1' N'obrara Power Com-pany. . . . Articles Omaha 100.MM Juiv Nebraska City Telephone Co- Dissolu- tion Neb. City Neb. City ioi July Nebraska Automobile Spec - ialty Co Articles Omaha in.000 July 21 Nebraska Automobile Spec- ialty ( Articles Omaha • July National Mercantile Company Vancoir. National Mercantile Company Vancouver II Articles IB. C lO.nnn July 2!&gt; aska Stock Powder Co... Articles Fremont s.non Jui aska Hog &amp; Cattle Pow - • Co Articl. .nt i &amp; Robinson Company he&gt; (formerly Xorth - binson-Dean Co.) Amend't Gr. Island 100.000 Aug. 1 lO.non July s.non July der Co Articles rton July K&amp; Robinson Company e&gt; (formerly North- Robinson-Dean Co.) Amend't Gr. Island 100,000 Aug Natlor iation Accred - ited Music Teachers and in a 1 Association Accred- 1 Music Teachers and iooIr Articles Lincoln ■&gt; Aug. 5 Lincoln 1 Aug. York, Wyoming OH &amp; I Co jArticles Sheridan 100. 000 Aug. 2 Sheridan 100.000 Aug. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of _ ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock Nelson Lumber &amp; Supply Company Articles Gr. Island 25,000 Aug. 50,000 Sept- 12 Norfolk (Taej Savings Bank Articles Norfolk 0 Nebraska Hog &amp; Cattle Pow- der Co Articles Tecumseh 25,000 Sept. Nebraska Corn Products Co- Dissolu- tion Beatrice Sept. 23 Nebraska Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Dissolu- Church tion Lincoln Sept. 25 I'M. North Nebraska Annual Con- ference of the M. E. Church Dissolu- tion Sept Nebraska (The) Annual Con- ference of the M. E. Church Articles Lincoln Sept 191 National Detective Associa- tion Articles Omaha Sept Nebraska Placer Company.. Amend't Omaha 50.000 Oct North Platte General Hospital Assn. Articles N. Platte Nebraska State Bank of Nor- folk Articles Norfolk n Nov 8 Nebraska Central Railway Company Article? Pierre, S. Dak. Nov. IS Nebraska Serum Company. . . Articles Lincoln Nebraska Blaugas Company. . Amend't Omaha io.ooo Nov. 28 ma 28 Dec. 22 1M3 Niemann (Carl J.) &amp; Bros.. . Dissolu- tion Omaha Dec. 26 1913 National Serum Company. . . . Articles So. Omaha i Dec L'ft Nebr. City Street Railway Co. Dissolu- tion Neb. City Dec. 31 1913 Nebraska City Brick Co. ... Dissolu- tion Neb. City Jan. 6 1914 Nebraska Feature Company Articles Lincoln Nebraska. Blaugas Company Amend't Omaha 1,000 Jan. 6 1914 3,500.000 Jan. 9 1914 Nicholas L. V. Oil Co Amend't Omaha Jan. 14 1914 North (The) Bingham Tele- phone Co Articles Bingham 4.000 Jan 2fi </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 MlSCELLAJiEOl/S ( :ORPORATU»S— (( ontiwd) Author- Kind of Place of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME Instru- ment Stock \orfoik Furniture Company Dissc u- Norfolk Feb. tion Nebraska Land At Live Stoc Art Chadror Feb. National Hail Insurance Co. (Mutual) Amer It Lincol Keb m National Hail Insurance ( lited Mutual An Linci t \ Nebraska (The I Security In- rly Owners Cor Amend't Om Jan Me Bank Arti&lt; ! At :e Co Bank Linct Linci M; 14 1914 Nebraska Lumbermen's Mut Lin A I At \ Nor Ball Association pany bra r ka Paint &amp; Lead Com- 11:1 tio I.ii Apr Nebraska F£ jpply Am t : Compa r )lk Country ( Nor- folk, Xeb Amend't Norfolk ■ Article .y 11 1914 National Remedy Company Co. Bluff* Ar*'ck Norfolk Landw Verein Norfolk None Giver is r.«n Nathan's Lake Summer Re- sort Articles ■Washington Co. Nebraska State Bank (The) Articles Beatrice </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOIS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Place of Business ized When Capital Filed CORPORATE NAME Instru- ment Stock National Detective Service... Dissolu- tion Omaha June 8 1914 Nebraska Typewriter Com pany Dissolu- tion Lincoln June 1 National Printing Company. Amend't Omaha June 16 1914 Negro Woman's Christian As sociation Articles Omaha June 19 1914 Niobrara Electric Light, Pow er and Railway Company. . Articles Ann-C'arr s 300,000 June 4."&gt;.&lt;m)0 June 40,000 July Moser Rogers Company Articles Omaha National Building Company Articles Omaha 25 North Platte Hardware and Furniture Co Articles N. Platte 30,000 July 25,000 Aug ::;: 28 National Buy. ciation Articles Omaha v ~ka and South Dakota Ferry Boat Company (The) Articles Niobrara 5.000 Aug 24 Nehawka Auditorium Com- pany (The) Articles Nehawka 1 Sept National Security Fire Insur- ance Co Articles Omaha 500,000 Sept. 11 1914 Norfolk Bridge and Construc- tion Co. Articles Norfolk 25,000 Oct. 30,000 Oct. 12 IS SJ Nebraska State Bank (The) . . Articles Ohiowa Omaha Metal &amp; Rubber Com- pany Articles Omaha 100,000 Jan 10,000 Jan 4 14 Omaha Automobile Club Articles Omaha t Equipment &amp; Supply any (formerly Lin- Typewriter Exchange Company) Amend't Lincoln Jan. 23 1913 &lt;y} Omaha Marble &amp; Tile Co. ..Articles Omaha 25.000 Jan. 25 191 Olympic Athletic Club Articles So. Omaha Feb. 4 191* Omaha Typewrite'- Exchange Articles Omaha 10.000 Feb. 10 191? Old Peoples Home (formerly Woman's Christian Associ- ation) Amend't Omaha Feb. 13 1912 Otter Creek Mutual Irrigation Articles Lemoyne 8.940 Feb. •7 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 REPORT OP THK SECRETARY OP STATE :? MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— ((o»tin«etl) Author- Kind of Flace of ized When Business Capital Filed CORPORATE NAMK Instru- ment Stock Omaha Taxi Cab and Auto Livery Company Amend't Omaha 50,000 Mar. 11 lMli Omaha Traction Engine Com - pany (formerly Ralston Xto- tor Co.) Amend't ; &gt;maha .Mar. 1 Mar. Omaha Foundry Company Khe) Articles Omaha 10,tM Mar. ha Musik Verein Build - ing Co. Articles Omaha "&gt; Apr. (The) Articles Omaha hi Mar 191 Co. Articles Omaha 8 191 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Company (formerly Orchard &amp; Wil - helm Carpet Company) ... Amend t Omaha Apr. Apr. 1 Omaha Auto Top Company (formerly Reynolds. K. W Mfg. Co.) Amend't Omaha I Apr Omaha Auto Top Company (formerly Reynolds, K. W Co.) Amend't Omaha ■ Apr Omaha Sanitary Supply Co.. . Amend't Omaha A|&gt;r. Odell Lumber Company Amend't Odell n Apr Omaha Evangelistic Associ - ation Article* Omaha T- Articles Omaha Omaha Structural Steel Works Amend t Omaha Ma\ Omaha Structural St Works Amend t Omaha May Omaha Distilling Company. . Articles Omaha Juni Omaha Distilling Company. . Articles Omaha 0 June Official Red Rook Publishing Co Articles Omaha 50,000 .Turn Official Red Book Publishing in Jur Old Line Accident Insurar Co \v ■ ■ Lincoln 100.000 Jum Old Line Accident Insurancf Articles Lincoln iO June i Iiha Taxicab Company 'ormerly Omaha Taxicab Auto Livery Co.) Amend't Omaha Lumber &amp; Coal Co Dissolu- July Ord Lumber &amp; Coal Co Pissolu tion Ord lull July rien. T. J. Company Articles Omaha • July 11 191 Old Line Accident Insurance Co Amend't Lincoln Aug. 6 191 Oxford (The) Country Club Articles Oxford - pt. 4 191 Omaha Optical Company Omaha Remedy Co Amend't Omaha 12,00' • 1H1 4 191 Articles Omaha 10.000 Oct Omaha Secret Service Petec tive Agency Articles Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of D Author " CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of lzed When nient Busin es B Capital Business Capital File Stock Stock Omaha Cement &amp; Paving Co. Dissolu- aba Cement &amp; Paving Co. Dissolu- tion Omaha tion Omaha Oct. 26 1913 igas Company Articles Neb. City 30,00( 30,000 Nov 20 191 Otoe Uiaugas Company Articles Neb. City Olyiqpis (The) Real Estate mo&gt;is (The) Real Estate Co Articles Omaha Articles Omaha 10,000 10,000 1). Oskaloosa Saddlery Co Dissolu- aloosa Saddlery Co Dissolu- tion kaloosa Iowa tion Oskaloosa Iowa Dec 191 Old Gold Bank Articles Taylor Gold Bank Articles Taylor 25,000 25,000 Jan 10 1914 Omaha Realty Owners .Cor- ha Realty Owners .Cor- poration Amend't Omaha ratlon Amend't Omaha Jan :o 1^14 ha Hat Factory Amend't On.aha 20.00C 20,000 Jan Omaha Hat Factory Amend't On.aha Omaha Refining &amp; Manufac- ha Refining &amp; Manufac- turing Co Articles Omaha ring Co Articles Omaha 18.00C 18,000 ,Iai Omaha Manufacturing Com- ha Manufacturing Com- pany Articles Omaha ny Articles Omaha 10,000 10,00( Mining ("om- ond (Jold Mining Com- p an y Articles Omaha Articles Omaha Oakdale Mercantile Company Articles OakdaU Construction Co Articles Lincoln dale Mercantile Company Articles Oakdal. Construction Co Articles Lincoln I Company. . . Dissolu- 25,000 Jan 31 1911 21 1914 ,pany. . . Dissolu- y tion Aurora tion Aurora Employ* Articles Omaha 10,00i Articles Omaha IO.OOd Mar ■ ha Rub' Dissolu- Dissolu- tion Omaha tion Omaha Mar. 18 1 :i and Lincoln Railway ha and Lincoln Railway M;i and Light Company Amend't Omaha )akdal' Light Com- d Light Company Amend't Omaha l dalp Light Com- pany Dissolu- ny Dissolu- tion Oakdale Mar. 31 1914 Orleans Erfuity Co-operative 10,000 Apr Articles Orleans Obert (The) Mercantile Com- pany AmenB't Obert Apr. 3 1 Orchard iThe) Fraternal Hall Assn Articles Orchard 5,000 Apr </seg>
            <seg id="p065">HIM KI.LANtOl S I UKPORATIONS— (Continued) it n K Plai When Filed )KPUKATE NAME ni-tru- Sto&lt; (T Omaha \pr. 14 atiiin \rticle Articlf Arts (T a 1 4 \ \r b. ( ompany. . Art t Artless omaha 10,000 Aug. 12 () No. 42. I ( </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OK STATE 66 M8CELLAKE0CS COKFOKATIOXS— (Continued) Kind of Autho1 " Author- Kind of CORPORATE NAM K Instru- PlaCe o( . iZed RATE XA.MK Instru- PlaCe of iZed ment pltal When Fi Stock Kc Barrice Construction npany v\ce Construction Articles Omaha 19,000 1 10. null Feb 4 uk Amend't Upland I Automobile Com- Peoples Bank Mar 21 P. C. (The) Automobile Com pany. Incorporated orporated Articles Flatte Our li.000 i 0 Apr l.iHMj Apr stherhood '.Amend't Lincoln I.ihmi.' Phoenix Brotherhood it Pounds Plumbing &amp; Heating Company mbing &amp; Heating Articles Lincoln 10,000 4 10 Apr 16 Porter Land A.- Investment Company 1 i Investment Articles Haigler 50.000 -&gt; Articles Articles Articles 50.000 -May IO.Oimi May 10.00(1 May 1 ige Articles Omaha lO.Onn 3 Paxton Garage &lt; lub Articles Brok'n Bow lO.OOii I Public Service Club. 24 Power Creek Manufacturing Company ■k Manufacturing Articles Omaha MO J ' Jun 4 Peoples' Department Store Company (partment Store Dissolu - tion Campbell J Insurance Com- Articles Omaha 1M.600 J June 24 Prairie Life Insurance Com- 150,000 June 24 Prime of Life Insurance As - sociation fe Insurance As- Articles Omaha J Articles Articles Articles July ss ine Engine Co. . . Articles Plattsm'th J Lumber Co Articles Weeping Platte Gasoline Engine Co. Pennel S. S Lumber Co. . . 50,000 July 31 Water lo.OOO A ■I Aug 9 Pickrell Farmers Elevator Company irmers Elevator Amend't Pickrell 25. &lt; 25.0(10 Aug Papillion (The) Mercantile Hie) Mercantile Articles Papillion MM ■ s.oflu Sept ;::.: n Co Amend't Omaha C Oct Potter-Griffin Co 15 Parlor Furniture &amp; Mattress ikure &amp; Mattress Amend't Fremont 25,000 C 25,000 Oct. 25,000 Not 10.000 Jan 30.000 Feb 10.000 Feb M in I Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Agree- Peters Bros. Company . Company Articles Millard 25,000 &gt; :hor Concrete Co. Articles Omaha 10,000 .1 21 Bird Anchor Concrete Co les (The) State Bank., gon Feature Film Co... ■s (M. C.) Mill Co le) State Bank. . Articles Anselmo 30,000 F ature Film Co.. . Articles Omaha 10,000 F 17 C.) Mill Co Agree - ment Omaha F Feb 20 s: es) Company.... Articles So. Omaha 6.000 F 6,000 Feb K (James) Company -Lefler Co 25 ■ Co Dissolu - tion So. Omaha M Mar 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">MIX ELLANEOUS ( OKI'OKA T1O&gt;S— (Continoed) \ Kina of -vuumr- ORPORATE NAME Instru- Place ° r ized * nent Capi Sto I'armer-Olson Co. I formerly F. I). Farmer Co.) A.nend't Omaha A.nend't Articles Articles Omaha Norfolk Omaha Mar v. ..-. _; u»u PBMwalk (The) Corporation Articles Norfolk ' Mar " Apr 1914 Parcel Post Hen Company .. Articles Omaha 10,000 Apr. 1 1H14 Parcel Post Hen Company lyu Power Creek Manufacturing Co Dissolu- Power Creek Manufacturing Co tion Omaha Apr T Apr Pennel (S- S. &gt; Lumber Com - pany . . Dissolu- Pennel (S 8.) Lumber Com- pany Dissolu - tion »tion ping Weeping Water Water Apr If 1914 Api 15 1914 Palm Insurance Agency ((). W.) Articles Lincoln 8 Apr tl Palm Insurance Agency (O. W.I Prescripto Drug Company. . . Plattsmouth Ice and Cold Articles Articles Lincoln Omaha ' Apr ■ May Prescripto Drug Company. . . Articles Omaha I May Plattsmouth Ice and Cold Storage Company Articles Plattsm'th Storage Company Articles Phelps Cigar Company Amend't Fremont .... May 14 1914 Phelps Cigar Company Amend't Plumfield Nurseries Kremont "0 June H Plumfield Nurserie- Articles Plattsmouth Boat Club Articles Plattsm'th 1.00i&gt; June tt 1914 Plattsmouth Boat Club Articles Philleo &amp; Harrington Lum - ber Co. (formerly Philleo &amp; Von Seggern Lbr. Co.) . . . Amend't Wayne June 24 1914 Von Seggern Lbr. Co.) ... Amend't Wayne Purdum Purdum State Bank (The).. Articles Purdum 10,000 July 6 1914 Purdum State Bank (The).. Articles i July 10,000 Aug. Pease Drug Company Articles Gr. Island 10,000 Aug. 19 1914 Pease Drug Company Articles Or. Island Kser Telephone Company Dissolu- Prosser Telephone Company Dissolu- tion Pro- : 1914 tion Prosser Sterling Sept 1914 Peoples Telephone Company Articles les Telephone Company Articles Sterling n) Sept. 30 1914 0 Sept 30 1914 Pankratz Telephone Company Dissolu- Pankratz Telephone Company Dissolu tion Henderson Oct. 23 1914 tlon Henderson Oct. 23 1914 P. C. Auto Co Dissolu- P. C. Auto Co Dissolu- tion Platte ( '••!. Nov. 9 1914 tion Platt. Beatrice Xov 9 1914 28 1913 Queen City Drug Company. . Articles Beatrice 10.000 Feb. 28 1913 Queen City Drug Company. . Articles &lt;i Feb Queen City Creamery Com - pany Dissolu- Queen City Creamery Com- pany Dissolu- tion Beatrice May 12 1913 tion Beatrice May 12 1913 Queen City Model Laundry. . Articles Hastings 20,000 Apr. 16 1914 Queen City Model Laundry Quincy Realty Company . . Rehner R. A. Co Articles Hastings Omaha 20,000 Apr 50,00' Feb 16 1914 30 1914 Quincy Realty Company .... Articles Cmaha 50,000 Ajpr. 30 1914 Articles Rehner R. A. Co Articles Columbus b. 3 1913 Articles Columbus 1913 Rylen &amp; Barrett Articles Omaha S.Mfl Mar 11 1913 Articles 5,000 Mar </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 IF VHK SECRETARY OF STATK MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) UPORATK NAME Inrtru- Place of „ ized W ' len Kind of I 'ORATE NAME Instru- |Mal Business Capital Filed ment Stock tsth-Horner Chautauquas rnierly Western Redpath ;ith-Horner C'hautauquas rnierly Western Redpath em) Amendt Kai Kans: Mo ua System) Amend't Mo. 0 Mai r John F. Company . . . Articles Omaha 10,000 May the Fred. Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 May n... Amend t Omaha 00 May - :l)lican River Power Articles Omaha 100,000 Maj -I Company Amend t Omaha 25,000 May : .1 Motor Company Dissolu- tion Neb. City Jun tion Neb City Jui. - &amp; Rose Live ck Commission Co. (for- merly Roberts Brothers).. Amend't So. Omaha July 3 1913 merly Roberts Brothers) . . Amend't Omaha Julj Rehner. R. A Company Dissolu- Rehner. R. A Company Dissolu tion Columbus July 15 1913 tion Columbus July 15 191 Ju 1 •. Company Dl ny Dissolu - tion lumbus Julj Columbi tion • I Baler Manufacturing d Baler Manufacturing Company Articles Lincoln 100.000 Aug. 30 Company Article \ Ticket Co. Articles Omaha 20,000 Sept. 19 191! Omaha i (The) Incubator Com- pany Amend't Omaha Investment Co Articles Omaha 10, (V 4 1919 it Articles Ruuiolph ■ Oft- I and Reel Club. BanK .... A ton 25,000 Ont. 1 t 3 Investment Co Article If Om Arti and Reel Club 25.00 BanK . Artiflo? Lincoln A Lin BnnV . . ArtiHo- RaM 18 191! Artie Ralstc .armacal Company. . Article? Lincoln Art Lincoln Rohlff. Henry, Company Articles Omaha tt,04 IS 1»1! Rohlff. Henry. Company .... ArtieU On ■ind E!e&lt;tric Lipht Co. Articles Rosoland 10,000 1&gt; trie Llpht Co lf.OOO T Stone Company . Article Omaha . Articles So. Omaha 10.000 Jan. 15 191' 15 1914 ■ Ids (Sam) Company. . . Articles im) Company. .. Articles Dundee 10,000 Jan. V Roundup Coal Mining Co. Amend't Omaha Feb 23 tson Furniture Co Amend't Lincoln Ma 23 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 Misrt.i.i. tM.or* (OHi'uu.vrios&gt; 1 i t 4 14 4 \ ■ \ te B A r W 4 n y ha Ian. 15 1913 Con Imp • Omaha Skinner Manufacturing Com- Amend't Omaha So. Omaha Articles Omaha Omaha pany Standard Brick Company... Articles Islington 50,000 Feb. 6 1913 Sturkev Brothers Articles pany Amend t Snyder. Malone, Coffman Company Amend't Stewart-Toozer Motor Com- Jan. 22 1913 25.&lt;Wrt jan. 27 1913 25 f&gt;nn Jan. 30 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">MISCELLANEOIS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Autiior- Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place o£ ized VVhen ment Business Capital Filed Stock 191 Soor Lihusi Sokolek Articles Crete Fet Souders, A. E. Mercantile Co. Dissolu- tion \u000b Feb. 8 1913 Saronville Farmers' Grain &amp; Live Stock Co Amend't Saronville fvl) in Sardeson-Hovland Company ( formerly Sardeson Cloak Co.) Amend't Lincoln Pe IS South Exeter Telephone Co Sand Springs Articles Exeter 1 48H Feb Sand Springs Telephone Com- pany . Articles Tyron 15,000 Feb 28 South Omaha Retail Grocers and Butchers Association.. Articles So- Omaha 500 Mar. 8 1913 s Security State Bank Amend't Homer Mar. 28 1913 State Bank of Arcadia (The) Amend't Arcadia Mar. 28 1913 Staplehurst Grain Co Amend't Staplehurst Apr. 3 1913 Speice-Echols-Boettcher Co. ( formerly Elliott-Speice- Echols Co.) Amend't Columbus Apr. 17 1913 Standard Land Company. . . . Amend't Lincoln 500.000 Apr IS 1913 Sioux City Machine &amp; Tool Co. (formerly Olson Manu- So. Sioux facturing Co.) Amend't City 19 1913 Apr. St. Edwards Church Articles St. Ed- wards Apr. 24 1913 Sterling Lutheran Orphans Home Association Articles Sterling May 28 1913 Standard Chemical Mfg. Co. (formerly Standard Stock Pood Co) Amend't Omaha May 28 1913 State Bank of Elk Creek Amend't Elk Creek June 3 1913 Stapleton Co - operative Creamery Association Articles Stapleton 25,000 June 4 Strang Telephone Company Dissolu- tion Strang June 6 1913 Stidham Grain Co Dissolu- tion Omaha lJune 23 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">MIM ELLANEOUS ( OKI'OK A TIONS— (( ontinaed) w OIU'ORATE NAME PI t. \nien pan t N Niobrara Art M Articles I nunders I Articl Wane mipan \\ Conferer Inked Blue Sprg Omaha July Artie Klitz Taxicab Company IM \- Warner Co Articl Articl Julv Omaha in July ribner Agricultural Society K Dodge County, Nebraska oseph's Church of Dodge &gt;r-Harris Jewelry Com- Articl Articl Scribne Dodge J un - ruly 24 ina Articl Articl Lincoln Shelton i July 4.000 Aug 28 1913 « uu pany Shelton Pharmacy Standard Timber Company of Nebraska Articles Articles Lincoln Cozad 200,00ii Aug 10 Aug 16 1«13 Ki Side Irrigation Co.. . . ff &amp; Sons Hotel Com- pany Articles Articles Gr. Island Aloys 100.000 Aug St. Aloysius Church of Aloys Streitz Realty Company Aug 25 1913 (The) Articles Dissolu - tion Omaha il \ug Shoop - Brundage Company . Sept. 6 1913 Lincoln Sioux City Machine and Tool Company Dissolu tion So. Sioux Sept. 16 1913 City State Bank of Melbeta Articles Melbeta 10,000 Sept 22 1913 Stlvey (J. A.) Lumber Co.. Articles Inavale 15,000 Sept 30 1913 Sack Lumber &amp; Coal Co. . . . Articles Ord 100,000 Sept 29 1MI St Anthony's Church of Co- lumbus Articles Columbus Oct. 1 1913 Shrimpton Mill and Grain Co. Articles Ainsworth 25,000 wet. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">MIS&lt; KI.I. WKOl S niKI'OKATH^S— ((-ontiniHMli Kind of iiiufacturin Art I ock I Amrn t L Articles Cra Bank Articles Sutt i lepherd M in A. me y t idt Til (; Okla aw. The C. P. Co Arti On t &amp; Glas Artiil Kearr &gt;n Hardware &amp; Furni ture Co Articles Sheltc Dec " iation Benevo Order of Deer Articlet Spt Wa lari Timber Company. . Amend't Lincol &amp; Mowe Co Dissolu- tion 1 s Seward Grain &amp; Live Stock Dissolu- r Coal &amp; Grain Co Dissolu- tion Norfolk Sprineview Race &amp; Carnival n \rt ; c!es Springvipw 0 Dec. 24 1913 Sartor Jewelry Company .... Dissolu- tion Lincoln Dec. 26 1913 South Side Irrigation Co. . . . Amend't Cozad 1 Dec. 30 1913 rhood of Pleiades Dec. 30 1913 &amp; Hill Company Articles Omaha Jan. 6 1914 CORPORATE NAMK Instru- Pla( ••nt A ft tion Dec. 20 191 Articles Callawav </seg>
            <seg id="p073">\ \ I1X KIJ.ANKOI S rORl'KKMIoNs ,i ntinoetl M \r O McC«ffi-ee Compar Apr Wyn Artirlps Stapl Apr Apr. 1 ; Bank of Nebraska ... Amend! Bruns- Apr. 1 Articles Brunswic I't Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p074">MISCELLANEOUS lOKFOKATIO&gt;S-(tontiBuwl) Auth&lt; IN- Kind of Place of ized When Business Capital Piled CORPORATE NAME Instru- ment Stock :ary's Church of Schuy- 16 1914 Articles Schuyler Apr Standard Auto Tire Company .Dissolu- A|pr tion Lincoln ity State Bank Articles So. Omaha 500,000 M&gt;r. 10,000 Apr 24 1914 u Company (The) Articles Plattsm'th Skinner Manufacturing Com Apr 1914 pany Amend't Omaha City Improvement i May Company (The) Articles Steel May i:&lt;14 Bing Grain and Stock Co. Amend't Sterling rity State Bank Articles Lawrenct ■i May 6 1914 Sunnyside Northern and Southern Telephone Com- pany (The) Dissolu- 1914 tion Long Pine May St Peter's De Alcantara May 6. 1914 Church of Ewing Articles Ewing South Omaha Live Stock Ex- change Dissolu- tion So. Omaha May 9. 1914 11 1914 25,000 May Security Staie Bank Articles Oxford St. Mary's Church of Prairie Center Articles Prairie May 16 1914 Center South Omaha and Western Railroad Co. (The) Dissolu- tion Omaha May 26 1914 Shelton Racing Association 10 1914 18 1914 (The) Articles Shelton 5,000 June 30,000 June 25,000 July Security State Bank Articles Curtis Star Clothing Company ..... Articles Lincoln Santo Domingo Colonization Company Articles Phoenix, A Stickel Lumber Company (W. 75,000 July 10 1914 L.) Amend't Kearney July 13 1914 Samaritan Army, (The) Articles Norfolk July 17 1914 Scottsbluff Mortgage Loan Company Articles Scottsbluff K0 July 0 July 21 1914 28 1914 Security SUte Bank .. Articles Spalding </seg>
            <seg id="p075">n§CELLAHK&lt;MJ8 &lt; OKl'OK V ll&lt;&gt;&gt;&gt; i Continued) Kind of Author- Author Kind of CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place ot ' lze&lt;1 Wllen ORPORATE NAME Instn ment Business Capital Filed ment Stock Stock Sargent State Bank Articles Sargent Sargent State Bank Articl •00 Au*; Security Savings Bank ...... Amend't Fremont ecurity Savings Bank ...... Amend't Spencer Hospital and Train ing School Articles Spencer Spencer Hospital and Train Articl Spencer Omaha ng Schoc Shafer &amp; Co., M. F ■ ? Omaha Kr A: Co., M. F V Proi-: Dissolu- Shelby Propr uti. IMssolu- i tion lby State Bank of Wolbach. V braska Articles Wolbach Wolbach Litchfield J00 Aus State Bank of Utchfield. . . . Articles Utchfield State Bank of Litchfield. ... Stadium Speedway Company (The Articles Articles Omaha Lincoln Sept. 11 Stoddard Company (T Skinner Manufacturing Com Amend"t Articles Articles Dissolu - tion pany Omaha Sept 1 15.14 Sunnyside Hastings Omaha Sept Steril Waterproof Fabri' Standard Filler Machine Co lO.Oii Omaha Oct Oct State Bank of Deweese . . . State Bank of Huntley .... Southern Cypress Pole &amp; Pil Amend't Amend't Huntley ing Co Articles Articles Omaha 25,00. 100,000 Oct State Bank of Grand Island. Simplex Tire Repair Com Gr. Island Articles Omaha Sacred Heart Church of Bur well Articles Amend't Dissolu - tion Eurwell Omaha Oct. N'ov 2 : ; 9 ,;: State Bank of Omaha Schneider-Lindermann Co. Snyder Nov. 5 1914 Scotia Farmers Grain &amp; Sup ply Co Articles Articles Scotia Seward 10,000 Nov 10,000 Nov 18 1914 30 1914 Seward Realty Company Tekcosocket Manufacturing Co. . Articles Holdrege 100,000 Dec. 25,000 Dec 12 1912 Tobias State Bank Articles Tobias 21 1912 Trevett, Mattis &amp; Baker Com pany Articles Beatrice 100,000 Dec. 24 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">''^ r'j J^\*J I • I F i I 1 £3 Fj\ #^^^ fj x I v X v^^P ij -1 — * i w * nSCELLAVKOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Aut kind of Place I'ORATE NAME Instru Cat St( Dissolu - tion *r 14 Land Company Aiti maha ■akery Company L \ loue Con Arti T l t;i Sok( Arti 4ii rt in, bull. ii. M. Lumber Vmend't Hildret ipany xn &amp; Building A Jul ation tain F ti Amend Kurn. Co. - Amend't Articles ) Sept 1 City Omaha Articl Artul and 1 lfl Um 49,000 Dec 15 1913 Articles Dissolu - tion Omaha 16 1913 y. J. B. Co. Limited Lincoln Dec. 19 1913 Thomas, (J. S.) &amp; Son Dissolu - tion Lexington Valentine Crawford Lincoln T Cattle Company Articles Articles Articles Thorp (G L.) &amp; Son Co Timitoh (The) Cone Company Thomas (Melville D ft Co... Thompson (O. D.) Company Theatrical Mechanical Assoc- Articles Articles Omaha 10,000 Mar 50,000 Mar Gr. Island iates ford Bank Rr County Telephone ipany City ittle Company • ;ilty Co. vor Company &gt;!&gt; Bakery Company kAmend't 'anical A and Canada. Omaha fo. 38 Articles D&lt; Dec. 29 1913 125,000 Jan. 12 1914 ■I Feb. 2 1914 25,00rt Feb. 28 1914 2 1914 3 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">M1SIKLLA&gt;£OI S (OKPOKAih»* i ( ..iiliiii.. il N Art ti' \). .. I A At Comnanv T ling I.iimbpr ft Coal Com </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Kh.rUK I Or irit. t&gt;h*C KKl AIO OK STATfcl MISCCLLASEOUS CORPORATIONS- (Continued) Author- Kind of CORPORATE NAME lnstiu- Hlace of ized Wh mem isiness Capital Kilt Wlu Stock pany Articles i Uehling 50,00" 40,000 Mar 6,00i' L'pham (Lynne D.) Co ; Articles Omaha 1914 United Clothes Shop Amend't Omaha 21 1914 Union Realty Company [Dissolu- tion Omaha June 25 1914 I ngles Hoggette Manufactur ing Co Amend't Lincoln July 9 1"11 United Machine Company (The) Articles Omaha 1,000 Sept 18 1914 Union Hall Association (The) Dissolu tion Mead Nov. 25 1914 Vogel Book Company Articles Omaha 5,000 Jan 24 1913 Von Seggern Auto Co Dissolu- tion Way in 'Mar 1 1913 Valparaiso Social Club Articles Valparaiso June 7 1913 Van Brunt Automobile Com- pany (Inc.) 'Articles Co. Bluffs 25,000 July 10,000 Feb. 12 1913 4 1914 24 1914 6 1914 Vienna Restaurant ; Articles Sidney Valparaiso Telephone Co. . . . Amend't Valparaiso Mar Vegetone Drug Company . .[Articles Lincoln 15,000 Aug Van Sickle Glass and Paint Company Amend't | Lincoln Aug. 18 1914 Vibrating Electric Razor Co. Articles Lincoln 500.000 Aug 19 1914 Valentine Hospital Associa- tion Articles !Valentine 20 1914 Aug Western Mail Transfer Com- pany Articles Gothenburg 100,000 Jan 40,000 Jan 10 1913 16 1913 Wilke - Mitchell Company. ..Amend't jOmaha Workman Building Associa- tion I Articles i Lincoln 50,000 Jan. 25,000 Jan. 22 1913 30 1913 Western Sales Company .... Articles Omaha Wa k e f i e 1 d Manufacturing Company Amend't jWakefield 100,000 Feb. 25.000 Feb 1 1913 18 1913 Wilson Investment Company Articles ;Fremont Woodmen Accident Associa tion i Amend't 'Lincoln Feb 19 1913 100.000 Mar Woods Updike Land Company Articles (Lincoln 1913 rn Furniture Co Dissolu- tion Lincoln Mar 19 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">V MIS4 ELLA'S EOia &lt; OKI'OK VTIO&gt;&gt; &lt; &lt; ontiniu -.1. K Arti Arti M Omah iar rn Alt &gt;r Wauneta Farmers Amend Wauneta it.yoo Apr Teh phone ( tern Brick &lt;V Supply Hastma An "I Apr Western (The* Saving vestment and Loan Conr \r Lincoli pany Wondt Lincoln »00 Junt Amend pany orks Dissolu Wak Wak. 1^ 1 tion June Wantland A: Company Shclton Land Hissolu- n Land Dissolu Com pan) tion Omaha June 1 II June 1 i;,l tior Waterloo Creamery Company Amendt Co. Bluffs m e M 19 iO June 1 Waterloo Creamery Company Amend Western Ranch Company Articles Omaha "' June L'l 19 Western Ranch Company. ... j Article June 21 191 Wauneta &amp; Galena Teleph&lt; Co Dissolu - te™ Nebraska Landtion GaL Jui Galena June rn Nebraska Land tion Company Dissolu- .In ompany tion tion Welch Grain Company Dissolu- Dissolu tion Oni. I . 191 tion Omaha »n Real Estate Cm • rn Real Estate Com Amendt Omaha Amend't Omaha "i Au s (The) Invests pany Articles Omaha 60,000 Aug. 4 19 60,000 Auk Articles Omaha Company rn Savings Investment •n Savings Investment ■ Loan Company JAmendt Lincoln , J. K. Lumber Company Ar . adia lngton and Western Tel- Loan Company ;Amend't Lincoln 1 1! .1. K Lumber Company Arti. idia "it Aug. I .000 Auk lgton and Western Tel- ne Company Amendt Verdigre I 19 26 191 Amend't .Verdigr \ Oswald - Childs Com- Art: Omaha Sept • Oct. Articles So. Omah -n Manufacturing Co. Articles Omaha 4 19 51230CH </seg>
            <seg id="p080">-1 .»! I &gt;( h LL V * r. Ol N lUKluKATIONS ( (on til) tied, i author-| Kuai at CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place ot ized kment ttusi»est&gt; Capil File.l Slock ht (The) Company So. Sioux it (The) Company So. Sioux Articles City 5,000 Oct. 11 la Articles City 5,000 Oct. 11 191 Clothing Company .... Articles Clothing Company .... Article* Coleridge 15,000 Oct. 8 IS Coleridge 15.00U ( • loon Implement Co. ... Articles Winnetoon 10,000 Oct. 6 19 ■ toon Implement Co. ... Articles Winnetoon 10,000 Oct. 6 1 tern Artit Water System Articles Whitney ihj Aut. 2S II Whitney JO Aujj '1 .and Credit Company 'Articles Spencer 50,00" Ivi. 6 1U The) Petersoni Land Credit Company'Artu Spencer 50,00u Pec. 6 1 i Articles Ong 25,000 Jan. 2 19 Ong iward (The) -Thomas - Co Article;- Aurora 1u,o&lt;m Jan. 2 IS Aurora 10,000 Jar. Washington &lt;t Western reie- . 'Amend' Amend't Verdigre 9,975 Jan. 5 19 Verdigre y,yT5 Jan. 5 1914 rn Tent &amp; Awning Co. Articles tern Tent &amp; Awning Co. Articles Lincoln 10,00o Jan. 19 IS Lincoln 10,00u Jan. 19 1914 ifl 1 Wood Lake l.,i:iioer Company Articles Wood Lake 24,000 Jan. 30 IS in Securities Co Articles Omaha 8,000 Feb. 18 IS Brothers Articles Omaha 250,000 Feb. 20 If. H- i Dry Lake LjrnDer Company Artie Wood Lake 24,000 Jan. 30 1914 i in Securities Co Articles Omaha 8,00" F&lt; i ■i Brothers Artie Omaha 250,00u Feb. 20 191 I! i Dry Beatr: 35,00" Feb. 24 191 35,00" Feb. 24 It :e Manufactur- den Package Manufactur- ing Co Dissolu- Co Dissolu- tion Omaha Feb. 24 1! tion Omaha Feb. 24 191 Company Dissolu - tion Omaha Feb. 26 If. 'o Amend't Columbus 25, 00^ Feb. 28 1J ment Store ..Amend't N. Pi 50,000 Mar. 3 If rigation Co. Amend't Fremont Mar. 16 If Article! Fall-; I 40,0&lt;&gt;i&gt;Mar. 19 1- urapany Diss&lt; tion Omaha Columbu N. Platt ■ Fe-b Feb Mar Mar n o Amend't 19 \ tment Store .. Amend' If 1 r Trrisation Co. Amend't Art 1 Falls C i'ford &amp; Son Co. Dissolu - tion Omaha 31 11 ford &amp; Son Co. Dissoh tion Omaha Omaha Omaha V.lrt A !d Advertising Co. Inc. Articles Omaha 10,00" Apr. 8 1! • Inn Company . . . Artie les Omaha 25. ' 18 If • ■ Company Jverttslng Co. Inc. Articles Apr. Inn Company . . . Arti 9^. Arti ewellen 10,000 May 2 1! c tore Article? . . Article? Uncoln 25.00" May 7 V. Lincoln 25.0 ■K ink (Thel Amf The) Amend't Weston May 28 1! ,r Weston May 28 i Serum Company . . . Dissolu- tion Pla&lt; June 2 1! PlattpiPtl: June 2 19 ■rn Elevator Associa Lake Rank Amend't </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 MISCELLANEOUS t UKl'OKATIoVs . ( •.ntiiiiied.; ■U 1U uI I .,„„ Plai ized \Vh&lt; ap ah A \ I o ti Ju Webster City Elevator Co.. . .Articles lOmaha UM &amp; Articles 'Omaha 5,0f 50,00 Articles Omaha rd Brothers Articles Lincoln V \ w Articles IWatertow 10,000 Sept o.OOii 3 1914 Ison. . .Articles Omaha 10,000|Oct 1914 \Tti la Dis Omaha tion rownli 50,0" 1914 Art \ Arti 40,00' i oln 5,0c 100,000 Feb \ Or Island 191 ppi 28 1913 14 1913 ncoln Mar C A. pany A 500,000 May 100,000 July 60,000 July M \rt Hi pan 3,000 Apr. 50,000 Aug 40,000 Aug v \ maha V Pi Articles Tor 6,000 Sept 3.000 Oct. n p York Quality tv D Zenith Products Co o. Omaha &gt; Dec M ltll </seg>
            <seg id="p082">RKPOHT ( U KOKili-N ( OIU'OIMilONS Appointing Hoiiii in Aifcnl&gt; in the State &lt;&gt;f Kebmsk Name of Corporation. Name of Corporation Adder (The) Maciiin.- Compai ! Adder (Th.-i Machine Company American Tire A: Uubi • American Tire A: Hubl pany pany American Steel &amp; Wtri New .Jersey a, N. J. , Wliite Lead I American Steel &amp; Wire Co. of New Jersey Works ... Avery Scale Company North Milwa ■ , Wi*. . I American Linseed Oil Compa Atlas Oil Company rican Linseed Oil Compaii Atlas Oil Company rican Bridge Company jlloboken, N. J. I American Bridge Compa American Linseed I Ho Jer American Lin I American Multigraph Sales (The) Building and Farm I poration Borden's Condensed Milk B inpany New York ( Borden's Condensed Mil Company \ Cherry County Cattle Comp iiany. . . Cusaek. Thomas. Cor;&gt; Carman Laundry Supply Co Cherokee Manufacturing Com Che pany Cu^ahy Refining Company Ch Equitable Mortgage and Trus Co. (The) Falls City Construction Co le, K Fairbanks. Morse &amp; Co Fleisrhmann Yoast Co. (The) . Goodrich (B. F.) Rubber Com panv Akron, f i 191- 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">I ION it in-. I i Apr. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 FOUKB COBPO1ATI0N8 f 1 ..iiiiiii»-.l.i Plac Busi Place of Name of Corporation. Bu^ " FiIed Name of Corporation York Wyoming Oil &amp; Gas I ork Wyoming Oil &amp; I Co Sheridan. Wyo. So. Oi Sheridan. Wyo. So. Omaha Aug. 2 Nichols &amp; Shepliard Company.. LSattlo Cre Nichols &amp; Shepliard Company. Mich Lincoln 1914 i Lincoln Nebra i Klectrir Co.... Dover, Dela... On. inia Rubber Company New York &lt; Nebr;. Electric Co.... Dover, Dela... 0 ■ Ivania Rubber Company'New York ( N. V. . unaha.. . 1913 H. Y Omaha. i O-Lite Company, Inc New York Citj • O-Lite Company, Inc New York C N. T Omaha.... N. Y Parker Gordon Cigar Company St. Joseph, Mo. Omaha.... Parker Gordon Cigar Companyist. Joseph, Mo. Om Penney fJ. C.) Company Salt Lake City Utah 2 1914 land Ma Pullman Company (The) 1'hicago, 111... Omaha Plckel Marble &amp; Granite Co St. Louis, Mo. Omaha Oct. 15 1D14 Pickel Marble &amp; Granite Co.... St. Louis. Mo. : Omaha Oct. 15 1D14 Royal I'nion Mutual Life Ins. Co. Des Moines, Royal Union Mutual Life Ins. Co. Des Molnt la Stuart Feb. 11 la Stuart Robinson. Straus &amp; Co St. Paul, Minn (Lincoln Api Robinson. Straus &amp; Co St. Paul, Minn Lincoln Apr. 10, Stewart. .Tamos &amp; Company. . . . New York City Stewart. .1 &lt;'ompany. . . . New York City N. Y. . .incoln Ian. 26 1913 N. Y Lincoln. . . Stwpp Brothers Bridge ft Iron Co St. Louis. Mo. Omaha July 25 1913 Stwpp Brothers Bridge &amp; Iron Sharpies Separator Company Sharpies Separator Company (The) West Chest' (The) West Chester Pa Omaha Dec. 15 1913 Pa I Omaha Dec. 15 191 Sioux City Brewing Company. . Sioux City, la. So. Sioux Sioux City Brewing Company. . Sioux City, Ia.lSo. Sioux y Jan. 12 1914 Scott (A. LI Lumber Co Kansas City Mo IDubois Mar. 17 1914 Spirella Company Inc. (The) . . New York Cit M. T Lincoln... 1914 Thomas B. Jeffrey Company (The) IKenosha, Wis. Omaha May 11 1914 United Cigar Stores Company. . ichicago. 111... Lincoln. ... July 18 1913 United Profit Sharing Corpora tion (Wilmington, Dela Lincoln Aug. 13 1914 Western Wheeled Scraper Com pany Aurora. Ill ... Omaha June 21 191 lington Apparel Company. 'Chicago. 111... Omaha ijune 30 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">KOKKMiX ( &lt;&gt;KrOKAIIO&gt;S &lt; ontimiecl A W A N </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 REPORT OF THE CORI'ORATK Kock Island and I'ac Railway Co. and Bank n r \ nt ;ent betwei-n Chics and N'on Many and The Karn: :i and Trust Edwin S. Marston Tr ment \ ! 11 Agreement between Illinois Central Railroad Co. and t,** Railroail nment and transfer be - tween Missouri Pacific Railway Co. and The Rank - ers Trust O Rel ofF Equip- Nen KAILKOAI) IMOKI'OHUi&lt;»\S VM&gt; KOI 'II'MKNT 4UREEME* Trust Compai tween 111 tral Railroad Tin- Union Trust &lt; Pittsbure </seg>
            <seg id="p087">KUI.KOVH &lt;oi;i ih;\ii..v </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 DRAINAGE DITCHES When Filed NAME Drainage Distict No. 1 of Otoe and Johnson Countie Nebraska June 18 191 Drainage District No. 1 of Frontier County. Wbraska June 16 1914 Drainage District No. 4 of Richardson Count. Julv 14 1914 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>