<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00091.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0091.0002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Department of Vocational Education</title>
               <date value="18??">January 1, 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Nebraska State Department Vocational Education I Bulletin No. 31 Report to the Nebraska State Legislature in accordance with the provisions of 79-227 C.S., 1927 for the biennium ending June 30,1939- LINCOLN, NEBRASKA State Capitol Building January 1,1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">NEBRASKA STATE DEPARTMENT : : of :\, VOCATIONAL EDUCATION State Board for Vocational Education W. W. Burr, Dean of the College of Agriculture .'. .Chairman Charles W. Taylor, State Superintendent of Public Instruction .......................-................... •¦¦ Secretary Margaret McCutchen.... ............... &gt;...........Central City : Office Staff C. A. Palmer, State Director State Supervision Agricultural Education...... ,L. D. Clements, Supervisor Howard W. Deems, Assistant Trade and Industrial Educa- I tion .. .Sidney Owen, Supervisor ¦¦¦¦'.J:''":'¦;.'• Howard L. Gorham, Assistant Home Economics Education. ..Birdie Vorhies, Supervisor 1 Rose Wanek, Assistant Distributive Education..,..... .Sidney Owen, Acting Supervisor Vocational Rehabilitation of i Physically Handicapped Per - sons ......................J.R. Jewell, Supervisor : j James R. Reed, Field Agent V ; .¦;¦¦¦"¦;.¦' ¦¦¦¦,•¦' van E. Jones,iField Agent ! Richard W.Cockburn, Field Agent ¦ ¦'¦.¦ ¦¦•' i ¦ ¦¦¦.¦' .-;j ¦-'¦- ' &#132;¦' . "¦'; ..¦'(¦•'V: ' ¦,'-'¦ Activities and Expenditures :of v State and Federal Funds During the Year Ending June 30, 1938 ,¦ - -.¦¦'¦: ': ¦"•¦ :. . ¦ •¦¦ :! ' ¦¦.;¦¦ ';¦¦¦ ¦¦.'¦¦. "¦' •;•¦ ¦•¦•¦ ' ';¦'¦. ¦' A report of the activities and expenditures of the, State Department of Vocational Education for the first year of the biennium is herewith submitted. ). NOTE: A large number of classes of various types do not begin until the last half of each year and therefore it is not possible at this time to report for the entire biennium. The expenditures and activities for the second year will be more extensive than for the . ' . first year.- ¦¦. ;. | .."; -.:; - : i; : ¦.¦ - 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p004">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page ¦State Board for Vocational Education 3 Department of Vocational Education —Office Staff 3 Table of Contents 4 State Department of Vocational Education 5 Comments on the Vocational Education Program 5 Vocational Education on a Cooperative Basis 5 Expenditures of State Aid to Schools and Federal Funds Year Ending June 30. 1938 6 Budget Requests for Biennium Ending June 30, 1941 7 Enrollment in Vocational Education Classes 8 Summary of Activities for the Year Ending June 30, 1938. .. 9 I. Agricultural Education 9-13 11. Trade and Industrial Education 13-18 111. Home Economics Education 18-21 IV. Distributive Education 21 V. Vocational Rehabilitation of Physically Disabled Persons 22 Facts and Conclusions of 16 Years 22-26 Rehabilitation Case Report for the Year Ending June 30, 1938 26-29 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">State Department of Vocational Education The State Department of Vocational Education was created by Legislative Act (C. Si 79-2201) in 1919. I The Nebraska Act enabled the State to cooperate with the Federal government in a program of Vocational Education under what is known as the Smith-Hughes Act (1917)1 &#132;-¦: i Since that time the George-Keed Act and later the George- Ellzey Act passed by Congress have supplemented funds appro - priated under the Smith-Hughes Act. The George-Deen Act passed by Congress in 1936,.superseded the George-Ellzey Act and became effective on July 1,j1937. ¦ . - '-' -¦¦¦¦-. - ¦ " .¦. ' "¦ Comments on the j Vocational Education Prog] 'am 1. AH states are cooperating \vith the Federal government. 2. The State Treasurer is custodian of all Federal funds. The department handles no cash and all funds are vouchered and warrants drawn in the usual way. i 3. All instruction is beloyr college grade. 4. The work is not duplicated by any other agency such as agri - cultural extension, including 4-H Clubs. 5. All funds, except those used for office salaries and office main - tenance, are paid to the treasurers of schools. With the excep - tion stated above, no funds are disbursed to individuals. Vocational Education on a Cooperative Basis In the state-wide program of Vocational Education local school districts assume a large part or the total expense. School district funds are supplemented by state and federal funds dis - bursed by the State Department of Vocational Education. Besides paying a considerable proportion of vocational teachers' salaries the schools provide buildings, heat, light, janitor service, equip - ment, supplies, etc. j j Funds disbursed by, the State Department of Vocational Education go directly toj school districts as a partial reimburse - ment for salaries paid to teachers for! such portion of their time as is devoted exclusively to vocational subjects. . In Trade and Industrial education, private modern industrial equipment and facilities iworth-hundreds of thousands of dollars are made available for instruction purposes free of charge. Thus it will be seen that the program of Vocational Education is on a cooperative basis with the local school district, private industry^ the State and Federal government participating. 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">The number of schools offering this practical type of training increases each year. The total enrollment of persons who received systematic training in the various types of vocational classes dur - ing the year endinjr June 30, 1938, was 25,418 which was an in - crease of 14.4%, or 3,137, over the year before. Expenditures of State Aid to Schools and Federal Funds Year Ending June 30, 1938 Agriculture State and State Federal Federal State Director $ $ 951.15 $ 951.15 State Supervision 3,872.51 3,872.51 Day Schools 50.00 80,067.65 80,117.65 Adult Classes 692.15 692.15 Young Farmers' Classes 2,790.55 2,790.55 Totals $ 50.00 $ 88,374.01 $ 88,424.01 Trades and Industries State Director $ $ 452.52 $ 452.52 State Supervision 2,328.49 2,328.49 Local Supervision 381.83 1,435.66 1,817.49 Day Schools 1,467.84 8,486.46 9,954.30 Evening Schools 835.40 4,702.03 5,537.43 Part-time Schools 1.655.45 10,960.46 12,615.91 Totals $ 4,340.52 $ 28,365.62 $ 32,706.14 Home Economics State Director $ $ 832.26 $ 832.26 State Supervision 3,713.02 3,713.02 Local Supervision 135.00 1,128.47 1,263.47 Day Schools 28,739.75 28,739.75 Evening Schools 646.51 11,676.84 12,323.35 Totals $ 781.51 $ 46,090.34 $ 46,871.85 Distributive Education State Director $ $ 141.96 $ 141.96 State Supervision 708.41 708.41 Evening Trade Extension 210-'i4 432.60 643.00 Totals * 210.34 * 1,283.03 $ 1,493.37 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Teacher-Training and Supervision Agriculture ......... I.s 3,485.22 $ 7,290.76 $ 10,775.98 Trades and Industries U 1,169.56 4,029.25 5,198.81 Home Economics.....l. - 5,793.84 7,548.15 13,341.99 Distributive Education . ... 73.14 73.14 '.:./...- Totals .;. .$10,448.62 $ 18,941.30 $ 29,389.92 GRAND TOTALS.. $15,830.99 ; $183,054.30 # $198,885.29 ?Combined Smith -Hughes and George-Deen Funds. Budget Requests for the Biennitun Ending June 30,1941 '¦;¦ •;.¦¦ State Funds : Increase &gt;,-: ¦ : ' . ' . .'. '¦ ¦-.¦¦ '.'• :¦¦¦¦ ','¦ i '•'••' Present:- ¦¦ ¦' or ¦ Requested Biennium Decrease 1. (#290) Salaries and ' ! ; Wages ...........$ 27,200,00 ($27,200.00) 2. (#291) Maintenance 10,000.00 ( 8,500.00) +$1,500.00 3. (#292) State Aid to Schools .......... 80,000.00 ( 100,000.00) — 20,000.00 4. (#294) Vocational I - Rehabilitation of I Physically Disabled Persons .......... »56,850.00 ( 50,255.76) +6,594.24 T0ta15....,".:... .^5174,050.00 ($185,955.76) —$11,905.76 ?Of this amount not to exceed $10,000.00 is authorized to be used for necessary maintenance and physical restoration in rehabilitation cases. : Bequests are $11,905.76 less than amounts appropriated for the current biennium. i Federal Funds 1. (#293) Smith- ! , ; Hughes ........ ..$164,561.08 ($164,561.08) $........ 2. (#296) George-Deen 385,368.54 ( 394,144.70) — 8,776.16 3. (#295) Vocational Rehabilitation of :] Physically Disabled ; Persons .:......;. 46,850.00; (46,850.00) _ 11J _ L^: T0ta15..,......] $596,779.62 ($605,555.78) —$8,776.16 Bequests are $8,776.16 less than amounts appropriated for the current biennium. [ : Total Bequests State Funds . ....j. .i.........511,905.76 Federal Funds ................ 8,776.16 | V ' $20,681.92 Less than for v ! ¦¦¦•' present biennium 7 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">ENROLLMENT IN VOCATIONAL EDUCATION CLASSES Agriculture Male Female Total High School Departments 2,891 2 891 Adult Classes 373 , &lt; &lt; 'gyg Vounsr Farmers' Classes. 631 631 Total 3,895 3,895 Trades and Industries All-Day Schools 272 22 294 Adult Classes (Evening) 2,380 65 2,445 Part-time Classes (ieneral Continuation 173 295 468 Trade Extension 203 1,221 1,424 T^l 3,028 1,603 4,631 Home Economics Day Schools 67 3,219 3,286 Adult Classes 528 11,968 12,496 Total 595 15,187 15,782 i Distributive Education Evening Trade Extension Classes... 127 137 264 Teacher-training Agriculture 213 213 Trades and Industries 158 50 208 Home Economics 6 416 422 Distributive Education 2 1 3 Total 379 467 846 Grand Totals 8,024 17,394 25,418 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p009">SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES FOR THE YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1938 Aid to Schools I. Agricultural Education A complete program &gt;of Agricultural Education as con ducted by the Vocational Agriculture department of a higl school is not confined to work with high school student alone. Young Farmers' classes for farm boys not regularli enrolled in school and adult classes in Agriculture for activi farmers of the community, are important phases of th&lt; program. a. Adult Classes in Vocational Agriculture Adult classes in Vocational Agriculture giving systematic instruction to adults who hare already enterec the vocation of farming, are practicable .wherevei there is a department of Vocational Agriculture. Meth ods of farming are changing constantly with the de velopments in machinery, discovery of new facts anc the consumers' demands and standards of living. Prog - :/ ¦!:,,- ress depends upon the rapidity with which the farmei . changes, his thinking and operations to meet the new - .:" ,;¦¦¦¦ conditions. His adjustment will be in direct proportior to new knowledge gained. The adult class in agriculture : ¦;', offers an opportunity for the farmer to obtain this new |; knowledge. A local school maintaining a department oi I Vocational Agriculture may through adult classes extenci '¦'| its influence and usefulness in the community. ¦'•;.'¦'v : Federal and School Center State Aid ; Albion ......,....... .... ................ .$ 47.50 Broadwater ¦..:'........................... 41.25 Campbell .../........................... 37.50 Gothenburg ............................. 47.50 Kearney ....:...........i. .... ...'&lt;. .. 53.40 Lexington ............................... 43.75 Loup City ....................;;..;...... 45.00 North Loup ............................. 7aoo : Orleans ............'......&gt;,............. 40.50 Ravenna 42.50 Seward .'.... .. ...................... 60.00 Sidney ......;"....:......;............... 57.00 Waverly ....;...... 60.00 York ............................;....... 4G.25 Total ...........................$692.15 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Enrollment —373 adult farmers. i Average amount State and Federal aid per student for the course was $1.85. Amount of reimbursement is based upon the length of the course. b. Young Fanners' Classes in Vocational Agriculture Classes for young farmers, not regularly enrolled in school, are feasible in many districts in which Vocational Agriculture departments are maintained. They offer suitable schooling to the large out-of-school group of farm boys in the community between the ages of 14 and •lii. many of whom have dropped out because the regular courses ottered did not seem to meet their needs. In Young Farmers' Classes the boys may receive j instruction in agriculture and related subjects during the \ fanner's "slack season." The work is largely concerned j with "doing things" rather than book study. Laboratory ( and shop-work constitute a large part of the course. The ' Young Farmers' Classes so interest many boys that they return to complete the high school course for graduation. A recent survey indicates that there is a surprisingly large number of out-of-school young men on the farms of eveiT community, to whom such courses appeal as being practical and very much worth while. Federal and School Center State Aid Albion $ 95.00 Beatrice 90.00 Eagle T5.00 Fullerton 84.00 Geneva 80.00 Hastings 120.00 Holdrege 100.00 Kearney 106.80 Keya Palm Co. H. S., (Springview) 87.00 j Lexington 87.50 Loup City 90.00 Lyons 85.00 Nebraska City 110.00 Nehawka 73.50 Neligh 82.50 Ord • 107.50 Pawnee City 200.00 Randolph 90.00 Ravenna 85.00 Sargent TT.SO Scribner 85.00 Shelton 75.00 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Strattoh 100.00 Stromsburg. 85.00 Tekamah ......... A 93.00 Verdigre ...... .............;...'... 80.00 Wakefieia 80.00 Walthill. ........... i... 85.00 Wauneta ¦„•'.. '.. .. 87.50 West Point ... .. &gt;.'¦... 93.75 Total. ................j... $2,790.55 Enrollment—63l out-of-school farm boys. Average amount of State and Federal hid per pupil for the course was $4.42. Amount of reimbursement is based upon the length of the course. j c. High School Agriculture departments \ High school courses in Vocational Agriculture are designed for the training of boys preparing for the vocation of farming. The boys Jearn by doing through direct participation in the activities of the class-room, laboratory, shop, barnyard, farm-home and field. The old approved and well established farming procedures, supplemented by the newer scientific jmethods in crop production, animal husbandry, farm mechanics and gen - eral farm management are studied and! put into practice by the future farmers enrolled. Courses for two, three or four years may be offered. ¦¦¦¦'¦ •¦¦¦¦.: '¦• •' ¦: ::-'¦';'.¦¦ ¦'¦¦.";; . :¦: ' ";-.i Federal and School Center State Aid Ainsworth ....;"...... •;........ &lt; .... .|.. .$ 949.43 Albion ...;................,.......!... 1,087.00 Alliance ¦¦...',¦ ;.!... 1,064.29 Anselmo ......................... . 483.81 Auburn ..... '... ...................... 893.18 Beatrice .......................... .J... 991.69 • Big Springs ..............;........|... 800.73 Bridgeport ............;...... .....1... 1,045.38 Broadwater . .:...'....... ........... J... 589.62 Broken Bow ...................... .1... 883.50 Burwell .;........;................!... 872.35 Callaway ...........-.............. j... Y17.06 Campbell ......................... J... 914.G3 Central City .(... 1,074.41 Chase Co. H. S. (1mperia1)......... J... . 854.36 Crawford .....;.............;......... 994.86 *Crete .....;.......,...,........... 797.10 Cozad .............. .......... j... 1,000.50 DeuelCo. H.S. (Chappe11)......... J... 078.15 Eagle ............v..,v...........i... 804.36 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Fairbury 977.36 Falls City 1,112.10 Filley 454.33 Friend 544.94 Fullerton 957.11 Garden Co. H. S. (Oshkosh) 706.68 Geneva 910.31 Genoa 815.25 Gordon 1,112.62 Gothenburg 1,120.93 Hastings 1,423.49 Hay Springs 1,141.23 Hebron 1,025.00 Holdrege 1,194.86 Kearney 1,219.96 Keya Paha Co. H. S. (Springview) 967.83 Kimball Co. H. S. (Kimball) 927.72 Laurel 816.01 Lewiston 793.23 Lexington 1,050.29 Litchfield 787.66 Loup City 1,075.03 Lynch .. 905.68 Lyons 916.12 Mead 696.89 Milford 1,092.59 Milligan 637.92 Minden 1,024.99 Nebraska City 1,163.12 Nehawka 526.44 Neligh 946.68 Nelson 955.22 Newman Grove 916.53 North Loup 758.49 Ord ! 1,191-92 Orleans 961.56 Otoe Cons. H. S. (Barneston) 772.42 Pawnee City 1.084.23 Perkins Co. H. S. (Grant) 974.31 Ponca ••• 772.98 Randolph 992-39 Ravenna 1,002.45 Red Cloud 822.79 Riverview Oons. H. S. (Holmesville).... 455.88 Rock Co. H. S. (Bassett) 1»01H Rushville 1,077.76 St. Edward 805.29 Sargent 859.92 Scotia 796.93 12 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Scribner ... • ......;.... 1,046.19 *Seward 930.49 Shelton ............ ....... 1.... 795.86 Sidney .....:.... 1,340.00 Sioux Co. H. S. (Harri50n)..,.....;.... 912.26 Stapleton ............;... ..:.......... 883.16 Stratton ...........;.... 1,075.37 Stromsburg 932.16 Tecumseh ........... .,... ................ 1,147.71 Tekamah ........... ...:.........:.... 1,044.59 Verdigre ......;......:..........:.... 952.59 Wakefield ................:.......1.... 873.27 Walthill ..;.... 549.57 Wauneta ............................. 954.03 ?Waverly ............................. 892.62 West Point ............... /... ...: .... 1,089.16 Wilcox ....;.......................... 87Y.55 York .............. ..... .. .v........... 1,007.43 Total ...................¦.[.... .$80,117.65 * Teacher-training centers for practice teaching. •¦¦ Enrollment— 2,B9l boys. ):¦'.' Average amount of State and Federal aid for tbe year per pupil was $27.69. Amount of reimbursement is based upon the time the teacher devotes to agricultural subjects. The following named schools have been added to the list : for the year ending June 30, 1939; Clarkson, Franklin, Gering, Hooper, North Platte, Schuyler, Sutton and :. :¦ Wisner. "¦' :;';¦. ''/ ¦;..- :'. •|. . - U. Trade and industrial Education a. Evening Trade and Industrial Glasses for Adults A program for the further training of Nebraska workers. It is designed to keep them up-to-date in new developments of their trades, to make them more secure in their jobs and to insure against unemployment. Evening school people are usually adults with families to maintain. While it may not be a cure for all unem - ployment certainly it is a remedy for unemployment. The night school is a very economical form of &#132; training since instructors are drafted oiit of industry and paid on an hourly basis only for the time actually engaged in classroom work. The classes usually meet one or two hours per night and one or two nights per week. They meet in schools, private shops, or industrial 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">plants utilizing equipment loaned by cooperative shop owners and industrialists. The State Department of Vocational Education reimburses local schools for only a portion of the wages of the instructor. All materials, heat, light, space and equipment are supplied by local persons, corporations or agencies. This is true not only in night classes, but all other trade and industrial training programs. Courses were offered in such subjects as the follow - ing : electrical code for house wiremen; carburation for auto mechanics: practical telephony; PBX and PAX maintenance; relay adjustment and switchroom trouble shooting: telephone sub-station installation; fundamen - tals of electrical engineering; air conditioning; oxy - aeetylene welding; sheet metal pattern drafting; blue print reading and estimating; drawing and sketching; highway drawing and pavement design; highway bridge design . design, construction and maintenance of low cost bituminous highway surfaces; locomotive engine defects; machinists blue print reading; American Eailway Asso - ciation rules; Morse Code telegraph operation; first aid,'. fuels and combustion; power plant operation; general! boiler room practice; job shop welding; aluminum weld - ing: metallurgy of cast iron for welders; refrigeration and air conditioning. _ , , _ Federal and School Center State Aid Ashland $ 45.00 Beatrice 45.00 Columbus 73.13 Fa.irbury 45.00 Bering 45.00 Hartington 45.00 Kearney 82.50 Lincoln 1,935.04 Omaha •. 2,749.88 Minden 46.25 St. Paul 45.00 Scottsbluff 185.63 Stromsburg , 37.50 Tekamah 52.50 West Point 52.50 Wilber 45.00 Total $5,529.93 Coordinator for Adult Classes Kearney $ 7.50 14 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Enrollment—2,3Bo men -Go women - Total 2,445. . Average amount of State and Federal aid for the year per pupil was $2.27. b. Part-time Trade and Industrial Education (1) Part-time Trade Extension, Classes These classes enroll young men and women be - tween the ages of sixteen and twenty-one who have entered upon employment as apprentices. These ap - prentices are returned to school for a minimum of four hours per week-to receive instruction which, because it takes too much of the foreman's time and interferes with production, cannot be given on the job. Due to shortage of jobs during the past several years, youth has been denied opportunity to learn on the job as an apprentice. With, conditions in in - dustry gradually improving, the youth of the State should be given more opportunity to secure training by part-time in school and part-time on the job. Trade extension classes include instruction in the following lines: Railroad Shop; metal trades; nursing; machine shop; carpentry and electricity: household employment (domestics); cosmetology. ¦'¦ .'-¦:¦&gt; Federal and School Center : State Aid Grand Island ....:.......,....,.,..$ 567.00 Hastings ...........J............... 168.75 Lincoln ............................ • 1,494.69 Omaha ............................ 3,046.31 T0ta1....................... -$5,276.75 Coordination Grand Island, .........:............$ 60.00 ¦: Lincoln .... .' .... .....,-,/.......... 1,625.00 Omaha 1,419.34 ' Total .......... ....... • •..;.. Enrollment— -203 men-j-1,221 women— Total 1,424. Average amount of Sitate and Federal aid for the ¦;¦¦¦;' year per pupil was $5.89. V (2) Part-time General Continuation Schools Under the laws of Nebraska the board of educa - • tion in any school district having fifteen or more children between the ages of fourteen and sixteen who hold employment permits which are in force 15 </seg>
         <seg id="p016">must establish part-time classes giving instruction to such pernut holders for eight hours per week. AUen part-time classes are established permit holders are required to attend, while the classes are open upon a voluntary basis for all others between 14 and 10. At the present time, Omaha is the only city having a large enough number of employed boys and girls to warrant organizing separate a part-time school. The schedule of instruction in the part-time school is not fixed as the pupils enrolled are of varying ages and .scholastic attainments. They are employed ,„ a va ri ety o f jobs and their experiences arc those of workers rather than children. Con - sequently, to make the school best serve their need it is organ-zed on an opportunity school basis to give the pupil the things he needs and can profit by most. A new type of training on a modified apprentice basis in diverse occupations has made a promising beginning m Arapahoe, North Pktte, Omaha, hidney, Crete. Fairbury, Kearney and Lincoln. For most of these towns this program has been in opera - tion for less than a year. However, it has proved so successful that it is the present plan of the JStat- Department to include other towns as rapidly as possible. J The jobs or classifications in which young people are employed and receiving training are as follows - retail groceries; electrician; auto ekctrician; drug Ptore_ clerk; service station operator; garage me - chanic; printer; dressmaking; radio repair: general merchandise saleslady; baker; blacksmith; depart - ment head variety store; saleslady variety store; alterations: alfalfa mills; shoe salesman; cream sta - tion operator; retail clothing sales; bakery sales - automobile parts sales; ready-to-wear sales; motion picture operator; meat cutter; cook; farm machinery • repair; shoe repair; retail jewelry and watch repair; plumbing; air conditioning and refrigeration; body and fender repair; photography; battery repair; cleaning and pressing; wholesale groceries sales - glazier; retail furniture sales. In this plan the learner is placed on a job with some employer in die local town who has the neces - sary equipment on which the youth may learn the 16 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">skills of the occupation. He works on this job one - half day and during the other half day returns to school to receive technical instruction pertaining to the job or occupation for which he is being trained. This is one of the most efficient methods of training Nebraska young people for jobs because all of the equipment and one-half of the instruction is supplied by some local employer.; School boards in small towns cannot afford to buy costly equipment for training only one or two persons in each trade. This plan is therefore the only one possible in which the youth of the small town may receive trade training and Mve at home. It is also feasible for certain occupations in the larger cities. Federal and School Center State Aid Arapahoe ...."'............. .... .$ 130.28 Nortn Platte ..:...;'......;..;...... 649.32 ' Omaha ........................]... .2,780.22 Sidney .......;........,........... 675.00 Total ..;.........;..,.'. :..": ....54,234.82 Enrollment—l 73 boys—29s girls—Total 468. Average amount of State and Federal aid for the year per pupil was $8.62. \ Amount of reimbursement is based upon the time the teacher devotes to the part-time students. &gt; c. All-Day Trade Schools , j The purpose of the all-day trade school is to fit the student for advantageous entrance Upon a trade or in - dustrial pursuit and to give occupational practice and . technical instruction in related subjects, which will best fit the individual for profitable employment in wage earning occupations common to the community. •The aim is both to prepare for advantageous entrnjice upon an occupation and to assist the potential expert worker to become a thinker having a larger vision of his field of labor. v i It is not the purpose of the all-day trade school to prepare students to go directly from the class room as full-fledged expert workers. — •'¦¦¦ Federal and School Center i State Aid Falls City ................;........... .$1,010.52 Hastings .............................. 6T5.00 Lincoln &#132;. ....'....... 3,485.00 17 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Omaha 4,783.78 Total $9,954.30 Enrollment—272 boys, 22 girls. Total 294. Average amount of State and Federal aid for the year per pupil was $33.86. Amount of reimbursement is based upon the time the teacher devotes to trade and industrial subjects. d. Local Supervision Federal and School Center State Aid Grand Island $ 180.00 Lincoln 677.89 Omaha 959.60 Total $1,817.49 111. Home Economics Education a. Adult Homemaking Education A vocational homemaking department has not at - tained its maximum service in a community unless it extends its service to the homemakers as weil as to the students in the high school. It is not necessary, however, that a day school program be maintained in order to have homemaking classes organized for homemakers. The majority of the classes meet in the afternoon, many of them meet in the morning and only a few meet at night. They are organized in short units of six to ten lessons in any phase of homemaking in which a sufficient number of persons desire the work and a teacher can be secured. As units are completed an opportunity is presented to enroll in advanced unit courses. In education for the home and today's social and economic problems as they affect the home such courses as the following were offered: parent education, family life, mental hygiene, personality development, child care and development, social and family relationships, health, first aid. Under "stretching the homemaker's dollar" such courses as the following were offered: sewing, make-over garments, budgeting, canning, care and repair of furni - ture, clothing, dressmaking, gardening and foods. 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Federal and School Center State Aid Albion ....$ 791.22 Bellevue 22.80 Campbell 32.00 Fairbury 36.00 Fremont ........... • •....-...'... • • 93.75 Grand Island. 294.75 Hastings 36.00 Lincoln ................................ 3,833.32 Kandolph .....................;....... 12.00 Omaha ...............,....;........... 7,171.51 Total .:,.......... -............. .$12,323.35 Enrollment—ll,96B women and 528 men—Total 12,496. Average amount of Federal and State aid per student for the course was $0.99 (ninety-nine cents). Amount of reimbursement is based upon the length of the course, b. All-Day Hbmemalring Departments - Homemaking training is an essential part of the general education of «very girl. Courses in the day schools are at least two years in length. They are planned to give the girls training in the homemaking responsi - bilities they should be carrying at the present, and to lay a. foundation for a continued development in home - making interests and abilities. Each year's work includes units in social and family relationships; personal hy - giene ; food preparation on the meal basis; clothing selec - tion, construction and care, and child care and develop - ment. The subject matter is selected and organized by the homemaking teacher so it will be most practical for each community. | Home projects are a part of each year's work. These are supervised through home visits to cooperate with parents and through individual conferences at school. In addition to units in homemaking the course in - cludes instruction in art applied to clothing, house furnishings and decorating problems; science related to home problems; and physiology. ; Federal and School Center State Aid Albion '&#132;....................... .'¦ .:•¦.:... .$ 546.98 Allen ........................ 387.03 Arlington ............................. 266.88 Arnold ..:..;,;....,.......... : ........ 325.06 Auburn 448.33 Blue Hill .................^.... ...;. 355.04 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Brainard 405.76 Burwell 396.00 Callaway 362.50 Cambridge 362.73 Campbell 394.53 Chase Co. H. S. (Imperial) 372.66 Columbus 540.00 Crawford 423.86 David City 490.63 Deuel Co. H. S. (Chappell) 362.62 Eagle 317.29 Ewing 369.83 Exeter 403.93 Fairbury 345.72 Falls City 560.23 Farnam 269.23 Fillev 234.43 Franklin 360.57 Garden Co. H. S. (Oshkosh) 447.33 Geneva 376.16 Gothenburg 410.47 Harvard 426.70 Kearney 670.50 Keya PaJia Co. H. S. (Springriew) 442.41 Kimball Co. H. S. (Kimball) 435.01 Laurel 438.09 Lewistan 284.88 Lexington 514.92 •Lincoln, Jackson H. S 478.50 ?Lincoln. Havelock H. S 435.00 Logan Co. H. 8. (Gandy) 260.73 Lyons 385.66 Mead 402.00 Milford 480.38 Minden 401.60 Xehawka 407.54 Xeligh , 430.43 Xewman Grove 291.56 North Loup 367.05 Omaha, Central H. S 476.40 Omaha. Technical H. S 370.47 Ord 356.01 Orleans 374.00 Otoe Cons. H. S. (Barneston) 331.05 Page 394.46 Pawnee City 419.36 Perkins Co. 11. S. (Grant) 494.32 Phillips 232.54 Plainview 525.33 20 </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Bagan . 228.16 Eandolph 398.96 Bed Cloud 407.02 Biverview Cons. H. S. (Holmesville).... 277.39 Bock County H. S. (Bassett) 383.13 Eushville 440.00 Scotia .................... 352.78 . Seward 440.00 Sidney 534.47 Sioux Co. H. S. (Harrison) ............. 380.09 Stapleton .;........................... 366.30 Stromsburg 346.50 Sunflower Cons. H. S. (Mitche11)........ 225.47 Tecumseh 411.30 Tekamah ............................ 423.76 Walthill ............ 333.56 West Point ........................... 105.53 Winnebago . 213.24 Wisner ..\ ....... ............."........ 409.27 Total ..;...............;....*. .$28,739.75 ?Teacher-training centers in practice teaching. Enrollment— s,2B6 girls. Average Federal and State aid.per pupil for the year was $8.75. Beimbursement is based upon time the teacher devotes exclusively to vocational homemaking instruc - •¦¦•¦'.¦ ' tion. ;; •"¦¦• ¦':¦'¦ ¦•-.•;'¦¦¦•¦¦'. :.'. . ¦" •¦ ' ¦ The following named schools have been added to the list for the year ending June 30, 1939: Gering, Hebron, Holdrege, Liberty Bural H. S. via Morrill, Bosalie, Sargent, Valentine, Wakefield, West Point and York. c. Local Supervision . Federal and School Center State Aid Omaha ............................... $1,263.47 TV. Distributive Education a. Evening Trade Extension Classes Federal and School Center State Aid Columbus ................^.............-$25a00 Grand Island ......:.................... • 375.00 Omaha .................v v .............. 18.00 Total ...........;.. •&gt;..... •• ¦- • .$643.00 Enrollment— l 27 men and 137 woirien--Total 264. Average Federal and State aid per pupil for the year was $2.44. Amount of reimbursement is based upon the length of the course. j . 21 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">V. Vocational Rehabilitation of Physically Disabled Persons Facts and Conclusions of 16 Years This program as defined by law is the rendering of phys- ! ically handicapped persons fit to engage in remunerative j occupations and placing them in employment. The act is based : upon the simple yet logical proposition that it is "better business" for the State and Federal governments jointly to assist persons who may be vocationally handicapped as a result of physical disabilities to prepare themselves for oc - cupations in which they may become self-supporting citi - zens than it is to support them at public expense throughout a lifetime of idleness. i Concurrent with the increasing use of machines and faster i production methods in industry and agriculture and with the introduction of the motor vehicle and greater speed in I modes of travel is a tremendous increase in the number of j, those disabled by accidents. j Accidents alone disable more adults annually in Ne- i braska than were disabled from our state in 19 months of the World War. Disease takes almost an equivalent toll and nearly 500 children become disabled each year as a result of childhood diseases. Thus, approximately a total of 1500 disabled persons in the state become eligible for the services of rehabilitation ea^h year. The department has found that approximately ! 60% or 900 of these persons actually are capable of self- i support when properly trained. Without special prepara - tion, many are prevented from engaging in occupations whereby they can earn their own livelihood. Many disabled persons require only counselling and I advisement with respect to— \ 1. Procedure to secure necessary physical restoration. 2. Selection of suitable occupations in which they will have a reasonable opportunity to carry on in spite of physical handicaps. ¦ 3. How to go about training themselves for the occupations .}) selected. To such persons, the department renders no direct finan - cial assistance, but it does make available suitable advise - ment services. However, the majority of disabled persons need finan - cial assistance before they can undertake training programs by which their rehabilitation can be accomplished. 22 </seg>
         <seg id="p023">".- - - With present funds and facilities the department can - not meet the needs of all who apply and must select from the eligible individuals only those who, it is reasonable to expect, 1 will become self-supporting as a result of the services rendered. During the past year, 66 persons vocationally handi - capped by reason of physical disabilities were-fitted for and placed in occupations in which they are now earning a liveli - hood. They were prepared by school training, by employ - ment training, by the provision of artificial appliances, by physical restoration and by careful readjustment to suitable occupations. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division is now assisting approximately 400 disabled persons to prepare for new occupations. Applications from an equal number are under investigation.- v j .-..'. The total earnings of 780 physically handicapped per - sons who have been rehabilitated by the Vocational Ee - habilitation Division during the past 16 years are approxi - mately $700,000 annually. These producers and taxpayers, once dependent because of vocational handicaps, are now engaged in 215 different types of occupations and by their earnings are supporting approximately 2400 persons. Every year their earnings add to the productive power of the commonwealth an income more than twice as large in amount as the total cost from both State and Federal funds of financ - ing the entire 16-year program. ;•;. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division has organized cooperation with the three following state departments : 1. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division has a perpetual agreement for cooperation with the State Compensation Court for the interchange of information regarding cases upon which there is joint departmental action. 2. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division annually makes an agreement with the Nebraska State Employment Service by which the two departments have free inter - change of information on cases in which joint action is necessary. The two departments work closely together to the end that physically handicapped persons may be given a reasonable opportunity to enter occupations in which they are capable of doing the work so that they may not be unfairly exploited or discriminated against. 3. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division has an agree - ment for cooperation with the Crippled Children Divi - sion of the State Child Welfare Department for the inter- 23 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">change of information on cases requiring joint depart - mental action. Federal acts, under which Federal funds become avail - able to Nebraska for use of the above mentioned state de - partments, require that such cooperative plans be in force. The Vocational Rehabilitation Division cooperates closely with other agencies such as the State Orthopedic Hospital, the State University Hospital, the State Tubercu - lous Hospital, the State School for the Deaf and the State School for the Blind, the State Elks Association Crippled Children Committee, the Shrine Hospital Committee, the International Society for Crippled Children, the American Foundation for the Blind, the American Federation of Organizations for the Hard of Hearing, Inc., the American Legion, insurance companies, employers, labor organizations and other public and private agencies to the end that the maximum number of persons who are unemployed as a result of physical disabilities may have opportunity to reestablish themselves as productive, self - supporting citizens. Needs for Expansion The economic situation during the past few years has made it increasingly difficult for physically handicapped persons to secure employment. It also has greatly reduced the opportunities for securing trade training by the em - ployment or apprentice training method. Employers now frequently say, "Why should I employ a man with a physical handicap when I can easily find an able-bodied man to do the job?" The Social Security Act has further added to the diffi - culties of securing training opportunities as well as employ - ment for physically handicapped men and women. The Act functions adversely for two reasons— 1. Many employers know that the addition of one employee, even though that employee be.an apprentice under a training program, will result in their having a minimum of eight employees and in their coming under the Un - employment Compensation Act and having to pay unem - ployment compensation fees at a cost of several hun - dred dollars per annum. 2. Also, the Unemployment Compensation Act causes em - ployers to discriminate against physically handicapped persons because an employee who is released by one em - ployer but is quickly absorbed by another creates no liability against the unemployment compensation fund 24 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">with its resultant eventual premium payment penalty against the first employer. Consequently, no employer wishes to hire an employee, even though he is capable, if such employee has a physical disability that will make it unusually difficult for him to secure new employment should the first employer find it necessary to release him. Therefore, within the last year, the difficulties ordi - narily to be surmounted in the placement of physically handicapped persons in permanent employment or in em - ployment or apprentice training situations have been mul - tiplied, v; Emergency Maintenance and Emergency Physical &#132;-.•¦¦- Restoration The demands of physically handicapped persons for services of vocational rehabilitation have been so heavy that the department has required that the applicants them - selves and their families provide living maintenance during necessary training programs or that such funds be supplied by county commissions, fraternal and civic bodies, local relief agencies or other persons directly concerned. Securing maintenance through local voluntary and public relief agencies has always been difficult and the difficulty has been tremendously increased by depression and drouth. Local relief agencies, while willing to grant necessities of life to physically handicapped individuals for care at their places of residence, frequently are unable to grant the slightly additional maintenance expense that would enable them to take advantage of a training or voca - tional rehabilitation preparation program elsewhere whereby they might become self-supporting. "Where the apprentice or employment training method was followed for preparing an applicant for an occupation, it frequently has been possible to so arrange the training that the person might do sufficient productive work during the training program to enable the employer to pay a "learn - ing" wage. The economic situation together with the situation created by the Unemployment Compensation Act has so increased the difficulty of successfully planning for the main - tenance of physically handicapped persons engaged in training programs that we find it necessary to discontinue the training of many individuals within a few months of completion due to failure of maintenance plans. A. small maintenance fund to be used in such emergencies would 25 </seg>
         <seg id="p026">prevent many breakdowns and enable us to carry on a more I effective and economical program. | The department depends entirely upon the resources of other agencies and interested persons in arranging for the j physical restoration of trainees suffering from physical dis- I abilities. The origin of these disabilities is frequently obscure. Usually, the persons having exhausted their own ; resources before causes of the disabilities have been de - termined. To attempt rehabilitation programs in such cases without first determining the origin, nature and extent of the disabilities and ascertaining whether the conditions are progressive, arrested, or can be arrested is to waste money and to invite defeat of rehabilitation programs that may be attempted. However, not to furnish physical restoration in eases where the proper treatment may minimize the dis - abilities is a waste of public money if the rehabilitation service must train around disabilities that can and should be minimized or eliminated. Therefore, the State Board for Vocational Education asked the Governor to request in his budget message to the Legislature that $10,000 of the next state biennial appro - priation be allowed for use in emergency maintenance and in ; emergency physical restoration of applicants approved by I the Vocational Rehabilitation Division. ! Rehabilitation Case Report for the Year Ending June 30, 1938 Live roll of cases 266 Rehabilitation was completed for I 66 trainees this year. : Sex: Males .53 Females 13 66 Age: ! Under 21 5 21 - 30 35 31 - 40 13 41-50 5 i 51 and over 8 ~ 66 ! Marital status: Single 41 Married 20 Widowed, divorced or separated 5 66 26 </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Dependents:/ None '.. .'. ... .43 One . V.............................. 8 Two ..../................................ 2 Three ..]................................ 5 Four or more. 8 I 66; Schooling: , V None .................. . 0 Grades 1-3.............................. 0 Grades 4 - 6.. ... .. 3 Grades 7 - 9....;.........................15 Grades 10 "- 12....:..:. ¦..... •.............. .13 High school graduate. . .20 Post high school. .................... .15 ':¦'¦¦ '¦¦¦. ¦;¦' C'¦¦¦¦•[ '\l -¦¦¦•¦¦ ;'.:: 'V, ¦'¦¦ I 66 j Origin of disability: / Employment accident—compensable........ 11 Employment accident—not compensable.... 6 Other accident....... .................. .18 Disease ........ ......................27 Congenital ............................... 4 '.}; ¦:¦;¦ . Vv.'- ¦;: -^,:... y/'? ¦' -66 Nature of disability: . ¦ Hand :\.\...................i....,.../.. d Hands .....;........v..........;..'....... 1* Arm ...................................; 8 Foot ....!........,.:...;................ 9 Feet &#132;..........................;....-.. 1 i Leg ...::....................;....... 20 Legs ...........;.,..........;..........!. 7 . Head ...... ...&gt;............................ I=. Cardiac ..*................................ 1 TB (pulmonary) .......;.......;..... 2 Vision, partial 1055........................ 1 ; Vision, total 1055.........................|. 2 r Hard of hearing.......................... 4 ' Deai ....;.............;............;...!. 2 27 </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Back 2 Miscellaneous 2 66 The 66 Gases in Detail Disability New Occupations Arrested tuberculosis Asst. claims adjuster Hard of hearing Domestic Hard of hearing General clerical work Amputated foot Optical lens grinder Amputated arm Incubator attendant and helper Disabled legs Grocer and bookkeeper Amputated leg Watch repairman Disabled foot Optical lens grinder and bench man Amputated foot Bench mechanic, optical company Arrested tuberculosis Linotype operator Amputated feet Livestock broker Disabled leg Farm laborer Amputated leg Junior clerk Disabled leg Sketcher —millinery shop Amputated hand Farm machinery parts man Amputated foot Cook Amputated foot Janitor Disabled hand Apprentice barber Back deformity General office work Amputated leg Automobile salesman Disabled arm Apprentice barber Disabled arm General office work Disabled leg Bookkeeper Disabled legs General clerical and sales work Disabled leg Shoe repairman Amputated foot Street commissioner Amputated foot Magazine salesman Disabled legs Watch and jewelry repairman Disabled leg Stenographer Disabled hand Baker Disabled hip Rural school teacher Cardiac Apprentice barber Amputated arm Instructor in Mechanical Engineering Disabled leg Shoe repairman Amputated leg File clerk TL'iu] injury lliil cleaner and blocker Disabled /eg J'ooldceeper and stenographer Disabled leg Rural school teacher 28 </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Disabled leg General clerical worker Disabled legs PBX operator Amputated leg Beauty parlor owner and operator Amputated leg Tire repairing and retreading Defective vision Body and fender repairman Disabled hands Apprentice illustrator, newspaper Amputatedam Bookkeeper Amputated legs Houseman Amputated arm Junior clerk Disabled leg Mechanical dentist Disabled foot Loading machine, operator, coal company Bli n d House-to-house salesman, paper products Hard of hearing Domestic ".";. Back deformity Bookkeeper and stenographer Amputated arm Field contractor and supervisor • Blind Proprietor rug and leather goods store Disabled legs Glerk and general clerical work D ea f Apprentice plumber Disabled leg . Auto machinist O. . ;¦ •; Disabled leg • Manager oil burner and fuel dept., fuel company Amputated foot Night watchman, coal company &#132;._:.; Hard of hearing Fitter, ladies' apparel shop Disabled leg Stenographer - Hernia Bench mechanic, optical companyl Disabled legs .Stenographer Amputated arm Parts man, garage Amputated foot Hot tamale vender | D ea f Junior watch repairman 29 </seg>
         <seg id="p030"/>
         <seg id="p031"/>
         <seg id="p032"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>