<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00013">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00013</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>FORTY YEARS OF NEBRASKA AT HOME AND IN CONGRESS</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-08</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">74 

CHAPTER II 

TKIMMTOKIAL DELEGATES 

Whoever attempts to write history for the people of Nebraska, 
or sketch the career of |n wlac at citiieaa, meeta with many 
I— prdiairati So jmng is the State, that many of the actors 
arc still in Stage costume, and extremely sensitive as to any 
criticism apoa the ptifmira or the play. Scenes that were 
thrilling to them and heralded as tragic, divested of their surroundings 
may innocently by strangers be classed as comical. 

An eloquent authiir e said: "Eyery attempt to present on 
paper the splendid effects of impassioned eloquence, is like 
gathering up dewdrops. which appear jewels and pearls on the 
gnaa, but run to water in the hand — the essence and the 
elements remain, but the grace, the sparkle, and the form are 
gone." And so when the writer erects a statue upon the historic 
page and exclaims. "Behold the man:" the disappointed reader 
may demand. "What of the electric current that warmed the 
heart, illumined the eve. and Hushed the cheek; what of the 
hopes that impelled, the fears that retarded, the placidity or 
turbulence that dominated the inner life?" In spite of all 
hindrances and discouragements, with an apology to the "old 
settler," and a salutation to the new-comer and his juvenile 
family, the writer enters upon the theme. Xihraska in Congress. 

Her first appeanaee before the government was as a very diminutive, 
nameless infant in arms, when in April. 1803. Frame, by 
treaty, gave her mother Louisiana away, in marriage, to "Uncle 
Sam.'" In 1804 Louisiana was erected into two territories, called 
Orleans and District of Louisiana, and provision was made for </seg>


            <seg id="p002">
75 

the formation of a Slate Constitution for the Territory &lt;&gt;f 

Kns whenever the population reached tid.tMMI. Having Bell 
the siMTified amount in 1S1II, an Knabling Act was passed 
11. and in lSli' the Territory of Orleans with the name of 
liana was admitted into the Union as a state; leaving the 
«e of the purchase for future disposal. 

Ee Louisiana purchase cost the I'nited States fll,259,M0; 
such an amount due the citizens of the I'nited States, from 
ice. as should not exceed |3,750,000. 

I was bounded north by the British possessions, south by 
in. and west by the Rocky Mountains, and is to-day included 
he states of Louisiana. Arkansas. Missouri, KjUMM, 
aska. North and South Dakota, and parts of Colorado. 
ming, Montana, and Idaho. 

The name of Louisiana was changed to Missouri Territory in 
1M"_\ and later tile southern part became the Territory of Arkan 
The necessary steps beiag taken, a part known as Missouri 
became a stale June. L821. As Missouri was coming in as a slave 
stale, the free states demanded "a set-off." hence the Missouri 
&lt; 'oinpromise was enacted, to quiet "slavery agitation forever." 
and this, when ruthlessly repealed in the Kansas Nebraska Act 
of 1 v"&gt;4. precipitated the "death to slavery forever" struggle. M\ 
thai notable act, all new states subsequently formed north of 
parallel of thirty-six degree! and thirty minute*, dividing the 
Louisiana Purchase, should come in free or slave, as the people 
might determine. And so a protecting barrier was erected be 
tween Nebraska and slave territory for a term of thirty-three 
years, ending in 1 S.~ 4 . 

This wm line was extended through Texas, under certain 
conditions, on her admission to the I nion in 1845. In 1830, 
when the 1'iiion was endangered by the fiery discussion over the 
admission of California as a free state, the doctrine of non-intervention 
as to slavery was attinned: and when it was" en ne ted in 
The organic law of Nebraska that the Missouri Compromise was 
"inoperative and void," and slavery was a question exclusively 
for the people to settle, Senator Benton of Missouri declared the </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
76 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

statement was "a stump speech injected into the belly of the 
bill." Had Nebraska then been as far south as Kansas, border 
warfare would have desolated her plains, murdered citizens, 
and laid homes and cities in ashes. 

Nebraska v. as introduced to congress, by name, in 1844, when 
a bill to define her boundaries was presented to the House of 
Representatives. In 1854 the step-daughter was considered of 
sufficient age to commence superintending her future estate, 
under the direction* and instructions contained in a law of congress 
denominated the Organic Act. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
TERRITORIAL DELEGATES. 

77 

NAPOLEON B. GIDDINGS. 

ird ("oni»Tes&lt;. IMS; Jan. 5 to Mar. 4. 

In ord'-r t» "set up howekeeptag" in accordance with the customs 
and manners of tin* eMer sisterhood, a selection of an 
agent, in Iliat behalf, was made on the 12th day of Deeeaber, 
1854. The student of history will remember that Napsiewi 
Bonaparte was a prime factor in behalf of France in Mr. Jcffer 
sou's negotiations for Louisiana, and the reader of the annals of 
Nebraska notes the fact that Xapoleon B. Q&amp;dntge, of Missouri, 

was her first delegate in Congress 

The election took place seven 
Organic Act of May :!&lt;&gt;th. 18M. 
designated at twelve places in € 
Missouri Kiver. Of 800 votes, Mr 

months from the date of the 

Voting precincts had been 
ight counties adjacent to the 
. (Jiddings received 377. which 

was a majority over any one candidate's rote, though a minority 
of the whole number cast. On the 5th day of January. ls."i." ( . 
just twenty-four days after the election, the CMfTVMiMMi (Unite 
has the following entry: 

Mr. Phelps of Missouri announced that the Delegate from 
Nebraska was present and desired to take the oath of office. 
Mr. (¦iddinsrs thereupon presented himself at the bar of the 
House, and the Speaker administered to him the usual oat'i 
of office. 

The term for which he was elected was to expire on the en 
suing 4th of March, within about two months. A few days 
before the advent of Mr. Giddings to the Mouse. Mr. Mace of 
Indiana introduced a bill modifying the Kansas Nebraska law. 
and re-enacting the Missouri Compromise act to protect 
Nebraska from slavery, and for the admission of Kansas as a 
free state, which failed to pass. Hon. Thomas Hart P.enton of 
Missouri, formerly Senator, having to be absent" for a few 
days, left a short speech to be read for him by a colleague, in </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
78 

NKRRASKA STATE HISTORICAL 8OCIKTT. 

wMek he deprecated 1 1n- opening up of 1 1 ¦ « - slavery discussion 
on general priBcipiea, but especially for fear of retarding emigration, 
which was so desirable to aid and r ai onragjf I lie con 
struct ion of a l'acirtc railroad. Admitting the border ruffianism 
of .Missouri, he claimed it was the natural product of New 
England Colonization Societies, from which he had from the 
first anticipated evil. 

Bills were introduced by Mr. (iiddings as follows: To establish 
post toads; to protect the proprietors of towns in their town 
rites; to establish laud offices; and tor sarrejiag, marking, and 
opening roads. He offered amendments to establish an arsenal 
in Nebraska, and to allow $50,000 for public buildings. On 
the 31st day of January he wound up his legislative career bv 
the delivery of his maiden speech. Mr. Giddiaga said: 

I wish tn say :i word or two in ;.iis\mt to the gentlema 
from Virginia in relation i&lt;. the power t&gt;r the gwrenor i 
locating the seats of government in these territories. X 

icli power is irivt'ii to them. They ;i r«- fires the right t 
¦lect the |&gt;iiint at which the first legislature shall be col 

veiled ; but after ilmt it is left in the lefrislainif to decid 
ai what ]inint the future capital shall he located. I ho\ 
the ireni leniiin will not try to |&gt;nt i-esirietions on Kanxs 

nd Neiiraska that have never been 

ipon any oil 

teiritoiies under the government of the t'nited Sta 

A very short tpeech of a very short term, and so passed the 
Napoleon of Nebraska front public observation, returning to his 
home in Savannah. Missouri. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
79 


l'.IKI) B. 

CHAPMAN. 

The second election for delegate to congress look place Nmtinber 
0, 18.".."., ai which Bird B. Chapman received :',so vot.-s ami 
Hiram P. Bennet 202, according to the returns of the eaavanteg 
board. Mr. Bennet instituted a eoatest which resulted in the 
presentation of a resolution by the committee on election* ¦!• 
daring that Bird B. Chapman was not entitled to the &gt; 
V..\h argued his side of the ca.se before the committee, ami in 
open session before the House of Representatives. 

In the. house Mr. Stephens of Georgia specially chatnpi. 
the cati.se of the sit t in «r member, while Washhurn of Maine 
ai^ued iu fa\ or of liie coniestant. il was a MM to reconcile 
serious irregularities and to eliminate from the count fraudulent 
votes. Of the two speeches in the house. Bennet's alone appear! 
in the Globe. 

Mr. Bennet complained seriously that after the case had d.-.-n 
closed before the committee, and each claimant had been so 

linwii tn we to exist till long after the majority report was 

inted. And ajjnin. becaoM tlnv were Made by mv political 
il personal ciii'inics. And fourth. I object to these affi- 

ts because they contain misre|&gt;iesi.ntations, prevarioa- 


BOOda. My olil enemy Sharp comes on hen 

he time the majority report was made: and after 

ooking over all my printed testimony and the majority re 

port, and conning it over three or four weeks, he fixes up 

n state of facts just sutVicient to carry his friend, the sitting 



II "Til lull. lci.V,-lll.-^i. U&lt;« 

nfnniKMl. i.r jiurtf testimony had Ix^n received and inoorp 

n tlie minority report: 

I Mr. Speaker. I object tn all r.r /mitt testimony in the ca - 
ami 1 particularly object to the four i r i«nh atliilavits upon 

which tin 1 minority report is li;ised: ;incl first. baaMMM 

i r purti ; seicnul. two— II it was never presented to the com- 

mittee, only to the minority; and third, because it was not </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
80 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

delepate. through, ¦wean to it in a corner, and then takes 
pood care to leave the city l&gt;ofore it was possible for me to 
know what was done. 

Eke lion. Qeo. W. Jones, United States Senator from Iowa, 
injr volunteered an endorsement of the veracity of Mr. Sharp, 
¦ived the speaker's attention: 

It is true, this deponent was once a member of the Iowa 
legislature, and while there I believe he supported the election 
of the Hon. (Ifo. W. Jones to the senate. Mr. Speaker, 
one jtdimI turn deser\ es another, and the senator comes to 
the rescue of his former qonstituent. 

K! loiiiesianl seems, from the recoid. to have been neither a 
f in debate, nor timid in attacks. Having parried several 
ts from the keen rapier of the mercurial Stephens, he ex 
ed in ¦ lone of exultation. "Mr. H pert If. the gentleman 
QCTgia. has not quite got me yet." Of the sitting delegate, 
liapman. he said: 

The gentleman alluded to his residence in the Territory 
of Nebraska. Now. I know. Sir. that that is mere claptrap 
talk: but as he lias alluded to it I will answer it. He 
says when he went to the Territory, thus and so. He went 

to the Territory the year that the territorial government 
was organized. He was a candidate for Congress before he 

pot there. He hap]K&gt;ned to be l&gt;eaten very badly at the 
election ami the next day after the election he went home 
to Ohio, and we saw nothing more of him. Yes. we — the 
squatters of Nebraska s;i\\ nothing more of him until 
thirty-five days before the election of a delepate last NovemWr. 
when he came back into the Territory. He had to 
!»• there forty days to entitle him to vote. He was not a 
roter, and did not vote at that election. Nevertheless, by 

getting all of the executive influence of the Territory in 
bis favor he ran a pretty pood race: but I beat him. That 
is. I beat him before the people, but he beat me before the 
canvassers all of whom were my personal and political 
enemies. One word further in reference to this matter. For 
the purpose of servinp a notice upon the sittinp delegate. 
that I intended to take testimony to use in the contest for 
liis scat. 1 inquired of him last January, in that lobby, where 
hi« residence was. Tn truth he did not know where it was; 
nnd I could 'not sen r a notice at his residence in the Terri- </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
81 

TERRITORIAL DELEGATES. 

tory because he had none there. It will be shown, in my 
further argument, that that fact worked a great hardship 
to me. 

It is a source of regret that the speech of Mr. Chapman does 
not appear in the Globe, as there is no way to restore the oratorical 
equilibrium. On the final vote there were sixty-three members 
of the house in favor of unseating Chapman, and sixty-nine 
opposed — so the contest failed. A resolution finally closed the 
case, on the 25th of July, 1856, allowing the retiring contestant 
mileage and per diem up to date. The allusions to Mr. Chapman's 
citizenship are corroborated in Nebraska history. 

Hon. J. Sterling Morton is reported as saying of the first 
election for delegate in Congress, December 12, 1854: 

Even in that early morning hour of the county our 
people exhibited a wonderful liberality in bestowing their 
franchises upon persons who had no interests in common 
with them, and who have never since been identified with 
the material development of this section of the world. Mr. 
Giddings resided then, as now, in Savannah, Missouri. Mr. 
Chapman was a citizen of Ohio, and never gained a residence 
in Nebraska, while Mr. Johnson was a denizen of Council 
Bluffs. Iowa. But as there were not to exceed twenty-five 
domiciles in Pierce County (now Otoe) at that time, nor 
more than fifty beds, it was always a mystery, — except to 
Col. John Bouleware and family, who then kept a ferry 
across the Missouri River, — where the 208 patriots came 
from who exercised a freeman's rights on that auspicious 
dawn in Otoe of the science of self government and the 
noble art of electioneering. 

In order to parry the point of this truthful charge, be it remembered 
that this was prior to legislation in Nebraska. Mr. 
Bennett had not only "come to stay," but was a member of the 
legislature from Otoe County in 1854 and again in 1859, and 
was justified in regarding Bird B. Chapman as a Bird of passage. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
82 


FEXXEK FEKUl SON 

Dec. 7. T-:.7 to Mar. 3. 1859. 

Fenner Fergaaoa, who was appointed Chief Justice October 
12 % ls."i4. was elected delegate io Comgremi Angaat, 1S37, ami was 
sworn in ui&gt;on the 7th day of December, 1887. 

On the ltith day of September. L857, Rird I?. Chapman, who 
had been a &lt; andidate for re-election, served notice of contest. It 
appe*n that there had been four candidates before the people, 
and the votes were distributed as follows: Fenner 
Ferguson. l.t&gt;4l ( ; Bird 15. Chapman. l..V&gt;!l; Henjamiu P. 
Rankin. 1.241; John Mi Thayer. 1.171. After one-half tlie time 
had ela|iscd for the taking of testimony, the contestant served 
notice November 14th, but the member elect had left the Territory 
for Yt'ashington. I). C. the notice being left at his usual 
place of residence. At the time specified, testimony was taken 
in the absence of Ferguson or any one by him authorized to act. 
A person, however, did appear, and informed the contestant, 
that unless lie was allowed to cross &lt;|iiest ion witnesses, certain 
Mormons would not testify for the contestant. If Chapman had 
inaugurated a game of delay, the tables were turned upon him. 
on the 3rd of December, when Silas A. Strickland, agent for 
Ferguson, left notice at Chapmma'l residence for the taking of 
testimony on the 14tli of the month. Chapman being absent 
from the Territory. 

As a way out of these complications the committee on 
elections. April I'l. 1866, reported a resolution to the House, to 
extend the time for taking testimony, which would virtual 1 1;-send 
the case over to the next session of Congress. That was 
passed by a vote of ninety-eight to eighty-ire Before this 
action of the Ho— e, January. 1868, the legislature of Nebraska 
passed joint resolutions, in the name of a large majority of the 
people, affirming belief in Mr. Ferguson's election and in his </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
83 

TEKIMTORIAL DELEGATES. 

"capacity, integrity, fidelity and incorruptibility,'' and indignantly 
repelling all foul aspersions cast upon him, for the purpose 
of prejudicing his right to a seat in Congress. The House 
of Representatives, feeling that the Nebraska legislature had 
overstepped the bounds of propriety by attempting to indicate 
their duty in settling the status of members, on motion, laid the 
resolutions on the table without printing. Accordingly, additional 
testimony having been taken, the committee, by a 
majority, decided in favor of Mr. Chapman; which report was 
taken up in the House February 9, 1859. 

Mr. Wilson (if Indiana said, in l&gt;ehalf of the contestant: "This 
whole case turns upon three precincts — Cleveland. Monroe, and 
Florence." There were but six voters residing in the Cleveland 
precinct and but live dwellings therein, and yet there were 
thirty-five votes cast, eighteen or twenty by persons erecting a 
hotel for the Cleveland Land Company, who voted for the sitting 
member and whose votes the committee rejected. He 
charged, further, that in the Mormon precinct of Monroe, where 
there were forty Mormon voters, and only live other persons re- 

siding there, the vote cast was eight v seven, of which the sittin«r 
¦ember, Vtrgmmom, received eighty three, and contestant 
one. And that before the polls were formally opened forty 
votes had been cast, as a large number of men came there at 
two o'clock in the morning, voted and went away. He said: "In 
the Monroe precinct appear names which of themselves are 
liriiiia fdii( evidence of fraud — Oliver Twist and Samuel Weller." 
In the Florence precinct, 4111 votes were returned, where 
the polls were kept open three hours later than allowed by law, 
of which .!&lt;;4 were for the sitting member and four for the contestant. 
One perMM voted four times and at least "one hundred 
persons were unknown to the oldest ¦ettlcrs." 

Mis. Washim rn: "Whs not that man whose testimony you 
refer to, accused of perjury?" 

Mr. Wilson: "Yes, but tin' man who accuses him is himi'lf 
accused of murder." 

Mr. Wilson charged in addition that none of the officers in </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
84 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

these three precincts were sworn by a legal officer, as though 
they intended fraud from the very start. In justification of the 
committee's decision, be quoted many precedents for the rejecion 
of votes, and though it was late in the Congress, eighteen 
months after the election, he demanded prompt action, and 
concluded: "Looking over the elections for the last few years in 
the Territories, it does seem to me that a certificate of election 

from a Territory has become almost prima facie evidence of a 
great fraud committed." 

The beautiful superstructure erected by the ingenuity of the 
gentleman from the state of Indiana was adroitly attacked by 
the wide-awake member from the state of Maine, Mr. Washburn: 

Mr. Speaker, not only is all this testimony ex parte (taken 
alone by one party), but a gTeat part of it is composed of 
affidavits, sworn to before a notary public who, the gentleman 
says, has no right to administer an oath in the Ter- 
Titory of Nebraska. And, Sir, there is not a single fact upon 
¦which he relies for the material points in his case, but what 
is hearsay. There is not a single fact of importance touching 
the precincts of Florence and Monroe but what comes 
from the declarations of third parties. There is not a 
scintilla of testimony here which is not of that character; 
whereas the rebutting testimony is that of witnesses who 
lived within the precinct, and who were sworn and crossexamined 
and stated facts within their knowledge. The 
sitting delegate did not see fit to rely upon the evidence 
of the runners and agents of the contestant, men who 
lived in Omaha and could know nothing certain; but he went 
to Florence and to Monroe and to Cleveland where the facts 
transpired. He took the testimony of the men, of all others 
in the world, who knew exactly all the facts in the case. 

In reply to Davis of Maryland, Mr. Washburn said 

The gentleman piles up precedents as high as Olympus, 
but I will never receive hearsay testimony to affect the 
rights of parties. It is not law, it is not sense, and indeed. 
Sir, it is not good nonsense. [Laughter.] No man can stand 
upon it. I have known several persons of the surname of 
Twist and Weller. and 1 want the gentleman to inform me 
whether it is impossible, or even improbable, that among 
all the Twists there is not an Oliver, or among all the 
Wellers there is not a Samuel? [Laughter.] And if so, why </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
85 


may they not be in Xebraska, as well as anywhere? Laughter.] 
And I think the gentleman is getting himself into a 
twist very fast. [Laughter.] 

After Mr. Washburn had examined precedents and testimony, 
he was followed by Mr. Boyce of South Carolina, who stated that 
fee^ly the law in Nebraska did not close the polls at 6 p. m.; 
the young men working at Cleveland Hotel building made 
their homes wherever they found work: that there were nearer 
one hundred than merely forty resident voters at Monroe and 
that fifteen votes were cast at Florence after six o'clock. Many 
other members participated in the dis» Mission, and when it was 
closed, "confusion so confounded" led to an effort to declare 

the seat vacant, and finally a compromise laid the whole subject 
on the table, leaving Ferguson in the chair: and the day before 
the session and ('(ingress closed, a resolution passed awarding 
Chapman six thousand dollars, salary and mileage. Thus endeth 
the second contest. 

From the number of bills introduced and arguments made 
before the committees on Public Lands. Indian Affairs. Judi- 

ciary. Public Buildings, and others, tin-re is every reason to 
believe that the legislature did not overestimate the "capacity, 
integrity, and fidelity" of their delegate. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
86 


EX PER1EXCE E8TA BROOK. 

Oct. 11, 1859 (election) to May 13. IMS. 

Mr. Estebrook was born in 1813 in the state of New Hampshire. 
At the age of forty-two years, in 1865, lie settled in the 
Territory of Nebraska. He was a student of Dickinson College, 
Pa., and ¦ law student of Chambersburg, in the same state. 
He graduated in ls:i!t. His time was occupied as a clerk at 
the Brooklyn navy yard for a short time, as an attorney at 
Buffalo. N. Y., for one year, and fifteen years at Geneva Lake. 
Wisconsin. His elections were: Attorney General of Wisconsin, 
member of the Wisconsin legislature, and member of the 
Nebraska Constitutional Convention of 1871. His appointments 
were: Attorney General of Nebraska by President Pierce. 1865, 
and Commissioner for Codification of Laws of Nebraska. 1S71. A 
good citizen and an honorable lawyer may In-come his epitaph. 

On the 18th day of May. lsco. Mr. Cainpl&gt;ell of Ohio, from the 
committee on elections, called up the following resolutions: 

Resolved. That Experience Estabrook is not entitled to 

the seat as delegate from the Territory of Nebraska to the 

Thirty-sixth Congress of the United States. 

Resolved, That Samuel G. Daily is entitled to the seat as 

delegate from the Territory of Nebraska to the Thirty-sixth 

Congress of the United States 

This was a unanimous report, agreed upon alike by Democrats 
and Republicans. Mr. Estabrook belonged to the former and 
Mr. Daily to the latter party. The election had taken place on 
October 11, 1859. The canvassing board gave Mr. Estabrook 
3,100 votes and Mr. Daily 2.N00. or a majority for Estabrook of 
300 votes. Of these 202 were reported coming from Buffalo 
County, but of that number 238 were cast in Kearney City which 
is not in the county of Buffalo. Mr. Campbell said: "The testimony 
discloses the fact that there were not over eight houses, not 
over fifteen residents, and not one acre of cultivated land, or a </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
87 

TKKItlTORIAL DELKGATES. 

farm house in tin- neighborhood of Kearney CHy. Nor was 
Buffalo Counly organized." Therefore "the entire vote was 
rejected as illegal and spurious." All of the spurious votes were 
{riven to Kstabrook and not one to Daily. The vote of Calhoun 
County was rejected because it was attached for voting purposes 
to Platte County, and though having only two families in the 
northwest and four in the southeast part, bad returned thirtytwo 
votes, twenty-eight for Kstnbrook and four for Daily. Mr. 
Campbell said: 

As to the vote of I/aril County, the committee rejected 
the twenty-one votes cast for the sitting member, and the 
three cast for the contestant, as the entire vote purporting 
to have been polled in that county was a fraud, and that no 
such vote was ever polled. • • * If there had been any 
settlers there, if there had been one acre of cultivated land, 
if there had been a single voter in the county, if there had 
been an election precinct, and if there had been officers 
who held an election there, how easy it would have been for 
the sitting delegate, after full notice, to have brought one 
of these twenty-four voters, one of these election officers, 
to show that there was a set tleinent and that an election 
had been held and that there were votes cast in the county 
of Izard. 

In I,'Kau-&lt;|iii-&lt;'ourt County, 128 votes were reported, all for 
Mr. Kstabrook, while a member of the legislature swore that 
there were only from thirty to thirty-five votes in the county. 
The names of members of Congress were entered on the poll 
book as Howell Cobb and Aaron V. Brown, and two messengers 
who procured a copy of the poll book from the clerk were mobbed 
by parties who declared, ''as they were parties to the fraud, they 
would never suffer any evidence of it to leave the county." 
These figures of 128 were reduced to sixty, and a majority of 
119 votes were awarded to the contestant on a final adjustment 
of all the votes east. In conclusion. Mr. Campbell said. 

The learned and able members of the committee who 
are friends to the sitting delegate, — and I trust all the members 
of the committee were disposed to do that which was 
simply right, — could not find in the case evidence enough 
to found a minority report on. </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
88 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

Mr. Estabrook desired to make a motion to recommit the ease 
to the committee. Mr. Campbell said: 

The motion which the gentleman is about to make has 
been made in the house once, and rejected there, or referred 
to the committee of elections, and argued and rejected 
there. 

Mr. (lartrell desired the sitting member should b;ive more tee, 
and said: 

I desire to say in justification to myself that while I voted 
in favor of ousting the sitting delegate and giving the seat 
to the contestant, I did so upon the ground that the record 
evidence before the committee disclosed that the contestant 
was clearly elected. I did not vote for ousting Mr. Estabrook 
with any idea that he or his friends in Nebraska had 
perpetrated any fraud. 

Finally, when Mr. Estabrook desired to speak more at length 
on some other day, and thought he could clear the Territory of 
charges of fraud, and admitted that "there always is irregularity 
on the frontier and you ought not to hold the frontiers of the 
country to the strict rules of law,"' the House desired him to 
close his remarks at that time. But when he declined to do so 
the final question was ordered, and Mr. Daily was sworn in on 
the 18th of May, 1860. That being the date of the convention 
that was to nominate Mr. Lincoln, Mr. Estabrook exclaimed, "I 
thank the House for making me a sacrifice to the gods of tin- 
Chicago convention."' Thus endeth the third contest. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
89 

TERRITORIAL DELEGATES. 

Samuel G. Daily of Indiana effected a sett lenient at Peru, 
Neniaha County, Nebraska, in 1857; and before the permanent 
organization of the Republican party in the Territory, was free 
to avow his utter hostility to the institution of American slavery. 
One year prior to this, the first National Republican Convention 
assembled in Philadelphia, Pa., and nominated for president 
John C. Fremont, and for vice-president William L. Dayton of 
New Jersey; while a remnant of the old Whig party nominated 
Ex-President Millard Fillmore of New York. Mr. Daily had 
thoroughly adopted the doctrines of the platform: 

That we deny the authority of congress or of a territorial 
legislature, or of any individual or association of individuals, 
to give legal existence to slavery in any territory 
of the United States while the present constitution shall 
be maintained. 

That the constitution confers upon Congress sovereign 
power over the territories of the United States for their 
government, and that in the exercise of this power it is both 
the right and duty of Congress to prohibit in the territories 
those twin relics of barbarism — polygamy and slavery. 

Ready and willing to do all in his power in aid of these principles, 
he was elected to the territorial legislature in 1858, and 
as a delegate in Congress contested the election of Mr. Estabrook 
in 1859. In 1860 he was a candidate for Congress, subsequent 
to Mr. Lincoln's nomination, and made a very thorough canvass 
of the Territory with Mr. Morton, his democratic opponent. In 
1862 he succeeded in defeating Judge J. F. Kinney of Nebraska 
City, and closed a third term in Congress. 

On his retirement, Mr. Lincoln gave him the appointment of 
deputy collector of the port of New Orleans, where he died in 
September, 1865. 

HON. SAMUEL G. DAILY. </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
90 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETV. 

.1. BTERLING MORTON. 

Nov. :;. i^dii (oertl4cmte of election) to May 7. 1M1 (cessation 

of privileges). 

Although his name was never entered on tlie rolls of the 
House of Representatives in ( 'ongress. the history of Nebraska 
and a manual published by the legislature in 1885 speak of him 
as elected to Congress. The contest in which he figured in the 
first session of the t hirty -seventh Congress, was the most remarkable 
in the past history of the government. He was then under 
thirty years of age, and already stood so high in the confidence 
of his party leaders that such men as Pendleton of Ohio, Voorhees 
of Indiana, and Richardson of Illinois became his champions. 
The latter, who had been governor of Nebraska for one 
year, said of him: 

I know him: I will say of him that, of all the young men 
in the country, and I am familiar with a great many of 
them. lu&gt; lias Mm greatest intellect and the most promising 
future. I pass this compliment upon him; I have known him 
for years, and 1 have watched him well. Beyond the Ohio 
Ki\er there is not a brighter intellect. Centlemen, you will 
hear of him hereafter: mark my words. 

And I will say of Mr. Daily 
that lie is a clever gentleman, 
islative assembly when I was 
tory. I found him ready to ! 

and I say it with pleasure - 
He was ¦ member of the leggovernor 
of Nebraska Terriupport 
me at all times in the 

vindication of the law. and in everything calculated to contribute 
to the welfare and prosperity of the country. I 
am not here. Mr. Speaker, to say one word offensive to him. 
But I do think Ihat the American House of Representatives 
have committed an outrage in permitting the Governor 
of the Territory, in violation of his oath, in violation of his 
duty, and in violation of every trust reposed in him, to 
unseat a delegate, as has been done in this ease. 

Mr. Daily had also the aid of true political friends. They had, 
in a previous Congress, ousted a Democrat and seated him, — the 
political excitement wax intense, — and now that he came a </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
91 

TBKBITOSIAL KKI-Eisatks. 

M-icind time claiming the right to Hurt BMUKf priiM upon t lit* 
altar of the newly enthroned Republican divinity, the admiration 
was shared between the ftfl and the donor. They pointed to his 
Mperior skill in strategy, admired his bold aggressiveness, and 
held him not too rigidly to the rules of rhetoric or the amenities 

of debate. 

On the !Hh day of October. 1 Stiff, the election for delegates took 
place. On the 3rd of November. 1 still, a certificate of election 
was issued to .1. Sterling Morton, declaring him as having received 
the largest number of votes, and concluding, "this shall 
be the certificate of the said election as delegate to Congress, to 
the thirty seventh Congress of the I'nited States." The canvass 
of votes was made by the governor, chief justice, and district 
attorney, as required by law. Six months thereafter, unknown 
to the chief justice and attorney, without any re canvass, or 
sending of it to the secretary of state for lejjal record. Governor 
Black issued a certificate of election to Mr. Daily, the opposing 
candidate, after .Mr. l»aily had months before been taking testi 
luony to contest Mr. Morton's right to the seat in Congress. The 
reason gkrem for this act was. that fraudulent votes had been 
discovered to the amount of ll'l'. the deduction of which from 
Mortons vote elected Daily. The governor enjoined secrecy 
upon Mr. Daily, saying that he owed Morton money, for which 
he was befog hounded, and if made known his departure from 
the state might be obstructed. 

The second certificate, attempting to revoke the first, was 
dated April 29, 18*1, and as there was an extra session of Congress 
to commence .July 4, lWil, that date would necessarily 
cause its publication. Mr. Daily stated to the House that, to 
avoid apparent undue secrecy when on his way east to Congress, 
lie telegraphed an eastern paper of the fact of a new certificate. 
Hut Mr. Morton never saw the announcement: and arrived in 

Washington on the supjKisition that he was a member of Congress. 
The former private secretary of Governor Black (March 
4, 1862) having made an affidavit of his copying the Daily certificate 
for the governor, ''after he (Black) had been removed from </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
92 


the governorship of Nebraska and Alvin Satinders had been 
appointed,"' made an explanatory affidavit in the interests of 
Mr. Daily April 30, 1862, in which he said he only intended by 
the word removed to say that it was after his removal so far as 
the appointment of Governor Xannders removed him. lint he 
was the governor up to the time he left the Territory. Not i&lt;&gt; 
be outdone by this flank movement, Mr. Morton ¦bowed, bj a 
letter of the Secretary of the Interior, "that Mr. Pent land MM 
appointed a temporary clerk in the general land office March 
15, 18C2, on the recommendation of Hon. S. G. Daily of Nebraska 
Territory." implying thereby that Pentland was under obli^a 
tions to Mr. Daily. This was parried by the assertion that kifh 
government officials of Pennsylvania had recommended Mr. Pentland. 
When, in connection with the Daily certificate, it was 
asserted that Mr. Daily had purchased the horse and carriage of 
Governor Black, as though "one good turn deserved another," he 
admitted the purchase, but said he got them one hundred dollars 
under their true cash value. On the subject of the second 
certificate of election, Mr. Morton said in opening his speech in 
thc&gt; House: 

He did this because he hated and desired to injure me. 
It was the vengeance of an assassin and :i eowwi wreaked 
upon one who had, by loaning him hundreds of dollars, 
saved him and his family from shame and mortification, 
saved even their family carriage from public auction at the 
hands of the sheriff. Mr. Black owed me money and became 
indignant because I, after he had enjoyed for three years 
the use of a few hundred dollars, which he had borrowed to 
return in three days, pressed him for payment. 

How this revoked certificate got on the house roll was stated 
by Mr. Daily in answer to Voorhees of Indiana: 

I went to Col. Forney, then clerk of the House, presented 
my certificate to him, and told him to read it and to consider 
whether it was proper or wrong: and if proper to put 
my name on the roll, and if wrong to put Mr. Morton's 
name on the roll. I told him Morton had another certificate, 
as he would see by the reading of mine; but when he 
read it, he said that a man who had been imposed upon by </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
93 

TEKKITOKIAL DELEGATES 

fraud had a right to correct his own act, as he thought 
Black had done in this case. 

The first vote taken in this case was upon a motion to substitute 
the name of J. Sterling Morton for that of Samuel O. 
Daily, which was lost, and Mr. Daily was sworn in on the 
second day of the extra session, July 5th, 1861. The second vote 
involved a refusal to recognize Mr. Morton as a sitting member 
peadiag the contest, which carried the case over to the next 
session of Congress. 

As this was the fourth contest in succession from Nebraska, 
inemtiers were reluctant to enter upon its settlement, only that 
the two certificates for the same election gave it a novel character. 
]t was the true policy of Mr. Morton to be respectful and 
conciliatory toward the majority, and hence he spoke of the 
mistake the House made in not allowing him to be sworn into 
the organization. But it was the policy of Mr. Daily to keep 
the majority in line, and hence his course of procedure to 
prejudice the House against his opponent. The war raging, 
and the very existence of the Union in peril, if the stigma of 
rebel could be attached to Mr. Morton's name, frauds against 
such an one would be hailed as blessings in disguise. But when 
Mr. Daily asserted .that he had a letter from a Democrat, a 
captain in the army, who said Mr. Morton "sympathized with 
Southern traitors," Mr. Morton exclaimed: 

I have simply to say this, that towards the close of the 
Thirty-sixth Congress, when the nation itself seemed in the 
convulsions of dissolution, when, amid the roar and din of 
assembling armies, I heard the voice of the venerable gentleman 
of Kentucky (Mr. Crittenden) sounding calmly and 
grandly over and above all the terrible tumult, saying unto 
the waves of sectional strife, "Peace, peace, be still," I 
caught the words and echoed them even upon the far-off 
prairies of Nebraska. If that may have been disloyalty, 
then I am disloyal; if that may have been treason, I am 
proud to be called a traitor, — a Crittenden traitor. 

Mis. Daily: "Will the gentleman please close with prayer?' 1 
He would make no charges himself, but would send up the 
letter. Members declared it personal and not in order. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
94 

NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

Mr. Johxbok: "I think the House has been sufficiently disgraced 
witli this scene already, and I object to it." 

Each of the gentlemen was an adept at evasion and retort. 
In a nraaiag debate with Voorhees of Indiana, Mr. Daily exclaimed: 


While the lamp holds out to burn 
The vilest sinner may return, 

and when Mr. Lovejoy said. "I feel bound to interpose in behalf 
of the sciipt urcs,"' Mr. Daily, unabashed, continued: 

It is jrood doctrine anyway. It ou^lit to be there if it is 
not. I have read Watts and the P.ible so much together that 
I Bomttimta mistake one for the other. [Laughter.] Now I 
would say further in regard to Governor Black, lie was an 
appointee of Mr. liuchnnan. The marshal and the secretary, 
Mr. Morton, were also ltuchanan men. They were all Breckenridge 
Democrats; and a larjre majority of them are now 
in the rebel army. But Mr. lilark. when the national diffi- 

culty arose, broke friendship 
went back to his native town 
a tine regiment, and we beard 
first man to eater the enemy's 

with these old friends, and 
&gt;f Pittaburg where he raised 
of him the other day as the 
works at Vorktown. 

Mit. Morton 

1 think he would have been the second man in. if there 
was as certain knowledge that there was-whiskey there, as 
there was that there was no enemy there. 

Mr. Daily, knowing what a center thrust this was in the 
knowledge of all Nebniskans. and that the House was i^noiani 
of its terrible point, indignantly answered, "That shows. Mr. 

Speaker, the character of men 

I do not reply to it. 

Mr. Daily, having passed a 
whose character when attack* 

pleasant eulogy upon a witness, 
¦d had been sustained by twenty 
following from Mr. Morton: 

of his neighbors, received the 

The cabinet of Jeff Davis could. I have no doubt, impeach 
the loyalty of this congress, cabinet, and president, and substantiate 
their own, l&gt;efore any tribunal in Richmond; the 
inmate* of a penitentiary establish among themselves their 
purity and the wickedness of the outer world; and the little 
imps in Tartarus would attest the virtue of Satan and impeach 
the court of heaven that banished him. </seg>


            <seg id="p022">
95 

Iiiasimicli as this contest was never decided on its merits, it 
matters but little that the analytic arguments of distinguished 
members should be omitted, and only a mere synopsis of those 
of tLe contestant and sitting member be given. The speech of 
Mr. Morton was first in order, and announced the consequence 
of the committee being bound by the primn facie action of the 
House : 

My conclusion must naturally and logically follow that 
the best manner to become a member of Congress with 

safety, security, and celerity, is not to become a candidate 
before the people at all, but quietly to go to the private 
residence of some governor of small means, easy virtue, and 
extravagant habits and purchase a certificate of election, 
being well assured that it is positively the last one to be 
issued, come here and secure the affections of the clerk 
of the House by some means, and if he is a bold man, and 
an anxious candidate for re-election, your name will be put 
upon the roll-call of the members and you will be sworn in, 
safely in, seated upon live oak and green morocco, to 
enjoy all the honors and perquisites arising therefrom, for 
the period of two years. 

Taking ap tlte case of L'Eaii-qui-Court county, where one 
hundred twenty-two voles were thrown out of his count, on the 
testimony of four witnesses, Mr. Morton referred to evidence in 
which Mr. Westerman said that in consideration of the testimony 
which they were to give in behalf of Samuel G. Daily, 

"I agreed to pay \V. \Y. Walford one hundred dollars and Heck 
tifty dollars." He further showed that, in a case in Dakota 
Territory, subsequently, this same \\ esicinian gave as a reason 
why the witness Walford should not lie believed upon oath, 
that lie was a hired witness in Nebraska; and of the fourth 

one. Cox. lie said, "He tendered his services to me as an itinerant 

witness, but I dec-lined to negotiate, and within a week he 

turned up as a witness for Mr. Daily 

When it was charged that the vote of the county for him was 
greater than the whole population, he showed that since the 
election a part of the county had been set off to the Territory of 
Dakota, and a new census taken. Of twentv votes denied him </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
96 


in Monroe precinct, Platte County, because some were of citizens 
upon a reservation, he claimed they were, nevertheless, citizens 
of Nebraska, and such residents had been entitled to vote in 
the nearest adjacent precinct, by a recent legislative enactment. 
Of thirty-nine votes from Buffalo County, he claimed that the 
sworn records of the county showed organization and hence the 
rate valid. In Rulo precinct, Richardson County, where 
niiiciv vnii's were cast for Morton and the committee deducted 
twenty for want of residence in the precinct, he claimed that 
custom allowed them to vote in any precinct where they might 
l&gt;e mi the day of election, and further said: 

Perceive that while they are painfully careful to deduct 
twenty votes from me, they are felicitously forgetful of the 
nine votes which they admit should be deducted from those 
returned for Mr. Daily. 

Falls City precinct returned one hundred and four votes 
for Mr. Daily. The ballot box, unsealed, was for hours in 
the hands of a person out of the possession or sight of the 
election board. It is proved, too, handfuls of ballots were 
taken out of the box by a political friend and supporter of 
Mr. Daily's and others put in their place by the same person. 
The whole 104 votes returned from Falls City should be 
thrown out. If L'Eau-qui-Court is thrown out the former 
certainly must be. If both g-o out, I am elected. 

Mr. Xohi.e of Ohio: 

Mr. Speaker, I have been acquainted with that judge and 
&lt;ociates a great while. Where they lived before they 
went there, they would neither be believed on oath, nor be 
entrusted with anything. I could relate instances of fraud 
nlmvc anything I ever knew, during an active practice of 
over twenty years. 

Mr. Morton presented in evidence an act of the Nebraska 
.Mine, since the commencement of the contest, legalizing 
the fust organization of Pawnee County, and claimed that he 
thirty nine votes in Buffalo County on a charge of nonorganization, 
while in a county of the same condition, his 
opponent gets one hundred of a majority. He claimed that the 
law was not observed in Clay and Gage counties and in the </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
I. STEItLIXO MORION, l </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
97 

TERRITORIAL DELEGATES. 

precincts of Otoe and Wyoming in Otoe County, and that the 
clerks of Dodge, Cass, Xemaha, Lancaster, Johnson and Wash 
ington made no abstract of votes, as the law required, and the 
minority report claimed they should be thrown out. He argued 
in conclusion, that to enforce the law as it had been construed 
against himself, would reduce Mr. Daily's vote two hundred 
and ninety-four. Mr. Morton concluded: ''Thanking the House 
for its courteous attention, I submit the case for its determina- 

tion. 

As I/Eau-(|iii-&lt;'ourt county was the objective point of attack 
Mr. Daily approached it promptly: 

Knowing 1 the means that they would resort to. while going 
through the canvass with the contestant. 1 said to him that 
I did not expect to pet the certificate; I said to him that 
these officials will manage affairs so that when it is ascertained 
how many, they will bring: from some place nobody 
has heard of before, votes enough to elect yon. Sure enough 
it turned out as I predicted. Neither the contestant nor I 
had ever heard of this northern precinct of I/Kau-qui-Court 
county; but it was from that precinct that a vote of one 
hundred twenty-two came in, all for the contestant, and 
sufficient to elect him. Hut. how. let me ask. were those 
one hundred twenty-two votes counted? They were counted 
contrary to law; they were counted contrary to the evidence 
before the territorial canvassers. Now how did the territorial 
canvassing board know that there was any vote of 
that kind'.' I'.ecaiisc the county clerk had stated to them 
that such a return had been presented to and rejected by 
him: anil because he rejected it they counted it. | Laughter. | 

There is a return included here, called Cottonwood 
Springs, some ninety miles beyond Fort Kearney, of mm 
seventy votes for Mr. Morton, which I did not go to the 
trouble of proving fraudulent. kMMM I bad enough to do 
to make out my case without. I now dare him to go back 
upon that issue (of fraud) to the Territory and I will show, 
beyond a doubt, that his certificate was obtained, counted, 
and this return, which was no return, counted, without 
which the certificate could not have l&gt;een given, by means of 
bribery, that the certificate was caused to be made out by 

w 

the appliances of bribery 

51 it. Mobton: 

I understand the sitting delegate to say that he is willing </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
NEBRASKA STATE HISTORICAL 

SOCIKTY. 

¦ i;i - k«i ami try the eonl^ 

re. 1 am willing to accept 

lint proposition 

Mil. I&gt;AI1.1 : 

No. Sir: at the next elect i 

in that Territory 1 will eonspeaking 
limply of these cernothing 
whatever To do with 

l) 

cut to that trial again. 1 am 
itieates. which, 1 repeat. ha\e 
he merits of the ea- 

Ilr. Daily stated that the witnesses, wbo received $l"&gt;n tar 
lin^r to Omaha to testify, traveled two hundred fifty miles 
were over sixty days making the trip, lie claimed that 
rton had votes counted for him in l'latte County, from I he 
ian Reservation, by men who took the oath on the condition 
t the Reservation was found to lie in Monroe preeiact. As 
chairman of the committee was to close the debate in behalf 
Mr. Doily, it allowed the silting delegate to disport himself 
will UMMg (Ik- multitudinous questions raise*! during the 
•iission. 

My friends are very impatient, and I must hurry to a conclusion. 
There are a great many things with regard to this 
case which I would take delight in talking about, because 
1 tell you that it reeks with the greatest fraud, and chican- 

ery, and trickery that erer was concocted in the darkest 
hours of the night amid the infernal regions below, or that 

ever could be eoateseted by Democratic official! under James 
Itiiclianan to carry the day in the territory, right or wrong. 
| Much laughter.] 

Mb. Voobhees: 

Inasmuch as this line of remark is indulged in. I shall 
say to gentlemen upon the opposite side of the house, that 
with this country filled and reeking from side to side with 
frauds committed by high officials of the present adminis- 

tration, it conies with a bad grace from them to say one 
word about frauds that have l&gt;ecn committed in times past. 

Mr. Daily: 

Oh. 1 hope these frauds are not to be brought into this 
case, (iod knows theie was enough fraud in the Nebraska 
case on the part of the contestant without bringing in all 
the frauds about horse contracts. 

Now. Mr. Speaker, I am constrained out of mercy for the 
house, so Jong bored by this case, to close this argument. 

1 1 m &gt; ii tin— •¦ &lt;¦&lt; -rtitu-iii. isfiiin Wfore the peiiple of N&gt; </seg>


            <seg id="p027">
99 

I blowing the rlosinjr tpcecli of Mr. l»aus. on motion of Mr. 
ihhuin. a friend of Mr. Daily, the whole subject was laid 
1 the table by a vote of sixty-nine to forty-eight. 80 the 
»st was aercr de&lt; ided. 1 m t Mr. Daily held the seat under 
second certificate. The privileges of Mr. Morton ceased 
7. 1802. </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
100 

NKIiKASKA STATE HISTORICAL SOCIETY. 

HON. 1'. \Y. HITCHCOCK. 1 

Into the political campaign of 1864, as republican eudkhrte 
for delegate in Congress. Mr. Hitchcock entered unconditionally 
and hopefullv. No man went beyond him in an endorsement of 
Mr. Lincoln's sublime prophecy that, "The mystic chords of 
memory, stretching from every battlefield and patriot grave to 
every living heart and hearthstone all over this broad land, will 
yet swell the chorus of the Union, when again touched, as surely 
they will be. by the better angels of our natures." Having 
been a delegate to the convention and voted for Mr. Lincoln's 
first nomination, and having heartily approved his official acts, 
and under his appointment acted as United States marshal for 
four years, it became more than a mere pleasure, a positive duty, 
to advocate his re-election. 

The Democratic candidate was General George B. McClellan. 
a splendid officer and pure patriot, who had been deemed too 
slow by the radical Republicans and too conspicuous for the 
scheming politicians. After the asperity of the war was subsiding 
lien: IVrley Poor, a Republican author, said of him: "(ieneial 
McClellan. who was then eulogized as a second Napoleon, soon 
found himself 'embarrassed' by men who feared that he might 
become president if he conquered peace." He was also impressed 
with this presidential idea by pretended friends who 
had fastened themselves upon him, and "between two stools he 
fell to the ground." 

All state or territorial politics were overshadowed in the 
canvass and national issues predominated. Mr. Hitchcock was 
elected delegate to Congress by a majority of one thousand, 
while Lincoln's majority in the United States, of the popular 
vote, was 4&lt;»7.:tl2. and of the electoral college over McClellan. 
was 191. Ten states were in revolt and not represented. 

' K..r iiinn- personal details of the life of Mr. HitcliriK'k. see j.ul&gt;. Near. State Hi-t 
Bac, fir-t series, vol. I., pp. 100-103. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
101 


Iie circumstances attending the advent of Mr. Hitchcock in 
ic life, as a delegate in Congress, were monumental as to 
marking the returning shadows of slavery, and the dawning 
glories of universal freedom. The hour in which he responded 
to the roll-call of "Nebraska," the newly elected 
Speaker of the House emphasized the living contrast: 

The Thirty-eighth Congress closed its constitutional existence 
with the storm-cloud of war still lowering over us; 
and, after a nine month's absence. Congress resumes its legislative 
authority in these council halls, rejoicing, that from 
shore to shore, in our land, there is peace. 

But the fires of civil war have melted every fetter in the 
land and proved the funeral pyre of slavery, and the stars 
on our banner, that paled when the states they represented 
arranged themselves in arms against the nation, will shine 
with a more brilliant light of loyalty than ever before. 

In the membership of the House was an infusion of the best 
young blood of the nation. The "Plumed Knight" of Maine, 
James G. Blaine; Roscoe Conklin, the gorgeous, of New York; 
(sauve and well-poised Samuel J. Randall, of Pennsylvania; 
scholarly James A. (Jarfleld, of Ohio; the chivalrous N. P. 
ks, of Massachusetts; with a long list of compeers, dial lengthen 
pre-eminence, and holding the scales of decision in 
il balance. Under the wig and upon the crutch came Thaddeus 
Stephens, the invincible old commoner of Pennsylvania, 
wielding the war club of leadership in the style of a Cromwell; 
while bearing the motto, "The pen is mightier than the sword, " 
came Brooks of New York, editor, orator, and statesman. It 
matters not that a delegate in Congress may be of finished 
education, devoted to principles, profound in the science of 
government and used to intellectual sparring in stormy debate. 
yet he is barred from national themes and confined to narrow 
and material lines of territorial wants. But if of studious haliits 
and sound morals, and making each opportunity a stepping 
stone to future elevation, the confined position of delegate will 
not prevent the acquisition of valuable material for use in the 
Senate or House of Representatives. 

The legislature of 1MM charged Mr. Hitchco* k with the </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
102 


presentation of memorials asking for bounty lands for Nebraska 
volunteers, and the same aid for the Burlington and Missouri 
River Railroad as that accorded to the I'nJon Paeilr, and land 
grants for railroads west from Xeliraska City and Hrownville. 
Also for reimbursement of excuses incurred in ¦¦pfHtaaing 
Indian hostilities; and for nmneroiis mail routes. 

In the first session of the thirty-ninth Congress, of his own 
motion, he presented bills for the creation and construction of 
a penitentiary, and for the Bit taping of the eapttol tariMtag; 
asked that internal revenue from Nebraska mifrlii be appropriated. 
To faciliate emigrant travel an&lt;l secure a western 
outlet for Nebraska productions, he presented a bill for a wagon 
road from Colunibns to Virginia City. Montana. To save the 
people from frauds of irresponsible corporations and heartless 
cormorants he presented and advocated before the appropriate 
committee a petition for "just and equal laws" respecting interstate 
insurances. When terror-stricken emigrant! Hed before 
the murderous and thieving forays of Arapahoe. Cheyenne, 
and Sioux, their claims for remuneration and protection were 
met by an anticipating effort. 

With a firm faith in the future of the great west and its commercial 
demands, tin' Missouri river ready for heavy transjiorta 
tion. and an indomitable enterprise promising to make the 
beautiful central prairie state the railroad checkerboard of the 
nation, he early advocated Omaha and Nebraska City for posts 
of delivery. Bills for a geological survey and for government 
buildings at Nebraska City were deemed advisable, in order 
that concealed treasures might be disclosed, and for the accommodation 
of United States courts, revenue office and postal 
department. 

In summing up the results of the first session of the thirtyninth 
Congress, the United States statutes disclose the following 
state of facts: Bills passed establishing sixteen post routes; 
for surveying public lands, f 25,000 appropriated; for territorial 
expenses, f2fi.5OO; and as much of $45,000 as the secretary of 
war shall deem necensarv to reimburse the territory for ex- </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
103 


jH-iiKt's incurred in the ¦nppreaokM of Indian hostilities in ls»&gt;4: 
and for 1 lit* rcinoval of the surveyor gmeral'l office of Wisconsin 
and Iowa to l'lattsnioutli. Nebraska. There was also found due 
and Appropriated for Indian tribes in Nebraska. und&lt;'r treaties. 
over $1&lt;IO.&lt;K)0. 

Inasmuch M the cloaiag KM0M of the thirty-ninth CoBgreos, 
closing; Mr. Hitchcock's term, was to l«- one of three months 
only, and as the senator and delegate from Nebraska wenawaiting 
admission, but little business was pressed upon tjie dele 
gate: and he returned from the position three days before the 
end Of his term, while the proclamation of the president. 
extiagsiaaiftg the taper of the Territory, unveiled the star of 
the State. 

Darteg that second session, however, the record shows the 
passage of an act allowing an annual appropriation of internal 
re\enue. for three years, ftglTfgBttf $40,004) for penitentiary 
buildings, $15,000 for land surveys, and an allowance for a 
geological survey, with $31..~&gt;00 for legislative expenses. In his 
argument before the various house committees on lands, Indian 
affairs, pensions, claims, pool offices, appropriations, commerce, 
agriculture and territories, as well as in his intercourse with 
fellow members, he manifested good capacity, liberal acquire 
meiits. commendable devotion to duties, with gentility of deportment. 
From the remembrance of their college days, it was no 
matter of astonishment when (iartield met him in the house, and 
subsequently. Ingalls in the senate. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>