<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>RURAL ELECTRIC SERVICE IN NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1931-03">1931-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 254 March, 1931 RURAL ELECTRIC SERVICE IN NEBRASKA FARM LINE EXTENSIONS OF 1929 COMPARED WITH THOSE OF 1927 K. E. BRACKETT AND E. 11. LEWIS Department of Agricultural Engineering E EL ft K3LV i"^ Electric Service is Coming to be a Part of Typical Farm Equipment THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN w. w. Burr, Dikrctok </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska E. E. BRACKETT AND E. B. LEWIS Agricultural statistics show that the total number of Nebraska farmers receiving electric service from central station lines January 1, 1930, was approximately 4,000. The period beginning with the latter part of 1927 and ending with che first few months of 1930 witnessed a greater increase in numbers thus served than any similar period in the history of the state.. A careful survey shows that slightly more than 1,400 farmers were connected during this period of a little more than two years. Previous to 1927 there was insufficient information avail - able to justify estimates of costs of rural line construction and maintenance, or of net revenues that could be depended on if such lines were built. Every effort made by towns, farmers, or private companies was of necessity pioneering in character. Some of this pioneering showed such poor financial returns that progressive organizations became hesitant to spend time and money for sm-veying conditions or trying to discover remedies. When a new town-to-town power' line connection was made or two private companies were connected across country for stand-by service, some few farmers asked for the chance to use electricity. ' Some little show of granting these requests was made, but very little was really done to make electricity of service to very many farmers. The year 1927 probably can be cited as the time during which a definite movement was started toward making studies and trying out plans that would make electricity available on the farms for permanent benefits to producer and consumer alike. SOURCE OF INFORMATION Data for 1929, which are presented in this bulletin, were secured by 'questionnaires similar to those used in the 1927 survey. 1 Very nearly every town and power company giving any electrical service in the state responded by giving the best information possible. CHARTS AND GRAPHS The graphic illustrations and the subject matter of this publication present data for 1929 and, where possible, have been made comparable with matter presented in Bulletin 236 for 1927. Some variations in averages and totals were found. Where these contrast to a very marked degree the more value may be placed on the 1929 data because of the greater percentage of towns and companies reporting. Data 1 The data for 1927 arc presented in Bulletin 238, which this bulletin supersedes. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 for the latter year include reports from nearly 100 per cent of the towns receiving service from municipal electric plants and from about 99 per cent of the towns receiving electric service from private companies. The responses were com - plete enough to warrant a feeling of dependability on most of the data. Of the 850 towns and villages in Nebraska, not including suburbs of Omaha and Lincoln, 550 have some sort of electric service. An estimate of the number of possible sources of farm connections may be indicated by the fact that most of these towns are so served that a number of farmers could be supplied near each town if an electric line were built to the corporate limits. The towns having no electric service were for the most part very small. Reports show that 119 towns were being served January 1, 1930, from 74 municipally owned power plants. On about 150 miles of lines with voltage of 13,200 or less connectirtg towns, there were 62 farm connections. There' was another 150 miles of these lines on which there were no farm connec - tions. Of the 197 towns having municipally owned distribu - tion systems, only 40 had any farm customers. This group reported a total of 413 farmers receiving electric service. Private power companies reported serving 1,947 farmers on exclusively rural lines and 1,206 on low-voltage lines con - necting towns. From all sources, then, a total of 3,566 farm - ers were reported as served from central stations January 1, 1930. The 1927 reports showed a total of 2,142. Of the increase of 1.424 farm service connections during 1928 and 1929, over 1,000 were reported as having been made on the inter-town lines. The scarcity of these connections was brought out in the 1927 survey. In 1929, as in 1927, it was found that very few of the municipal officials could give data concerning revenue from their farmer customers or costs of upkeep debited against the farmer connections or losses due to distribution. Until recently municipalities have been able legally to serve any needs of other municipalities, companies, or farmers, provided those consumers outside the corporate limits built and main - tained the transmission or service lines,, and provided this extra demand did not interfere with caring for the needs of the city owning the generating station. This probably accounts for the fact that in nearly all cases where farmers are receiving electric service from municipalities the service lines have been owned and maintained by farmers. Less than two per cent of the farms receiving service from municipal electric systems are served from lines owned and maintained </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska by the municipalities. In the few instances where two or three towns have built to a central station usually owned by the largest municipality of the group, very few farmers have received service, and in many instances these farmers have had to buy the electricity at rates too high to encourage the use of current. The revenue from the farmers on these inter-town lines has averaged about $27.00 per year per farmer, at about 8.5 cents per kilowatt hour, which indicates a probable loss to the town and little benefit to the farmer other than that derived from lights and possibly one or two small appliances in the home. This fact should be of interest to those towns hoping to take advantage of recent legislation which permits the building of lines to give farm service and the dependence on these lines for net incomes to pay con - struction costs. Figures 1 to 10 may assist in answering some of the ques - tions coming before any group planning to build lines and give service to rural consumers. Line construction costs, as reported, varied from $650.00 to $1,100.00 per mile, exclusive of transformers and service connections, with an average cost of $860.00 per mile ; maintenance varied from $4.00 to $50.00 per mile per year, with an average of $26.00; operation varied from $4.00 to $20.00, with an average of $12.50 per mile per year ; and energy loss varied from 12 per cent to 50 per cent, with an average of 26 per cent loss of all the electrical energy supplied to farm lines. Figure 3 shows the average revenue per mile of line and emphasizes the importance of the data above. It may also serve as a basis by which net returns can be estimated. The costs of construction of rural electric lines presented are to a large degree the estimates of construction engineers and accountants. The difference of $450.00 between the high - est and the. lowest in cost per mile can be partly explained in this way, but on the whole these figures represent actual con - ditions. A certain engineer and a certain set of conditions may produce a line costing only $650.00 per mile. Usually this low-cost line will be built for 2300-volt, two-wire, single - phase service, will have poles not over 25 feet long, light cross - arms and insulators, very few lightning arresters, very few corner braces or guy wires, and no railroad or telephone lines to cross, demanding high poles, and will require very little tree trimming and no purchase of a right of way. Another engineer and another set of conditions might produce the more expensive line. The low-priced line might be thought to be too expensive in maintenance and unsatisfactory from the view-point of reliable service. The conditions might require </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 liSfilBi definitely separated on partculaTc^tTtem^bfLS'' 6 ?°' mmmmm centage of such loss Wheri tt -f lnfl uenced the per - amounts of cu'&amp;ntthe lo^was Xh^igS 5Z connections, were such that larire imnVint, ere the used thru the smaller-sized SansfoxCrs the n"'™!' loss was lower. Altho the average loS of pnf, percenta^ e of was 26 per cent, many farm lines show ™ S} \u S ve V ort^ cent loss of all en^BuppUedl^A^ '^ 3 ° Per RATES AND RATE CONTRACTS Most Nebraska towns having populations of onn had lower rates for electric service in 1929 ?Ln in ?2o- r °^ er or two towns had lowered the rates tn «,Vif 927 " One 50 kilowatt-hours could be purchased in io 2 q n f eXtent that the cost in 1927. Several towns ; showed « r) ° r one " h alf one-third in the charges on 50 kilowatt hn.f dec T ease &lt;* about were compared with 1929 rates Someo? «£ V&amp;teS charges were passed on to the farme? Date of de ?. reased terest show that towns that enioverl Vh* lS ? Peculiar in - municipally owned syateJ hSSSSJSSd^ry gJflS any </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska for service. Nearly all of the 83 towns in which the munici - pal-distribution systems were sold during 1928 or 1929 to a private company, reported lowered charges for the first 50 kilowatt-hours in 1929 as compared to the 1927 costs. In most instances farmers receiving service from these towns were enjoying lowered rates also. In one or two towns having municipally owned systems the rate was $1.25 per month minimum and the first block of energy sold at 15 cents per kilowatt-hour. The farmers re - ceiving service from these towns had the same minimum but paid 15 cents per kilowatt-hour for all energy, plus 75 cents per month transformer charge. In one or two instances where the town had a minimum of $1.00 and charged 12 cents per kilowatt-hour for the first block of energy, the rate to the farmers was a $2.00 minimum and 15 cents per kilowatt-hour for all energy. Some cases were found where the step rate in use in the town was also applied to the farm customer, plus a transformer charge which varied from 75 cents to $3.50 per month. The largest group of farmers served by any one organiza - tion in the state was receiving service under one rate, having a fixed charge of $3.50 per month (based on a transformer not larger than 3 kva) with step rate for current of 8 cents for the first 25 kilowatt-hours, 6 cents for the next 25 kilowatt - hours, and 4 cents per kilowatt-hour for all electricity used over 50 kilowatt-hours per month. This rate was based also on construction costs per consumer, amounting to $400.00 or less. Other groups were receiving service under a rate guaran - teeing a definite return each month or year to the distribut - ing source. There seemed to be a gradual acceptance of the fact that rural line extensions should be self-supporting and that because of the high costs of construction, maintenance, and operation of these lines, each rural connection should pro - duce an income to the central station of $6.00 to $10.00 per month. To the average rural consumer these amounts per month did not seem excessive but there were very few average rural consumers. Figure 5 shows that the average consumption of electrical energy by farmers was 60 kilowatt - hours per month in 1929. A large percentage of these people were in a class that used 10 to 40 kilowatt-hours per month, or the electrical energy usually consumed by the lights and a few household appliances. Most of the other farmers used much larger quantities of electricity for power and labor - saving equipment to bring the average consumption up to the amounts shown in Figure 5 and also Figure 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 g£5K£SB3SFSn ■'I i 1 if 1 1 1 90 7.30 8 1 orX »g-i- 10.00 12.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska AVERAGE ANNUAL REVENUE PER C0NSUMER-I9J7 AND 1929 . C LAS% ' DOLLARS CONSUMERS \ p;----;v--."-vx.-:-i?^i] 75.00 5 LEGEND »o| "** " 1 I 19X9 K C *°*° *56 4 p-^-"r--.'.--NJ5g| sr.^i 4e&gt; ■ I '■■■-'. ■ ■ AVERAGE OF A U "&amp; ■■■■■■ 54.95 4l 8 MUNICIPAUTIES 15 I^.^.Vvij 9&lt;lA . , 7S Fig. 1. — Many of the municipalities having some rural connections in 1927 had sold their distribution systems before the end of 1929. For this reason any interpretation of the change in revenue from 1927 to 1929 would be a mere guess. Data for the two years do give indication of the financial return to the municipalities from the farm connections. Class A towns owned and maintained the lines, Class B towns owned the lines but the farmers maintained them, Class C towns did no financing or maintaining of lines, and Class D towns aided in both financing and maintaining the lines to serve the farmers. Very few definite contracts were made and very little insurance was carried against loss or liabilities. The number of towns from which these data were secured is indicated by number. Other reports were incomplete. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 AVERAGE ANNUAL REVENUE PER. COHSUMERM927 AND M9 • NUMBER. OF COMPANY DOLLARS CONSUMERS . , p— — I — 194,06 Zl * |'-.-..'.tr;.-.-.^'.?TOa 15? r 76 ZX 3 LmM . £2.50 4 4. pHHl 6I.-JB* i5 I I 1 " 6 LbHH 58.71 "57 Lbbhhi 5a. 55 in ■ I.-.; i ---- •■a se&gt;.58 sa^ - (■■■ 49.37 348 ° [••:••■•; v.-.i Ae.oo 448 Q ■■■ 4&amp;.-3B 19-5 v 115.37 -390 . o mm . 3o.ro -3^4 p^i 3S.W 5&lt;bZ .. Lb 28.17 90 11 pT^.-vi 48.50 LtGtViD,, mmm\3Z7 523S23 «8.I4- . 4 EE23\9W ._ 10 ■■■•■■■•.'. ■■v.J.'f.a 10-3.9^ 3 '* ■.'■'.••;••..■'.&lt; sg.SO 13 AVENGE FOB. LhBI - 49.^2. UIZ. AU.C0M6UMER.S k'-i-'.^-'.-.'.'^Ti 68. 9O X.485 FIG. 2. — Some of the private companies that made reports in 1927 have changed status, but the 1929 questionnaires were made to include all farm connections shown in 1927. Several companies reported in 1929, that made no report in 1927. As nearly as possible, the graphs in Fig. 2 represent the same class of farm consumers for each com - pany. Each company is represented by iG, number. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska AVERAGE REVENUE PER MILE ON EXCLUSIVELY RURAL SERVICE UNES TOR 1927 AND 1929 COMPANY DOUMJS WILES ' jv.-.-.K-. ■■-,■■-■■■■■■■■■:«■■ ■■■■■r.:,..v.V&gt;V.V,.-.:. ; l.-.;iJ'.cmn|^TI&amp;Ol +".0 * k-w.'..-.-...".^^--.-.-..'.^-.-^-..-..^..^.-^.'.'.^-.:;.-! 363.13 6.5 G, [■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ Z3TTd ll ° 7 ;--.-:,--y/.v-v.--.-v,---,---;.-;.----i JZO.XO IST.O ■■■■ re.5o r&amp;o *■.'.'■■■.'■■■»«-, =,-.^531 \43/S3 &gt;S0.O 9 ■■■:w;.-.v.i.- J; -.rv.-A-. J ...'i.!iJ:.?J7??i Z90.V. »35.0 ■■■■■■■■■ 14-3.49 61.0 av: W .^'-vj=^i u*.77 aa.o ■ . ZO.I7 »0.0 y^n 45.5fe 17.0 '* ■■■='.-,V.v&gt;-.--.-.'-^.-l IIZ.80 IJ» 13 ■■■/■■■.••■•■■■■■■!Jv.-/.V.-ir?i ■ . !55.90 Z.O VEGEND ■■ "" ,x AVERAGE FOftAU ■■■■■■■ 11645 184.75 CONSUMERS \,:-:'.:'.&lt;.::v.-i:'..:..&gt;~::&gt;:)M J98.03 566.75 Fig. 3. — The gToss revenues per mile for both years were taken from data reported on lines of various construction costs and ages. The averages from both Figures 3 and 4 might be considered as returns from the average of about $860.00 per mile construction cost as shown -from a partial report. If average costs of service connections, •energy loss per mile, maintenance, and operation were deducted from these gross returns, the net returns for average conditions would be closely estimated. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 i ■ •. •■'_.. :■■_■_. AVERAGE REVENUE PEQ MILE ON EXCLUSIVELY RUQAL SEPVICE LINES-I93T AND l«9 CLASS D0LU?5 MILES F"*&lt; : &amp; 53.40 7.0 B F* *6.67 fe.o C f*" 1 ** 1 * 90.^ II4-.37 D aOl.fcl 57.0 |;v---{-----.-.;ai 6 , ro 3) 5 AVERAGE ALL Municipal F^~!z^^ 1z0 - |j *- ioo.37 consumed tesnszi 8U4 . IM : 79 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska AVERAGE KW-MR. PER YEAR PER CONSUMER-1927 AND 1929 COMPANY KVM-H1*. CONSUMER? ■--■'■, p»«lM«»W—— — ■ *4oe l\ ■.'.■■•^''■'■■'■.••^■•.^•."'■•■i^w^l *4*7 45 . - . ■■■■■■■■■ 1304- 19 Uv:..:w^v: t; :;w;, ;W i |99 S *" L--.--.t'.-.i 4so aio .„ ■■■■■ O75 37 6 MB 407 97 7 PBBB1 721 II - Um 39X. -S49 I _ L&gt;.:,:-_-:,l-J 5»| ©97 . 9 pBl 438 I9S to h— «* 3t+ „ ■ - iSO 80 ES23 4i4 se '.; U 23 , «Z6.5 4 1/3 ■:-:;-,v.---.v.-...^..t| I24O » LEGEND IV ■■■ 192.7 r.vry-^'^A 73S 19 «S3 I9A9 15 Z223 . 3OS.8 4* AVERAGE FOQ ALL IBSl 3X0.S IX.IX CONSUMERS |., j ... -; ... ; .m.. i 72-3.5 AB99 Pig. 5. — As in 1927 the only available data on annual consumption of electrical energy for 1929 were from the private companies. Ap - parently officials have felt- it would be better for all concerned if consumption were increased rather than if construction, mainten - ance, and operation costs were lowered. Boosting the annual con - sumption has been the aim of most who were closely associated with the rural electric service work. The increase shown here should be very encouraging. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 AVERAGE REVENUE PER KW.-HR. 1927 AND 19*9 COMPANY . CENTS , p—— I . s.oe |:w:&gt;-.vv»-.'j &lt;O.IO |..:;-,v.v.-:»::nt T.65 - ■■■■■■■ 9.00 I Lv.v.w.v:.'.-.' ;;.'.". vi -.'4 \Z.S7 -" t.-i.-'.-..vY.v.-. l .'. l 3 e.es |.Y-,i-.- ; -N ti.'M !v.V.'-:s.v.-.-'.:v.f:H:v.l II. ?O | ll ■^,-y.N-V;v.'-;:A-,.,.p,. r .;:v,,.-,rr77T T m &gt; i»o 1-3 :-i.';.»y- ;•■'■■ viTTTT • 8. 30 LEGEND l4 " "•■-■•■•'■••••• »v;;;a a.»o f..-.".vi ioao :.v.-&gt;.'.--.- i .-.-.v.-. l .'.v:.'a U.fce AVEQAGE POtJ ALL p^——l &lt;D AT CONSUMERS V.--.------ ■■,-■■-■■■■3 e.95 Fig. 6. — A natural result of an increased consumption under most of the present farm rate schedules is a decreased average cost per unit of electricity. Many rural people are curious to know the trend of the cost of service. A confidence that the cost will probably lessen as time goes on is an incentive to prepare to use electricity as soon as possible. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska AVERAGE NUMBER OF CONSUMERS PER MILE OF POLE LINES SERVING FAQMS OHLY (not wteq- town) COMPANY CONSUMER*, CONSUMER PHI M&gt;V.E ' ■■■■-, , 1 .-».j-a..m * e ■■■ .89 O * ■-.';■■•&gt;! ; I -V. - .| I .*S S * ."■.;■■■&gt;.■■■■■■••:!!.&lt;' *..IT WO . ■■■■■■■■■■■ A.05 a% _ HH 1.59 I-ST ° o.'.'j:,v.-.vii-V».'-.-r?a .; ».«» 4*O 9 SESZS32SS3 *.St 99O 10 ,,,:,,v,......j 1 .,.v.. !1 * t*^. ■■1 I Q 11 SZ3 .59 10 \2 14. . LEQEND ■■ iw , 6 j_V f.-.:"'l I9Z.9 ■ "■■■■-■•■"' ■■•■ = &gt;.•■•.■&gt;■■■ ••■■■■■■•■■.••j ;■•■!.-■■•■ ■.■■■M'w.,1 6.6 IO AVEQAOEALU ! fe^,/ w }S «9^ Fig. 7. — Although many companies were still below the average of two farm connections per mile, most of the companies having any considerable number of consumers show an average of well over two connections per mile to bring up the general average. On the exclusively rural service lines running from municipally owned systems this average was 1.8 per mile. These lines were owned mostly by the farmers themselves. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 AVERAGE NUMBER OF CONSUMERS PER MILE OF LINE l^OO VOLTS 01*. LESS -19*7 AND )9Z9 COMDANY CONSUMER V.WWWT ; PEI^MILE MILES I ' .0- Ii5 I I * !l7 V».7 i ™ J .» 86.3 :"",'. -b f" .» i*.o 1 -4 ■ ■■■■■-.■■ ;■■■■■ ■-,■•;■ ■•-'.■■-■I. , | 3a _5 S " ■ .» 310.0 I . . ■ I pv;ii-nr l ',Twi i.aii 3J9.0 a P*^^^** LSI taro [^'^ : '*'' ; '' ; ' iV *' V| 1-4^ 6IS.O 9 • 8 « 10 •''fe 336.0 '■■■■■&gt; -.■."".••.-■-.iiiVj-a i_ 5 i 37i j 0 | M B .15 210.0 33 .»S7 2U0 u , : 1 .OSS A7.0 LEOEfiD •-■■■ L ..-.i-.--.-.. a . )5 iQ ! ■■ »9X7 '♦ .,.n j|., v ,. k .,... E3 l9A 9 ' ' ■■•■•''•^"i-^^a • 1.63 ao 223 .317 31.5 . ! AVEIJAGEALl. \l\l CONSUMECS . .004 JSOfcB Lu;;v •-vr.-,; f -.-. 1 j T93 CON5UMEBS l.i 73«tO Fig. 8.— Many of the low-voltage inter-town lines served very few farmers prior to 1927. Several companies secured most of their . new farmer connections during 1928 and 1929 by adding to the con - nections on these existing lines rather than tapping new territory. Paragraph 2 page 4, shows that the municipally owned svstenis "her t P o r wns b a y re a s d e d r ved any C ° nnecti °" s to «■•" throu K h\vhieh </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Rural Electric Service in Nebraska PERTINENT DATA FROM Z ORGANIZED FARM UNESM927 ANNUAL REVENUE PER MILE * [aaaaa— *»15.75 AvEtjAce ■■■■■■■■■I •* IX^. e&gt;3 ANNUAL REVENUE PER CONSUMER &gt; ■aaaßi *.?X.\Q *■ aaaaaa * ■■■■ AVERAQE LhB^BH ANNUAL KW.-HR. PEQ CONSUMER 1 ■■^i^HBHBBI 475 ■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■i se&gt;a AVEIJAQE ■■■■HIH^iMHHBHBaHi 4e&gt;T ANNUAL REVENUE PER KW.-HP. 1 |— —^— ■ I S.I CENTS j^i— i^—— 19.1 CENTS. "3 ■■■■■■■■■■■■^ \5.&amp; CENTS Average ■■■■■■■■■■iii^ iva cents AV. NO. CONSUMERS PER MILE OF LINE 3 pHMBHHH 1.79 Average LaaaHnßaß^BM i.&amp;a- Fig. 9. — These data are duplicated from Bulletin 236. The farm lines from which the data were secured were formerly owned and managed by farmers but have recently been purchased and are now being managed by corporations. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 AVERAGE REVENUE PER KW-HQ. FOR. ALL FARM CONSUMERS AND EX - CLUSIVELY RURAL LINE CONSUMERS COMPANY 1929 CENTS fslv:&gt;\.:'.:U 5.TX. h *-p r '■' - j * " J £} AQ r B— — e.j.5 e |i^— I^^M . • IJ.8T .lv-.'-v-.-'-'. ! i-'.';''-.'-.'-"J-'-i u.*5 viiivrtijvyn-3 e.73 II SS"""™ '■'. M.to «x «-*° ■■■■■■■■■-•,v ■■■,■■■.;■;■.■;■■-■■■■.■■-■;■•.■. i'.-,- ,-.■•■•■■•■ '■■•■■S3 3O.Q0 [••■'•--"••■•.-•.■"•&gt;:--r- e.oa AVEPAGfe ALL consumeqs Haaa^ : • a 95 AV. EXCLUSIVELY E233Z3 LEGEND 7TT HUQALUNE CONSUMERS ALL CONSUMERS k •'•• v'-*i EXCLUSIVELY RPRAt UAOE CON&amp;UMEftS Fig. ,10. — A rather peculiar situation was shown in comparing the costs per kilowatt-hour to farmers on the exclusively farm lines with costs of the same unit to farmers on all low-voltage lines. Evidently there should be some more adjustments made in the rates to farm - ers who are connected to lines that join towns. ' These connections should require lower costs than those where the total revenue is from farmers only. ■•"'.. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Rural, Electric Service in Nebraska ■■■ . ■'...■■■ ■''.- * lo\L lc r I MONTHLY BILLS TO CONSUME** AND L \ \\ AVENGE COST PEfc KW HR.-FOUR | I. \ ■ WFFtftENT TASM HATES ~| ri¥f [~H 11^ .» I I" I II" I I I I I «e*o«o m ao mo tie i4o in aao kv. Htt». pro woAtm w&gt; »v tabm« Fig. 11.— Curves show monthly bills for various amounts of current on farm rates of (aa) a farmer-owned line, (bb) Company 8, (cc) a proposed rate for municipalities under the new law, and (dd) Com - pany 9. AA, BB, CC, and DD show average cost per kilowatt-hour when various amounts of current were used under the separate rates. The intersections on the perpendicular line at 60 kilowatt-hours show the average costs when average consumption corresponds to that reported in 1929. The perpendicular at 125 kilowatt-hours shows what the average costs would be if the consumption averaged that figure. Attention should be called to the very small variation of costs, from one rate to another, when a consumption of 125 kilo - watt-hours per month is reached by a farmer. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 BUfcAL CONSUMERS 1 MONTHLY U3EOF ENEQGY i USE OF NUMBED. PERCENT TOT. KW-MJ. PEft CEtfT TOT. i rNEgqv CONSUMER CONVMEQS . monthly CUIJ8.ENT I IQI-OVEg ~j * 3.8 • feffi«&amp;# i 3.8 510 19.10 &gt;: )yj}]/}y a. \:.-'. - : "»:•.■.•• p^^ ||1§|| 14S I i ■ ' lliiiiiM I : • • O I .• P &lt; ItVV^HP zo ' ST - e •" lUJlUil D ■ ** Ml » &gt; Of /////// Si a^^ I ■ I o co-iocvv Fig. 12. —^What to do about the very small consumer is always a prob - lem. This chart was .made up from a farm line on which very little effort was made to increase use of current. Consumption of current by groups is also shown. A study of Figures 11 and 12 shows a part of the problem that confronts a rate maker for any line. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">riS KW-HQ. CONSUMPTION PCS MONTH ___^_ i* » " "** »*.?« FARMS'?* / 40 — — \ LEGEND [ / C 10 4iT ra. mck n may June Juvx— " Aik SeE 5?t nov. dec Fig. 13. — A seasonal average consumption showing a tendency toward increased consumption in a small way even where no promotional work was done. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 254 FAgM UNE TRANSMISSION LOSSES asoo : : ; I EC, LND J.6OO 1 • ■ ■ : ' 1^ &lt;VfrH?. DELIVECEO i Moo _ . _j_ WZk KVNt-t-C. TQ^MSFCIJMER COQiLOSS ':• ■ 4,!Oo — . .— ■— — ___ _ _^ '. .■ ■ KW.-l-tJ. O-HER TIJANb- .. .'■'$'• MISSION LOSS. • • ■ '.:'. . ■' •sao« ■•• •• : :■■■'..■■■ :■ . ■•■' ■ ■■■■•••• KNA/.-4Q. P(&gt; ' : — f^~. — ~ ..'■'.. aaooll^ :•.-•-• ]% ! T~T- : i-V - ; V v: ' -.-:•:■ Koo ;■;-/ ■ * ■ , ■ ; ■■•, ' O " " . • —L^J— '•*'•.'•■ .• ■■•'.■ .■ ■■'■' '■ ■ ■ »*oo ;';://.'• .•■'-■ : •-.. "' ■' - : •/•-'' - : ■' '■' '"■ .- '■'■'■■'■:'■ ■ .' ■ ■ .:■ .-•■' .' - ■ ;."' looo !";■;.•'.• .' " . ' : •'•*■•■ -'■'■• ■ ":■'■ •'•'.-'•■'!■ ■!■'■'■■: '■•'■•'..•. -'■•■' : ■ :. ■ . '. id i-'"Vv ..■■"• : . •'■'.•■■-•"■■■..■■'{■• •■•.:'•■•' '■ ••■':■■■■••.'-■.'•.••-'. '- ; :•.■■••"-••"•• "•'••:. •:••-. or i^ff^- ■.•."•.•;|l ;■';-;: t—^ 4^-i — 1C- -ilJlL: li__ iiHi _v^, i *boo^r-|- r i^v-^ -S'- : y "' : : I)'-'-'- '■ ";'•'■•'■• -•*■'"•■"•■'■ ';••:■'•'' '•V--'-: ■';■■' '■ ■ "•■•.-•■ : ; ■ ■' t &lt;4oo Li4^- r^^-^ V; ; y. ■■•,;';■." - &lt;: ;.y :•■"•■■'•' ;.l-''v •■•."•'•^ ;^_vl •'■":•■•"■■ JArt. Feb. M*8 APii. may JuHE Jotv Aug. Sun ; Oct- Mov Dec. Fig. 14. — Transmission line losses on the farm service lines c-ontinue to be of importance. The data for this chart (W27) were taken from a farmer-owned line. The core . loss from 47 transformers varying in size from l ] /6 to 10 kva., amounted to 1,000 kilowatt hours per month, regardless of consumer requirements. The average total transmission losses of 31.9 per cent shown here is slightly higher than the average of all lines as reported for 1929. Irregularities show up because of some variation in time when different meters were read. ■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Rural Electric Service in Nebraska ELECTRIC EQUIPMENT THAT THE FARMER USES AVERAGE OF 564 FARMERS 1 *■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ LIGHT 2 ■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ WASH I NQ MACHINE ' ■■■■■■■■■^■M IRON '4 ■■■■■■Mi RADIO ■■■■■■ WATER PUMP tt ■■■■■■ CHARGE CAR, BATTERIES T ■■■ © ■■ 5H0P 9 ■■ PERCOLATOR 10 ■■ VACUUM CLEANER 11 IB TOASTER 1% ■ LIGHTS TO INCREASE WINTER EQQ PRO- I OUCTION 13 ■ REFRIGERATOR. 14- ■ 5EWINQ MACHINE n M QRlNDSTONE 16 H FEED GRINDERS IT ■ FAN . 18 I CHURN 19 I &amp;OL0ERINO IRON 20 1 MILKINQ MACHINE Fin. 15. — Equipment and appliances and their relative importance to farmers. Items are shown in the proportionate place that farmers have siven them' in usage. This represents 1927 conditions; no later survey of these conditions has been completed in Nebraska. ' [5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>