<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION TWENTIETH ANNUAL REPORT 1928</title>
               <date value="1928">1928</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION TWENTIETH ANNUAL REPORT 192 8 v JSIe"" John C. Trouton State Fire Marshal L. J. Butcher. Assistant State Fire Marshal Sigrid Rasmussen Secretary E. E. Hayduk ...Deputy State Fire Marshal Thomas L. Wilson Deputy State Fire Marshal Ray E. Eaton..... Deputy State Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Ti'imm.il Printing Company </seg>
            <seg id="p003">ARTHUR J. WEAVER Governor of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">111 ' ■ ■ -39™ 88l 1^ j ■i y" "^^^ . - .^^| SSI JOHN C. TROUTON Slate Fire Marshal </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">TWENTIETH ANNUAL REPORT of the STATE FIRE MARSHAL . Office of State Fire Marshal, State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska. To His Excellency, Arthur J. Weaver, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Your Excellency: In compliance with the law governing this department, which provides that a report of all business transacted, orders issued, and acts performed by the State Fire Mar - shal, his deputies and other constituting the Department be made to you annually, I take pleasure m submitting to you, this the Twentieth Annual Report, covering the ac - tivities of this Department which you have placed under my direction. It is a pleasure to have the manifestation of your interest and helpfulness m this great work of Fire Prevention and I take this opportunity of expressing my appreciation of your confidence m me, and of your great help to this De - partment. This report will show a marked reduction m fire losses throughout the state. This we feel is due to the assistance rendered to the Division of Fire Prevention by the fire chiefs and members of the fire departments m the various cities, towns, and villages of the state, by the county attor - neys, sheriffs, the Nebraska State Fire Prevention Associa - tion, and all their fire prevention agencies who have aided m the elimination of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fires, and I take this opportunity of thanking them for their aid and assistance. The inspection work of this division has been more effect - ive this year than heretofore as the reduction m fire losses </seg>
            <seg id="p008">State op Nebraska will prove, and as a result I am pleased to report that our cities and towns are cleaner and freer from fire hazards today in Nebraska than ever before, and I look forward hopefully to the time when this work can be extended to the farms and rural sections of the state, to the end that farmers and others may have a greater knowledge of the value of fire prevention work. This extension of our work has not been possible due to the limited amount of funds at the disposal of the Fire Marshal's Office. The Department has been operated in a business likt manner and well within the funds at its disposal, and what - ever measure of success has been obtained has been due to the courteous, loyal and uniting efforts of everyone con - nected with the Department. Assistant Fire Marshall Lynn J. Butcher, Deputies Ed. E. Hayduk, Thomas L. Wilson, and Ray E. Eaton, and our secretary Miss Sigrid Rasmussen, have worked earnestly and consistently in an effort to reduce fire hazards and I am pleased to report that their efforts in this direction have been rewarded in a very gratifying manner. In submitting this report for your consideration, I want to thank you for your confidence in me and for the helpful advice you have given to me, and that I may always con - tinue to merit this confidence and esteem is the most ear - nest wish, of, Yours respectfully, JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire Marshall. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Division op Fire Prevention 1928 TAX Aetna Fire Insurance Company $ 688.31 Agricultural Insurance Company 143.46 Allemania Fire Insurance Company 4.67 Alliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia.... 105.90 American Alliance Insurance Company 34.25 American Central Fire Insurance Company 73.4!". American Druggists Fire Insurance Company.... 5.90 American Eagle Fire Insurance Company 47.98 American Fire Insurance Company of Newark.... 363.30 American Merchants Marine Insurance Company 5.29 Atlas Assurance Company, Limited, of London... 23.83 Automobile Insurance Company of Hartford...... 35.99 Bankers and Shippers Fire Insurance Company.. 8.86 Boston Insurance Company 77.42 British American Assurance Company 23.39 Buffalo Fire Insurance Company 39.95 Caledonian Insurance Company 80.66 California Insurance Company 12.93 Camden Fire Insurance Association... 78.19 Carolina Insurance Company 1.45 Central Manufacturers Mutual Insurance Co 18.83 Citizens Insurance Company of Missouri 21.44 | City of New York Insurance Company 35.44 Columbia Insurance Company 10.21 Columbian National Fire Insurance Co .61 Commerce Insurance Company 11.83 Commercial Union Assurance Company 128.73 Commercial Union Fire Insurance Company 7.67 j Commonwealth Insurance Company 108.59 1 " Concordia Fire Insurance Company 74.97 J Connecticut Fire Insurance Company 623.59 V Continental Insurance Company. 443.43 j ■ County Fire Insurance Company of Philadelphia 13.24 Detroit Fire and Marine Insurance Company 14.59 Druggist Mutual Insurance Company 9.79 Dubuque Fire and Marine Insurance Company.... 78.75 t Eagle Fire Insurance Company. 2.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">State of Nebraska Eagle Star &amp; British Dominions Ins. Co 53.68 East and West Insurance Company 15.58 Employers Fire Insurance Company 83.61 Equitable Fire and Marine Insurance Company.. 38.84 Equity Fire Insurance Company .51 Eureka Security Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co. . 2.95 Farmer's Fire Insurance Company 17.90 Federal Insurance Company 26.94 Federal Union Fire Insurance Company 21.95 Fidelity-Phoenix Fire Insurance Company 454. 33 Fire Association of Philadelphia 105.36 Firemen's Insurance Company 153.94 Firemen's Fund Insurance Company 103.96 First American Insurance Company 11.12 Fitchburg Mutual Fire Insurance Company 3.53 Franklin Fire Insurance Company 149.58 Franklin National Insurance Company 12.90 General Exchange Insurance Company 102.64 General Insurance Company of America 25.88 Girard Fire and Marine Insurance Company 51.09 Glens Falls Insurance Company 305.66 Globe and Rutgers Fire Insurance Company 1,204.00 Grain Dealers National Mutual Fire Ins. Co... 163.54 Granite State Fire Insurance Company 60.15 Great American Insurance Company 430.84 Great Lakes Insurance Company 3.16 Guaranty Fire Insurance Company 22.86 Hanover Fire Insurance Company 132.87 Hardware Dealers Mutual Fire Insurance Co.. 122.99 Harmonia Fire Insurance Company .02 Hartford Fire Insurance Company 819.15 Henry Clay Fire Insurance Company 20.26 Home Fire and Marine Insurance Company 8.38 Homeland Insurance Co. of America .65 Home Insurance Company 1,057.01 Hudson Insurance Company 34.20 Imperial Assurance Company 15.04 Implement Dealers Mutual Fire Ins. Co 114.38 Importers &amp; Exporters Insurance Company 28.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">. Division op Fire Prevention Insurance Company of North America 660.38 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 35.00 Inter Ocean Reinsurance Company. 16.27 International Insurance Company .248.81 Law Union and Rock Insurance Company. 40.59 Liverpool, London_ and Globe Ins. Co.... 329.89 London Assurance Corporation 30.33 London and Lancashire Insurance Company.. 129.21. London and Scottish Assurance Corp., Ltd 2.34 Lumbermen's Mutual Insurance Company 7.99 Maryland Motor Car Insurance Company. 6.81 Massachusetts Fire and Marine Insurance Co 8.89 Mechanic's Insurance Company of Philadelphia 95.34 Mechanic's and Traders Insurance Company...... 21.20 Mercantile Insurance Company of America 293.09 Merchants Fire Insurance Company.. 37.22 Merchants Fire Assurance Corporation 69.13 Merchants Insurance Company 27.48 Mercury Insurance Company 32.11 Michigan Fire and Marine Insurance Company... 12.93 Michigan Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Co 37.37 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Association 36.07 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Company 14.60 Millers National Fire Insurance Company 53.51 Mill Owner's Mutual Fire Insurance Company.... 88.38 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Company.. 182.85 Minnesota Implement Mutual Fire Insurance Co. 46.05 National American Fire Insurance Company 759.59 National Ben Franklin Fire Insurance Company 105.89 National Fire Insurance Company of Hartford.... 2,056.32 National Implement Mutual Insurance Company 13.20 National Liberty Fire Insurance Company 147.22 National Reserve Insurance Company 29.00 National Retailers Mutual Fire Insurance Co °"&gt;..t* National Security Fire Insurance Company. 397.9? National Union Fire Insurance Company 337.79 The Netherlands Insurance Company 32.30 Newark Fire Insurance Company 30.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">State op Nebraska I New Brunswick Fire Insurance Company 39.15 New England Fire Insurance Company 8.35 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Company 135.38 New York Underwriters Insurance Company 263.54 Niagara Fire Insurance Company 43.68 North British and Mercantile Insurance Co., Ltd. 179.56 North Carolina Home Insurance Company 8.84 Northern Assurance Company, Ltd 41.65 North River Insurance Company 141.24 Northwestern Fire and Marine Insurance Co 84.38 Northwestern Mutual Fire Association 15.52 Northwestern National Fire Insurance Company 134.70 Norwich Union Fire Insurance Company 53.76 Ohio Farmers Insurance Company .67 Ohio Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Company 55.53 Ohio Millers Mutual Insurance Company 12.82 Old Colony Fire Insurance Company 15.12 Orient Insurance Company 140.24 Pacific Fire Insurance Company 18.90 Palatine Insurance Company 20.28 Patriotic Insurance Company of America 7.00 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company 155.88 Pennsylvania Fire Ins. Company (Millers Mut.) 9.79 Philadelphia Fire and Marine Insurance Co. 48.82 Phoenix Insurance Company 385. 7- r Phoenix Assurance Company, Ltd. of London 55.23 Potomac Fire Insurance Company. 53.82 Preferred Risk Fire Insurance Company 33.36 Providence "Washington Fire Insurance Company 26.76 Prudential of Great Britain 45.45 Queen Insurance Company 271.51 I Reinsurance Company Salamandra 151.88 Reliance Insurance Company of Philadelphia. 17.88 Republic Fire Insurance Company 10.T2 Retail Hardware Mutual Fire Insurance Co 104.44 Rhode Island Insurance Company 97.91 Rocky Mountain Fire Insurance Company 4.04 Royal Exchange Assurance Company 14.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Division op Fire Prevention Royal Insurance Company 351.24 Safeguard Insurance Company. 17.40 Scottish Union &amp; National 121.91 Security Insurance Company : 211.74 Security Mutual Fire Insurance Company. 9.76 Sentinel Insurance Company. 19.11 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Company.. 682.89 Standard Fire Insurance Company 4.39 Star Insurance Company of America 59.33 State Assurance Company Limited of Liverpool.. 18.74 St. Paul Fire and Marine Insurance Company.... 660.57 Sun Insurance Company of London 147.12 Superior Fire Insurance Company.. 4.13 Svea Fire and Life Insurance Company, Ltd 30.46 Transcontinental Insurance Company 2.03 Travelers Insurance Company 157.43 Twin City Fire Insurance Company 47.32 Union Assurance Society, Ltd 4.83 Union Automobile Insurance Company 54.60 The Union Fire Insurance Company of Paris 27.16 United Firemen's Insurance Co. of Philadelphia 6.62 United Mutual Fire Insurance Company 34.66 United States Fire Insurance Company 245.15 U. S. Merchants and Shippers Insurance Co 7.93 Victory Insurance Company :.... 12.60 I Westchester Fire Insurance Company 104.61 Western Assurance Company 11.90 , Western Fire Insurance Company 1.53 .' Western Gram Dealers Mutual Fire Ins. Co 79.40 World Auxiliary Insurance Corporation, Ltd 3.37 World Fire and Marine Insurance Company .'. 12.45 TOTAL TAX COLLECTED ..$22,009.61 ; ) Balance on hand January 1st, 1928, iii Treasury....20,297.32 Total Tax Collected 22,009.61 TOTAL FUND JANUARY 1st, 1928 42,306.93 The above figures show the amount of tax money on </seg>
            <seg id="p014">State of Nebraska hand to cover the expenditures for the year 1928. These expenditures were as follows: Salaries . $12,600.00 $12,600.00 Office Expense Printing 535.10 Stamps 250.00 Supplies and Equipment.. 76.98 Telegraph 2.50 Telephone 102.80 Miscellaneous 16.00 TOTAL 983.38 983.38 Inspectors' Expenses (Traveling) Railroad Transportation.. 330.40 Hotel Expenses 2,158.75 Auto Expenses, Taxi and Carfare 2,539.62 Miscellaneous 88.56 TOTAL 5,117.33 5,117.33 Expenses Incurred in Investiga - tion of Fire Temporary Services 26.75 26.75 Fire Report Fees Paid to Fire Chiefs for Reporting 1927 Fires .. 600.00 600.00 TOTAL EXPENDITURES FOR 1928 $19,327.46 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Division op Fire Prevention SUMMARY OF THE ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Inspections made 11,098 j Orders issued..... 11,238 Orders complied with while inspectors were in town.. 4,747 Buildings demolished by order of this department... 243 Buildings repaired by order of this department 679 Public buildings changing doors to swing outward, (churches, hotels, schools, hospitals, lodge halls, dance halls and theatres) 128 New fire escapes installed: Schools (Tubular 3; Spiral 9) 12 Apartment houses, dance halls, lodge halls and theatres 18 Iron fire escapes on schools lowered to floor level and doors placed as exit to escape in place of windows 23 Schools extensively repaired 19 Moving picture theatres extensively repaired 89 Moving picture theatres closed on second floor of buildings 7 Public buildings receiving extensive electrical repairs 72 Panic bar locks installed on public buildings 127 Kerosene tanks removed from store buildings 584 Fires investigated 92 Persons arrested for arson 5 Persons convicted of arson 3 ', Persons acquitted 2 Persons bound over from 1926 and cases still pending 7 ! ' CAUSES OF FIRES AS REPORTED DURING 1928 Balance if Of _ Omaha Lincoln State Total Unknown causes 45. 36 160 241 Sparks from chimney on roof 96 50 144 290 Defective chimney '. 14 6 70 90 Gasoline and Kerosene stoves.... 10 6 54 70 ...... ... . . _-.'.. __ - ; </seg>
            <seg id="p016">State op Nebraska Overheated stoves and furnaces 13 10 73 96 Communicated 11 5 23 39 Defective electric wires 8 7 73 88 Spontaneous combustion 5 9 29 43 Children and matches 16 5 18 39 Cigarettes, cigars and pipes 18 1 20 39 Inflammables too near stoves 2 4 14 20 Bonfires and burning grass 13 5 25 43 Incendiary 2 1 17 20 Gasoline explosion 12 0 18 30 Hot ashes against wood 9 2 17 28 Oil Burners 1 1 8 10 Sparks from engine 10 3 4 Lightning 3 2 20 25 Stills overheating 2 0 0 2 Brooders and incubators 4 1 13 18 Oils and greases on stoves 0 0 6 6 Starting fires with kerosene and gasoline 0 0 4 4 Motor back fires 2 2 8 12 Mice and matches 2 0 5 7 Electric curling and flatirons 3 5 10 18 Motion picture films 0 0 2 2 Fireworks 2 15 8 Smoking in bed 4 12 7 Thawing out water pipes 4 0 15 Washing clothes with gasoline.. 2 12 5 Static electricity 0 0 3 3 Rubbish 5 2 47 54 Careless use of matches 7 2 9 18 Miscellaneous 7 4 10 21 Total number of fires.... 323 169 913 1405 Less communicated fires 11 5 23 39 312 164 890 1365 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Division op Fire Prevention FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Adams - $138,800.00 $ 79,400.00 $ 18,674.00 Contents 27,081.00 24,706.00 8,502.00 Antelope 40,810.00 22,250.00 5,145.00 Contents 28,390.00 15,600.00 3,380.00 Boone 83,800.00 52,000.00 16,025.00 Contents 21,230.00 2,000.00 5,020.00 Box Butte 72,800.00 51,400.00 9,985.00 Gonte nts 99,800.00 29,600.00 11,835.00 B °y d - 3,200.00 1,200.00 150.00 Contents 900.00 700.00 none Brown • 3,750.00 2,500.00 3,400.00 Cont ents 7,000.00 6,750.00 3,800.00 Buffalo 48,850.00 35,652.00 8,847.00 Contents 16,875.00 11,350.00 1,475.00 Burt 11,580.00 4,400.00 2,330.00 Contents 2,462.00. 900.00 260.00 Butler ......... 35,050.00 25,300.00 16,310.00 Contents 24,273.00 22,100.00 10,480.00 Cass 29,900.00 16,000.00 2,491.00 Contents _.-.? . 18,400.00 10,900.00 330.00 Cedar 38,600.00 20,075.00 4,995.00 Contents 57,580.00 41,380.00 2,107.00 Cherry 5,350.00 2,900.00 2,650.00 Contents ., 6,825.00 900.00 5,600.00 Cheyenne 123,350.00 91,000.00 5,397.00 .'. Contents 24,500.00 6,500.00 1,625.00 Clay 6,770.00 2,950.00 4,970.00 7 Contents , 4,675.00 1,900.00 4,525.00 Colfax , 3,000.00 2,200.00 2,365.00 Contents 3,200.00 1,735.00 1,300.00 * Cuming 52,225.00 24,250.00 6,680.00 Contents 17,325.00 14,110.00 ■ 4,237.00 Custer 31,325.00 20,000.00 2,800.00 • Contents 16,640.00 7,775.00 2,855.00 Dakota 33,200.00 21,700.00 7,465.00 Contents 21,600.00 9,700.00 3,125.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Dawes 95,600.00 39,000.00 51,400.00 Contents 11,300.00 10,000.00 7,890.00 Dawson 31,740.00 20,300.00 3,760.00 Contents 41,120.00 37,275.00 5,370.00 Deuel 3,800.00 2,000.00 300.00 Contents 2,500.00 1,000.00 400.00 Dodge 154,965.00 103,880.00 26,406.00 Contents 156,095.00 105,050.00 24,187.00 Douglas 13.200.00 9,100.00 670.00 Contents 4,925.00 2,600.00 750.00 Fillmore 18,230.00 8,400.00 3,915.00 Contents 16,850.00 2,400.00 1,340.00 Franklin 11,500.00 7,800.00 5,065.00 Contents 6,650.00 4,350.00 4,100.00 Frontier 6,400.00 3,300.00 1,150.00 Contents 3,200.00 2,200.00 1,550.00 Furnas 52,400.00 25,400.00 27,740.00 Contents 34,075.00 23,750.00 17,142.00 Gage 751,425.00 498,350.00 117,120.00 Contents 641,345.00 425,100.00 64,440.00 Garfield 6,400.00 11,000.00 550.00 Contents 2,000.00 2&amp;0.00 200.00 Grant 3,000.00 1,500.00 75.00 Contents 800.00 300.00 100.00 Hall 5,177,475.00 127,725.00 22.828.00 Contents 436,350.00 351,575.00 18,993.00 Hamilton 4,900.00 3,175.00 1,065.00 Contents 1,800.00 150.00 1,200.00 Harlan 35,350.00 13,750.00 1,077.00 Contents 8,400.00 4,500.00 1,251.00 Hayes 3,900.00 2,200.00 2,725.00 Contents 1,400.00 none 1.300.00 Hitchcock 9,475.00 4,925.00 1,340.00 Contents 3,260.00 1,650.00 760.00 Holt 50,550.00 33,250.00 2,900.00 Contents 21,420.00 11,000.00 1,400.00 Hooker 12,000.00 7,500.00 150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Division op Fire Prevention County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam on Bldgs. Contents 7,000.00 5,000.00 * 25.00 Howard 8,300.00 5,800.00 565.00 Contents 2,305.00 1,500.00 240.00 Jefferson 180,040.00 136,570.00 -17,090.00 Contents 650,453.00 595,793.00 70,636.00 Johnson 57,520.00 37,575.00 5,555.00 Contents .... 26,963.00 13,100.00 3,788.00 Kearney 27,175.00 7,215.00 1,900.00 Contents ............ 16,265.00 6,025.00 1,885.00 Keith -■--'• 5,500.00 3,300.00 200.00 Contents 3,500.00 2,200.00 2,078.00 Kimball 8,300.00 5,000.00 2,435.00 Contents ,. 13,000.00 14,500.00 10,800.00 Knox 29,940.00 16,500.00 12,057.00 Contents 19,550.00 13,775.00 13,651.00 Lancaster 74,625.00 49,900.00 28,880.00 Contents 27,405.00 15,800.00 11,290.00 Lincoln 43,275.00 28,300.00 11,700.00 Contents 20,530.00 14,600.00 7,780.00 Madison 88,325.00 53,420.00 14,765.00 Contents 65,040.00 45,430.00 14,212.00 Merrick 25,300.00 13,550.00 1,025.00 Contents 11,675.00 6,800.00 290.00 Morrill 4,300.00 6,000.00 650.00 Contents 4,100.00 2,500.00 125.00 Nance 65,250.00 40,750.00 4,101.00 Contents 35,660.00 15,400.00 3,361.00 Nemaha 42,300,00 27,430.00 4,437.00 Contents 76,550.00 13,730.00 3,620.00 Nuckolls 93,500.00 67,150.00 10,476.00 Contents 53,725.00 27,905.00 4,408.00 Otoe 24,300.00 14,400.00 18,085.00 Contents 12,100.00 8,500.00 10,727.00 Pawnee 27,765.00 13,625.00 5,557.00 Contents 18,051.00 12,300.00 3,691.00 Perkins 2,000.00 1,300.00 550.00 Contents 750.00 500.00 75.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">State of Nebraska County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam on Bldgs. Phelps 49,100.00 30,500.00 33,440.00 Contents 15,640.00 7,000.00 6,890.00 Pierce 20,200.00 11,500.00 247.00 Contents 18,300.00 11,500.00 175.00 Platte 126,575.00 92,350.00 11,513.00 Contents 56,650.00 37,350.00 5,340.00 Polk 41,225.00 28,500.00 751.00 Contents 6,175.00 3,850.00 565.00 Red Willow 28,450.00 19,100.00 4,875.00 Contents 13,900.00 4,800.00 8,825.00 Richardson 235,725.00 160,400.00 25,565.00 Contents 127,900.00 40,250.00 6,085.00 Rock 150.00 none 60.00 Contents none none none Saline 59,230.00 34,375.00 15,179.00 Contents 28,020.00 15,600.00 2,355.00 Saunders 96,725.00 50,700.00 22,087.00 Contents 80,350.00 36,300.00 22,691,00 Scotts Bluff 160,975.00 112,500.00 20,970.00 Contents 187,470.00 113,500.00 36,232.00 Seward 110,540.00 . 45,500.00 4,415.00 Contents 19,970.00 10,121.00 1,955.00 Sheridan 35,600.00 24,000.00 6,675.00 Contents 44,550.00 21,500.00 9,050.00 Sherman 1,400.00 none 150.00 Contents 700.00 none 250.00 Stanton 18,000.00 12,800.00 982.00 Contents 2,015.00 1,200.00 155.00 Thayer 27,000.00 13,650.00 7,162.00 Contents 35,450.00 9,376.00 14,195.00 Thomas 1,525.00 1,200.00 100.00 Contents 320.00 280.00 120.00 Thurston 22,250.00 13,950.00 3,270.00 Contents 15,800.00 10,350.00 2,020.00 Valley 5,000.00 5,000.00 2,000.00 Contents 5,000.00 4,500.00 3,000.00 Washington 56,050.00 39,800.00 19,992.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">• Division op Fire Prevention County Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam on Bldgs. 1 Contents 13,850.00 12,100.00 2,800.00 Wayne 72,375.00 44,500.00 5,535.00 Contents _.-... 65,100.00 31,500.00 1,310.00 Webster 11,650.00 5,800.00 2,743.00 Contents 9,600.00 ' 3,600.00 1,500.00 York 102,750.00 62,200.00 39,139.00 Contents 75,520.00 46,400.00 27,670.00 FIRE LOSS FOR 1928, VALUE, INSURANCE, AND LOSS AS REPORTED BY COUNTIES Value of Bldgs. - Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Total .... $16,450,155.00 $ 2,734,092.00 $ 757,993.00 Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont Total ....$3,680,048.00 $2,427,791.00 $ 467,994.00 Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Omaha.. $10,983,955.00 $ 7,691,710.00 $ 390,027.00 Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $ 6&gt;583,330.00 $ 6,308,715.00 $ 223,513.00 Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Lincoln.. $ 1,339,015.00 $ 1,031,800.00 $ 159,097.00 Value of Cont. ' Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $ 1,648,890.00 $ 1,211,550.00 $ 62,329.00 Grand Value of Bldgs. Ins. on Bldgs. Dam. on Bldgs. Total $28,773,125.00 $11,457,602.00 $ 1,308,017.00 Value of Cont. Ins. on Cont. Dam. on Cont. $11,912,268.00 $ 9,948,056.00 $ 753,836.00 . , TOTAL DEATHS FROM FIRES Men 41 Women 15 Children : 23 Total 79 CAUSES OF DEATHS Kerosene explosions 6 Starting fires with kerosene 18 Gasoline explosions 15 Starting fires with gasoline - ......._: 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">State of Nebraska Bon fires 2 Playing with matches 10 Electricity 9 Lightning 1 Fire Works 1 Dynamite caps 1 Firemen fighting fire 1 Heating combustible liquids 2 Miscellaneous 12 Total 79 TOTAL INJURIES FROM FIRES Men 74 Women 38 Children 31 Total 143 CAUSES OF INJURIES Kerosene explosions 7 Starting fires with kerosene 18 Gasoline explosions 4U Starting fires with gasoline 5 Fire works 10 Torpedos and dynamite caps 5 Firemen fighting fires 7 Electricity , 4 Lightning '. 1 Heating oils 5 Miscellaneous 36 Total 143 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Division of Fire Prevention DEATHS FROM FIRES Ashton— Robert Kowalewski, a farmer, was struck by lightning and killed while in the wheat field. Belmont— Zachariah Mithem, 92, burned to death in his covered wagon, which probably caught from an overheated stove. Bridgeport— W. H. Stoddard died of burns received when a gasoline tank, which he was filling, exploded throwing the burning gas over him. Static electricity caus - ed the explosion. Bridgeport— Mrs Clyde Meglemre, Jr., died of burns re - ceived when she poured coal oil on the fire to hasten it Her baby was severely burned and the house nearly de - stroyed. Campbell— Reynolds Koch burned his wife and himself to death, after the couple had a quarrel. He knocked her down with a base ball bat, then" saturated her clothing with gasoline, placed her in a straw stack, set the stack on fire then soaked his own clothing in gasoline and leaped into the flames. Chadron— Phyllis Muhm, 5, died of burns received when her clothing ignited while she was lighting a jack o'lantern on Halloween. Coleridge— John Loester, 76, died of burns. His clothing ignited from a bon-fire. College View— Mrs Ellen H. Nethery, wife of President J. J. Nethery of the Seventh Day Adventist Central Union, died of burns received in the basement of her home. She had been cleaning clothes with gasoline, then turned on the switch to start the washing machine, and a spark from the motor ignited the fumes. Columbus— Marie Schmalz, 17, died of burns. She was starting a fire with kerosene and an explosion occurred. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">State op Nebraska Columbus — John G. Janssen, 45, a farmer bachelor, sat - urated his clothing with gasoline and set himself on fire. Culbertson — James Whitworth was fatally burned while working on a broken gas line under his car. Elkhorn — Leroy McArdle was killed instantly when he touched a live wire which had been brought down by a storm in front of his home. Elm Creek — Lucille and Floyd Streeter, 2 and 4, were fatally burned when in the absence of their mother they attempted to start a fire in the stove with kerosene. They had probably seen their mother using kerosene for the same purpose. Ewing — Mr. and Mrs. J. D. Honeywell and their two little daughters were burned to death when their farm home was destroyed by fire. Cause unknown. Fremont — -Magdalen Bohaboy, 4, died of burns received when her clothing caught fire. She was playing with matches. This was a clear case of criminal negligence. Fremont — Herman Borgemeyer of Howells, Nebraska, his daughter Mildred, 12, and his sister-in-law, Mrs. Fbsch, were burned to death. Their auto was struck by a Burling - ton freight engine on a crossing near Fremont. Fremont — Ruby F. Skibsted, 2, died of burns received when her dress caught fire from a match she was playing with. Grand Island — S. E. Tipton, in starting fire with kero - sene, was burned so badly he died six hours later. Gretna — P. E. Hubbard, 25, a telephone lineman, was fatally burned by a high tension wire on which he was working. Hay Springs — Phillip C. Cross, a small boy, was burned to death playing around a kerosene barrel. His clothing became saturated; he then struck a match. More negli - gence. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Division op Fire Prevention Hay Springs — Clyde W. Morey, on June 28, died from effects of burns received from an explosion caused by lighting a giant fire cracker in an oil storage warehouse. Property loss $10,000.00. Johnson — Carl Blinde, 20, died five hours after coming in contact with a live electric wire. He was trimming trees. Lexington — Lee Isaacson, druggist, died of burns receiv - ed when acids exploded in the rear part of his store. Long Pine — Jean, the 3 year old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Lloyd Kyner, was fatally burned while playing with matches. Lincoln — Herman Walz, 9, was instantly killed, and his body severely burned, when he came in contact with a high voltage wire up in a tree in which he was chasing a squirrel. Lincoln — Jimmy Jones, a lineman for the Nebraska Power Company, was killed when he came in contact with a high voltage wire. He was badly burned. Lincoln (West) — Mrs. Roy L. Hiskey died of burns she received when she threw kerosene into the stove. An ex - plosion followed which set her clothing on fire. Loup City — Alvin Mendyk, 30 months old, died of burns received when his clothing caught fire from burning weeds and brush set on fire by his brother Edward, aged 7. (See injured). Martel — Mike Garcia, 38, a Mexican railroad vyorkman, died of burns cause'd by gasoline fumes exploding in a bunk car of which he had been cleaning the interior with gas - oline. (See injured). Martinsburg — Vincent, aged 3, son of Mr. and Mrs. Walr ter Bauman, died of burns. His clothing caught fire from corn stalks his father was burning in the field. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">State op Nebraska Miller — The ten months old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Ludeman was burned to death when she upset an incubator lamp and her clothing caught fire. (See injur - ed). Nehawka — John Whiteman, 35, was blown to pieces. He was blasting stumps and a charge exploded prematurely. Oconto — Mrs. Ella L. Tingley, 89, died of burns received when she attempted to start a fire with kerosene. Omaha — William H. Clark. 48, was fatally burned while using gasoline to start a tire which exploded. He started the fire. (See injured). Omaha — Hugh McLaughlin was fatally burned trying to save his wife whose clothing had become ignited while she was starting the fire with kerosene. She lost her husband and was severely burned herself. (See injured). Omaha — James McClean, 48, formerly a jockey, burned to death in the Ak-Sar-Ben racing stable hay barn fire, probably caused by a cigarette. Omaha — Eleanor Chalupka, 3, died of burns received when her dress caught fire from some paper she was en - deavoring to put in the furnace. (See injured). Omaha — Mrs. Sophie Rybenski was fatally burned while pouring kerosene in the stove to hasten the fire. "SHE DID." Omaha — Frank G. Gregory, 31, colored, was fatally burned. He wanted to hasten the fire. Omaha — Peter Hemingsen, 85, was burned to death at - tempting to fill an oil stove with gasoline while it was burn - ing. Omaha — Melvin Robbins, 9, died from burns received while assisting his brother Charles, 11, (who was also ter - ribly burned) in saving the life of their partly paralyzed mother. Their home had caught fire from an explosion in an oil stove. The mother was saved without injury. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Division of Fire Prevention Omaha — Jane Walters, 3, died of burns. Her clothing caught fire from matches she was playing with. Omaha — R. C. Wise, 45, died from burns he received from a gasoline explosion. He was cleaning a room and brought in a lighted blow torch. Omaha; — Ida Nigro, 3, was burned to death. She pour - ed kerosene on a fire in the living room to make it burn faster as she had seen her mother do. WILL PEOPLE NEVER CEASE THIS DANGEROUS PRACTICE?^ Omaha — John Haller, fireman, died from a skull fracture he received in a fall of thirty feet from the second story of the Parker building when it was on fire. Thomas Boyle, 60, died of burns he received at this same fire. He was caught in his room. Two others were severely injured. O'Neill — Ed Williams was electrocuted when he attempt - ed to turn on an electric light in the basement. He was barefooted. Ord — The 11 year old daughter of Arthur Smith was fatally burned when starting a fire in the kitchen stove with kerosene. Ponca — Charles Daugherty, 33, and Jeff Anderson, 27, employees of the Interstate Power Company, were killed when they came in contact with high voltage wires while looking for radio interference. Randolph — Herman Naber, 67, died of burns received when he tried to start a fire in a kitchen stove with kero - sene. Scottsbluff — John Gongales, Martin Ornales, Pedro Or - nales, and M. Cortez, all Mexicans, were burned to death in a car. Gasoline fumes exploded when one of them tried to light a cigarette. Shelton — Imogene Holtz, 16, died from burns received trying to start a fire with kerosene. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">State of Nebraska Sidney — Henry Frietz Segelka, 18, suffered burns which resulted in his death when the cushion of his truck caught fire from a cigarette or a match. He lost control of the truck and it overturned pinning him in the wreckage. Spalding — Mrs. Stella Cook, 30, a farmer's wife, saturat - ed her clothing with kerosene, ignited it and burned to death. Spalding — Charles Nunaman was fatally burned using kerosene to start a fire in the stove. His house burned down and his wife barely escaped with her baby by jump - ing through a window. Spencer — Mrs. J. C. Peterson was burned to death and four others severely burned. Two buildings and contents were destroyed and another building badly damaged, caused by heating a small quantity of crude oil in a barrel with a blow torch. The fumes exploded and threw the burning oil over those looking on. (See injuries). Stanton — Mrs. Rose Steiner died from burns received when she tried to start a fire in the kitchen stove with kero - sene. Tecumseh — Verna, 5, and Fern Smith, 3, died of burns received when they set fire to some wall paper clippings in an outhouse. Tilden — Sam Crowell was burned to death when his tent caught fire from a kerosene heater. Union — Elmer Fahrlander, 20, was burned to death in an air plane which fell. (See injured). Valentine — Mrs. Helen Farran, 24, died from burns re - ceived when the gasoline in which she was washing clothes exploded as she turned on the switch to the washing mach - ine. Her sister, Sadie, was painfully burned about the face and arms. (See injured) . Valley — Madeline Morgan, 10, was fatally burned when she used kerosene to start the kitchen fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Division of Fire Prevention Wilber — J. W. Meyers was found badly burned and dead. He was holding a 2,000 volt electric wire in his hands. *■ ". &gt;j Wahoo — Mrs. Ed C'ernik died from burns received while starting a fire in a kitchen stove with kerosene. Yutan — Robert Hollst, 4, played with matches and was burned to death. INJURIES FROM FIRES - Alexandria — Garnet. House, 16, was badly burned when starting a kitchen fire with kerosene. Allen — Mrs. Roy Troth was severely burned about the arms and face starting a fire in the kitchen range with kerosene. :. • '•■! Bassett — Mr. Prisco was severely burned while filling the oil container of his stove with kerosene when he struck a match to see what progress he was making. •Beatrice — Chief Whiteside was slightly burned, and Roy Wilcox who operates a dry cleaning plant suffered severe burns when his establishment was partly destroyed by fire. - Beatrice — Mrs. J. P. Classes and her son Albert were badly burned when powder exploded that had been placed on the kitchen stove by Albert. } Beatrice — Mrs. Roy Patton, who lives on a farm near j, Beatrice, suffered burns on the face and arms. The barn ' had caught fire from some unknown cause and she was en - deavoring to rescue the horses. She saved several but three were destroyed. p. Beatrice — Ora Weeks, a young lad, was struck in the eye by the explosion of a torpedo cap. He may lose his sight. Bee — Florence Navratil used kerosene to hasten the fire in the furnace. , Her face and hands were severely burned. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">State of Nebraska Bloomington — Marion Harger had her hand and arm burned while pushing a burning car out the garage. The car back-fired and set the garage on fire. Blue Springs — Mrs. Susan McGinnis was severely bu:n ed about the face and hands when she dumped oil soaked rags into the stove. Brainard — Richard Swoboda, aged two years and nine months, was painfully burned on the right leg while play - ing around the kitchen stove. Bridgeport — The infant child of Clyde Meglemre, Jr., was burned in a fire which caused his mother's death and nearly destroyed the home. Mrs. Meglemre poured kero - sene on the fire to hasten it. Bridgeport — Freil Renner, a jeweler, was severely burn - ed about the hands and face when benzine in an electrical - ly propelled watch cleaning machine exploded. Columbus — Mr. Hodges was slightly burned about hands and face when his car caught fire from an overheated motor. Crete — Harry Hogue, dairyman, filled the tank of a gas - oline stove while the stove was burning. An explosion oc - curred and he was burned about the head, shoulders, and arms. Crete — Robert Vasalka was badly burned by a prema - ture explosion of dynamite. Crete — Mrs. E. E. Handenman was burned on face and hands when the gasoline stove exploded. Crofton — Axel Carlson was seriously burned starting a fire with kerosene. (It started). Diller — Mrs. A. J. Hutchinson was severely burned when she was pumping air into a gasoline lamp that was lit. Diller — Kenneth Albers, 19, fell against a hot stove and burned his face, hands and arms. He slipped on a rug. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">! Division op Fire Preveniton Elm Creek — Mrs. Joseph Streeter and her son Harom were painfully burned in an effort to save the lives of Lu - cille and Floyd who had tried to start a fire in the stove with kerosene as they had seen their mother do. (See deaths) . Farwell — William Dobish, 25, may lose the sight of both eyes from powder burns received while firing a cannon- Fremont — Helen Thompson, 16, was seriously burned when she spilled burning wax over her clothing. Mrs. C. Hyatt was painfully burned while tearing Helen's clothing off. Fremont— Fred Jessen \yas burned on the lower limbs by the premature explosion of a bomb at a fireworks dis - play on Armistice Day. Fremont — Harry Owens, engineer in the Fremont Ice Company plant, was badly injured in a gas explosion that wrecked the plant. Farwell — Selicia - Pawloski, 17, was seriously burned about the face and right eye when a cannon cracker ex - ploded in front of her. Fullerton — Harry Green was burned on face and arms while filling a gasoline stove. Gordon — L. P. Steadman was repairing a gasoline coffee urn when an oil stove near him exploded the fumes and burned him severely. Grand Island— Wellington Nutter, a lineman, fell over 15 feet from a pole coming in contact with an electric wire carrying 6,6000 volts. His right hand and right side were badly burned. Grand Island — William Pfenning, 17, was severely burn - ed while experimenting with a carbide plant in the base - ment of his home. The tank exploded and wrecked the house. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">State of Nebraska Grand Island — Mrs. Tipton was burned on arms and legs when her husband started fire with kerosene causing his death. Hartington — Mrs. Charles Thompson was struck by light - ning and severely burned. Holmesville — Cecil Whitehead, 17, was painfully burned about the legs when the gasoline engine operating a wash - ing machine exploded. Liberty — Eli Pyle attempted to start his car by pouring ether in the spark plug holes. It became ignited and he was severely burned. He was saved from a possible death by his wife who wrapped him in a blanket. Loup City — Otis White had his feet and ankles badly burned when he started a fire with kerosene. Loup City — Mrs. Tony Mendyk and her son, Edward, 7 years old, both received bad burns on their hands in trying to extinguish the flames from the clothing of baby Alvin which had become ignited from a fire started by Edward in the weeds along the fence during the absence of his mother. (See deaths). Lincoln — Paul Neu's eight year old son suffered burns on his right hand when a two-inch cannon cracker exploded. Lincoln — William Krelke, student at the Nebraska Uni - versity, was badly injured by a fire cracker he held in his hand. Lincoln — A red hot rivet fell on Stanley Webster and burned his back, while he was employed on the State Cap - itol building. Lincoln — Vern C. Barney, fireman, was seriously injured when the truck on which he was speeding to a fire was hit by a taxicab. Both his legs and one arm were broken. Lincoln — A gasoline engine caught fire and burned the hands and arms of E. T. Staten. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Division of Fire Prevention Lincoln — Mrs. Frank Kosta was severely burned by floor • wax which she was heating on a gas range. Lincoln — Frank Franks was severely burned by hot oil when his tractor tipped over. Lincoln- — Mrs. B. S. Townsend was severely burned about the forehead and hands. She dropped a lighted match on her clothing when looking for linens in a clothes closet. Lincoln — Mrs. Sargent, 70, was slightly burned about the face while endeavoring to extinguish a fire that had started in her home. Lincoln — Harold Calvert, 19, was severely burned about the hands and chest when his gasoline and oil soaked shirt ignited as he leaned over a gas stove. He had been work - ing on an automobile a short time before. Lincoln — Harold T. Hoden, 24, student pilot, was slight - ly burned and otherwise injured when his plane took fire from back fire of the motor. He plunged 80 feet to the ground. The plan was destroyed. Lincoln — William Bandelow was severely burned while he was cleaning a gas meter with gasoline which ignited. Lincoln — Mrs. Lee W. Werble and three of her six chil - dren, Philip 13, Robert 3, and Ray 8 months old, were sev - erely burned when Philip attempted to revive the fire in the kitchen. stove with kerosene. Lincoln — Sylvia McDonald, 19, who lives on a farm four miles west of town, was severely burned about the face and left arm when a gasoline lamp exploded. Lincoln — Mr. C. N. McNew washed a pair of trousers in gasoline. The fumes were ignited by a gas stove and he and his wife were severely burned. Lincoln — Stanley Betzer, University student, was severe - ly burned on his arms and abdomen when working with creosote and benzine in his chemistry class. Two other </seg>
            <seg id="p034">State of Nebraska students were slightly burned in their efforts to put out the fire. Lincoln — Mrs. W. J. Maxson was severely burned on her right leg and hand when her dress caught fire from a gas stove. She saved her life by wrapping herself in a blanket and rolling on the floor. Lincoln — Jacob Burback was painfully burned about the face and chest when his father struck a match to aid him in putting gasoline in his car. Lincoln — Velma Harwood, 7, was injured when a fire cracker exploded in a glass jar throwing the glass in her eyes. Lincoln — M. H. Line received severe burns on his left leg trying to put out a fire in his car that fiad started from a short in the wiring. Martel — A railroad bunk house was being cleaned with gasoline. The fumes ignited and a Mexican laborer was slightly burned. (See deaths) . Miller — Mrs. Joseph Ludeman was severely burned about the arms and body in attempting to save the life of her little daughter who had upset the incubator lamp. The baby died. Nebraska City — Elmer Branson, 7, ignited some blasting powder that had been left in front of his home and was badly burned on his hands and face. North Platte — John Eskelman was burned on hands and arms from a gasoline heater. Octavia — Peter Saul cut his leg seriously with flying glass. He was fighting a fire which eventually destroyed his neighbor's home. Omaha — C. Tucker, 38, was burned about the face and neck when a gasoline lantern he was holding exploded shooting flames about his head. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Division op Fire Prevention Omaha — Two boys were slightly injured in a fire at Fa - ther Flanagan's Home. ■.[..-• Omaha— Mrs. Dorothy Person, a widow, was badly burn - ed on her face-, arms and body when her clothing caught fire from a gas heater. Her life was probably saved by her 15 year old son who wrapped her in an overcoat and smothered the flames. / Omaha — Mrs. William H. Clark and three of her small children were painfully burned trying to save their father who was in flames. Mr. Clark had started a fire with gas - oline. (See deaths). i Omaha — Mrs. Antonia Vondrucka, 63, burned her hands in an effort to take the burning clothes from little Eleanor Chalupka, who burned to death. (See deaths) . Omaha — Patrick F. Kelly, 88, may die from burns he re - ceived attending to the fire in his furnace. Omaha — Michael Bean, 7, lost the sight of both his eyes f when a large fire cracker exploded near his face. Omaha — E. E. Smith, 32, salesman, was severely burned about the face and hands when he lit a cigarette shortly after he had cleaned his necktie with ether. The fumes ignited and destroyed his tie, shirt and coat. Omaha — Louis Herandes, 8, was badly burned by a live wire that had been broken in a storm. Omaha — K. Edwin Blanchard, 28, was seriously burned, and John Matscha, fireman, crushed his hand when a brick fell on it. This happened at the Parker Building fire in which two others lost their lives. Cause of fire unknown. (See deaths). Omaha — Charles Robbins, 11, was horribly burned while aiding his brother Melvin, 9, in saving the life of their part - ly paralyzed mother. An oil sfbve exploded and burned .. their home. Melvin died. (See deaths). </seg>
            <seg id="p036">State of Nebraska Omaha — Captain Pat McElliott and John O'Brien, fire - men of No. 3, and D. C. Siampaus and Stanley Komorski in an automobile, were severely injured when No. 3 fire truck and the car met in collision at 19th and Jackson streets. Omaha — Mrs. Frank H. Heavrin tried to start a fire with kerosene; it exploded and Mrs. Heavrin was severely burn - ed. Omaha — H. K. Forsythe, 73, president of the Omaha Blaugas Company, suffered burns on the back of his head and his right hand. The fire was caused by an empty tank exploding when it was being. cleaned. Omaha — Ingebord Carstens, 2, suffered from powder burns on her leg when boys threw a fire cracker in her father's car. Omaha — Michael Doane, 9, may lose sight of both eyes. He lit an open fire cracker with a match. Eyes, face and left hand were painfully burned. Omaha — Harold Thorpe was severely burned mixing paint in the basement. Benzo gas exploded. Omaha — Jim Kernes was burned about the forearms and ankles while saving the lives of four children that had been playing with matches and ignited their box-car home. Omaha — Fire Captain Homer Howe's daughter, Clare, 10, was terribly burned when her dress caught fire from a match with which she was lighting the gas stove. Her two sisters Edith and Helen burned their hands extinguishing the fire. Omaha — Mrs. Hugh McLaughlin was seriously burned on the arms starting a fire with kerosene. Her life was saved by her husband, but he was fatally burned. (See deaths). Omaha — Ernest Webster, engineer, Blau Gas Company, was badly burned when an explosion occurred which threw </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Division of Fire Prevention him through the door and wrecked the building. Cause unknown. Omaha — Marion Fadaelli was severely burned when a sixty gallon still exploded burning him and demolishing his home. Omaha — Mrs. G. A. Carlson, 25, was severely burned when gasoline she poured into a boiler of water on the kitchen stove exploded. Omaha — Mr. and Mrs. Gus Carlson were severely burn - l ed, and their two sons,, Ben and George, were slightly burn - ed, from gasoline explosion. Omaha — Florence Smith was burned about the hands and face in a gasoline explosion. Omaha — Mrs. Mary Norton burned her hair ana arms in extinguishing a fire started by boys with matches. Omaha — Lizzie Gakaiof burned her face and left hand in a fire started by boys with matches. Omaha — Mrs. F. D. Greene was burned slightly in an oil stove explosion. Omaha — Frank Anson was burned on the left hand and arm when a gasoline stove exploded. Omaha — Juanita Miller was burned on face, hands, and arms, while cleaning clothes with gasoline. O'Neill — Bob Tomlison was badly burned while taking gasoline from a truck tank. He had a lighted lantern. Randolph — Leo Naber, 22, was so badly burned that he will be crippled for life, trying to save his father who died from burns received when he tried to start a fire with kero - sene. The kerosene exploded. Rockville — Robert Garner, a young lad, was badly burn - ed. He poured gasoline on a bon-fire to help it along. The gasoline exploded, </seg>
            <seg id="p038">State of Nebraska Red Cloud — Bobbie Fountain was burned on hands and feet while swinging on a guy wire leading from a pole that was heavily charged with electricity. Scottsbluff — 0. A. Nelson, fireman, had his hand injured by glass while fighting a fire. Sidney — Jesse L. Thompson, in attempting to remove an oil stove which had exploded and was in flames, was sev - erely burned. Sidney — Harry Gee, a farm hand, was struck by light - ning. His clothing was torn to shreds, one shoe burned off, and he was burned about the head and face. He will re - cover. Sidney — John Lopp, 12, a ranchman's son, was struck by lightning, rendered unconscious, and severely burned about the head and face. Sidney — Mrs. G. A. Johnson was severely burned about the hands and face when gasoline with which she was washing a dress (out in the back yard) ignited from fric - tion sparks. Sidney — Andrew Christensen, an employee at the Cent - ral Meat Market, was seriously injured when his clothing caught fire following the explosion of a gasoline stove he was trying to adjust. Spencer — A. Holstein, George Barta. Herman Woidneck and Paul Woidneck were all seriously burned about the face, arms, and body, by burning oil from a barrel that was being warmed up with a blow torch to make the oil flow. (See deaths). Stromsburg — The high school basket ball coach was slightly burned about the hands and face while washing basket ball uniforms in gasoline. Static electricity caused an explosion. Sterling — Jack Miller, foreman at the Light and Power Company, was severely burned about the face and head when a blow torch exploded. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Division op Fire Prevention Sterling — Charles Conkle was painfully burned : on his hands while trying to fill a lighted oil stove. Sutherland — Henry Cokes and Thomas Martindale were painfully burned when the gasoline tank of the motorcycle overflowed while being filled by Cokes. Union — Raymond Fahrlander, 28, was seriously burned, and his brother died of burns, when their air plane caught fire and crashed. (See deaths) . Verdigre — Grace Tusch and Stasie Ellis, 11 and 8, were painfully, but not seriously, injured when dynamite explod - ed in the school house stove. Pieces of the stove struck them. Valentine — Sadie Hammon. and her sisters were seriously burned. The sister died. (feee deaths). They were washing curtains in gasoline and an explosion occurred. Weeping Water— Dale Patterson volunteered to start the fire in the I. 0.' 0. F.'s hall. He started it with kerosene, which exploded, and he was seriously burned. Wymore — Mrs. J. W. Marquette suffered severe burns about the arms and face in a fire which destroyed a farm house where she was visiting. The fire started from the kitchen stove. York — David Mayo, a cripple, was burned severely by the explosion of a kerosene oil heating stove in his covered wagon home. William Muckey was also burned on the face in helping to put out the fire. INVESTIGATION OF SUSPICIOUS FIRES During 1928 the Fire Marshal's office made investigation of 92 suspicious fires. Of this number investigated it was believed that 56 of these fires were, without doubt, of in - cendiary origin. Five men were arrested and charged with arson; three confessed and were sentenced to the peniten - tiary; one was tried and acquitted, and two were dismissed. Of the remaining 52 cases, up to date, no charges have </seg>
            <seg id="p040">State of Nebraska been preferred, as the collecting of evidence still contin - ues. Twenty-seven of the fires investigated proved not to be of incendiary origin, but in most cases carelessness on the part of the occupant in allowing fire hazards to exist. The other nine were listed as unknown or doubtful. In the investigation of these fires the utmost care was taken to avoid publicity and reflections being cast on any innocent party or parties. It is a greater satisfaction to the investigator to be able to exonerate the suspected ones than it is to bring charges of arson against them. AMES — John E. Mathews, Jr., chief engineer of the Pathfinder hotel, Fremont, Nebraska, set fire to his father's frame dwelling at Ames, Nebraska, ten miles west of Fre - mont, on March 12, 1928. The dwelling was occupied by Earl Sink and family. During their absence, a couple of nights before the fire, Mathews gained entrance to the house through an up stairs window and set an electric con - trivance which he could manipulate from the outside by pulling a string. When faced with the facts, obtained by the investigators, he confessed to having attempted to set this fire so that his father would get the insurance. He was sentenced to four months in jail and fined $300.00. NEBRASKA CITY— The Bert Ryder building, occupied by Bob Cohn and Chas. Foley as a clothing and jewelry store, was set on fire March 14, 1928. Fire was started with gasoline in basement of jewelry store. Foley was arrested the night of the fire and pleaded not guilty. Preliminary hearing set for March 23. On the morning of March 19, Bob Cohn committed suicide. The preliminary trial ac - quitted Foley and proved that Cohn had entered Foley's basement and set the fire in hopes that his place of business would burn also, as it was heavily over-insured, and he was bankrupt. VALENTINE— On December 25, 1927, Milan J. Walling - ford hired Alfred J. Bradley to set his house and contents on fire, so he could collect the insurance. Bradley remov- </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Division of Fire Prevention ed part of the contents to his home before setting fire to the house. The loss was settled and no investigation was made until the latter part of February when the sheriff, W. B. Harmon, was searching for stolen goods in Bradley's house discovered the Wallingford goods. Bradley, after being questioned, admitted burning the building and im - plicated the owner, who was then in Califorhia. After hav - ing been brought back Wallingford also confessed and was sentenced March 8, 1928, to from 1 to 20 years in the Pen - itentiary and Bradley from 1 to 20 years in the Reform - atory. INCENDIARY FIRES Bulletin for Fire Departments It is desired to call the attention of the members of the fire departments throughout the State of Nebraska to the ever increasing number of fires of suspicious origin. Some officials are on record as making a positive statement that more than 30 per cent of the fire loss is incendiary. This is undoubtedly an extravagant statement, but it is conserv - atively estimated that 10 per cent of fires show evidence of incendiarism. It occurs to me that by cooperating togeth - er and thoroughly investigating every fire of suspicious or - igin we may materially decrease the fire waste in this State and make the crime of arson so unprofitable and so unpop - ular that it will be seldom attempted. Arson has always been considered one of the most ser - ious crimes and has been classed with murder and treasont and in some states, even now, a conviction of arson carries with it the death penalty. Incendiary fires can, for ordin - ary purposes, be separated into five classes, according to motive: 1. To conceal evidence of some other crime. 2. Malice or revenge. 3. Malicious mischief. 1 4. Pyromania or some other form of insanity. 5. Desire to defraud to insurer. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">State of Nebraska Every fire is presumed to be of accidental origin, and as the firemen are the fjrst to reach the scene of the fire, it is usually within the province of these men to overcome the presumption of accident and to discover evidence to show that the fire was incendiary. One of the first and most im - portant steps in an arson trial is to prove what the lawyers call the "Corpus Delecti", or the body of the crime. In other words, before evidence of a motive, or even a con - fession, can be introduced in a criminal trial it must first be proven that the specific crime charged has been com - mitted. In a case of arson the specific charge is the burn - ing of a building or other property. In the investigation of a fire care should always-be taken to ascertain the character of it, in what part of the build - ing it originated, how it burned, and other facts and cir - cumstances which may be suggestive of the nature of the fire under investigation. The incendiary origin of a fire is sometimes shown by direct and positive evidence, such as the saturation of the premises with kerosene or some other explosive compound. It may be shown by the fact that there are two or three separate fires, one having no con - nection with another. It sometimes manifests itself to the firemen by the manner in which it burns, or by the presence of dense smoke, indicating the use of oil. The appearance of the interior of a building frequently shows whether a fire is the result of accident or design. The articles of furniture may be so placed as to retard the work of the firemen, or there may be evidence that a con - siderable part of the furniture, fixtures, or stock had been removed previous to the fire. The Supreme Court of a western state, in commenting on an arson case, said, "Where the same person has a series of fires and collects insurance it furnishes a basis for an in - ference of more or less strength that the fires are not acci - dental." In the investigation of a supposed incendiary fire it is frequently thought important to eliminate insofar as is pos- </seg>
            <seg id="p043">. Division op Fire Prevention sible all the accidental caUses which might possibly be put forward as the probable cause for the fire. It is highly important to inspect the heating and the electrical equip - ment of the building, to see whether such equipment could possibly have been the cause of the fire. It is thus impor - tant to know that the electrical equipment is intact or that there is no electric wire near the origin of the fire, as some of these things will undoubtedly be advanced by the de - fense as the probable cause. Any of these things and many others not here mentioned, may tend to excite the suspicion of the firemen that the fire was not accidental, and in such a case a thorough investi - gation as to its cause should be immediately made. If any physical evidence of incendiarism is found it should be im - mediately taken possession of by the officer in charge and held for the Fire Marshal, or his deputy. It frequently happens that the remains of a "plant" ar - ranged by someone to start or accelerate the fire is f oiihd in the building after the fire is extinguished. It is highly important, in the event candles on oily bottles, or things of that character are discovered, that they be left exactly as found until they can be photographed. If the candle is to be picked up, lift it by the wick and turn it over to the fire marshal's office for examination for fingerprints. The same care should be. exercised in handling any other articles which were plainly used by the incendiary, for their examination for fingerprints. . All cases of suspicious fires should be immediately re - ferred to the State Fire Marshal for further investigation, but the members of the fire department should bear in mind that, being the first at the scene of the fire, it is their duty, if the fire is incendiary, to collect and develop the evidence to support this fact. Of courses it is impossible to proper - ly investigate the cause of a fire during its progress, but where the circumstances are suspicious, as soon as the fire is extinguished a watchman should be placed in charge of </seg>
            <seg id="p044">State of Nebraska the building until such time as proper investigation can be made. (Signed) JOHN C. TROUTON, State Fire' Marshal. STANDARD EQUIPMENT OF FIRE DEPARTMENTS The hose couplings of all fire departments in this State should be brought to a standard. The standard for hose couplings established by the National Board of Fire Under - writers is known as seven and one-half threads to the inch, National Standard. It is essential that this standard should be adopted by all cities, towns, and villages, so that in case of a big fire occurring, and a call for help being sent out, other fire companies responding to the call can couple on the fire hy - drants wherever and whenever necessary. At the Baltimore fire, Washington and Philadelphia sent their equipment to assist, but their equipment was useless for they could not connect onto the fire hydrants. The fire loss was forty million dollars. This might have been greatly reduced had all equipment been standard. DANGER IS ALWAYS PRESENT: GUARD AGAINST IT The most frequent cause of fires and the one that calls the fire department out at all hours is the roof fire ; a dirty flue, a cold night, a dry shingle roof and a hot fire is the finest combination we have. It causes the local fire depart - ment to make more mileage than any other one fire; hazard. The remedy is simple. Before starting fires in the fall of the year, be sure the chimney is clean, and that the stove and furnace pipes have been cleaned out. See that the pipes are properly cemented in the flue, as this will give better control of the fire and will mean a great saving in fuel. If the furnace door is left open in the summer it will </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Division op Fire Prevention prevent the condensation which occurs when the furnace is not in use and prolong the life of the pipes. It creates an air circulation which minimizes condensation. If any bricks are loose in the chimney and the mortar is gone, danger is present. Repair all defects at once. You may be saving a life. A USEFUL PURPOSE Water being scarce, a fire was extinguished, in Chatham, England, in 1774, with beer. This same beverage render - ed a similar service in Whitebreads Brewery in 1807. Fire had destroyed the supports of a thousand barrel vat of beer, which poured out and extinguished the flames. In Paris, in 1820, firemen dammed up a lake fifty feet square and a foot deep. They pumped the fiuid into a burning building, but as an extinguisher it proved a failure. The fire loss was eight hundred thousand dollars. Not so good. NEBRASKA BOY SCOUTS AND CAMPFIRE GIRLS Great credit is due to the members of the Boy Scouts and Camp Fire Girls organizations, as they are taught from the time they become members to be careful in all things, and particularly so in regard to the prevention of fires. The Boy Scouts and the Campfire Girls have rendered great service to the cause of fire prevention in seeing that waste papers are removed from the homes and in noting just what disposition is made of rubbish, weeds, and other inflam - mable trash in or around the home and to see that such disposition is a safe one; in telling their parents about pilot lights for electric irons; how dangerous an oily mop can become ; in giving warnings about the use of gasoline for cleaning purposes, and in warning their home folks not to use kerosene in starting fires. It cannot be stated in figures what the value of this service really is, but it can safely be said that these things accomplished by the little members of both of these organizations has aided greatly in the now steadily growing decrease in our State's fire losses. The Boy Scouts are individually and collectively thank- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">State op Nebraska ed for their assistance in inspection work, and for the en - thusiasm which they have brought into this work and for the cheerful response they are always willing to give when called upon to render service. This was particularly not - icable at one of the monthly inspections of the Nebraska State Fire Prevention Associations held in Tekamah. A force of Boy Scouts was on hand to run errands; to furnish information as to where certain owners or tenants might be found, and to aid in locating them, and in performing many other services of similar character, which greatly facilitat - ed the work of the inspectors. The Fire Marshal is more than pleased to add this little tribute of his appreciation for their usefulness, and to thank both organizations for the valuable assistance rendered. CLEAN UP Clean up your cellars, yards, alleys and closets. Rid them of all rubbish. Whitewash all you can. There are several good whitewash preparations on the market that will render wood fire resistive to a very perceptible degree, and the result is fewer fires, better health, and a cleaner city. A clean city is a safe city. CLEANLINESS is next to GODLINESS; get as close as you can and keep close. "DO IT NOW", is a good slogan. SMOKING AND ITS DANGERS One hundred billion cigarettes are lighted and consum - ed every year. Every one of them are a potential fire ha - zard. The cigarete butt and the cigar stub cause many fires. One careless smoker burned up eighty city blocks in Baltimore. A discarded cigarette ignited some rubbish on the floor of a shirt waist factory in New York causing the death of one hundred and forty-five persons and destroying the building. NEVER smoke near a gasoline filling sta - tion; some one might have to open the cemetery gate. Re - move all benches from the vicinity of gasoline pumps and filling stations; they invite the careless ones. Screen all </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Division of Fire Prevention street gratings to prevent rubbish from accumulating un - der them; a match, a cigar, or a cigarette may find its way into the rubbish and the fire is started. The State Fire Marshal will willingly furnish you with "NO SMOKING" signs to place in dangerous places. . ..'■ '. ■':.■■' ' j SOME OF THE UNDERLYING CAUSES OF FIRE . ■ ■ ■ ■ GAS OILS ASHES LITTER MATCHES GASOLINE FIREWORKS EXPLOSIONS ELECTRICITY CARELESSNESS DON'TS DON'T use make-shifts instead of proper fuses in your elec - trical circuits; the fuse is the safety valve of the system. DON'T leave electric flatirons or other heating devices turned on while attending to something else. DON'T look for gas leaks with an open flame light; you will be sure to find them. DON'T use gasoline or other volatile liquids to remove spots from clothing or for other purposes. It is cheap - er to pay for dry cleaning than for a funeral. DON'T throw your matches or lighted smoking material where they can possibly start a fire. DON'T smoke in bed; even if those guilty of this practice are too green to burn, the beds are not. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">State of Nebraska DON'T let the children play with matches or bonfires. DON'T fail to have your defective chimneys and flues mended ; they cause numerous fires in our state. DON'T forget to have your smokepipe cleaned of soot; if clogged it may overheat and start a fire when you op - erate the furnace. DON'T neglect to protect walls, ceilings and partitions from the overheating of stoves, furnaces and pipes. DON'T put hot ashes into wooden boxes or barrels. DON'T fill oil lamps or stoves by open flame lights; many lives have been lost by this form of carelessness. DON'T let rubbish accumulate; uncleanliness and fire go hand in hand. DON'T fail to keep a bucket of water and a bucket of sand in a convenient place for use in case of fire; they may save the lives of your family. DON'T fail to purchase a good fire extinguishing chemical (one or more) for your home. DON'T save your burnt out fuses; they have no value. DON'T fail to look after chemical extinguishers; see that they are immediately charged after being used. A 2 1 /* or 3 gallon turnover chemical can be used by man, woman or child and one or more should be installed in every home. REMEMBER, IN CONCLUSION. "FIRE IS A DANGER THAT NEVER SLEEPS", SO BE CONTINUOUSLY ON YOUR GUARD. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Division of Fire Prevention SLOGANS America never has been licked — except by flames.' A match has a head, but no brains. When you use its head, use your brains. A fire extinguisher on hand is worth two in the store. Fire loves a disorderly housekeeper. A tree will make a million matches, but a match will start a fire which destroys a million trees. Clean property seldom burns. A man steals a few dollars and is sent to prison, but when a man through carelessness and indifference causes a fire which results in the loss of thousands of dollars worth of property, and sometimes the loss of life, he is not pun - ished. Which is the greater criminal? Careless smokers burned over millions of dollars worth . of property last year. Do not smoke where smoking is for - bidden. Fire prevention protects your home and family. Fire waste is not paid by insurance companies; they on - ly distribute the. money that is paid by the people when they buy merchandise. The cost of fire tax is concealed in the price of the goods. If we all use precaution and teach our boys and girls the hazards of fire, it won't be long until the fires will be re - duced to a minimum. Fire is not the only form of waste, but it is the most mal - ignant. If we are careful in all things we will avoid waste, and carefulness does not cost a cent. From little sparks may burst a mighty flame. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">State of Nebraska Courting Danger. "How'd they come to bounce the fire chief?" asked Abe Hinkle, who had been out of town for a couple of days. "He took too many dad-blamed risks," answered Joe Mudge. "Why he even wore his celluloid collar to fires." If your fire insurance rates are too high, see that your city conforms to the state law the state marshal is called to enforce and then watch the results. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) A tumbledown wooden building cobwebbed and trash - bedecked in the rear of a block of business houses is more expensive luxury than a perpetual marble fountain bedeck - ed with vari-coJored lights by night, set in the public square. (Kansas State Fire Marshal's Bulletin.) FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX "Section 4469. Compiled Statutes for 1922. FIRE DE - PARTMENT AND FIRE ALARM TAX. All cities of the metropolitan, first or second class or village, organized un - der the laws of the State of Nebraska, shall have power and authority to levy a special tax of not more than one and one-half (lV-&gt;) mills each year upon all taxable property in said city. Such special levy shall be made by the same officers or board and shall be levied in the same. manner as in the case of general city taxes. Revenue raised by such special levy may be used only for the purpose of purchas - ing equipment for a fire departmenfof such city or for in - stalling and equipping a fire alarm system, or in payment of bonds as hereinafter authorized. Note. Sections 5820 and 5910 C. S. Neb. 1922 now fix levy at twenty per cent of one and one-half mills actual val - uation.) "Section 4470. BONDS— AUTHORIZED. Any city or village having levied a tax as herein authorized may anti - cipate the collection of such tax so levied, and for that pur - pose may issue bonds with interest coupons attached, in a </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Division of Fire Prevention sum amounting to 90 per cent of the tax so levied. Such bonds may run for a period of not more than fiv&amp; years, and may bear interest at.a rate not to exceed 5 per cent per annum. Bonds so issued shall be secured by such tax so assessed and levied, and shall be payable only out of the funds derived from such tax. In any case in which bonds are issued as herein authorized, it shall be the duty of such city, on receipt of such tax paid, to hold the same as »a separate fund to the amount of the bonds, so issued, and the interest thereon, for the purpose of paying or redeem - ing such bonds." </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>