<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves</title>
               <date value="1931-10">1931-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 263 October, 1931 Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves MARVEL L. BAKER Bulletin 31 of the North Platte Experiment Sub. tation W. P. SNYDER, Superintendent '- - ■ '-" '.^■.^»SB^Oa!w«??KL«!E^^^WH^H^HBI^WI^^WBHSKi EXPERIMENTAL CALVES AT THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, DIHECTOK </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY &gt; l n a 20 5-day test, five lots of calves were fed shelled corn, ground wheat, ground rye, equal parts of shelled corn and ground wheat and equal parts of shelled corn and ground rye along with "alfalfa hay 2. No digestive difficulties were experienced which could be ascribed to the use of wheat or rye in the ration. Neither was there any dif - iKateo 1 b k yTi n gSre h I. CaIVeS °" feed at ** ° f «"»» consumption pra^fe^sffidS £ S e h v e ery d r^ct a . nd *""* M *" .4. The mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and ground rye was 95 pei cent as efficient as shelled corn on the basis of average daily gains 1 he selling price, dressing percentage, and carcass grades of calves fed this mixture were slightly lower than for calves fed shelled corn. 5. Ground wheat and ground rye were equally palatable as indicated by the average daily grain consumption. Neither ground wheat nor ground rye was as palatable as shelled corn or as a mixture of shelled corn and ground wheat or shelled corn and ground rye. 0. On the basis of average daily gains, ground wheat was 91 per cent and ground rye 90 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. 7. The calves fed on ground wheat produced higher-grade carcasses and sold slightly higher than the calves fed on ground rye. Neither of these two lots of calves equaled the calves fed on shelled corn or on the mixture of shelled corn and either ground wheat or ground rye in dressing percentage or in carcass yield. 8. In economy of gains, there was very little difference between lots In general, the calves that ate a relatively high proportion of grain to alfalfa made faster gains, showed more finish, produced higher-grade carcasses, and sold higher than the calves that ate relatively less grain and more hay. 9. Either. ground wheat or ground rye as one-half the grain ration lor fattening calves was entirely satisfactory in this experiment. Either grain fed as the only concentrate was less satisfactory, although gains on such rations were economical. Calves fed on either ground wheat or ground rye alone ate less grain, made somewhat slower gains, and be - cause of less finish yielded lower-grade carcasses than calves fed mix - tures containing shelled corn or shelled corn alone. Where corn is not available, calves can be finished reasonably well on either ground wheat or ground rye with alfalfa hay. Where it is possible, corn should be added to the ration, at least during the latter part of the feeding period. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves MARVEL L. BAKER Relatively low prices for wheat and rye in the summer of 1930 stimulated interest in their value as feeds for livestock. Little information as to the value of wheat for fattening cattle was available. Even less work had been done in this country with rye as a cattle feed. Rye is an important crop in some sections of Nebraska, including the territory ad - jacent to the North Platte Substation. This experiment was conducted to obtain data on the value of wheat and rye for fattening cattle. It was begun November 25, 1930, and closed June 18, 193.1, thus lasting 205 days. OBJECTS The objects were (1) to compare shelled corn and ground wheat, (2) to compare shelled corn and ground rye, and (3) to determine the advisability of feeding a mixture of shelled corn and either ground wheat or ground rye. CALVES USED Grade Hereford calves of fair type and quality originating in Hayes county were used. They averaged 372 pounds per head at the beginning of the experiment. They were not de - horned. ... FEEDS USED Yellow shelled corn was used for practically the entire feeding period. It varied in moisture content from 14 to 22 per cent with an average of 17.6 per cent. It is reported on a basis of 14 per cent moisture. For a period of three weeks the corn used was somewhat musty. For the remainder of the feeding period, aside from its high moisture content, the corn was of excellent quality. The wheat used was hard red winter wheat which averaged 13.74 per cent moisture. Rosen rye averaging 13.1 per cent moisture was used. The wheat and rye were ground as coarsely as possible in a burr-type mill; Second-cutting alfalfa hay was used. This hay was bright and leafy and of better than average quality. All feeds were locally grown. SHELTER AND LOTS The calves had access to a shed 32 x 120 feet in size divided into five equal parts. The doors to this shed were left open at all times except during the most severe weather when they were partially closed. Lots 24 x 150 feet in size were provided directly south of the shed. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin .263 FEEDING AND WATERING i, Q 3 h^ CalveS Y^ re Siven all of the grain and all of the alfalfa hay they would clean up readily. They were fed regularly twice each day in the open. Automatic waterers were located m all lots. These were open at all times except during severe weather when they were covered at night to prevent freeriS RATIONS USED All lots received alfalfa hay. The following grain rations Lot 1 — Shelled corn, •'■ ' Lot 2 — Ground wheat, Lot 3 — Ground rye, Lot 4— Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and ground Lot 5— Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and ground rye. WEIGHING AND MARKETING Individual weights of the calves were taken on three con- Th^ZLl ? ayS f\, the be ? inmn S and end of the experiment. a * ve \ ases . of these weights were considered as the initial and final weights respectively Weights were also taken at 28-day intervals throughout the experiment except for the last period, which was 37 days in length The day following the last experimental weighing, the calves were trucked to the shipping yards at North P atte They were held there until the following clay, and then loaded at 9 :30 a. m. and sold on the Omaha market a clay later While in the yards at North Platte, they were fed prairie hay and were given water. Shrinkage in transit was calculated from the final experimental weight. SLAUGHTER DATA The slaughter data were secured through the courtesy of Armour and Company, Omaha Nebraska. They are presented in lable 1 and are discussed below. PORK PRODUCED The pork produced per steer is shown in Table 1. The piers available for this test lacked uniformity; hence, too much emphasis should not be placed upon the differences in oork produced. y SHELLED CORN VS. GROUND WHEAT VS. GROUND RYE As shown in Table 1 and Figure 4, shelled corn was more palatable than either ground wheat or ground rye The calves in Lot 1 ate an average of 10.62 po.unds of shelled corn per head per day as compared to an average daily consump - tion of 8.91 pounds of ground wheat per head by the calves </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Corn, Wheat, and Eye for Fattening Calves " : - hay hay Number of calves* 12 11 ,„ Average initial weight 372 372 372 qU o 10 Average final weight.. 869 823 III III fl? Average gain .;. 497 4*1 ill 8 Ai 8U Average daily gain.... ™\ A2 *% 0 "l 18 472 Average daily ration : SK.w:::::::::::::: $j K. f- Feed required for 100 pounds of gain: Sa-hay:::::::::::::: % ill Si ill Hi thrinfS^tSf 844 " ?89 781 821 806 n^Tfesir 2 - 88 4 - 13 4 - 52 4 - 98 4 -^ based on market wt. 58.0 57.2 56 6 «58 4 nan Dressing percentage, ° 8 - 4 58 -° based on final ex - perimental weight.. 56.3 54.8 54.0 55.5 55.4 Carcass grades: Ay. choice (p. ct.).. 42 9 0 37 on'. Low choice (p. ct.) 50 73 75 54 70 Good (p. ct.) 8 9 17 9 In High med. (p. ct.).. 09 g q Q Selling price per cwt. $8.00 $7.85 $7.75 $8.00 $7.85 Pork produced per steer 17.8. 5.5 13.5 17.2 12.7 wa S 1 T^^ 0 i 2 L C o a &gt;T^aSfoJ 0t W o a at i t n h e °. *%£*&amp; 0^X™?\ ** </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 263 in Lot 2 and of 8.91 pounds of ground rye per head by the calves in Lot 3. Lot 3 ate as much grain during the first four weeks as Lot 1, while Lot 2, which received ground wheat, started on feed more slowly than any other lot. Lot 2, as shown by Figure 1, increased its grain consumption more rapidly than Lot 3 and during the latter part of the experi - ment ate more grain than Lot 3. The calves in Lot 2, fed ground wheat, ate more alfalfa hay than any other lot in the experiment. Their average daily consumption of alfalfa was 5.66 pounds per head as compared to an average of 5.33 and 5.53 pounds in Lots 1 and 3 respectively. The average daily gains per head were 2.42 pounds on shelled corn, 2.20 pounds on ground wheat, and 2.18 pounds on ground rye. The gains by periods are shown in Figure 2. As indicated in Figure 3, Lot 1 required 438 pounds or 7.82 bushels of shelled corn and 220 pounds of alfalfa hay for each 100 pounds of gain pro - duced. In Lot 2, 405 pounds or 6.75 bushels of ground wheat and 257 pounds of alfalfa hay were required, while 410 pounds or 7.32 bushels of ground rye and 255 pounds of alfalfa hay were required in Lot 3 for 100 pounds of gain. The calves yio 1 1 1 z 7 !.:^ I &lt;^-7* 1 I - - I JLOT I It ZZIZZZ-Z I 1 1^ 2 §* ' I JLOT 3 g 3 JL0T4 i I I I • 1 1- 1 I 2 3 4 5 6 7 AVERAGE DAILY GRAIN CONSUMPTION PER HEAD BY SIX 2S-DAY PERIODS AMD A FINAL 37 -DAY PERIOD Fig. 1. — Average daily grain consumption by periods. Lot 1 received shelled corn; Lot 2, ground wheat; Lot 3, ground rye; Lot 4, shelled corn and ground wheat; and Lot 5, shelled corn and ground rye. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves | LOT I 4 .-^j LOT 3 . [1 3 fv^ LJ3T4 ' I ■ &amp;'■■ D lotj; • h Ifin &lt;! n n f3 2 is gj [jPpn JLL-4 ■ : ] b (I Bniji ,_l|:|L ,!,;,. J L. j. . . ii . !| . ! J IISBII illBll IIBBII HI lilBII ISBB11 IBM IBIB1I PERIOD 1ST.. 2ND. 3RD. 4TH. -5TH. 6TH. 7TH. Entire 2a ows 28 DAYS 28OWS 28 DAY'S 2 8 DAYS DAYS J7 DAYS oqjdayS Fig. 2. — Average daily gains per head by periods. The slump during the fifth period was due' to the severe March blizzard and the slump during the seventh period was probably due to excessive handling during the 1931 Feeders' Meeting. in Lot 1 were more highly finished-than those in Lots 2 and 3 and sold for $8.00- per hundredweight, as compared to $7.85 for Lot 2 and $7.75 for Lot 3. Table 1 shows that these prices were in line with the dressing percentages and carcass grades. MIXTURES OF SHELLED CORN AND GROUND WHEAT AND OF SHELLED CORN AND GROUND RYE The mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and ground wheat proved practically equal to shelled corn in every re - spect. The calves that received the corn and wheat mixture ate an average of 10.11 pounds of grain per day as compared to 10.62 pounds for the calves receiving shelled corn. They gained 2.40 pounds per day while the calves on shelled corn gained 2.42 pounds. As shown in Table 1 and Figure 3, the calves on the mixture of shelled corn and ground wheat (Lot 4) made slightly more economical gains than the calves on shelled corn. They required 3.68 bushels of shelled corn and 3.58 bushels of ground wheat or 421 pounds of the mix - ture for each 100 pounds of gain. Lot 1 required 438 pounds of shelled corn for the same gain. The hay requirement per </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 263 j 300 ■ | I E Blot. § 100 1 — § _ /^ _\\_E -PI ALL LOTS. R B X X ' — ' — I ALFALFA Fig. 3. — Pounds of grain and alfalfa required to produce 100 pounds of gain. I ip- 1 • ■ . . -i &gt;O / \ ZZ Z ■ X&gt; // N ZZ I LOT I 4 ■ 'I "^ "^ "1 - 0LiDT3 — 22 ■ "I "^ "^ "E -g L^5 — i ' — H -X&gt; -X -\ -— — I — I ALL LOTS — ° « H V N H ' — I ALFALFA 0. *" —^^ m i k^m i r xi i i\ 1 i i | | Fig. 4. — Average daily grain and hay consumption per head. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves 100 pounds of gain was practically identical in the two lots, being 220 pounds in Lot 1 and 218 pounds in Lot 4. Both lots sold for $8.00 per hundredweight. In carcass grades and dressing percentages, there was very little difference. Lot 5, which was fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground rye, consumed on the average 9.78 pounds of grain per head per day and required 424 pounds, or 7.57 bushels, for each 100 pounds of gain. The alfalfa hay requirement was 228 pounds for 100 pounds of gain. Figure 1 shows that Lot 5 started on feed more slowly than either Lot 1 or 4. In fact, it was not until the fifth month of the experiment that this lot consumed as much grain as Lot 4. For the remainder of the period, the calves of Lot 5 steadily increased in grain consumption until at the end of the experiment they were eating more grain than the calves of any other lot. The reason why this lot started on feed so slowly was not ap - parent. It would be interesting to know how the gains in Lot 5 would have compared with those in Lots 1 and 4 had the grain consumption been as high in the early part of the feeding period. As it was, the calves from Lot 5 made an average daily gain of 2.30 pounds per day. They sold for $7.85 per hundredweight, the same price as that obtained for Lot 2. A study of Table 1 shows clearly that Lot 5 excelled Lot 2 in both carcass grades and dressing percentage and it is likely that on a market with a wider spread Lot 5 would have sold higher than Lot 2. [BM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>