<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, FEEDING EXPERIMENTS WITH CATTLE AND PIGS</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
		       <change>
		          <date>2007-09-12</date>
		          <respStmt>
		             <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
		          </respStmt>
		          <item>Enrichment</item>
		       </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 75 The University of Nebraska BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA Vol. XV, Article I. FEEDING EXPERIMENTS WITH CATTLE AND PIGS By E. A. Bdrnett and H. R. Smith. Distributed November 6, 1902. CURLY, FIRST IN HEREFORD "SPECIAL," AT INTERNATIONAL, CHICAGO, 1901 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Experiment I. Alfalfa vs. Sorghuin for Wintering Calves 3 Experiment II. Grain vs. No Grain for Steers on Pasture 5 o Experiment III. Wheat vs. Corn in a Ration for Fatten ing Steers 10 Experiment IV. Comparison of Shelter and Rations in Feeding Steers 19 Experiment V. Raising Calves for Beef Production. Skim-milk vs. Sucking Dam 24 Experiment VI. Wintering Calves on Roughness 31 Experiment VII. Wheat Compared with Other Grains for Pigs. 33 Experiment VIII. Corn vs. Wheat for Pigs on Alfalfa Pasture 38 ERRATA. In the first paragraph of page 3 of this bulletin, at line 4, the sentence, "Twelve of the steers and the two heifers were «rade Shorthorn," should read. Twelve of the steers and the two heifers were grade Hereford and six of the steers were grade Shorthorn. On page 4, in Table I, the "Lot" column should read, Shorthorn 1, Hereford 2, Hereford X In Table I in some copies of the bulletin, the figures in the column "Alfalfa hay" are indistinct, and should read 7098 pounds, being the same for Lots 1 and 2 as the sorghum hav for Ix&gt;t 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">FEEDING EXPERIMENTS WITH CATTLE AND PIGS. Experiment I. ALFALFA VS. SORGHUM FOR ViNTERING CALVES. E. A. BURNETT. I October, 1900, 18 steer calves were purchased from the ton Breeding Farm Company, Madison, Nebr., for ex - aental feeding. Two heifers were also included, which e in the summer feeding tests of 1901. Twelve of the s and the two heifers were grade Shorthorn. These 20 were selected from a bunch of about 250 head and rep - ited fairly uniform size and quality, being from pure - sires and out of cows having at least one cross of the blood, making these calves at least three-quarters Here - or Shorthorn as the case might be. No special breed test was made with these steers, but in each experiment carried on, except the first, the Shorthorns and Herefords were generally equally divided, placing an equal number of Shorthorns and Herefords in each lot. In the first experiment an opportunity is given to compare six Shorthorns with six Herefords on the same feed. I he calves were received at the university farm October 1, ). They were placed on a clover and mixed grass pasture. October 15 they were given a small ration of grain con - ng of one half corn, one fourth bran and one fourth oats, eh was increased gradually until on November 1 they e eating 2^ pounds each per day. On October 19 these es weighed 6780 pounds, or 339 pounds each. During the ith of November they received alfalfa hay with an increas - grain ration until, November 30, they were eating five ods each per day and weighed 7425 pounds. On December 1, 1900, the steers were divided into three lots of six steers each. BULL. 75, AGR. EXl'. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XV, ABT. I. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Lot 1, six Shorthorn steers, weighed 2515 pounds Lot 2, six Hereford steers, weighed 2485 pounds. Lot 3, six Hereford steers, weighed 2425 pounds, Lots 1 and 2 received alfalfa hay and a grain ration t)t 3 received sorghum hay and the same grain ration, h consisted of one half corn, one fourth oats and one th bran. Beginning with a grain ration of five pounds per day and a hay ration of six pounds each per day, grain ration was gradually increased to eight pounds per day and continued at that rate until April 20, 1901, l the experiment was terminated on account of dehorn - which caused a considerable shrinkage in weights that not recovered until after they were turned on grass May ABL 'a vs. son Utttj r or ca ■('.5. Lot a 5" 1=1 CO I 1 It 4-&gt; T^r*fr»ri1 1 6 6 6 6195 6195 6195 7i96 7098 7098 3930 3950 3735 2515 2485 2425 1415 14R5 1310 *otal for each steer 1032 1183 Average gains on alfa; Average gains on sorg Gain of alfalfa over sc lfa and ;hum h- &gt;rghum grain, iv and , 22 poi 240 poi grain, unds pi inds. 218 pounds. :r calf in five montl </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Experiment II. GRAIN VS. NO GRAIN FOR STEERS ON PASTURE. E. A. BURNETT. On May 4, these lots were redivided, one half of the sor - ghum-fed steers and one half of the alfalfa-fed steers being placed on pasture only, while the other half were fed grain with pasture throughout the summer. This placed nine steers in each lot, but the grain-fed lot was added to by two Aber - deen-Angus steers which were purchased in April. Iq May 4, 1901, nine steers weighing 5545 pounds, or an age of 616 pounds each, were placed in a 16-acre pasture aining brome grass, mixed grasses, and three a [falfa. Two acres of this field was newly seeded and fur - ed very little pasture during the summer. On account tie extreme drought of 1901, the feed became very short ng the latter part of August, but with the rains of early :ember the pasture improved, especially the alfalfa, and e was fair pasture in the field at the time they were re - ed, November 1, 1901. STEERS ON GRAIN. I tie nine steers on grain, which were to be compared with nine on pasture, weighed 5485 pounds, or an average of pounds each. To the nine steers were added two Angus rs weighing an average of 600 pounds each, making en head. These 11 steers were placed on grain and pas- May 4 and had the run of about thirteen acres of low om land until August 15, when they were given another ure for 45 days and returned to their original pasture it October 1, after it had been improved by autumn s. For the sake of comparison, the records of weights were so kept as to determine the gains of different steers. It will be seen that while the gain of the steers wintered on sorghum hay was less during the winter than those wintered on al- STKEHS ON PASTURE. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 falfa, the summer gains of these sorghum-fed steers was lgh greater to overcome their smaller gains of the pre - vious winter and to place them on even weights with the al - falfa-fed steers by the end of the pasture season. The grain ration from May 4 to August 17 consisted of corn meal. On this date the ration was changed to 75 per cent corn and 25 per cent bran, which was continued until November 1 without change. During the entire period each steer on grain consumed 1893 pounds of corn meal and 260 pounds of bran. In the financial statement corn is valued at 40 cents per bushel, bran at $16 per ton, and pasture at $3 per acre. Table II. — Grain vs. no grain on pasture. 5545 pounds at 5 cts $277 25 To 16 acres pasture at $3 .48 00 To profit on nine steers 18 10 Not. 1 By 9 steers, S175 pounds, at $4.20 $343 35 $343 35 $343 35 May 4 To LotB 7, 8, and 9, nine steers, 5485 pounds, at 5 cts $274 25 To 11 acres pasture 30 00 To 2340 pounds bran at 80 cts. per 100 pounds . 18 72 To 305.4 bushels corn at 40 cts. per bushel 122 16 To profit on nine steers 48 16 by nine steers, 9135 pounds, at $5.40 $493 29 $493 29 $493 29 I A ?! 41 TS m is ■x. ■ is 4-t 1 3 *4 U o '§ Z 9 o 2 -S 2 c a -I -3 s I. 1-2-6 8-911 13-15-16 1 (9 bes H-4-5 7-10-12 14-17-18 29-31 1 (lib rage poi Shorthorn . . . Hereford .... Hereford .... ad) Shorthorn . . Hereford .... Hereford Angus steers. ead) unds grain co Alfalfa ... None Alfalfa .... None Sorghum . None Alfalfa..!. 6459 Alfalfa .... 6459 Sorghum . 6459 Not known 4306 23683 asumed.... 2153 27401875 865 27501910 840 26851760 92o 817;'. 5545 2630 2940 1870 1070 3175 1850 1325 3020 1765 1255 20201200 820 11155 6685 4470 i 288 i 280 308 i i 353 &gt; 441 &gt; 414 &gt; 410 913 91C 292 895 On grain 980 1058 "4oi" 1010 I FINANCIAL STATEM EXT BY LOTS. M,, 4 To Lots 4, 5, and 6, nine steer: s, on grass only. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pigs. 9 $109 08 $109 08 I he prices on these two lots of steers were estimated by Albert Noe, with Clay, Robinson &amp; Company, South iha, on November 1 at $4.00 per hundred pounds for the 58 steers and $5.75 per hundred for the grain-fed steers )maha on that date. These values were varied by charg - the cost of delivering the grain-fed steers in Omaha ■ :s per hundred, making them worth $5.40 at the farm, by adding the cost of freight to the or feeding le, which would have made them cost about $4.20 per dred delivered at the farm. fThis experiment shows that when steers are to be mar ?d in the fall or early winter there is more profit in sum - feeding with grain on pasture. Where steers are to be ter fed on grain for a spring market, there is more profit eed no grain on pasture. See Experiment III. 8. The failure of the corn crop of 1901 made the market for ing steers very bad and destroyed the profit that would ordinarily have been produced on a bunch of cattle making pounds gain in six months on pasture only, but tin - sequent winter feeding was very profitable and warranted placing a higher value on these steers as feeders. K. The high price of fat cattle permitted us to sell the in-fed cattle at a profit even after having fed them on corn •th forty cents per bushel during the summer. CONCLUSIONS. To 2 Angus steers, 1200 pounds, at 5 cts $ ! 60 00 To pasture 6 66 To 520 pounds bran at 80 cts. per 100 pounds. . To 67.86 bushels corn at 40 cts. per bushel 4 16 27 14 To profit on two steers 11 12 By two steers, 2020 pounds, at $5.40 $109 08 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Experiment III. ▼HEAT VS. CORN IN A RATION FOR FATTENING STEERS. E. A. BURNETT. H. R. SMITH On November 1, 1901, the 20 steers that had been on the Grain vs. No Grain experiment during the summer were taken to the yards to prepare for an experiment on the rela - tive feeding value of wheat and corn in a grain ration. Eighteen of these steers were grade Hereford and Shorthorn and two were grade Angus. Eleven had been grain fed dur - ing the summer and were divided into Lots 1 and 2. Nine head had been on pasture only and were divided into Lots Lot 1 contained six steers for Period I and four steers for Period II. Lot 2 contained five steers for Period I and four steers for Period II. Lot 3 contained five steers for both Period I and Period II. Lot 4 contained four steers for both Period I and Period II. These steers were given a four-weeks preliminary feeding period before the experiment proper commenced. During this time the steers in Lots 1 and 2 gained 36 pounds each and those in Lots 3 and 4 gained 72 pounds each, which should be taken into account in a six-months feeding period or in a financial statement. The experiment proper is divided into two periods, Period I of 11 weeks and Period II of 12 weeks. The ration for Period I was as follows : Lots 1 and 3 received a grain ration 80 per cent wheat and 20 per cent bran. Lots 2 and 4 received a grain ration 80 per cent corn and 20 per cent bran. IJ1 lots received alfalfa hay for roughness. On February 902, two of the best steers were withdrawn from Lot 1 and from Lot 2 to use for class-room instruction, leaving n with four steers in each lot, and the first experimental iod was closed. The ration for Period II was as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Lots 1 and 3 received a grain ration of 70 per cent wheat, 15 per cent corn and 15 per cent oil meal. tots 2 and 4 received a grain ration 70 per cent corn, IS cent wheat*and 15 per cent oil meal. All lots received ut one half their roughness in alfalfa hay, one fourth iu irie hay and one fourth in wheat straw. Each steer con - ted about half as much roughness as grain. These steers were followed by twenty pigs weighing 137ft pounds when the experiment commenced, one pig with each steer. The pigs were fed an additional grain ration of 2878 pounds of shorts for the entire 23 weeks and made a gain of 1340 pounds. Valuing the pigs at f 4.50 per hundred pounds at the beginning of the experiment and at their market value of |6.00 per hundred pounds at the close of the experiment, they made a net profit of f 72.17, which is credited to the steers. The price $6.00 is fixed as the market value because ae pigs were still too small to market. They wore fed oa experiment to July 21, and sold at $7.00 per hundred as re - ported in Experiment VIII, "Corn vs. wheat for pigs on al - falfa pasture." Inuring the period when alfalfa only was fed as rou^lu steers were often in too laxative a condition to produce best results, and the addition of prairie hay aud wheat w in the ration overcame this trouble in the second period he experiment. I be steers which had been summer fed on grain should e properly have been sold for beef in early winter, bn were only 18 months old and weighed only 1050 pounds n the experiment commenced, November 30, 1901, we de - 1 to feed them through the winter. The main object in feeding was to get a comparison between the cost of is on long-fed steers and short-fed steers of the same also wished to determine how much difference then- Id be in the weight and killing value of yearliir. , had been fed continuously for 18 months, compared l those that had been on pasture only during the summer were fed for a six-months winter period. K; is worthy of note that these steers consumed a relatively 11 amount of grain when compared with ordinary steers he feed lot. At no time did thev consume more than 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Eds average grain per day, whereas mature steers on full often consume 24 to 30 pounds of shelled corn and from 16 pounds of ground corn per day. See Tahle III. Kiese steers were sold in South Omaha May 8, 1902, by , Robinson &amp; Company. l.i its 1 and 2 weighed 1320 pounds average in Omaha and sold for $7.10. Lots 3 and 4 weighed 1298 pounds av&lt; : and sold for f6.90. Deducting the cost of freight, commis - sion, shrinkage, etc., which amounted to 23 cents per hun- I pounds, gave us a net juice at the farm of $0.87 per 100 pounds on the long-fed and $6.67 per 100 pounds on the short - fed cattle, which is the price figured in the financial si f. These steers were just about 24 months average and were classed as long yearlin Iota 1 and 2 had been fed grain continuously from wean - time, consuming in all 5790 pounds. Lots 3 and 4 v. grain during the first winter and again from November 901, to the time of selling. They consumed in all 3 nds of grain from weaning time to the time they v Piese steers were sold to Cudahy &amp; Company and « filtered for export. After cooling, Lots 1 and 2, which hed 1320 average alive, dressed (»4.48 per cent of their weight. Lots 3 and 4, which weighed 1298 average alive, dressed JS per cent of live weight. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 "««■« »S^S : SS8S 2 S d 'pamns UO3 UlBiO i SS5S : r~ &lt;s ie CD I ;o ■* &lt;c &gt; to ■w ■* t— 05 00 00 00 t" ureo o tfl io o 53 OO 00 V 02 t~ )q3i3M ■«• o ?5 5 t~- *f 0d CO w O I s * t*™ 00 IO ■*•&lt; "^ »3 I i f I ! iq2i3M js«^ S S § § § t- o o c[5 sssnqSnoj Xcq aijiwj UIBiS l«?OX "JWIV mBJis «oon o ~* f-t — i Q "* i-H 2 3 S S * •3 o 5SSS 5 1 — ' d 00 30 CO QO QO QC c^ *i o M g? 50 213123! N Hi-lHH 1O Cl ?J O 50 g) ". T. X -»&lt; r^ fH •T" • «i m §.8.8. yi 111 III 2 52* t&gt; w u %%% o o o -- w — •= — — 0 0 0 .5 .3 .9 S£ =£ M V V «l Hi Si S Si &lt;&lt;&lt; irara i;o »-H CQ | I UBjg •M II -r -n »J&lt; — 1 rH &gt;-&lt; •« f-l i iuoo • ■« -S t- cq r*^ w — 4 »«»qA^ a r*- o t— en en ?i n — « •* 35 1°\ ni ON Bi3O« © 3 9 I S • B • u s v a •° fc- 13 S I •S :-S : «t E 1/ S3 3 (2 a o (S3133M XI) I POLI'd (S3133»CX) II P°w»j </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pigs. 14 }i s s I S § 3 9 § &gt; {14 li — s «-t i-H tH 3 1 g'5 ° | r-* ■ s I— I I H i iH I Si fl "Si il. i-sl t. e E ill ltl|1 g I g g i • I 1 5 f-H CD rH s I- 4 I s g f-H g f-H | s i I 3 s I g g g g g a ■. 1 1. si ir O m !! f It 11 f* l-l C5 o ft 1^ r-1 I r-t I »-H CO S f-4 i— » '. 1 II a I o 1^ 'II 1 § *-4 CD — s 1 ■ I 4 3 S § I || 00 s 00 ao rH •^1 • a B : C : S' : £ : a : a : 1 : JJ : S : i ■ a J a : few*-* g J * 4 ° J a J J &lt; &lt; s :B* is ifi '-"a : a : H : S :jj : S :-J- : ■*,"" :•&gt;*,&lt;» : « «. ■ g — JIM J? w J3" h&gt;J "- 1 "50. H q 3 J o» '10. I 'T =»a '«^33^ TI— I POU3J SO. 'E * B W oi 'SO. 'H </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pigs. 15 each steer in Lots 1 and 2, with a grain-feeding period of 18 months, had consumed 2105 pounds more grain than each steer in Lots 3 and 4. They have to their credit 22 pounds additional weight and a difference in value of 20 cents per hundred, or $4.14 for 1976 pounds of grain, which was largely corn meal fed during the summer. Had these long-fed cattle been disposed of November 1, when they came off grass, they would have paid a larger profit than the steers on pasture, hut the subsequent feeding showed some profit on account of the high price per pound at which they were sold, as will be Fable •OCK consumet an. gains iy one s&gt; &lt;eer r or p e , JO, Is. Aver. cor dui ige amount of grain isutned by each steer ing the 23 weeks. Avera rou; by &lt; the ghnet ;ach i 23 w! unount of is consumed steer during ?eks. a" i Lot s « I 5 « 8 B o a 5* "ed Ifi &lt; ■ "a J — — lbs. 1053 198 Of. ,^r lbs. lbs. 1676 184 lbs. lbs. lbs.\ Lot 1, wheat . 204 184 2248 143 1397 294 •&gt;.« Lot 2, corn . . . 184 1676 204 184 2248 1053 198 143 1397 279 -.- Lot 3, wheat 1803 206 210 206 2425 1048 198 143 1392 349 n.n Lot 4, corn. . . 205 1803 211 a* 24.4 1163 198 1^ 1397 326 k« I ■ i Food consumed per pound &lt; of gain, bot l peril , f by wheat stei \ by corn steei ers, 11. 85 pounds. •s, 12. 48 pounds. All lots w ere of th( z same a&lt;; it they hi harging ;e ani d had been un ider the same in during the , we find that conditions e xcept thj id re ;ceived no grai lie grain eaten previous sui tnmer. C all tl </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Feeding Experiments with Cattle and Pigs. 16 FINANCIAL STATEMENT BY LOTS, Lot 1. Nov. 30 To 6 steers, 6445 lbs., at $5.40 $348 03 8334 lbs. of wheat at 66 cts. per bu. ($1.10 net profit on pigs with Lot 2 17 58 Feb. 7 By 1 steer, 1075 lbs., at $6 per 100 $ 64 50 ■ 8 " 4 steers, 5288 lbs., at $6.87 per 100 net 363 28 net profit on pigs with Lot 2 17 58 36 (Profit on each steer, $11.30.) per 100) 91 67 " 1224 lbs. of bran at 80 cts. per 100 lbs 9 80 ' 736 lbs. corn at 56 cts. per bu. ($1 per 100) 7 36 " 736 lbs. of oil meal at $1.50 per 100 11 04 " 5616 lbs. of alfalfa hay at $8 per ton 22 46 " 792 lbs. of prairie hay at $8 per ton 3 17 584 lbs. of wheat straw at $4 per ton 1 17 " profit on 4 steers 23 weeks and on 2 steers 11 weeks 25 60 " net profit on pigs with Lot 1 19 27 =■■ By 2 steers, 2500 lbs " 4 steers, 5390 lbs., at $6.87 net " net profit on pigs with Lot 1 «£ $539 47 (Profit on each steer, $8.97.) Lot 2. — To 5 steers, 5100 lbs., at $5.40 $275 40 " 7520 lbs. of corn at 56 cts. per bu. ($1 per 100) 76 20 " 1020 lbs. of bran at 80 cts. per 100 8 16 " 736 lbs. of wheat at 66 cts. per bu. ($1.10 per 100) 8 10 " 736 lbs. of oil meal at $1.50 per 100 lbs 11 04 " 4914 lbs. of alfalfa hay at $8 per ton 19 66 " 792 lbs. of prairie hay at $8 per ton 3 17 " 584 lbs. of straw at $4 per ton 1 17 " profit on 4 steers 23 weeks and 1 steer 11 wppks . SS fiP </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 Lot 3. Nov. 30 To 5 steers, 4925 lbs., at |4.20 $206 85 9015 lbs. wheat at $1.10 per 100 99 16 1032 lbs. corn at $1 per 100 10 32 1049 lbs. bran at 80 cts. per 100 8 39 1032 lbs. oil meal at $1.50 per 100 15 48 4240 lbs. alfalfa hay at $8 per ton 16 96 990 lbs. prairie hay at $8 per ton 3 96 730 lbs. straw at $4 per ton 1 4« profit on 5 steers, 23 weeks 82 17 net profit on pigs with Lot 3 19 62 U ay 8 By 5 steers, 6668 lbs. at $6.67 net $444 75 net profit on pigs with Lot 3 19 62 1464 37 $464 37 (Profit on each steer, $20.29.) Lot 4. Nov. 30 To 4 steers, 3900 lbs., at $4.20 per 100 $163 80 7115 lbs. of corn at $1 per 100 72 15 821 lbs. of wheat at $1.10 per 100 9 03 1049 lbs. of bran at 80 cts. per 100 8 39 821 lbs. of oil meal at $1.50 per 100 12 31 4212 lbs. of alfalfa hay at $8 per ton 16 85 792 lbs. of prairie bay at $8 per ton 3 17 584 lbs. of straw at $4 per ton 1 17 proflt on 4 steers, 23 weeks 60 17 net profit on pigs with Lot 4 15 70 May 8 By 4 steers, 5203 lbs., at $6.67 net $347 04 net profit on pigs with Lot 4 15 70 $362 74 $362 74 (Profit on each steer, $18.97.) Proflt on two long-fed lots $101 07 Proflt on two short-fed lots 177 68 Total proflt on four lots $278 73 Neither the interest on investment nor risk has been charged in this statement 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 CONCLUSIONS. KThe gains of Lot 1 on a wheat ration exceeded those of 2 on a corn ration by 16 pounds per head in 23 weeks. t'fhe gains of Lot 3 on a wheat ration exceeded those of i on a corn ration by 22 pounds per head. This one ex - nent is not conclusive evidence that wheat exceeds corn eding value but indicates that the feeding value of wheat per cent greater than corn for cattle. 3. This experiment indicates that a 6-months folding pe - riod in this case is more profitable than a 12-months fowling period. 4. This experiment shows a profit of f 10.14 per head on summer-fed yearling cattle compared with f 19.63 on cattle of the same quality which were on grass only during the sum - mer. Taking the statement for the year, the cattle fed 12 months show a profit of $ 15.49 against a profit of $21.64 &lt;&gt;n the cattle fed grain during the winter only. experiment shows that hogs will make good gains wing steers fed on ground feed. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 EXPERIMENT IV. COMPARISON OF SHELTER AND RATIONS IN FEEDING STEERS. E. A. BURNETT. In December, 1899, 18 steers were purchased in South iiha for the Experiment Station to test the value of ons and of shelter for winter feeding. The three condi - 18 imposed were as follows: Six steers were confined in ■ sheds 8 x 14 feet with a yard attached of the same size, ting a stall and yard 8 x 28 feet, in which a single steer i confined. This shed opened on the east and was tected from southwest winds and partially protected from theast winds. Six steers were also confined in box stalls 8 x 12 feet, open lag to the south. They had no exercise except when driven to the scales, and the privilege of a small yard while the stall - being cleaned daily. One steer was confined in each stall. Iix steers were also fed in an open yard 100 x 200 feet in ensions, having an open shed 16 x 24 feet facing south, er which they could run at pleasure. They were also pro - ed from the north by a shed 85 feet long and 10 feet i, a tight board fence 6 feet high along the remainder of north side of the yard. These different yards and pens been built the previous year with a view of determining effect of exposure upon the gains of animals in the feed iind, though the number subjected to the experiment was small to give definite results, the data secured is lished. It was not thought wise to complicate the experiment bj many different rations, and we therefore determined to alfalfa hay for roughness and to use three different grain rations, viz., corn meal, corn meal and one fourth oats, and com meal and one fourth bran, as the grain rations to test their relative values when fed with alfalfa hay. The results of the experiment indicate that more definite information on the value of shelter might have bam secured had only one grain ration been used. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 The lot of 18 weighed 14,870 pounds at the stock yards in Omaha, December 4, 1899, or an average of 826 pounds. They were probably yearling steers with possibly one exception. These steers were fed alfalfa hay in an open yard until December 23, when they were separated into thirteen lots and put for one week upon a preliminary period of feeding, after which, on December 30, 1899, the experiment period be - gan. During the period of 17 days in the open yard the steers consumed 30G8 pounds of alfalfa hay and 756 pounds of corn meal, and at the end of the preliminary period, the 12 steers in the stalls and pens — Lots 1 to 12 inclusive — received daily eight pounds each of grain and from 12 to 16 pounds each of alfalfa hay. Lot 13 in the open yard received daily per head only six pounds of corn meal and sixteen pounds of alfalfa hay. As the grain ration increased, the hay ration decreased, until — during the latter part of the feeding period — the various lots of steers received daily from 16 to 18 and, in one instance, 20 pounds of grain and from 5 to 10 pounds of alfalfa hay. The correct average weight of the steers was difficult to determine, but an attempt was made to secure this weight by taking an average of three weights taken on three different days as the nearest estimate to the correct weight. This method was also followed in securing the last weights used in this experiment. The 18 steers were separated as follows : SHELTER. RATION. WEIGHT. II. Open shed and pen. Corn meal and alfalfa hay. 935 lbs. 2. Open shed and pen. Corn meal and alfalfa hay. 915 lbs. 3. Open sbed and pen. Corn meal, oats, and alfalfa hay. 865 lbs. 4. Open shed and pen. Corn meal, oats, and alfalfa hay. 900 lbs. 5. Open shed and pen. Corn meal, bran, and alfalfa hay. 1085 lbs. 6. Open shed and pen. Corn meal, bran, and alfalfa hay. 810 lbs. 7. Box stall In shed. Corn meal and alfalfa hay. 805 lbs. 8. Box stall In shed. Corn meal and alfalfa hay. 880 lbs. 9. Box stall in shed. Corn meal, oats, and alfalfa hay. 915 lbs. 10. Box stall in shed. Corn meal, oats, and alfalfa hay. 835 lbs. 11. Box stall in shed. Corn meal, bran, and alfalfa hay. 920 lbs. 12. Box stall in shed. Corn meal, bran, and alfalfa hay. 810 lbs. 13. Large yard and open shed. (Six sUers.) Corn meal and alfalfa hay. 5160 lbs. Average weight of Lots 1 to 6 inclusive (Dec. 30, 1899) 918 lbs. Average weight of Lots 7 to 12 Inclusive (Dec. 30, 1899) 860 lbs. Average weight of Lot 13 (Dec. 30, 1899) 860 lbs. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Tablb VI. (a) Steers an corn mea, and a. //a^a. Time, 23 wee] s. . I Shelter a s a •3 * A II m a 3 290 315 450 314 13.8 12 18 1- 1 1 1 1 1 6 Shed and yard 2(570 Shed an&lt;l yard '1 Box stall - Box stall 2 Open yard and shed ... 2 1332 1472 1480 1024 1500 122.') 1236 1290 ia&lt;5 1166 950 8OT&gt; 880 8G0 Average gain 372 (*)■! r/^wj &lt;?n three fourths co, •«, £&gt;«/ • fourti oa/i, nd al. !(/fl. Time, ! 3 wee ks. z s a Z Shelter a "a .5 i a 3 1 1 1 1 1 Shed and yard Shed and yard Box stall Box stall 2)99 25S3 2392 1446 1437 1126 1567 1220 1230 1205 1180 865 900 915 835 355 11.1 320 12.5 290 11.7 11.5 Average gain . . . . 327 I fleers on hree 'ourlhs cot it, oni /b«rj 'ran, a*&lt; r al/a. Time, 5 3 wee ;s. o 3 a 6 Shelter c n 2 SI 4-* J| I -* .S s O 365 330 405 425 I I 1 1 1 Shed and yard 2828 Shed and yard 2490 Hox stall 2409 Box stall '2548 1531 1430 15!Mi 1591 1450 1140 1345 12.15 1080 810 940 810 11.9 11.8 9.9 9.7 Average gain 381 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 FINANCIAL STATEMENT. DR. Dec 5. To 18 steers, 14,870. at $4.66 $ 69145 To freight Omaha to Lincoln 14 00 To preliminary feeding — 5000 pounds of alfalfa at $4 per ton 10 00 1472 pounds of corn at 44 cts. per 100 . , . . 5 47 66 pounds bran at 60 cts. per 100 40 66 pounds oats at 60 cts. per 100 40 ■ 30. To 13 tons of hay during experiment at $4. . 52 00 To 39,170 pounds of corn at 44 cts 172 35 To 2890 pounds of oats at 60 cts 17 34 To 3062 pounds of bran at 60 cts. 18 37 To feeding from close of experiment to selling — 3087 pounds of corn at 44 cts 13 58 1550 pounds of oats at 60 cts 9 30 1550 pounds of bran at 60 cts 9 30 4000 pounds of alfalfa at $4 per ton 8 00 To interest on $1,000 for six months 40 00 July 2. To freight to Omaha 18 70 To internal revenue 11 To yardage, 25 cts. per head 4 50 To hay 40 To commission, 50 cts. per head 9 00 To balance ( profit ) - 3 16 I By 18 steers, 21330 lbs., at $5.10 $1,087 83 $1,087 83 $1,087 83 CONCLUSIONS. In these feeding operations, as in all feeding, the large sains proved to be the cheapest gains, and these were not made by any one ration. All the extremely large gains were made by steers in the box stalls in the shed. Four of the six is in the shed made an average gain of 444 pounds each. whereas the average gain of the 18 steers was only 350 pounds. It was also true that the poorest gain made by any of the 18 steers was made in a box stall in this shed by t, but it is probable that this was due to the peculiarities of the steer rather than to the surroundings. He was never •&lt;&gt;d feeder as he consumed from 100 to 400 pounds less ii than the other steers, and was one of the heaviest steers -ide of No. 5 when they were put into the experiment. At time he weighed 915 pounds, while the six in this shed </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Bhe average gains of the lots of six steers according to the ter was as follows : I open-shed-and-pen steers made 330 pounds average Six box-stall steers made 400 pounds average gaio Six open-shed-and yard steers made 315 pounds average The average gain by lots on the same kind of feed and under the same condition is given in Table IV, but if average all lots on one kind of feed but under different ditions we find the following results : Ken steers on corn meal and alfalfa hay made :U4 pounds •age gain. tour steers on corn meal and oats and alfalfa hay made pounds average gain. our steers on corn meal and bran and alfalfa hay m pounds average gain. In this experiment corn meal and alfalfa in the box stall gave the largest gain. Corn meal, bran and alfalfa in the box stall gave the second largest gain. Corn meal, bran and alfalfa in the open shed and pen gave the third largest gain. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 RAISING CALVES FOR BEEF PRODUCTION-SKIM MILK VS. SUCKING DAM. E. A. BURNETT. Ii the spring of 1899 the Department of Dairy Husbandry he Station undertook an experiment to determine the tive profit of milking beef-bred cows and feeding the es from these cows on separator skim-milk and a grain on, compared with allowing the calf to run with its her until weaning time. Six calves were used in that ex - ment, the results of which are reported in Bulletin No. All these calves were well-bred grade Elerefords except 2, which steer was one half Jersey with considerable rthorn blood, but was a good blocky steer of moderate iity. the calves that sucked the cows in this experiment were ned December 1, 1899, and on December 9 they were isferred to the Department of Animal Husbandry to be for the purpose of determining what effect their previous tment would have on their value for beef production. Ei December 9, 1899, these calves were divided as follows : skim-milk calves were numbered Lots 1, 2, 3. The calves had run with their dams were numbered Lots 4, 5, 6. ' weighed as follows : Lot 1, 435 pounds ; Lot 2, 415 pounds ; Lot 3, 380 pounds : average of the three lots fed, 410 pounds; average age, 190 Lot 4, 390 pounds ; Lot 5, 360 pounds ; Lot 6, 380 pounds : average of the three lots sucking cows, 377 pounds ; average age, 191 days. These calves were carried forward for the next 16 months in three periods, as follows : Eeriod I, from December 9, 1899, to May 5, 1900, 147 days, ing which time they were fed alfalfa hay and a grain on three fourths corn and one fourth bran. Keriod II, from May 5, 1900, to November 3, 1900, 183 i, during which they were on pasture and received a Experiment V. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Bn ration of eight pounds each per day, consisting of one corn, one quarter oats and one quarter bran. Period III, from November 3, 1900, to April 27, 1901, 147 days, during which time five animals only were fed, the ration consisting of one half corn, one quarter oats and one quarter bran, with alfalfa hay and roots. |)t 6, a heifer, was withdrawn from the experiment after nd period. As she made average gains during the two periods, there is no reason to think from this ex - rnent that the calves running with their dams are better beef production than calves fed under the best known tiods on sweet separator milk and a grain ration to re - e the fat and solids which are taken from the milk in miing. It will be noted from the first weights that the es that had been fed were heavier for their age at wean - time than those that ran with the cows and ha&lt;l pasture l no grain. Some difference in quality was visible, « he end of the first winter, in favor of the calves that had ted their dams, but this could not be detected after I been on grass, and was not apparent at selling time. Table VII. — Skim-milk vs. sucking dams. Period Decem r&gt;er , to B ay 5, 2 | a 5 I 31 = 5 3 4 5 6 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 906 888 902 894 894 894 793 786 796 786 786 786 730 675 700 750 710 7.0 435 415 380 390 360 380 SB8 260 320 300 350 320 5378 4733 ge 896 789 ge gain on fed calves ( Lots 1-2-3) ge gain on sucking calves (Lots 4-; 4265 23W) 1906 292 343 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">RECORDS OF CURLY AND JOHN. Two steers of this lot, viz., No. 3, "John," from the skim milk lot, and No. 5, "Curly," from the lot that sucked the dam, were retained and their records carried forward for a period of seven months, closing the records on November 23, 1901, when these steers were sent to the International Live Stock Exposition at Chicago where they were entered in the class of Grades and Crossbreds over two years. In the last feeding i&gt;t&gt;riod, John, which was the coarser and growthier steer, made the larger gain and also a some - what cheaper gain than Curly, owing to the fact that he was not ripe and thoroughly matured. Bn the show John was unplaced, but was afterward sold to Dour &amp; Co. at f 7.65, bringing $132.33. Curly was a steer of most excellent type. The Iire&gt; Hie and «* i, 1900, to Nov mber 3, 1 ( 00. u S B O a 3^ 4-« SI 3 2 i I 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 1417 1417 1417 1417 1417 1417 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 1000 910 1035 1000 985 925 730 675 700 750 710 700 I Per :od I I — November 3, 1900, t April 27, 1901. I u E B 2 ? - 1 .3 ts.se eg V ,3* I ! 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 147 days 2617 2628 2694 2530 2575 1471 1471 1579 1471 1538 455 455 455 1015 1325 1245 1370 1335 1320 1CO0 910 103T) 1000 985 I Average Average jam on L 'ain on L&lt; &gt;ts 1, 2, a its 4 and nd3 ■ s 5 Averaj 903 pout ?e gain of Lots 1, 2, and 3, from December 9, 1899, to April 27, 1901, ids. Average gain of Lots 4 and 5 for the same period, 903 pounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Feeding Experiments tdth Cattle and Pigs. 27 E-te said : "He was a grand good steer, thicker and riper Garcia (the steer which won first prize), not quite so filled in his quarters, but a steer that indicated more ty in his flesh." Curly was given second place against competitors. Curly also took second prize in the class for Grades and -ses in the Agricultural College Competition with el&lt; competitors, winning over Garcia by whom he was l&gt;eaten the day before, but losing to St. Hubert which stood fourth in the competition of the previous day. Curly also won first prize in the Hereford Special, Two - year-old Grades and ( Ethe block he compared favorably with some of the pion steers of the show as indicated in the following taken from the Nebra$ka Fanner. Table VIII.— Curly and the Hereford Champions dressed. I I I I | | I ►j a £ » CO The Woods Principal, Hereford, owned by Geo. P. Hendrv, Goodenow, 111 1615 1102 i 66.99 5.78 6J0 Uncle John 2d, Hereford, owned by Geo. S. Redhead, Des Moines, la 1520 960 63.10 6.91 5.M Beau Lou, Hereford, owned by Makin Bros., Lee's Summit, Mo 6.81 6.8B By, Hereford grade, owned by Netir tperiment Station 1107 67.30 8.21 6.08 = 1/ u </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 tral Nebraska. He was sired by the Hereford bull Legal Tender 61224 by Earl of Shadeland 22d. I he calf, Curly, was grown on the Station farm without idea of his being shown in competition. He came into department when he was about six months old and was during the first winter on alfalfa hay with a prain ration « quarters corn and one quarter bran. On May 5, 1900, 'inparing the fi eedi Qg records of these iteers from birth to tim ie of slaughter ', thi : records are given •tow. Table IX .—John, calved Jul iy*,. S99. h a ■3 X a iS (A a . =1 I 0) b 3 &amp; Q JS u. t 1 S 6 1 o o 5 1 — ' ■sJ 12 ~93| 93 58 136 IIS 1 1 July8toDec.8,1899 13 V 3 5 e I m I I 3 1 it = o I X to O s a 216 355 99 3 I s O 1 Dec. 9 to May 4 . . May 5 to Nov 2 . . Nov. 3 to April 27. Apr. 28 to Nov. 23, 1901 651 707 1912 '355 670 867 1417 2G8I 787 18 1523 — .... 485 700 1035 1370 an 700 1035 i i aao 335 335 5.16 4.28 12.69 ... H 687 321 H H 1715 1370 315 13.17 .... u Total 1712 1208 3J1 8504 3335 485 1717 135 1..80 ~urly t cal\ td June 16, 1899. ! M June 16 to Dec. 8, 1899 Dec. 9 to May 4... May 5 to Nov. 2. . Nov. 3 to April 27. April 28 to Nov 23, 1901 : . . . Sucking i 679 .... 709 355 1287 644 1665 774 4340U773 cow 360 85 . . 905 787 .... 710 360 355... 1419 18 .... 935 710 644 ... 2575 1538 1015 1320 985 715 311 3465 567 .... 1645 1320 1940 3118364 34101015 1645 85 483 - 15601 m\ Total rly was bred and rais&lt; ?d on the Station farm and was •4 i a grade Hereford co\ r purchased on the rangi B in cen- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 lie was turned on pasture, where he remained until v be 2. Again on April 28, 1901, he was placed on where he remained until about August 1. Beginning on May 4, 1900, the grain ration of this steer was made up of half corn, one quarter oats and one quarter bran. The char - r of this grain ration was not changed from that time until about August 1, 1901, a period of about fifteen mon After August 1, 1901, he received a small ration of oil m and during the months of October and November, 1901, he ived a ration of 50 per cent corn, 20 per cent &lt; cut bran and 15 per cent oil meal. During the winter of I'.io0-1901 he received alfalfa hay for roughness and about pounds of mangels per day for a period &lt;&gt;f nearly months. This steer was never limited in his supply of ro . and during the last six months of his feeding it necessary to guard against over-ripeness, as will be indi - cated by the rather small consumption of grain betl April 2*8 and November 23, 1901. He was fed twice uailj until about the first of October, after which time he I both grain and hay three times a day. It is interesting to note that this steer, during the 1 years of his life, required 6.6 pounds of grain to product pound of gain and less than ten pounds of total food to dnce a pound of gain, not counting the food secured during lays on pasture. This record would tend to show that tinished cattle can be economically produced if they are so fed that they continue to make good gains up to the time when they are finished. The killing records show that this [■ dressed 67.3 per cent, giving a dressed weight of 1.107 poundl from a live weight of 1,646 pounds, with only per cent tallow and 6.08 per cent hide. The rather h hide was due to an exceedingly heavy coat of hair and no extreme thickness of the skin. This steer is a conspicuous example of the effect i Mood in improving the common cattle of the country. lie a low-down, blocky, thick-fleshed type, which ai as being good feeders, and was a worthy scion of his illn - ous grandsire, Earl of Shadeland 22d. He d&lt; ited tin - fact that steers of the right type are rent pi md that profit lies in continuous growth. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 it It Cattle and Pigs. E H -3 C3 U I— In j M a a B « Z 3 m c Q Z &lt; '1 5 i </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Experiment VI. WINTERING CALVES ON ROUGHNESS. E. A. BURNETT. H. R. SMITH E January, 1902, a lot of twelve Aberdeen-Angus purchased for the purpose of determining how such si 1 be most cheaply wintered and still be brought to grass &gt;od condition to go on and make summer gains. These ?s were divided into two lots of six each. tots 1 and 2 were placed under test on January 18, 1' r two weeks of preliminary feeding. Lot 1, six steers, weighed 2950 pounds. They received a ration of alfalfa hay and prairie hay with no grain. Eot 2, six calves, weighed 2885 pounds. They received the e roughness as Lot 1, but in addition received a ration our pounds of grain per day. Ehe experiment continued until April 2i&gt;. ■ iktwmI of thir- I weeks, when these steers were turned together upon :ure in the same field. rt 2 required 8.90 pounds of food to make one pound of in weight. Eiguring hay at $8 per ton, the gains on Lot 1 cost |6 per dred, while the gains on Lot 2 cost only |4.66 per dred. t?he experiment shows that it is ordinarily more econom - l to feed a small grain ration even when good gains can secured on hav alone. ABLE 3 jrain vs. no gram m win 'enng calves. 1 2 ■a • =3 ►. 6 I 55 !5 H &lt;! 1 ■ ■ 1 0 bc •a so — 2~ SP £« 5? tj'5 fc £ « h i Pounds 6 91 days 1237 6 91 days 1050 Pounds 250 243 Pounds none 350 592 666 492 481 11 1 ' Lot 1 required 14.87 pounds o hay fo weigh each pound of gain daily on hay alone. Nit made a gain of 1.1 pounds i </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 ■ "■riments with Cattle and Pigs. The character of the roughness should be noted, as the too prevalent habit of wintering calves without grain gen - erally results in their coming through the winter in bad condition and without having gained in weight. From the B at hand, this does not seem necessary when good alfalfa and prairie hay are available. A mixture of alfalfa and prairie hay was thought to be preferable to alfalfa alon&lt; it prevented scouring, which often resulted when prairie was not fed regularly. The proportion in which this hay was fed, namely, 80 per cent alfalfa and 20 per cent prairie ■coined to prevent nearly all scouring and to represent it the proportion desired 1 &gt; v the animals of the qualit hay being fed. October 30, 1902, these steers were weighed again, to de - n'ne the summer gains. Those in Lot 1 weighed 880 pounds each and those in Lot 2, 900 pounds each. Those that had no grain during the winter had therefore gained 288 pounds since April 20, or a period of 192 days, while these in Lot 2 had gained only 234 pounds in that time. Ilthough the steers in Lot 1 were only 20 pounds lighter &gt;ber 30, there was yet a noticeable difference in quality. Noe, with Clay, Robinson &amp; Co., South Omaha, esti - ed Lot 1 at $4.75 per hundred and Lot 2 at $5. At these res the steers in Lot 1 are worth $41.80 and those in Lot 15 each. With pasture at $3 per acre, charging each the e rate, we find that the steers in Lot 1 make a net profit 4.74 and those in Lot 2 $5.73 each from April 20 to Octo - 30, 1902. The steers of both lots will be fed through the ter, so the final results will be known a few months </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 Experiment VII. WHEAT COMPARED WITH OTHER GRAINS FOR PIGS. H. R. SMITH. Iorty-eight pigs were divided into eight lots, each lot con ing of four of the so-called bacon pigs, Tamworth and kshire, and two of the block type, Duroc-Jersey and kshire. While the pigs were not prime feeders, they « ded in such a way as to make the lots fairly even in qual - and weight. The experiment was carried on in a closed 1 where each lot had the run of a small pen 8 x 12 feet small yard adjacent 8x16 feet. All pens had cement rs, which proved unsatisfactory during the severely cold ther. The only way by which the pigs could be kept at comfortable was by keeping them heavily bedded with l\v so they would not come in close contact with the I cement. i'revious to the experiment, all lots had the Mine ration, sisting of corn, shorts and wheat. Each lot was pu experimental ration nine days previous to the first w. so that all should become accustomed to the new rations. ) experiment was begun October 1, 1901, and closed Jan - y 20, 1902. Table XI shows the feed record, gains and fits by lots, and Table XII the average for each pig by lot. n </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Table XI.- U compa rfi ?&lt;/ ariVA o/An grains for pi^ ■5. Thirteen wee' s, fn im Octot &gt; 21, 1901, t&lt; January 20, 1! IA. Lots I ■ — "a V = I 0 ■3 j "3 as ■fe C l-&lt; to -ti 5 a. 0 a I 1* "S-a it i c I s\ be ME P = lbs. lbs.. lbs. lbs. 16 pigs, whole t, dry 1004 6 pigs, whole t, soaked 18-24 6 pigs, ground t 1062 6 pigs, ground t and corn, equal 1069 6 pigs, ground t and rye, equal 6 pigs, ground t and shorts, parts 1044 6 pigs, ground 6 pigs, ground 1004 1046 1062 1069J 662 661 648 668 342 385 414 401 2178 2317 2351 119 96129 79 20 24 29 74 23 08; 29 id 23 97 29 06 149 75 49 98 52 24 53 03 855 47 57 79 53 67 59 06 « 7 81 6 43 - 1024 641 383 237 23 39 28 84 52 23 56 57 .. 656 338 2375 22 51 29 52 52 03 57 68 5 65 660 387 2356 24 54 29 701 54 24 57 84 3 60 639 367 229Q 22 28 28 75 51 03 I 55 58 4 55 Total profit on forty-eig it pi; ;s during ie thirteen weeks' feeding . ,44 U </seg>
            <seg id="p035">ling l'.i i ith Cati 35 Table XII. — Wheat compared with other grains for pigs. Averages for one PV Sfn H i. S^ 5 &gt;, 'SO a Iff!) S 3 iU &gt; Pounds Pound. Pounds Pounds Lot 1, whole wheat dry 167 110 57 .63 363 6.37 Lot 2, whole wheat soaked 171 110 64 .70 :ttw Lot 3, ground wheat 177 108 69 .7*; 386. Lot 4, ground wheat and corn . 178 111 67 .74 39-2 Lot 5, ground wheat and rve .. 170.7 107 63.7 .70 TO'3 wheat and shorts 174 109 65 .71 3M s Lot 7, ground corn 174.5 110 .71 393 LotS, ground rye. 168 107 61 381 NOTES ON THE EXPERIMENT. r ground feed was mixed to a thick slop in the tr weighings were made. The wheat for Lot 2 was weighed, then placed in pails of water, where it soaked from 18 to 24 hours before being fed. I^he whole wheat for Lot 1 was placed iu a flat trough. The s were rather slow in consuming the dry wheat because difficulty in mastication. Many kernels passed through iigested. One pig in Lot 5 on wheat and rye was off feed for several days, which put that lot at a disadvantage. All were occasionally fed charcoal and lime, which was greedily consumed and seemed to whet the appetite. E reckoning the profits of Lots 3, 4. ."&gt;. »;, 7 and 8, eight i per hundred pounds was charged for grinding wheat rye, and six cents per hundred for corn. These are the i charged in this locality. The pigs wore sold on the farm at ?."&gt;.! 52i per hundred. Two bacon pigs, one fattened on corn and the other on Lot 6, ground </seg>
            <seg id="p036">■crimcnts with Cattle and Pigs. 36 at, and two of the block type, in this case Duroc-Jersey, one fattened on corn and the other on wheat, were slaugh- I attle difference was observed between carcasses of wheat and carcasses of corn-fed hogs except that perhaps a lit - more lean meat was noticeable on the wheat hogs. re larger proportion of lean meat on the bacon hogs apparent. The tables show — ■1) The most economical gains were made by. Lot 2, on ted wheat. K2) The largest gains per pounds of food consumed were le by Lot 3, on ground wheat, but the gain of this lot over 2 is more than offset by cost of grinding. The smallest profit was made by Lot 7, on corn alone. | Table XI.) This is partly due to the fact that corn at this time was the highest-priced feed used in the experiment. However, the column in Table 2 showing food consumed per pound of gain puts ground corn at a feeding value 9 per cent below wheat, pound for pound. V round rye is shown to be 2 per cent below corn for feed - purposes but the cost per bushel in this case, 50 cts. for and 55 cts. for corn, puts the rye ahead in the net proliiv In drawing general conclusions from this experiment, at :ion should be given to the amount of food required to luce one pound &lt;&gt;f gain as well as the column showing profits, since the relative prices on these grains vary m ly from time to time. CONCLUSIONS. Two important conclusions can be drawn from this ex - periment, — II) Wheat can be profitably substituted for corn in feed - pigs so long as the price of wheat is not more than nine cent higher than corn. (2) In feeding wheat to hogs it should first be soaked or ground. Of the two, soaking is more economical unless the grinding can be done for about two cents per hundred pounus. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Experiment VIII. CORN VS. WHEAT FOR PIGS ON ALFALFA PASTURE. £. A. BURXETT. H. R. SMITH. May 8, 1902, 18 pigs were placed in three quarter-acre lots of alfalfa. The pigs were divided so that each lot contained six pigs approximately even in quality and weight. These were a mixed lot of Tamworth and Duroc crossbreds and had previously run behind experimental steers where they subsisted on ground wheat and corn droppings, one pig to each steer, with one pound of shorts additional. Lot 1 was given a ration of ground corn ; Lot 2, 95 per cent ground corn and 5 per cent dried blood; aud Lot 3, ground wheat. Each lot was given freely of alfalfa pasture and all were on rape one w The following table shows the average gains aud cost pet hundred pounds of gain. corn was valued at $1.00 per cwt, wheat at f 1.10, and dried blood at that time was quoted at $2.50 per cwt. From the table it will be noted that the gains on corn with alfalfa were smallest, the wheat ration' and the ration con - sisting of 5 per cent mixture of dried blood and corn giving the same gains. Figuring these products at market values it will be seen that the cost of 100 pounds gain on corn and alfalfa was slightly below corn and dried blood, and thii cents per hundred below wheat. Table XIII.— Wheat vs. corn for pigs on al/a( /a//a /ai/, «'&lt;■. 1-r W. %s l 7* 7*7 7*i 7*7 7*7 7*7~ Lot 1, corn 223 140 77 1.22 3U8 2 {d°n&gt;dTw 5 o/o} 2" "5 82 1.30 306 U&gt;t3,wheat 229 147 82 1.30 308 lbs. 4.00 m oo 3.76 i 04 388 3.76 4 1? 3 K Is of In determining the cost of food per 100 poun </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 t&gt;iy 1,.1'j ts icith C'tittlc and Pigs. Had the wheat been purchased at fl.06 per 100 and the dried blood at |2.26 per 100, the cost of 100 pounds of gain made by Lots 2 and 3 would have been the same as in Lot 1 on corn at f 1.00 per 100. While the cost of 100 pounds gain on corn and alfalfa was lowest it will be noted that the net profits on both Lot II and III were greater than Lot I on corn. This seeming in - sistency is explained by the fact that the gains on w and also on dried blood and corn were much greater than on corn. This extra gain with an advance in price of f l.(Mi per 100 lbs. accounts for the greater profits on Lots II and the addition of five per cent dried blood to corn makes a on containing the same amount of digestible protein and same nutritive r;itii&gt; ;is the ration of wheat. It is that the gains on these two lots were the same. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE GOVERNING BOARD CCOT. or M »■,«......) GEO. F. KEKOWER,/V«/rf»/, Wisner E. v. FORELL, Kearney EDSON C. RICH, Omaha JOHN L. TEETERS, Lincoln CALKINS, Kearney ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS B BURNETT, B. Sc.. Director and Animal Husbandman LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist S. AVERY, Ph. D., Chemist tHAECKER, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman SNCE Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist Emerson. B. S. A., Horticulturist P. STOUT, C. E., Irrigation Engineer Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist BWiancko, B. S. A., Assistant Agriculturist . Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman GAIN, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist . Perin, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm NEBRASKA </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>