<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifty-Second Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska </title>
               <date value="18??">February 1, 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FIFTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT ..'¦¦ - " '¦: : :.' :: ' I'--' 1- of-the •.. ¦ .'¦;¦.¦ : v.¦;¦.-;•¦.;¦ Agricultural i Experiment Sixition ¦|". ;¦ ..oF: '¦¦'¦¦' Nebraska ¦•¦'.¦ ¦¦•¦.:;vj:¦'¦¦•.¦'" ¦¦i':.-- : ';.':.--.--l ¦¦¦. .'¦¦¦¦¦¦ *-• ' ¦- :¦¦¦: ¦'."':: --: ':' i ¦ .¦ ' ¦ ¦ ¦ i - ¦. ¦ . ¦ .. ¦ ¦: .: ¦ : . . ! . ¦ ¦¦.¦¦¦: .v;5.;.m-v¦¦¦¦¦•&gt;¦&gt; .'¦.-,; ' •;. ¦'. '¦' ¦¦.'¦¦¦:"¦'..'¦¦'.¦"¦ -; . '-:! .'..•- - : ¦ '". '-. ." - ... ... ¦ ¦. : ; :¦ -.¦"". .; ' ¦ ¦'¦¦''. I i-;. • •'"¦' ¦.;. Presented to Ac jGovcrnoc February 1, 1939 rr ¦¦¦ ¦'¦'.¦ '¦'¦¦¦ ¦]:¦¦"••¦•.¦ •¦ '¦¦'¦ ;V : : ' '; 1 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ¦ ¦¦: V.S. A. /".-.¦¦. ;"' </seg>
         <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska ! Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, R. L. Cochran, Governor oj Nebraska: Sir:—ln accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act oi the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Fifty-second Annual Report of the Agri - cultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. W. W. Burr, Director. February 1, 1939. * - I ! GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE j State of Nebraska, Executive Department Mr. W. W. Burr, Director. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: Sir:—l hereby acknowledge receipt of the Fifty-second Annual Report ] of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. ! R. L. Cochran, Governor. Lincoln, Nebraska, February 1, 1939. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) ' ; . Frank ]. Taylor, St. Paul.... ; Term expires January, 1939 Stanley D. Long, Grand Island, President. Term expires January, 1939 Marion A. Shaw, David City.... ... ............. .Term expires January, 1941 Chmu.es Y. Thompson, West Point .Term expires January, 1941 Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha. '. &#132;....".-.Term expires January, 1943 R. W. Devoe, Linc01n,........'. .Term expires January, 1943 C. S. Boucher, Ph.D., Chancellory ...-' '.-: • ¦¦. - L. E. Gunderson, 1 Finance Secretary - . . - '¦ THI STATION OFFICERS ! W. W. Burr, B.Sc., Director \ ''.-. W. H. Brokaw, Director o/ Extension Service ; : '¦ W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk. ' \ '¦' R. T. Prescott, A.M., Agricultural Editor THE TECHNICAL STAFF C. W. Ackerson, Ph.D., Associate Agricultural Chemist ¦'.:.', M. A. Alexander, M.Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman . i S. W. Alford, D.V,,5., Superintendent of Serum Plant Arthur Anderson,* Ph.D., Land Use Planning Specialist [ . Marvel L. Baker, M.Sc, Animal\Husbandman, North Plaite Substation R. E. Baker, M.Sc, Assistant in Horticulture I Arnold E. Baragar, M.Sc, Assistant Home Economist \ M. J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemist (Chairman). .. ! E. E. Brackett, B.Sc. in E.E., Agricultural Enp'nrer (Chairman) ¦¦ E. M. Broike, B.Sc, Superintendent, Valentine Substation M. P. Brunig, A.M., B.Sc. in A.E.,' Assistant. Agricultural Engineer y E. G. Conard," M.Sc, Junior Agronomist . . L. K. Crowe, M.Sc, Associate Dairy Husbandman R. L. Cushing,"Mjc* t Assistant Agronomist H. P. Davjs.M.Sc., Dairy Husbandman (Chairman) :W.E: Deacon, M.Sc, Assistant in Plant Pathology :; • P. A. Downs, Ph.D., Dairy Husbandman j F. L. Din-Ey,* Ph.D., Senior Soil Conservationist j . ; L. S. Evans* M.Sc, Junior Agronomist . ; J Margaret Fedde, A.M., Home Economist (Chairman) ¦.' H. C. Filley, Ph.D., Rural Economist (Chairman) ]. W. Frrrs, M.Sc, Assistant Agronomist ¦ . A. L. Frolik, Phi)., Associate Agronomist '¦"-, -. L. F.Garey, Ph.D., Rural Economist ! ; Samuel Garver, 3 B.Sc.i Associate 'Agronomist . [ R. W, Goss, Ph.D., Plant Pathologist (Chairman) ;' H. J. Gramlich* B.Sc, Animal Husbandman (Chairman) : Lionel Harris/ M.Sc, Junior Agronomist, Acting Supt., Scottsbtuff Substation, Mitchell I. L. Hathaway, M.Sc, Assistant Dairy Husbandman L. W. Hum-but, M.Sc, Assistant Agricultural Engineer James H. Jensen, Ph.D., Associate Plant Pathologist " ¦ F. D. KtlM; Ph.D., Agronomist (Chairman) T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomist : '... Eric Kneen, M.Sc, Assistant Agricultural Chemist and Assistant Plant Pathologist 'By an act of the Ltijillaturc of the [Sate of Ncbmlia, approved and in effect February 15, 1899, too State Trcaiurcr became ex affltia ciulodiin of the Experiment Station fund on and after Mr I, ' ISS9. ... ' ¦ ¦:-..••¦ .1 '¦¦'.' ¦ • ¦ •Detiiltd from V. S. D. A., Waihington, D. C. •On lave November 1, 1938. to September 1; »3». . .-¦ . ¦ . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Ruth Leverton, Ph.D., Assistant Home Economist W. J. Loeffel, M.Sc, Animal Husbandman (Acting Chairman) W. E. Lyness. M.Sc, Assistant Agronomic H. A. McComb, B.Sc, Horticulturist, North Platte Substation C. B. McGrath, B.Sc, D.V.M., Assistant Animal Pathologist R. A. Mapes, Manager, Union Fruit Farm, Union A. W. Meour, A.M., Associate Rural Economist Frank. Miller, M.A., Assistant Rural Economist R. F. Morgan, M.Sc., Assistant Dairy Husbandman F. E. Mussehl. B.Sc. Poultry Husbandman (Chairman) L. C. Newell, 1 M.Sc, Assistant Agronomist I F. Olney. D.V.M., M.S., Associate Animal Pathologist K. S. Quisenberry, 1 Ph.D., Agronomist E. L. Reichart. M.Sc, Associate Dairy Husbandman Cletus K. Rei.vmiller, 7 junior Animal Husbandman H. F. Rhoades, Ph.D., Assistant Agronomist Raymond Roberts, M.Sc, Associate Entomologist ]. C. Rvssel, M.Sc, Agronomist R. M. Sandstidt, M.Sc, Associate Agricultural Chemist George Schmid, B.Sc, Manager, Box Butte Experimental Farm, Alliance C. W. Smith, ME., Agricultural Engineer Edna B. Sxyder, M.Sc. Assistant Home Economist L. B. S.nydfr, Ph.D., Assistant Rural Economist Leland Stott. Ph.D., Associate Home Economist M. H. Swenk, A.M., Entomologist [Chairman) R. R. Thalmax, M.Sc. Associate Animal Husbandman G. W. Trimbercf.r. B.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry H. M. Tvsdal, = Ph.D., Associate Agronomist L. Van Es. M.1).. VS.. Animal Pathologist (Chairman) H. £. Weakly "" M.Sc. /unior Agronomist, North Platte Orrin ). Webstfii. B.Sc, Field Assistant in Agronomy, North Platte M. D. Wkldon. Ph.D., Associate Agronomist H. O. Werner, Ph.D.. Horticulturist D. B. Whelan, M.Sc. Assistant Entomologist C. C. Wiocans, Ph.D., Horticulturist (Chairman) F. D. Yung, M.Sc, Assistant Agricultural Engineer C. L. Zink, B.Sc, Tractor Test Engineer L. L. Zook. B.Sc. Agronomist and Jnfir. of Experimental Substation, North Platte CONTENTS Agricultural Engineering 5 Home Economics 43 Agricultural Chemistry 7 North Plane Substation 47 Insects, Rodrnu, and Birds . II ScottsblufT Substation 50 Soils 13 Valentine Substation 5] fie/t) Crops 19 |(ox Buttc Experiment Farm 52 Fruits and Vegetables . 30 State Serum Plant 53 Plant Diseases 32 Publications of the Calendar Year Animal Diseases 33 1938 54 Livestock Feeding 36 Financial Statement of Money Received Dairy Husbandry 37 from the United States Government. 56 Poultry Husbandry 39 Financial Statement Exclusive of Rural Economics 40 Federal Funds 59 Utilization of Land 43 3 Detailed from U. S. D. A. Wajhinpton. D. C. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">' Fifty-Seconfl Annual Report ..'.;. The general plan of the following report is similar to the reports pubi lished in recent years. Thi: contents are arranged according to subject matter with the exception that the reports of the experiments conducted at the substations are grouped separately toward the back. The purposes of the report are to present a brief summary of progress made during the year and to list the published matter. The report covers the calendar year 1938 so far as the experimental work is concerned; the financial report at the back covers the fiscal year which ended July 31, 1938. On the whole the year 1938 was favorable to crop production in Nebraska, and agriculture in the state has experienced some recovery even though crop production was below normal. A good deal of attention has been given to grain and forage sorghums during the year. The trend toward regional cooperative research work has continued. During the year a circular summarizing the achievement o£ the first 50 years was completed, and is now being published as Circular 60, "Fifty Years of Achievement in Agriculture Investigation." . ¦ . AGRICUI .TURAL ENGINEERING Tractor testing.—ln the 1938 season (March Ito November 30) 19 tractors were tested. New uel-economy records were established during the season on the Diesel ty| c and on engines burning 70-octane gasoline, third-grade gasoline, and distillate. Bulletin 321, Nebraska Tractor Tests&gt; 1920-1938, was published. By addressing the Tractor Testing Laboratory one 9m obtain mimeographed reports of the individual tests, which are issued soon after the tests are completed. The prices are 5 cents for a single report or a dollar for all tht: reports during one testing season. Use of electric power on Nebraska farms.—A motor overload signal which uses a small neon lamp as a visible indication that an-electric motor is drawing full-load current is being tried out under actual farm con - ditions. The signal was developed last year and after a few preliminary trials was installed on a three-horsepower portable motor which is to be used for various farm jobs.i The hearing of drinking water for hogs was continued during a 65-day period beginning December 30, 1937. Water temperatures were main - tained at approximately 40°, 55°, and 75° F., the same as for the previous year. Results were similar to those of the preceding season but not close enough to be conclusive. Tihe results of both seasons indicated that for hogs it is not practical to maintain drinking-water temperature higher than necessary to prevent freezing. Observations are to be continued. Tests were made during February and March, 1938, on two inexpensive home-made types of electric jheaters for livestock water tanks. Soil-heating cable was used for the heating elements in both types, which were designed to keep a drinking opening|free of ice. Under severe test conditions the l\ mimeographed report. ARticuUunil Enßtncerinc. ProßrtM Report No. 2. describing the unif, ran be obtained by addrcsiing the Department of Agricultural Engineering. College of Agriculture. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station C°"nT tiO fn °f thesC hCaterS 3VCraged leSS than two kilowatt-hours and the maximum was 20° F 2 ° I*P»nma,, o! Agnchunl S,A^nn ( . °"X ""' ""» *« ¦*"'»"&gt; b/ </seg>
         <seg id="p007">I . Fifty-second Annual Report i ¦ ¦.•¦¦. . ¦ ¦ ¦ &lt; ¦ ¦ ¦¦ ¦ ' ¦ - ¦ ¦ . ¦ ¦ : ¦ season in the same house and handled in the same manner as in the pre - j ceding year to serve as a che:k for determining the effect o£ seasonal differ - s ences on energy consumption. The first six-weeks period of the 1938 sea - son averaged .s*. F. warmer than the same period in 1937 and energy consumption was 13.4 kilowatt-hours less. Briefly summarized, the results of the 1938 season seem to indicate that with a small ventilating fan the relative humidity can be kept definitely lower than in an unventilated brooder but at an added cost and with no apparent benefits. Indications also seem to point to an advantage in the use o£.bright aluminum paint to retard the flow of. heat worn within the brooder but the data are too meager to be conclusive. 3- | Methods and equipment for curing and preserving perishable farm pro - ducts under controlled temperature and humidity adaptable to use on the farm.—The first studies arej now in progress. Freshly laid eggs are kept under controlled conditions lof humidity and temperature, for periods of various lengths. Not enough data have been secured on which to base definite conclusions but indications are that fresh eggs may be kept in a desirable condition for marketing over a period of two weeks or more, provided the storage temperature is below 65° F. and relative humidity above 65 per cent. The work with eggs is to-be continued and plans are made to extend observations to dressed poultry and highly perishable fruits and vegetables for short carry-over periods, and for curing cheese. AGRICULTURAL CHEMISTRY Preparation and study of the cereal glutelins.^— Special attention has been directed toward studies of the nature and the measurement of the breakdown of the gluten proteins by the proteases naturally and normally present in wheat flour. Th:se studies are considered necessary for two reasons: (1) There is strong possibility that the gluten proteins undergo some proteolytic degradation during the processes involved in their prep - aration and isolation, and this constitutes a serious handicap in efforts that are being made toward the establishment of the true identities and individualities of the proteins themselves. (2) The flour proteases are gen - erally believed to have an important bearing upon flour baking properties and baking performance. . ; The studies thus far have disclosed considerable information as to the . nature, activity, and stability of flour protease as affected by various dis - persing agents, acidities, salts, preservatives, oxidizing and reducing agents, etc. The information thus obtained is being usefully applied in the establishing of suitable specifications for methods that will be trust - worthy and informative. A detailed report is in process of preparation. Enzymes of wheat flour as related to flour grade and baking character - istics.—Further studies of starch-amylase phenomena in cereals have been carried out. It is now possible not only to present a fairly complete ex- a A mimeographed progress report (A.E. No. I) is.available from the Department of Agricultural Engineering. i "..:: . .. .-.''. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station planation of the diastatic properties and behavior of flour, barley, and malt, but also to account for the wide variations among different flours with reference to these properties, thereby affording an improved basis for the technological control of diastatic properties in flour and bread produc - tion. A comprehensive repon, bringing together the various individual phases of these flour amylase studies, has been prepared and published. A new and improved method for the quantitative estimation of alpha - amylase {dextrinogenic amylase) involving a modification of the Wohlge - muth iodine method has been developed and a description of it •will soon be prepared for publication. Some progress has been made in the development of simpler and more convenient procedures for the quantitative estimation of starch and sugars, respectively. A paper on the significance of maltose fermentation "acti - vaiors" in baking has been published. A list of articles published during the year (1938) follows: "A Short Gassing Power Method," by R. M. Sandstedt, Cereal Chem. 15: 114-16; "The Cereal Amylases with Reference to Flour and Malt Behavior," by M. J. Blish, R. M. Sandstedt, and Eric Kneen, Cereal Chem. 15: 629-37; "Maltose Fermentation Activators as Affecting Baking," by R. M. Sandstedt and M. /. Blish, Cereal Chem. 15: 788-94; "The Rapid Determination of Moisture," by R. M. Sandstedt, Cereal Chem. Id: 813-15; "The Relation of Alpha- and Beta-Amylases V the Evaluation of Malts in Flour Technology," by R. M. Sandstedt Cereal Chem. 15: 832-35. j . Physico-chemical studies on the nature of cold resistance in crop plants. —The influence of nutrients on hardening and cold resistance has been studied as one phase of this project. Previous results were verified as re - gards the beneficial effects of high phosphate, or low nitrogen, or of low magnesium sulfate in stimulating the development of cold resistance in winter wheat, and likewise the detrimental effects of low phosphate, high nitrogen, or high magnesium sulfate. Feeding of sugar produces positive "artificial hardening" in winter wheat, spring wheat, and winter barley. The influence of carbohydrate storage and reserves on hardening and cold resistance is another phase. Methods of analysis have been further refined and applied to a considerable amount of material. With plants subjected to differential nutrition no correlation was found between sugar content and induced difference in ability to develop cold resistance except in the case of "artificial hardening" by sugar feeding. '.¦ ' Continued studies of controlled greenhouse low-temperature harden - ing with winter and spring wheat and winter barley emphasize the im - portance of sugar storage in the hardening process. While light intensity during low-temperature hardening is highly significant, the length of day appears to have little significance. Hardening is induced by low tempera - tures under long as well as under short day conditions. Last year six varieties of winter wheat were arranged in order of their field-exhibited winterhardiness on the basis of their ability to accumu- </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Fifty-second Annual Report ¦ ¦-... . .. ¦¦-.¦- -, , . ¦ ¦ -. . late sugar under controlled low-temperature hardening and retain this sugar against dehardening influences. At the present time this same tech - nique is being applied to thirty varieties of winter wheat in order to have data, that may be treated statistically. ¦'¦/" . Another aim has been a 1 determination of the influence of enzymatic action on food reserves in relation to hardening and cold resistance. Fundamental studies have been made on the nature and mode of action of enzymes involved in the hydrolysis of carbohydrates. Preliminary investigations of the cold resistance of unhardened plants indicate that varietal differences exist in potato plants and that such dif - ferences may be measured by controlled freezing technique. These differ - ences have no apparent relationship to sugar content of the plant. Varietal differences exist in unhardened winter-wheat seedlings,, such differences not being related to the varietal orientation in the "cold-hard - ened" condition. Here again no relationship is evident between sugar con - tent and exhibited cold resisl ance. Freezing experiments are being conducted with nursery transplant stock. Preliminary experiments indicate that light freezes may do little or no damage even to the tender varieties when the plants have had an opportunity to "harden off" previous to freezing. " ' -. The same 30 varieties of winter wheat that were studied in 1937 were again included. The object was to; compare controlled freezing survival data with survival data from the field. The data from the controlled tests of 1938 compared very well with the 1937 data, the correlation for survival being +.9298. When the tw &gt;-year average survivals from controlled freez - ing were compared with fiell data a correlation of +.8095 was obtained. This value would indicate that the controlled test is a very accurate and usable measure of cold resistance of winter wheats. The results of a study or the eSect of defoliation on hardiness were not as satisfactory as last year! but in general showed that there was a close relationship between the amount of defoliation and the reduction in cold resistance. This study is important from the standpoint of pasturing winter wheat. •." '.¦¦'¦".' \)....- .'¦'.'¦.-¦', . '. '. A large number of hybrid strains were subjected to freezing in order to select the more hardy plants. The surviving plants were matured in the greenhouse. Most of the lines frozen were from crosses of Hope x Cheyenne and Hope x Turkey 1069. All field-hardened material showed yellowing and hence no differences were obtained in this respect. However, nitrogen deficiency produced a very positive increase in winterhardiness,this effect being minimized by the addition or (NH 4 ) 2 SO 4 ertilizer to the deficient soil. All field-hardened materiil for the study of bunt.infection as related to winterhardiness was ruined by a sudden early freeze. Greenhouse - hardened material indicated that bunt-infected plants were less hardy, confirming the data obtained in 1937. This was especially true of plants hardened under continuous ow temperatures. With these plants a fair </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station correlation between sugar content and cold resistance was exhibited. With plants hardened under alternating temperatures results were less positive. Again it was impossible to get a measure on the amount of bunt infection. Comparative efficiency of various proteins in poultry feeding.— Contin- ! umg this series of studies with growing chicks, a comparison of cotton- ; seed and linseed meals in chick rations was made. In one lot the concen - trate portion of the ration was made up of five parts each of meat meal, fish i meal, and cottonseed meal, and in the other linseed oil meal was sub - stituted for the cottonseed meal It was found that the chicks of the lot ', fed the ration containing cottonseed meal made slightly better gains per unit of feed and nitrogen fed than did those fed linseed oil meal, and that the retention of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus was slightly higher in the case of the former. It was concluded that, with the base used, cottonseed meal is somewhat more efficient as a supplement to meat meal and fish meal than linseed oil meal. i In two series of feeding trials with growing chicks comparisons were made on the utilization of nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorus at two levels of protein intake. Feeding trials were carried out at jevels of 16 and 22 per cent of protein secured in one series by diluting a 22 per cent protein ration with starch, and in the other by varying the proportions of base and concentrate. In both instances the chicks fed the rations containing 22 per cent of protein made greater gains on the same dry-matter intake over the same period of time, than chicks fed the 16 per cent ration, but the ratio of gain in weight to nitrogen fed was greater in the chicks fed the lower protein ration. Differences in the retentions of calcium and phos - phorus were not considered significant. The feeding of a complete ration which had been diluted with starch to decrease its protein content from 22 to 16 per cent resulted in uniform and definite evidence of depraved appetite including feather pulling and coprophagy. In a recent feeding trial ground yellow corn and ground kalo were com - pared in rations for growing chicks. As the kalo was higher in protein it was diluted with starch to bring it to the same level as the corn. This modi- [ Tied 32 parts of kalo and 32 parts of yellow corn were each mixed with 68 parts of a mixture made up of shorts 20, bran 10, oats 10, alfalfa meal 10, meat meal 5, fish meal i, dried buttermilk 5, calcium carbonate 2, and ¦ sodium chloride 1. The food intake was controlled so that each chick of each lot fed the two rations consumed equal amounts of feed. Differences in growth secured on the two rations by the chicks of the two lots were not significant. Data on the retention of nitrogen show no significant differences while data on the calcium and phosphorus retentions are not available, ft was noted that the chicks of the lot fed the ration contain- ' ing the kalo exhibited marked cannibalistic tendencies while no instances were observed in the lot fed the corn ration. One research bulletin was published during the year: The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chickj—V, A Comparison of Cottonseed Meal and Linseed Oil Meal as Portions of the Protein Concentrate, by C. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">. ¦ Fifty-second Annual Report W. Ackersori, "M. J. Blish, and F. E. Mussehl, Nebr. Agrl. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 108, 8 pages, June, 1938. INSECTS, RODENTS, AND BIRDS Control of rodents and {other injurious mammals.—This study of the classification, distribution, habits, and economic status of the mammals of Nebraska was continued'during 1938, and further progress was made on the proposed memoir on the mammals of Nebraska. A report on one phase of this project, involving.the woodchuck or "ground hog" and en - titled "Distribution of Marmota monax in the Missouri Valley Region," by M. H. Swenk, was published in the August, 1938, issue of the Journal of Mammalogy. A series of similar preliminary reports is planned for publication prior to the appearance of the monograph above referred to, one of which will deal with the prairie dog and another with/ground squirrels. : ¦ [: . ¦ : ' Control of major field crop and other injurious insect pests. —The 1938 season was characterized by] low population of both the chinch bug and the Hessian fly. A cursory survey of the chinch-bug population in south - eastern Nebraska in the fall!of 1937 indicated little probability of chinch - bug damage in 1938, and no such damage subsequently occurred. t As in previous years, in 1938 a survey was made in June, in cooperation with the Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, to determine the Hessian fly population of southern and southeastern Nebraska, with jthe result that, as in 1936 and 1937, this was found to be at an extremely low level. No Hessian fly trouble of con - sequence was found in the winter wheat crop sown in the fall of 1937, either that fall or in the spring of 1938. Because of the low Hessian fly population, no studies of this insect-Were made in 1938, as was true also during each of the preceding five seasons. . The extreme damage to. fruit, shade, and ornamental trees over; the entire state during 1936 and 1937 by the flat-headed apple-tree borer abated decidedly during the 1938 season, and no further experiments were conducted on the control of this pest. A report on a study of the 1937 infestation in Nebraska was made by N. D. Wygant of the Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine in the Journal of Forestry for October, 1938, under the title "The Relation of Insects to Shelterbelt Plantations in the Great Plains." ¦ .-,•:' ¦ Distribution, life history, and means of control of the common Nebraska cutworms. —Investigations were continued on the life histories, food habits, and distribution of the different kinds of injurious cutworms found in the state; Notes were made on a number of different species, and in a number of cases parasites were collected. During the year the insectary procedure in cutworm rearing was improved by the addition of two pieces of equip - ment. One was a cabinet holding a number of metal trays designed to hold the small cutworm-rearing cages. This cabinet helped to shade the individual cages from the sun and to keep the table tops free for </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station other work. The other was a bait trap useful in capturing live moths I i for the purpose of studying the earlier stages of development. From the i j data accumulated it now seems possible, in some cases, to predict coming ' outbreaks of cutworms and army worms by our accumulated knowledge .1 of their life histories and by correlating the current abundance of the moths I ! at the Jight and bait traps with the records of previous seasons. I : Grasshopper control.—Considerable time was devoted during the winter •. of 1937-38 and the spring and summer of 1938 to greenhouse and field j studies designed to determine whether castor bean plants (Ricittus sp.) ; had any relation to grasshopper control. These studies were instigated by (¦¦;• a considerable amount of newspaper publicity in which allegations of a i valuable relation of this sort were indicated. The greenhouse tests, con- •.] ducted during the winter and early spring, showed that while grasshoppers j of different species fed upon castor bean leaves, such feeding was not fatal j to them, though they did not prefer this food plant nor develop well ; j upon it. During the growing season six varieties of castor bean plants • ' were planted, and observations were made as to any insecticidal value i against grasshoppers or any protection of crops from grasshoppers by !. border or strip planting of castor beans. Grasshoppers were observed feed- j ing freely upon the field plantings, but no significant kill was noted. One j early variety of castor bean had been entirely stripped of its leaves by &gt; midsummer, there being sometimes as many as fifteen grasshoppers on a. !. single leaf. At first the grasshoppers seemed to select and congregate upon ; certain individual castor bean plants in the mass planting to do their feed- • ing, but by fall the entire planting had all of the leaves quite well riddled \ by the grasshopper attacks. While the grasshoppers seemed to prefer castor bean leaves to tomato leaves, for example, no important protection of any crop by castor been plantings was demonstrated. The 1937 experiments on different materials and combination of materials, including ground cornstalks and corncobs, as bases for grass - hopper baits, as reported in Station Bulletin 312, were continued on a more extended scale in 1938. Those materials which showed the least i promise in 1937 were eliminated, and other materials, chiefly alfalfa meal, \ were substituted. Tests were also made with other attrahents to replace i amyl acetate, and some interesting results were obtained. Since sodium ; j arscnite was the poison used exclusively where federal aid in grasshopper ¦ i control was received by farmers, the 1938 experiments included tests .'.'¦¦ t of this poison also. The 1938 experiments involved the distribution of i baits on 90 half-acre plots; it is intended to re-check the results of the 1938 I experiments during the summer of 1939, on a more restricted scale. ] A brood study of the codling moth in southeastern Nebraska. —The . j active accumulation of data under this project, which is designed to deter- I mine the effect of varying seasonal weather conditions upon the number ;..j of generations, and the period of development of the broods of eggs, larvae, i | pupae, and moths of each of these generations, was completed in 1937, j f the tendi and concluding year of the project as it originally was planned. &gt; </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Fcftv-secono Annual Report The data secured have been highly voluminous, and much effort has been devoted in 1938 on the tabulation, condensation, and analyzing of these data. A comprehensive memoir entitled "The Life History of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Nebraska, with Special Reference to the Influence of Weather Conditions on Winter Survival, Brood Development, and Population Fluctuation," giving the complete results of this decade of work on this problem, is in process of preparation. This study will serve as a scientific basis for recommendations for timing spray applications in codling-moth control, in relation to varying seasonal meteorological con - ditions, and is expected to be of much practical value to the apple growers of southeastern Nebraska. ¦.".'. Principal biologic factors determining the population level of the upland game birds of Nebraska.— The game birds included in this study are the bob-white quail, greater and lesser prairie chickens, sharp-tailed grouse, and ring-necked pheasant. A report entitled "Late Autumn Food of the Sharp-Tailed Grouse in Western Nebraska," by M. H. Swenk, was pub - lished in the October, 1938, number of the Journal of Wildlife Manage - ment. The object is to secure information on the distribution, food supply, external and internal parasites, natural enemies, and ecological relation - ships of the more important upland game birds of Nebraska. A report on the bob-white quail is in preparation. This project is cooperative with the Nebraska Game, Forestation, and Parks Commission. . V Studies of insects attracted to light traps.—The light trap at Lincoln used in a study of the nocturnal activity of the adult stage of cutworm moths, other moths, and beetles that are attracted to lights, was started in 1938 on April 18, and, except for the month from July 29 to August 29, was operated continuously until October 31, No similar light trap was maintained at Mitchell in western Nebraska, as in previous seasons. The object of this study is to accumulate data on the geographic distribution and seasonal activity of the principal economic species of moths and beetles, and to test out the value of such records in predicting impending outbreaks of insect pests, such as various species of cutworms, armyworms and web worms, leaf beetles; and of beetle larvae such as white grubs, wireworms, and rootworms. f- The work in 1938 yielded some important data. In accordance with a cooperative agreement with the field laboratory of the Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine located at Manhattan, Kansas, where parallel studies are being conducted, a summary of the cutworm and related moths caught at the Nebraska and Kansas light traps is being prepared for publication. Other insect groups will be reported upon as time and material permit. Eventually a summary study of the relation of the flight of these insects to varying weather conditions is to be made and published. 1 .;¦¦¦¦;¦,;. ... \ ;.- ¦•¦;•¦¦ ;., ' ; SOILS '¦/¦¦'.., ¦ " ¦', Vfy-. v .•¦ Soil organic matter.— A \ study pi three analytical methods for the estimation of soil organic matter has been made. The wet-combustion, </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultvsm. Experiment Station hydrogen-peroxide, and chromic-acid-titration methods were used on 162 samples from prairie, black grassland, dark-brown grassland, gray-brown forest, and immature calcareous soils. The soils were grouped according to origin, and correlation coefficients were computed on each group for data secured by the different methods. It was concluded that when it is necessary to have an absolute measure of organic matter, the hydrogen - peroxide method is preferable. If a quantitative determination of organic carbon is desired, wet combustion is suitable. The chromic-acid-titration method of Schollenberger was found to give results closely correlated with those from the hydrogen-peroxide method. Although it is less precise than the other two methods studied, it has advantages of being simple in man - ipulation, rapid, inexpensive, and applicable to calcareous and manean - uerous soils. Commercial fertilizers, manure, and lime.—Analytical work has been continued on the soil samples from the fertility plots at Lincoln. The application of 48 tons of manure per acre in the course of 16 years has scarcely maintained the nitrogen content of the soil. Where no manure has been applied, the nitrogen content was significantly lower after 16 years than at the beginning of the period. Applications of sodium nitrate, superphosphate, and potassium chloride, either singly or in various com - binations, failed to produce any significant change in soil nitrogen. The soil of the manured plots was found to have a higher base ex - change capacity, higher exchangeable divalent base content, and lower exchangeable hydrogen content than that of the untreated plots. Potassium chloride and sodium nitrate lowered the exchangeable hydrogen and in-, creased the exchangeable monovalent bases but slightly. Superphosphate used at the rate of 16 pounds of phosphorus pentoxide per acre annually had no significant effect on the base exchange properties of the soil. Preliminary tests indicate that the soluble potassium in the manured plots is more than twice that in the unmanured, and is somewhat greater than in the plots receiving potassium chloride at the rate of 16 pounds of potash per acre annually. Cooperative field-plot tests of treble superphosphate on wheat and barley in eight counties in southeastern Nebraska showed the Mowing results. In more than half of the tests on wheat the phosphate increased the yield 3.8 to 8.5 bushels per acre, while the remaining tests showed no significant effect. In four of the six tests on barley, the phosphate in - creased the yield 6.8 to 21.8 bushels per acre. On the basis of these results, the tests are being made somewhat more extensive. In addition several cooperative field-plot tests of lime and superphosphate on new seedings of alfalfa have been established. A study was made of the soil from the fertility plots at Lincoln to determine the influence of manure applications on certain physical prop - erties. The same physical properties were determined for an adjacent area of native grassland to determine the influence of more than 50 years of cropping. A paper was presented at the Soil Science Society of </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Fifty-second Annual Report America in 1938 by bVr. Bertramson and H. F. Rhoades on "The Effects of Cropping and Manure Applications on Some Physical Properties of a Heavy Soil in Eastern Nebraska." The results may be summarized as follows: :•.' ' • . The addition of manure has had no appreciable effect on the con - sistency constants, the moisture contents, the volume weight, or the. aggre - gation. , '•• i For the first six-inch depth, the values for the uncultivated soil ex - ceeded the average values for the cropped soil as follows: (a) the upper plastic limit, 9.8 per cent; (b) the lower plastic limit, 6.9 per cent; (c) the scouring point, 7.4 per [cent; (d) the hygroscopic coefficient, 1.2 per cent; (c) the moisture equivalent, 63 per cent; and (f) the maximum water, capacity, 16.2 per cent. . . •' The average "state of aggregation" for the cultivated soil was 73 per cent of that for the uncultivated soil. The great difference was in the aggregates larger than 0.5 mm. The cultivated soil had only 12.8 per cent as many aggregates larger than 0.5 mm. as were found for the uncultivated soil. Air drying the soil gready decreased the size of the aggregates. Exchange capacity, excha igeable calcium, exchangeable magnesium, ex - changeable monovalent ions, and readily oxidizable organic-matter determ - inations were made on the soil samples taken in 1935 from the rotation plots of Field K. at the Scot isbluff Substation. The results indicate effects of cropping and of manure applications on these properties. Manure in - creased the exchange capaciy and the readily oxidizable organic matter. The soils from the plots growing potatoes and sugar beets continuously were considerably lower injexchange capacity and readily oxidizable or - ganic matter than the soils from the plots growing wheat and oats con - tinuously. In general, the soils from the plots growing alfalfa in a rotation were somewhat higher in exchange capacity and readily oxidizable organic matter than those soils from plots growing no alfalfa or receiving no manure applications. I . ¦ Revegetatioh of abandoned land.—ln connection with a study of the succession of vegetation on abandoned land in Kimball County, made in cooperation with the Division of Conservation and Survey of the Univer - sity of Nebraska, a study of the changes in the soil after abandonment was made. Determinations tyere made of the rate of infiltration of water, volume weight, state of aggregation, and the quantity of plant roots, or - ganic matter, and nitrogen in the soil. . The rate of infiltration of water was considerably greater under wheat stubble than under native vegetation. It was relatively low after one year of abandonment, but after several years became approximately equal to that of stubble land. Bare areas in the abandoned land generally had a low infiltration rate. The volume weight and state of aggregation of the soils were closely related. The volume weight and the percentage of aggregates larger than </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 0.5 mm. in diameter were highest in the soils of lowest infiltration rate and were generally lowest in the soils permitting the fastest infiltration The root content of the soil of the cultivated fields, determined shortly after wheat harvest, was found to be one-fourth to one-third of that under native grassland vegetation. After several years of abandonment, the root content of the soil was greater than in cultivated fields, and was approxi - mately half of that under native grasses. The organic matter and nitrogen content of the soil of cultivated and abandoned fields tended to be lower than in the native grasslands, but the difference was not great enough to be statistically significant for the num - ber of samples taken. Under the native grasses 7.3 per cent of the organic matter in the sur - face six inches of soil and 2.2 per cent of that in the second six inches was found to consist of plant roots. Studies on the solubility of soil phosphorus.—Soil samples have been taken trom the fields in which the cooperative tests of superphosphate were located, and soluble phosphate determined by leaching with a buffer solu - tion at pH 5.0. Soils on which crops respond to phosphate are generally low m soluble phosphate, while those on which no crop response is obtained are usually very high in soluble phosphate. A study was made of the soils from the fertility plots at Lincoln to ascertain the influence of manure and phosphate fertilization on the soluble phosphorus content of the soil. Soluble phosphorus was deter - mined by leaching the soil with 2,000 cc. of a solution of 0.04N botic and acetic acids with sufficient sodium hydroxide to give a pH of 5 0 The percolates were obtained in two 250&lt;c, one 500-cc, and one l,ooo&lt;c' portions and analyzed separately. In comparison with the untreated soils there was twice as much phosphorus removed from the soils receiving 48 ions of manure during 16 years, approximately four times as much removed from the soils receiving 72 tons of manure, and six times as much from the soils receiving 8 tons of lime in addition to 48 tons of manure during the 16-year period. In comparison with the untreated soils, there was about one-third more phosphorus removed from the soils receiving 16 pounds of phosphorus pentoxide per year, twice as much from the soils receiving annual application of 32 pounds of phosphorus pentoxide per acre, and five times as much from the soils receiving annual applications of 64 pounds of phosphorus pentoxide per acre. Factors affecting permeability of soils to water.—During 1938 further studies were made on the permeability and tilth of alkali claypan soils Work was continued on two series of enclosed 4'x4' plots to ascertain the influence of different rates of application of calcium chloride, sulfur and gypsum on the permeability of these soils to water. The results in - dicate that at first calcium chloride gives the best results but after a few months sulfur is superior to calcium chloride and gypsum for use in cal - careous slick spots. Alfalfa had been planted in one-third of the triplicate </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Fifty-second Annual Report. treatments in 1937. In 1931 alfalfa was planted in a second one-third of the triplicate treatments and replanted in the untreated plots which had been seeded in 1937. Good jstands of alfalfa were obtained in most of the treated plots but none was obtained on the check plots. The special subsoiler used to channel the soil between the rows of sugar beets in 1936 and 193/ was again slightly modified for use in 1938. It was used on five fields lust before the first irrigation. Three of the fields were very dry and the subsoiler did not work as satisfactorily as in the other fields. The use of the.subsoiler increased the yield of beets on all five fields, the average increase being 1.58 tons per acre. ¦ ¦ : Further studies were made on mechanical analysis, maximum water capacity, exchangeable base content, and calcium carbonate content of three depths of several of the slick spots and normal areas. Carbonate-free day and pH were also determined. Most of the: soils were high in calcium carbonate and sand and relatively low in carbonate-free clay and silt. There were no consistent differences found in the clay or calcium-car - bonate content between slick spots and normal soils. All of the samples from the slick spots had a higher percentage of saturation with monovalent ions than corresponding depths of normal soils. However, some of the layers from thenormal soils contained considerable exchangeable monovalent ions. Slick spots vary so much in their ability to support plant growth and in other characteristics that it i; difficult to designate any one factor as being responsible for their poor conditions, but observations of physical and other characteristics in both field and laboratory make it logical to assume that exchangeable sodium is largely responsible. Large amounts of calcium carbonate in the presence of Considerable exchangeable sodium apparently aggravate the unfavorable cc nditions for plant growth. A close correlation was round between the pH of the slick spots and normal soils and their respective percentages of monovalent jons and cal - cium carbonate. : • ; Relationships between slope, depth of topsail, and productivity. — Further studies were made to obtain information on the relationship be - tween the degree of slope of the land, the depth of topsoil, and the yield of wheat. Approximately 20 samples were collected from each of twelve counties in the eastern part:of Nebraska. The samples were divided into two groups; one group consisted of samples taken on soils derived from glacial material and the other group was the samples taken on soils derived from loessial material. Differences in slope did not have any appreciable effect upon the [yield of wheat on any of the soils. A very significant decrease in yield was shown; on soils derived from glacial material which were shallow in comparison to the deeper soil. This was found on both the level upland and the undulating soil. The depth of top - .soil was not nearly so significant in soils derived from loessial material. No difference was found in yields on the level upland between shallow and deep soils. A slight difference in favor of the deeper soil was found on the undulating land. This work has not progressed long enough and </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska, Agricultural Experiment Station is not extensive enough to justify the drawing of any definite conclusions. Soil erosion control and soil moisture conservation. —This work is in cooperation with the Division of Research, Soil Conservation Service, U. S. Department of Agriculture. During the year 1938 a new series of studies was started dealing with the control of soil erosion and with methods of making more efficient use of the rainfall.^ A series of seven plots was started in the spring of 1938 to compare the relative effectiveness of different methods of soil treatment in conserving water on uncropped land. The results of this first season's work show that those' methods which tend to reduce the amount of evaporation from the soil and which also permit little run-off are the most efficient in saving water. Another series of plots which are designed to study the effect of. mois - ture-conservation methods throughout a whole cropping system was started in August. The object in this first test was to measure the effect on mois - ture conservation of different methods of preparing small-grain land for fall wheat. Where the straw was removed and the land plowed, only 22.4 per cent of the August and September rainfall was stored and this in the upper two feet only. Where the straw was plowed under, 38 per cent of the rainfall was saved. Where the straw was left on the land and one-way disked in, or cultivated beneath the surface with a new-type, broad, flat duckfoot, 49.9 and 48.6 per cent respectively of the rainfall was conserved and this penetrated into the fourth foot. The moisture saved by the use of the basin lister was intermediate between the plowed land and that having the straw left on the surface. Another phase of this investigation has been the determination of the effect of different factors on the rate at which rainfall water enters the soil. These studies have been conducted by the mechanical sprinkling of water on plots 1/200 acre in area and measuring the amount of runoff. On cultivated land no great differences in the rate of intake of water were found for the different soils tested. When some surface cover was on the soil, such as a growing crop like grass, or when the surface was covered with debris like stubble and straw, the rate at which water enters the ground was greatly increased and the runoff decreased. Apparently the surface condition has a much greater effect on infiltration than does the type of soil. Nebraska soils, even though they may have heavy subsoils, seem to be able to absorb large amounts of water provided the surface is protected from scaling over during rains. After the point of runoff is reached, the rate at which the rain falls apparently does not greatly affect the rate of intake into the soil. From these studies it would appear that if the so\\ can be protected by some organic matter in the form of crop residues or other debris when it is not protected by a growing crop, the amount of water absorbed by the soil may be increased and less may be lost by surface evaporation. At the same time water erosion would be decreased and soil blowing greatly reduced. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Fifty second Annual Report Special laboratory and field work is being carried out to determine the importance of various phys cal factors influencing the rate of evaporation and infiltration. The results of these studies should help to explain the re - sults obtained on the field plots and serve as the basis for additional field tests on practical methods of increasing the efficiency of the rainfall. Certain phases of the field work are being extended to include the North Platte Substation. .¦'.':, ..' ;.' Experiments to determine the effect of different soil conservation prac - tices and various cropping systems on the rate and amount of runoff and erosion from field-size areas are being established in Webster county. FIELD CROPS Corn improvement.— Be&lt; ause of recent failures of corn on the Experi - ment Station farm at Linco n as a result of drouth, an important part of the experimental hybrid coin testing was removed to Burt and Nemaha counties this past season. /While all of the tests at Lincoln failed through drouth and grasshoppers, ihese tests provided satisfactory data. Pour official state corn variety am 1 hybrid yield tests in cooperation with Agri - cultural Extension also materialized satisfactorily in four eastern-Nebraska localities. Under irrigation, very good progress was made with the breed - ing program at Lincoln. '}•: . In the station test in Bu;t county, a collection of 16 Nebraska Experi - ment Station experimental d juble-cross hybrids and 66 commercial double - cross hybrids from various sources in the Corn Belt gave an average grain yield of 44.9 bushels compared with 30.0 bushels as an average for six standard, open-pollinated, eastern-Nebraska varieties. This is a 50 per cent increase. Compared with the varieties, the hybrids had the advantage of averaging fewer plants that were lodged, smutted, barren, or suckering. Their mean height, time of ripening, and shelling percentage were almost identical with those of the varieties. The range in. yield among the hybrids was from 23.5 to 56.5 bushels, which emphasizes the need by farmers for careful choice of hybrids; Eight experimental hybrids developed by the Nebraska Station fell among the top 15 hybrids, which is suggestive of definite progress. Very favorable results were obtained from many of the commercial hybrids developed in other states, which again indicates that Nebraska growers may benefit directly from the corn-breeding work done by public and private corn breeders elsewhere. The origin of hybrid corn is not necessarily a limiting factor in its adaptation, but the local suitability of any specific hybrid needs to be established by local or regional tests and preferably during a period of several years. The corn-improvement program was further aided by the testing in Burt county of 144 additional Nebraska experimental double-cross hybrids and 40 single crosses. A top - cross test in cooperation with'the |U. S. Department of Agriculture, planted for the evaluation of new Corn Belt inbred lines, also materialized satis - factorily. \ . ¦...' .'¦ .[ ¦ ; ¦'¦¦¦ . ;¦' ¦ .¦"¦'¦¦¦•¦/:¦'' ., '¦ .-.¦". </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station For the Station test located on subirrigated bottom land in southeastern Nebraska near Peru, a special effort was made to include a number of, large and late-maturing hybrids which might have special suitability for such favorable conditions. Ai an outcome the eight highest-yielding of die 22 hybrids averaged 92 bushels per acre and varied from 18 to 24 per cent higher in yield than the four varieties. Of these eight hybrids, six were developed by private hybrid corn companies, while the first and fourth in yield were produced by the U. S. Department of Agriculture and the Illinois Agricultural Experiment Station, respectively. In the four official state yield tests located in Wayne, Dodge, Saline, and Richardson counties, with approximately 50 entries in each, the hybrids averaged respectively 17, 14, 29, and 6 per cent higher grain yield than the varieties. This is an average of 15 per cent superiority. As an average for six years, the four hybrids that are state-certified in Nebraska have averaged 17 per cent higher yield than standard open-pollinated corn. Some headway was made toward the development and testing of early - maturing hybrids suitable for western-Nebraska upland. The Box Butte Experimental Farm is especially useful in making these tests. In five of the outlying test fields in eastern Nebraska, the corn was grown at the rate of 2 plants per hill in three of the replications and 3 per hill in the other three replications. Grouping the fields according to yield, it is found that the three lowest averaged 36.2 bushels per acre for the 2-plant stand and 34.0 bushtls for 3 plants. In the two fields that were most productive, largely because of more favorable moisture conditions, the 2-plant rate averaged 70 bushels compared with 86 bushels for the 3-plant rate. This further substantiates the opinion that stands of corn should be adjusted to the tavorableness of moisture conditions. In the controlled breeding program 176 of the most promising inbred lines were advanced by an additional year of self-fertilization. Many of these were combined to make 210 single crosses to be tested in 1939. Seed of 220 double crosses was also obtained for testing in 1939 as possibilities for commercial production. in tests concerning the artificial drying of seed corn with heated air under forced draft, no injury to the seed viability was experienced at a lemperature range between 107° and 112° F., when the initfal moisture content of the corn was under 38 per cent. But when the moisture approached 50 per cent, drying at 112° F. proved somewhat harmful, while even 107° F. lowered the percentage and vigor of germination when the moisture content was as high as 55 per cent. A temperature range of 107° to 110° F. is thus satisfactory when the moisture content does not exceed 40 per cent. The artificial drying of seed corn is a growing practice among hybrid seed-corn producers. It can be recommended as a precautionary practice to avoid freezing injury in the fall and to expedite early processing of the seed. Publications: T. A. Kiesselbach, "Production of Foundation Seed for Hybrid Corn," Nebr. Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 29: 73-83; T. A. </seg>
         <seg id="p021">Fifty-second Annual Report Kiesselbach, V. H. Welch, D. L. Gross, and E. F. Frolik, "Report of the Nebraska 1938 Corn Variety and Hybrid Tests," Nebr. Agr. Ext. Cue. 115 (mimeographed); V. H. Welch, "The Results of the 1937 Corn Hy - brid and Variety Tests," Nebr. Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 29: 67-73; and "Corn Hybrid and Variety Tests," Nebr. Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 30: (in press). j' ¦¦" ; • ¦ Winter wheat—Becausej of the lack of soil moisture it was impossible to seed at the optimum time in the fall of 1937. As a result the wheat plots and nursery went into the winter in poor condition. Some winter - killing occurred but: a warm, moist spring encouraged heavy tillering and straw growth. Two cold waves of early April and early May checked growth and no doubt caused some damage. Leaf rust appeared early and rapidly developed into one of the heaviest epidemics ever reported. Stem rust was also a factor on late wheat. Just before harvest, drouth became a faqtor and with the heavy straw growth the grain shriveled badly. 1 As a result of the unusual season the grain quality was poor and the yields werel low, ranging from 12J to 21 bushels; per acre. Early-maturing, leaf - rust-resistant wheats were at a distinct advantage and gave the best yields. Chiefkan, a beardless hard wheat of questionable baking quality gave the highest yieldin plots. The varieties having the highest average yields dur - ing a period of nine years are Cheyenne and Nebied with yields of 3.4 and 2.1 bushels higher, respectively, than Turkey. A Turkey selection (Ne - braska 1063) was named Nebred and released to farmers in the fait of 1938. At that time about 1100 bushels of certified seed was available,; all of which was seeded. Nebred is resistant to forms of bunt or stinking smut now known to be in| Nebraska. While it is not resistant to stem rust it seems to he able to produce better grain under epidemic conditions than does Cheyenne. Nebred has unusually fine milling qualities and'the flour makes a good loaf of bread. .-":¦'.' • : From the nursery, information was obtained on the reaction of.the various strains to leaf and stem rust. The performance of the Hope x Ne - braska 1069 and Hope x Cheyenne lines is still being watched very care - fully. A selection of Hope x Nebraska No. 1069 was the highest-yielding wheat in the nursery. This strain carries resistance to both rusts and to the Nebraska forms of bunt. More winterhardiness must be bred into the Hope crosses before they will be safe for Nebraska.; Several selections of Kawvale x Tenmarq and Oro x Tenmarq gave good yields as a result of leaf rust resistance. '¦". \ : . ! Work on winter wheat! and other small grains is .cooperative with the Division of Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agricul - ture. Publications: K. S. Quisenberry, "Survival of Wheat Varieties in the Great Plains Winterhardiness Nursery, 1930-37," Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 30: 399,405; H. A. Rodenhiser and K. S. Quisenberry, "Bunt Reaction: of Some Varieties of Hard Red Winter Wheat," Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 30: 484-492; C. A. Suneson and Geo. L. Peltier, "Effect of Weather </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Variants on Field Hardening of Winter Wheat," Jour. Amer. Soc. Aeron. 30: 769-778. fi Oats.—The yields of the oat varieties in plots were unusually good in 1938, ranging between 55 and 74 bushels. The highest yield was made by a selection of Victoria x Richland (C. I. No. 3310) grown for the first time. This new strain is highly resistant to both stem and leaf rust and to smut. Brunker and Columbia also made very good yields, although Brunker lodged rather badly. This oat probably is too weak-strawed for eastern Nebraska. Burt 518 yielded fairly well and because of good results over a period of years this strain probably will be released as soon as pure seed can be increased. Among the varieties tested for six or more years Bun 518, Burt 520, Trojan, Columbia, and Brunker have all given relative yields at least 10 per cent greater than Kherson. Brunker, grown for six years, has yielded on an average 22 per cent more than Kherson, giving it the highest relative yield. Considerable nursery work was continued with oats; observations were made on resistance to rust and lodging. An oat rust nursery was started where selections can be made under epidemic conditions. Barley.—The year 1938 proved rather favorable for barley, the varieties yielding from 22 to 56 bushels per acre. The results from the test plots were not conclusive, however, since grasshoppers caused a great amount of damage to the later varieties, especially those with nodding heads. Flynn, North Platte No. 1, and Club Mariout gave the highest yields. Glabron gave a rather low yield, due to grasshopper injury. Lodging was rather severe; only Club Mariout and Spartan stood up well. On the basis of the last seven crops Flynn, Spartan, Ezond, and North Platte No. 1 have the highest average yields. Club Mariout has been tested for four years only, during which time it has yielded about 2 bushels less than Flynn. In the nursery some yield tests were started, and a large number of selec - tions from various crosses were grown in head-rows. Spring wheat—The spring-wheat varieties gave yields ranging from 6.1 to 19.0 bushels per acre. The highest yields were made by Ceres x Hope-Florence (C. I. 11708), a new strain from North Dakota, and Mindum, a durum wheat. Thatcher was rather low in yield because of damage from leaf rust. Marquis was practically ruined by both stem and leaf rust. The Ceres x Hope-Florence strain has resistance to both rusts and was the highest-yielding variety on the Box Butte experimental farm at Alliance this year. During the last four years Thatcher has had an aver - age yield of 13.3 bushels per acre compared with 5.7 bushels for Marquis. During the same period Reward, a very early variety, yielded 11.0 bushels per acre. Alfalfa improvement—The year 1938 was the first in which comparable yield tests were obtained on a number of new strains resulting from the alfalfa-improvement program which has been under way at this Station in cooperation with the Division of Forage Crops and Diseases of the U. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">V. Fifty-second Annual Report S. Department o£ Agriculture for a number of years. While this test is ¦preliminary, it is interesting to note that of the 20 new strains in the replicated test, 11 yielded higher than Grimm and all but one ranked higher in yield than Hardistan. Of the 11 strains higher than Grimm in forage yield, four were superior to Hardistan in bacterial wilt resistance, while the remaining seven were about the same as Hardistan according to controlled bacterial wilt tests. : Progress has been made during the past year in increasing the seed supply of some of these new desirable strains. Approximately 40 isolated increase blocks produced seed under irrigation in the North Platte valley. This seed will make possible more extensive tests in Nebraska and in many other states which are much interested in obtaining a wilt-resistant variety. Results from the uniform nurseries now established in over 40 states indicate that some of ithe new strains may be better.than any com - mercial varieties now available. 'Further studies of hybrid vigor were made by testing about 40 addition - al crosses during 1937-38. Half of the crosses yielded higher than an aver - age of the Grimm, Ladak, and Hardistan checks, while the best 10 hybrids yielded an average of 24 per cent more than the checks. ' A rather intensive study of seed setting in alfalfa under field conditions was made in the breeding nursery located at the Scottsbluff experimental substation. This included detailed data on such factors as time of fertiliza - tion of the ovules; whether seed setting takes place in : the absence of trip - ping or of insects; effect of lodging on seed setting; and influence of irriga - tion and time of cutting on 'seed production. More than 75,000 individual flowers were observed for time of fertilization, percentage setting pods, and number of seeds per pod under different environmental conditions or treatments. Several hundred Rowers were collected from these various treatments for further study under the microscope in an effort to determine why some plants set seed and others do not. " A number of promising pasture-type plants were selected from the crosses between the creeping-rooted introduction and wilt-resistant selec - tions. These segregates retain the re-rooting habit from the one parent and bring in greater wilt resistance, vigor of growth, and seed produc - tivity from the other parent. 1 ¦ Three years' data from the alfalfa nursery-method study were summar - ized and prepared for publication in the Journal of the American Society of Agronomy. Results indicated a considerable range in type of nursery plot which would give results comparable to field plots. Interplot varietal competition was evident'in rows spaced 7 inches apart, but rows spaced 12 or more inches failed to show significant competition. • During the past year numerous controlled cold-resistance tests have been made on lots of Argentine alfalfa seed, gathered from different parts of that country. Without exception the lots have proved to be considerably inferior to Grimm or Hardistan in ability to withstand cold successfully. This agrees with field results where alfalfas from Argentine and from </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the southern states have killed out more rapidly than hardy northern strains, and would suggest that these unadapted types should not be used in Nebraska, even though the price of the seed is considerably less than seed of better adapted strains such as Hardistan, Ladak, Grimm, Cossack, or Northern Common. Improvement of permanent pastures and native meadows.—This work is cooperative with the Division of Forage Crops and Diseases, U. S. De - partment of Agriculture. The improvement of species found to be best adapted for reseeding is being continued. Over 30,000 seedlings of nine grass species were transplanted to the field during 1938 as progeny tests of previous selections and for further selection. The seedlings were estab - lished in the field with a survival of 97 per cent. Most of these plants set seed in their first season of growth. Studies during the past two years on methods of propagation of these species for breeding work have deter - mined the most suitable practices in the handling of the seedlings in the greenhouse and in the transplanting to the field. The excellent results this year were due to a favorably early season and to the application of these methods. The most promising selections from this material were secured with bromegrass, bluegrass, and crested wheatgrass of the intro - duced grasses, and with side-oats grama, switchgrass, big bluestem, and buffalo grass of the native species. The fundamental breeding procedures such as selfing, recrossing, mass selection, and "strain building" are being applied to these species to determine the most feasible methods of im - provement. Additional yield data were obtained during 1938 on the successtuDy established plots oi several introduced forage species in comparative tests for grazing studies on an irrigated field at the North Platte Substation. Bromegrass, crested wheatgrass, alfalfa, and sweet clover are the most promising. Excellent stands of several native grasses were established dur - ing 1938. Corresponding seedings in 1936 and 1937, with the exception of two species, were failures but were successful in 1938 because of the pro - gress made in determining the proper cultural practices and time of seed - ing. Stands were obtained of big bluestem, switchgrass, side-oats grama, alkali dropseed, and buffalo grass. Stands of western wheatgrass and blue grama were previously established. The plots of native grasses are to be used for comparative testing under grazing. Yield data will also be obtained. Eight introduced and five native grasses were seeded during the spring of 1938 at Lincoln for the purpose of studying their response to various intensities of clipping. Excellent stands were obtained of all the species but several failed to survive the summer drouth. Among those surviving were all of the five native grasses, big bluestem, switchgrass, side-oats grama, blue grama, and buffalo grass, and two introduced grasses, brome - grass and orchard grass. Grasshoppers also damaged several of the intro - duced grasses severely but did not injure the native grasses. </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Fifty-second Annual Report | .¦•¦;¦¦ ; .¦ .. .-.]. ¦'. ; ¦..-_ •\¦ ; : ¦.. Experiments concerning the eradication of the more serious and com - mon pasture weeds by mowing at proper times are being continued. Studies with respect to determining the germination of the seed of these weeds are being concluded! . ¦ .•. A range survey was conducted in cooperation with the Western Range Survey, U. S. Department of Agriculture, during 1937, covering approxi - mately 115,000 acres in a typical sandhill area in Cherry county. The sur - vey was conducted according to accepted methods of range appraisal. The average carrying capacity of each of the five major vegetative range types varied from 6.4 acres on the most productive to 31.2 acres per animal unit per year on the least productive type, the average for the entire area being 26.4 acres. The 1937 survey indicated that the productivity ratings for evaluating the native forage species were inadequate. Accordingly, a study was made during 1938 in [ which jpalatability and productivity ratings of the important sandhill species have been determined. [ . Publications during the year. 19*38: E. H. Doll and D. L. Gross, Brome - grass for Erosion Control: Nebr. Agr. Ext. Circ. ll!9; 8 pages; A. L. Frolik, "Progress of the Grass Research Program," 30th Ann. Rpt. Nebr.' Crop Growers' Assn. (in press); A. L. Frolik and E. F. Frolik, "Seed - ing and Management of Nebraska Pastures," Nebr. Agr. Ext. Circ. 138 (mimeographed), 20 pages;,A. L. Frolik and F. D. Keim, Common Native Grasses of Nebraska, NebrJ Exp. Sta. Circ. 59, 52 pages; E. F. Frolik, A. L. Frolik, and J. C. Baird, "Range Management in Nebraska," Nebr. Agr. Ext. Circ. 137 (mimeographed), 10 pages; D. L. Gross and E. H. Doll, Soil an A Moisture Conservation in Nebraska, Nebr. Agr. Ext. Circ. 118, 31 pages. ¦ : ; . -.. •¦...' , Sweet clover improvement.—This work is in cooperation with the Division, of Forage Crops and Diseases, U. S. Department of Agriculture. It concerns especially the testing of varieties for pasture and hay and in - cludes a breeding program designed to improve the quality and yield of forage. A total deficiency of 35 inches in precipitation in the six years preceding 1938 has resulted in a marked depletion of subsoil moisture and greatly increased weed competition. These conditions have added to the difficulties of testing sweet clover and other small-seeded legumes. ¦..¦¦,: ¦ Sweet-clover varieties are found to differ in their ability to overcome the unfavorable factors of drouth and weed competition, and their merits under such conditions should be considered from the standpoint of sur - vival as well as yield and quality of forage. It would seem reasonable- to assume that results applicable to regions of abundant moisture may not apply where moisture is limited. . - ' ' • The varieties which were most productive of hay and pasture during their first year of growth irr 1937 and 1938 were lowa Late White, Ohio Evergreen, Madrid White, Madrid Yellow, and Commercial White. This is partly explained by their! rapid seedling emergence and vigorous early growth. Slow seedling emergence and early growth are characteristic of </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the late-maturing Redfield Yellow, but under weed-free conditions it has been more productive than either Common Yellow or Common White. In comparisons of first- and second-year yields of biennial sweet clover grown in dose-drilled plots over a 4-year period and under conditions relatively free from weed competition, the three distinct types, Common Yellow, Common White, and Redfield Yellow, yielded respectively 140, 110, and 170 per cent in the second year as compared with the first. Results of clipping tests with first-year sweet clover for the control of weeds indicate serious loss of stand when the clover is clipped as low as 6 to 8 inches above ground after its height exceeds about one foot. Breeding investigations, involving the use of field nurseries, laboratory, and greenhouse facilities, have been continued. Individual plant progenies resulting from selection and inbreeding are under observation as regards coumarin content, lateness of maturity, seed and forage productivity, vigor of growth, freedom from disease, and quality of forage, particularly fineness of stem and leafiness. A statistical analysis has been made of the variability of several vegetative characters with the view of exploring many introduced and selected strains for desirable individuals. Results from studies made during the past year in connection with coumarin content indicate that reliable, suitable methods of determination of this bitter principle, applicable to small amounts of plant tissue, are available. The selection of types lower in coumarin content than those now in general use has as its objective the increasing of the palatability of the crop and the possible reduction of the danger of toxicity, particularly in connection with feeding improperly cured sweet-clover hay. Preliminary studies regarding the inheritance of green cotyledon color and of dwarf branching habit indicate that 'Jiese characters are relatively simple in their manner of inheritance. Other abnormal characteristics are under observation with the intention of subjecting them to genetical an - alysis. Grain and forage sorghums.—Twenty-eight sorghum varieties, Sudan grass, a corn hybrid, and a corn variety were included in the Variety test. With the return to somewhat more favorable moisture conditions, the later-maturing varieties produced higher yields of grain than the early - maturing ones. Hegari, Chiltex, White Darso, Dwarf Yellow milk, and Darso ranked in that order with yields of 40.7, 40.1, 36.1, 35.8, and 333 bushels of grain per acre, respectively. However, varieties like Hegari can not be depended on to produce satisfactory grain yields in seasons of severe drouth. This is indicated by the fact that during the past five years, a period in which the total precipitation deficiency at Lincoln was 33.48 inches, Hegari has averaged 8.4 bushels of grain per acre compared with Early Kalo, Sooner milo, and Day milo, all early-maturing varieties which have produced average yields of 16.5, 163, and 16.2 bushels per acre, respectively. During diis same period, Krug corn, a locally adapted variety, has yielded an average of 2.2 bushels per acre. Because of drouth and grasshoppers, corn in the sorghum-variety test plots produced no </seg>
         <seg id="p027">. FIFTVrSECOND ANNUAL REPORT • ! ¦ ¦ . ' [¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦¦-." 1 "¦ ¦ ¦ " •¦! ¦.'".'. ' ' grain whatever in 1936, \937, and 1938. Tests during a 12-year period have demonstrated the superiority of Atlas sorgo for forage. Its average yield of silage (70 per cent moisture) for this period has been 12.47 tons per acre, compared with 8.73 tons {corn Black Amber sorgo and 5.84 tons from corn. ...::•'; In addition to the yield data from the variety test at Lincoln, results were secured from 42 outlying variety tests which were conducted in co - operation with the Agricultural Extension Service, county farm bureaus, and farmers. As an average of these tests Kalo yielded 27.7, Early Kalo 27.6, and Sooner milo 24.2 bushels per acre. In the eight tests where Early Kalo could be directly compared with corn, the average yields were 19.0 and 73 bushels per acre respectively. While only two years' data are available, they indicate that with most varieties, medium-late seedings produce the best yields. All varieties have given higher yields from late than from early seedings but late-maturing varieties must be planted earlier to permit them to mature before frost, although late seeding shortens the vegetative period of all the varieties 'tested. .¦¦ " , ;. '.. .'[:-.'. '.¦_'¦ ''::¦- ;¦. ./ .¦[¦'¦'¦¦':'.'': Data from the. rate-of-planting test are not available from a long enough period to be conclusive but they suggest that there may be consider - able variation in plant spacing within the rows without materially affecting ¦ grain yields. Forage yields have been greatest from the close spacing*. In the rnanner-of-plantirig test, best stands and highest yields have been obtained when listing is done in soil that has been previously tilled. Studies in the greenhouse have.shown that sorghum is a "short-day" plant. Flowering was delayed when the plants were grown in long days and was accelerated when they were grown in short days. The demonstra - tion of this principle helps to explain why some sorghum varieties intro - duced from southern states are not adapted in Nebraska. It also offers at least a partial explanation for the effect of time of planting on length of the vegetative period in sorghum. .-.,•¦' : In the. breeding nursery, ;68 introduced varieties and strains were grown for observation. Most of them are unadapted for commercial production in Nebraska but some may have value as parent material in crosses. The breeding project has progressed satisfactorily with 77 selections made in F 4 , 15 in F 3) and several hundred in Fa material in 1938. Seed increase was made in 1937 of Kalo, Day milo, Black Amber, and Leoti, considerable quantities being distributed to farmers in the spring of 1938. -. ¦'"-_ '. ¦-..- ' i :¦¦/. :":. ¦¦¦¦:¦¦ ¦:{ :\ ..; -Publications during the (year 1938: R. L. Cushing, "What Sorghums Are Best for Nebraska," Nebraska Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 29: 33-42; "Producing New Sorghum Varieties," Nebr. Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 30 (in press); "Report of the 1938 Sorghum Variety Test," Nebr. Crop Growers' Assn. Ann. Rpt. 30 (in press); R. L. Cushing, T. A. Kiesselbach, D. L. Gross, E. F. Frolik; and G. T. Webster, "Report of the 1938 Cooperative Sorghum Variety Trials," Nebr. Agr. Ext. Circ. </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station (mimeographed); T. A. Kiesselbach, R. L. Cushing, and E. F. Frolik,: Grain and Forage Sorghums in Nebraska, Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 316,' 28 pages. Soybeans. —lnterest in this crop has greatly increased since the estab - lishment of soybean processing plants in Omaha and Fremont during the current year. It is expected that these will result in a more favorable market for the beans grown as cash crop. Under these circumstances it seems possible that soybeans may be profitably substituted for part of the present oat acreage in eastern counties. Information that should prove of considerable help in the early stages of the commercial production of soy - beans in this state is available as a result of the fact that the Experiment Station has been growing them for the last 30 years. During the 30-year period, standard varieties have averaged 15 bushels per acre at Lincoln as compared with 44 bushels of oats, 30 bushels of winter wheat, and 35 bushels of corn. Soybeans have yielded as high as 33 bushels per acre in the more favorable years, and this may represent about the maximum that can be expected. The extent to which soybeans will be grown will doubtless depend largely on the price paid in compari - son with the price of oats. A number of outlying cooperative experiments are now being planned for eastern Nebraska, and it is possible that results will prove more favorable in other localities. ,' Miscellaneous crop studies.—ln a comparison of surface vs. furrow drilling of winter wheat, oats, and barley during the past 6 years, the surface drilling with rows spaced 7 inches apart has yielded significantly! more than furrow drilling with the rows 14 inches apart. By surface drill - ing in alternate rows only, with a row spacing of 14 inches, the yield was lowered to correspond closely with that of the furrow drill. It appears that under these conditions the 14-inch spacing of furrow drills is too wide for maximum yields and also that there has been little advantage from seeding in furrows. Plowing cornstalk^ land for oats or barky in the spring as compared with double disking has not materially affected the yield of these crops. The pasturing of winter wheat at various degree? of severity has regularly caused material yield reductions under the prevailing conditions. In recent years the growth of wheat has not been so rank as to be aided through pasturing by way of reduced lodging. Because of recent public interest in artichokes as a crop for use in the production of power alcohol, rather extensive varietal and cultural tests were again conducted at Lincoln. The yields of tubers were again very low, about 3 tons per acre, because of both drouth and'grasshoppers. The low yield and high cost of harvest again substantiate former conclusions that artichokes are not a practical crop under present conditions. Bindweed research.— Experiments in cooperation with the Division o£ Cereal Crops and Diseases, U. S. D. A., have been conducted at Lincoln {or several years and since 1936 at York with different methods of con- </seg>
         <seg id="p029">- V Fifty-second Annual Report ' ¦ trolling field bindweed. The period 1936-38, during which the experi - ments were conducted at Yorkj was abnormally dry and the results may not represent average seasonal conditions. The following information will be subject to modification as further experiments may indicate. Clean cultivation has proved to be the most reliable and economical method for infestations of one-half acre or more. The data obtained at York show definitely that:it is not necessary to cultivate infested areas as soon as new plants appear above ground. The first new growth after each cultivation draws more food material from the roots than is returned to them. Cultivation 8 days after emergence required a total of 18 culti - vations during a two-year ; period to kill bindweed, whereas cultivations at each emergence required 30 operations to accomplish the same results. Adding the 8 days of growth to the 4 to 6 days that are required for new plants to reach the surface it is apparent that a period of 12 to 14 days is the most effective interval between cultivations. . An experiment conducted to determine the best time of year to begin cultivating revealed that when the program was, started June 1 or earlier, fewer cultivations were required than when begun after smalt-grain har - vest. Soil moisture was deficient and prevented normal emergence and development of the bindweed when treatments were started after harvest. As a result the tillage after harvest did not reduce the food reserves of the roots to any noticeable extent. In years of more favorable moisture it may be advisable to start cultivating after harvest rather than the following spring. Counting depreciation on equipment and the cost of labor, fuel, lubri - cants, and repairs, the cost of bindweed tillage with a tractor and a 10-foot duckfoot cultivator averaged about 35 cents per acre for each cultivation. The total cost per acre for nearly complete eradication varied from $3.80 per acre on a thinly infested area to $9.43 where the infestation was heavy. A system of alternating a year of clean cultivation with a crop of wheat appears promising as a control measure and present indications are that complete eradication will be accomplished in a 4-year period. This sys - tem is probably best suited for treating extensive infestation. Experiments relating to (the use of sodium chlorate have been con - cerned primarily with methods, rates, and dates of application. Dry application of sodium chlorate made during September or October has given the best results. Spray treatments have been less effective and in - volve more risk from fire. Broadcasting the chlorate on the surface without any tillage gave the best results. Disking the land to get the chlorate in - to the soil quickly may bej advisable on rolling land where hard rains immediately after the application might result in loss of chemicals. Dry chlorate spreaders now on die market are more suitable for distributing chlorate than ordinary grain drills. ; ..-.'¦' The data from the rate-of-application experiment indicate that under average conditions rates in excess of 3 or 3.5 pounds per square rod are not likely to result in enough better results to justify the cost of heavier </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station applications. It is more economical to make the first application at a moderate rate and retreat the surviving plants individually the following fall. Publications during 1938: F. D. Keim, D. L. Gross, and R. C. Kind., Bindweed Eradication, Nehr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Circ. 50; J. V. Srb, L. S. Evans, and F. D. Keim, "Cost of Bindweed Eradication by the Tillage Method," Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron., Vol. 30, No. 5. FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Orchard culture.— At Lincoln further steps were taken toward the establishment of the orchard on contour lines so as to facilitate the use of irrigation water. Winter injury at the fruit farm near Union has con - tinued to show up in increasing amounts, requiring the removal of ad - ditional trees. Irrigation will apparently enable some injured trees to recover. Mulched areas at Union continue to show more soil moisture in the spring than similar cultivated areas. Harvest data from mulched and un - mulched trees show again that the diameter of the fruits is much greater for the former but the fruit was noticeably paler. (Data were given in the 51st Annual Report.) / In the vineyard, mulched areas have continued to remain filled to carrying capacity with soil moisture but the soil in the cultivated block has continued to lose. Fruit stocks investigation.—Yield and growth data were continued at Union. For the replanting at Lincoln some new and apparently superior stocks are being used in comparison with French Crab seedlings. Supplementary water for orchards in eastern Nebraska.—During the months from April to November water was supplied to the orchard at Union as a supplement to rainfall. From the data on storage and use of moisture it is apparent that at least % acre inch or 80 to 85 tons of water are required to supply a mature apple tree with its seasonal needs and also to supply the amounts lost through other channels. Evidence obtained from measuring the size of apples indicates that supplementary moisture was influential in increasing fruit size. Vegetable experiments (other than potatoes).—Yield tests of 25 yellow sweet-corn hybrids and observations of an additional 50 hybrids were con - ducted at Lincoln and at the Scottsbluff Substation. Many of the strains were found to have desirable characteristics. 3' Early Grano onion and a white strain of the Sweet Spanish onion de - veloped by the Utah Experiment Station were found to be highly desirable in tests. The use of large onion plants for transplanting was found to be a very certain way of increasing yields. Breeding work is being done with carrots, and the use of manure and irrigation with asparagus is being tested. 'a Horfcullunl Progrm Rrpori No. I, "Golden Pjntam Hybrid Tests in 1937" (mimeographed) ptnrnii detailed data. Thii it obtainable by addressing lhe Department t&gt;t Horticulture, Collese ol Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">: Fifty-second Anndal Report Storage of potatoes.—The data from three storage seasons have been compiled for publication. An initial period of three weeks in a humid cellar was found to be very desirable, because it aids wound healing and prevents decay. Dry cellar and cold storage were found undesirable at the beginning of the period. For winter and spring, the humid cellar is to be preferred above the dry cellar because of the control of weight loss. Spring cold storage was found to be useful as a means of preserving seed potatoes for late planting. In the study of nine bins in a western-Nebraska cellar, differences in weight loss and rot were found in various parts of the bin. No difference between bins, however, could be attributed to varia - tion in types of construction. Research Bulletin 102, Wound Healing in Potatoes {Triumph Variety) as Influenced by Type of Injury, Nature of Initial Exposure and Storage Conditions, by H. O. Werner (42 pages), was published in July. Nutrition of the potato plant—Efforts are being made through green - house experiments to find methods by which the drouth-enduring ability of strains or varieties can be determined. Plants were grown in nutrient solutions of different concentrations but the experiment failed to yield results. A porometer test is being conducted in the greenhouse to deter - mine the water requirements of six selected strains. Readings made with cobalt chloride paper during the summer showed that varieties differ greatly in the transpiration of the leaves.. ' . ; ¦¦¦¦.. At Lincoln and Alliance soil moisture investigations were made in the field in an effort to determine differences between the varieties in ability to remove moisture from the soil. . Cultural experiments with potatoes are being conducted. In the study of crop rotations at the Box Butte Farm, where potatoes arc an important crop, the removal of soil moisture was again, studied by periodical sampling. '.¦¦¦. i.. . ¦ ... '.-'.¦¦ Potato breeding.—By means of temperature control and a 16-hour day in the greenhouse, pure-line and hybrid potato seeds have been produced, and lover 250 different crosses were made in the spring of 1938. Experi - ments indicate that very good results can be obtained by growing seedling plants in gravel with nutrient solutions. In the early summer of 1938 plots at Alliance and North Platte were planted with seedling tubers, and tubers from about 400 plants were saved in the fall of 1938 for increase and further observation. Characteristics such as earViness, drouth endurance, disease resistance, tuber size, and cook - ing quality are being considered. Yield tests of promising early varieties are conducted at Lincoln, North Platte, Scottsbluff, and Alliance. The ¦ Warba variety performed very well but was susceptible to scab and fre - quently was rough. Early strains of Triumph were satisfactory in the cooler regions. The Earliane was unsatisfactory except on dry land at Alliance. &#132;'. ¦ j . Cooking tests were beguh at Lincoln in the fall of 1938 and some time was devoted to improving technique. It has been noted that culinary qual- </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ities vary considerably. It is apparent that the cooking quality of potatoes produced in the warmer parts of, Nebraska in 1938 was inferior. PLANT DISEASES Scab, fusarium wilt, and rhizoctonia of potato. —The effects of crop - ping practices upon the occurrence of three soil-borne potato diseases, scab, fusarium wilt, and rhizoctonia, have been studied in the irrigated rotation plots of the Scottsbluff Substation and in the rotation plots of the Box Butte Experiment Farm. The study of the irrigated plots has been completed and the records for the period 1926 to 1936 have been published in Bulletin 317, Influence of Rotations under Irrigation on Potato Scab, Rhizoctonia, and Fusarium Wilt, by R. W. Goss, 18 pages, May, 1938. It was found that scab was most severe in the short rotations with sugar beets and least in the long rotations with alfalfa preceding potatoes. Applications of barnyard manure in the short rotations have increased scab but also increased the total yield so that more marketable tubers were produced. The amount of rhizoctonia and fusarium wilt was likewise reduced by the use of long rotations with alfalfa preceding pota - toes and the percentage of tubers infected with rhizoctonia was reduced by the application of barnyard manure in the shorter rotations. Consider - ing both yields and diseases, the best rotations were those with alfalfa preceding potatoes and with a three- to six-year interval between potato crops. In the short rotations the use of manure was profitable. The only effect of the cropping sequence at the Box Butte Experiment Farm up to the present time has been the reduction of scab and rhizoctonia as a result of increasing the time interval between crops of potatoes. No effect on fusarium wilt has been evident as yet. The records are being con - tinued and will be prepared for publication at the end of the second cycle of die five-year rotations. The effect of irrigation upon these three diseases is being studied in regard to die time, amount, and number of applications of water. The stages of development of the potato plant in relation to its susceptibility to fusarium wilt are being investigated in the greenhouse. Investigations into the effect of cropping practices and soil factors upon the occurrence of the fungi in the soil which cause these three diseases have been made. The results are being prepared for publication. Potato breeding for disease resistance.—This project has received major attention during the year. Seedlings, hybrids, inbreds, foreign introduc - tions, and numerous commercial varieties have been tested for resistance to fusarium wilt by the use of inoculated soil in the greenhouse as well as in field plots at the Scottsbluff Substation. Great differences in suscep - tibility have been found. The work to date has consisted chiefly in work - ing out experimental methods and attempting to find desirable parent stocks. A method of testing first-year seedlings in large numbers under controlled conditions has been devised and should result in speeding up the work on this project. While the resistance to fusarium wilt has been </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Fifty-second Annual Report emphasized, records are also being obtained regarding resistance to scab and rhizoctonia. During the! past summer tests for. resistance to spindle tuber were included, and thislphase of the project will be continued. (See also under Fruits, and Vegetables.) . ¦ ¦-.-¦'..'¦ ¦'¦¦¦: • The bacterial blight of the bean.— The search has been continued for desirable parent stocks for hybridization in an attempt to produce varieties o£ field and garden beans resistant to both halo blight and common blight disease. Promising selections have been crossed with desirable commercial types and the progenies are bejng tested in the greenhouse and in the field. The effects of temperature and moisture upon the development of the symptoms have been studied.! It was found that these environmental fac - tors influenced the severity of the symptoms and the length of the incu - bation period. The results are being prepared for publication. Progress is being made in the study of the physiology of the causal bacterial organisms in culture, the infection phenomena, and the nature of the physiological resistance! which occurs in certain varieties. Studies on the nature of cold resistance in crop plants.—This project has been broadened to include exploratory studies of cold resistance in deciduous nursery stock and also in varieties of potatoes. (See under Agri - cultural Chemistry.) j Plant-disease survey.—An increased number, of diseased plant specimens have been received during the year with letters of inquiry regarding identi - fication and control methods. A detailed summary of the occurrence of potato diseases in fields grovn for certification is being prepared. Un - usually severe losses due to fusarium wilt of potatoes: were encountered this year. An unusually heavy epidemic of wheat leaf rust occurred dur - ing the early part of last summer in the southern and eastern portions of Nebraska, while black stem rust caused about 9 per cent loss to the wheat crop over the state as a wholeJ Bacterial spot of tomato was very prevalent last year and caused serious loss in eastern Nebraska. Halo blight of beans caused severe losses in the varieties being grown for canning in western Nebraska. The loss in field beans due to blight was slight. The cause of a wilt and canker of privet in nursery stock has been determined to be Glomerella cingulata, the same fungus that causes bitter rot of apple. The relative susceptibility of different varieties of privet is being tested in the greenhouse. ; ! : ".'¦ .: ANIMAL DISEASES The nature &lt;of certain phases o£ swine erysipelas.—Activities have been considerably delayed, particularly attempts at attenuating the swine erysip - elas bacillus by chemical and biologic influences to such an extent that the cultures of this organism could be safely used in the process of immuniza - tion. There is evidence that this may not be attainable, but further effort will be made. . : ' / ¦..'••' An attempt has been made to find an answer to a frequently asked question, "To what extent can the rather sudden dissemination of swine </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station erysipelas be attributed to the presence of the causative bacillus in the hog-cholera virus used in vaccination?" With that purpose in view a series of experiments were undertaken in order to determine the longevity ol the erysipelas bacillus in phenolized hog-cholera virus. The survival periods of E. rhusiapathiae in phenolized hog-cholera virus averaged 29 + days, as an average for six samples of virus, the range being 11 to 46 days. Similar tests of the survival period of B. suipestifer, the cause of pig typhus, were also made. The survival periods of B. suipestifer in phenol - ized hog-cholera virus ranged from 11 to 39 days and averaged 17+. The relatively long survival periods of the erysipelas bacillus under laboratory conditions suggested the advisability of challenging commercial hog-cholera virus with reference to the possibility of its being accountable for the transmission of the swine-erysipelas bacillus. Hence in the course of one year which terminated in 1938, bacteriologic analysis of 251 samples of hog-cholera virus, prepared by 43 concerns distributed over the United States, has been made. In none of these samples could the presence.of the swine erysipelas bacillus be demonstrated and in only one was the B. suipestijcr found to be present. Immunity studies of hog cholera.—Results obtained during the year largely confirmed those reported a year ago. The indications are that to recommend crystal-violet-treated hog-cholera virus for the routine im - munization of swine would be entirely premature. Although swine may be thoroughly immunized by this means, the method lacks constancy and the degree of stability of the immunizing powers of such vaccines is not sufficient to place dependence upon it. In a yard experiment, considerable losses from tuberculosis were sustained and in a measure this reduced the significance of the results. Fifteen pigs in the experiment failed to become immune to cholera after crystal-violet-virus inoculation and succumbed to this infection after natural exposure. Twenty-one lived to the end of the experiment even in the face of a most severe exposure to the infection. i During the year attention has also been given to the influence on B. suipestifer infection of the establishment of immunity to hog-cholera by vaccination, h was possible to utilize for this purpose the swine in the yard experiment for serologic and bacteriologic tests. Apparently the presence of B. suipestifer infection as a cause of vaccination failure could lie established by the fact that 50 per cent of the swine which died of cholera were either B. suipestifer carriers or had been proved to be so by ¦ specific serologic test. Of the cholera-resistant swine 19 per cent showed a positive blood titer and in none of them could the pig-typhus bacillus be demonstrated in their organs. The results were significant even when swine treated with crystal-violet virus instead of serum and virus were studied. In future experiments only swine immunized by the common method will be used. The feasibility of simultaneous serum-culture inoculations in the pre - vention of swine erysipelas.—This project is carried on cooperatively with </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Fifty-second Annual Report -. - the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry, the Nebraska Bureau of Animal Industry, and a number of veterinarians practicing in swine-erysipelas areas. It was undertaken at the suggestion of the U. S. Bureau of Animal. Industry. '•.: .. The method of immunization of swine by the simultaneous use of anti - serum and virulent cultures (Lorenz method) has been successfully prac - ticed abroad for not less than forty years, but owing to conditions peculiar to this country, the distribution of virulent cultures in interstate traffic has thus far been wisely discouraged by the U. S. Department of Agri - culture. 1 Work has consisted of the preparation of the cultures, their issue under authorization of the Nebraska Bureau of Animal Industry, and the determ - ination of the potency of the various serums used by the cooperating veterinarians. The U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry undertakes the co - ordination of the work in the field and the final checking of the results. In!the years covered by [this report the Department has supplied to the cooperating veterinarians virulent culture material sufficient for the treatment of 8,099 swine distributed over 134 farms, all situated in definite swine-erysipelas territory. Hovvever, not all of this material has been used. In a few instances, intercurrent swine diseases other than swine erysipelas intervened, while in others the veterinarians were fearful of the results because of some difficulty in [securing a supply of dependable anti-serum. As part of the working program the cooperating veterinarians are re - quired to submit samples of j the serum used in simultaneous immuniza - tion. These samples, as well as some others obtained from various sources, were subjected to potency tests. In the course of this work 92 samples were subjected to 128 individual tests. These revealed a variance in the protec - tive power of the various serial numbers examined. This fluctuated between no potency at all and a potency of five times die arbitrary normal standard. The tests also showed that during the year the potency trends were' dis - tinctly downward. ;. ; . The few instances in which the results in the field were.unsatisfactory could all be attributed to the use of serum of inferior quality. Information has also become available which indicates disappointing results obtained by veterinary practitioners in attempts to stop further progress; of swine erysipelas in outbreaks by the use of anti-serum. The results of the potency tests were brought to the attention of the U. S. Bureau of Animal Industry and of a number of. serum producers. A number of conferences weri held with die various agencies concerned. As a result the Serum-Virus Division of the Bureau has taken the matter in hand and serum producers are now making an effort to make more dependable products available. ; A The final checking of the results obtained by this year's work has not yet been completed, but the Jones obtained on 104 farms have recently be - come available. On the Whole, both veterinarians and farmers were highly pleased. ¦ i : V: ' </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The bacterioiogic, serologic, and pathologic diagnosis of specimens. — In the course of the year 1938 a total of 6,630 laboratory specimens were examined and the results reported. Circular 56, The Prevention of An - thrax, was published during the year. LIVESTOCK FEEDING Sorghum grain vs. corn for fattening steers. 4 —ln this experiment corn was compared with white kaflr grain and sufficient lots were used to com - pare these grains when fed with cottonseed cake at the rate of 1.05 pounds fed with alfalfa and at the rate of 2.11 pounds with silage. Both corn and sorghum grain were cracked. The kafir was more palatable to the cattle when fed with silage than when fed with alfalfa. This probably increased die feeding value of. grain sorghum slightly. Grain sorghum proved to be worth 86.4 per cent as much as corn when fed with alfalfa and 87.7 per cent as much when fed with silage. Differences between lots were not great enough to cause any difference in selling price, and carcass grades and dressing yields would bear out this statement. There was a slight difference in color of fat but the difference was too slight to be of practical importance. The fat of sorghum-fed lots was whiter than that of the lots fed corn. Like - wise all silage-fed lots showed whiter fat than the alfalfa-fed lots. Self-feeding sorghum grain to fattening pigs in dry lot. s —Whole corn and whole sorghum grain were self-fed to pigs in dry lot with a supple - ment of tankage 2 parts, cottonseed cake 1 part, and alfalfa meal 1 part. In this test the whole sorghum grain proved to be 95 per cent as valuable as corn. Grinding the sorghum grain, self-fed with the .same supplement, did not prove beneficial. This was true of both coarse and fine grinding. In a test of Sooner milo and white kafir as compared with corn, fed whole, the former was 84 and the latter 83 per cent as valuable as corn. This would indicate that there is little difference between the two varieties. Supplements tor grain sorghums fed to pigs.—This test was conducted at the School of Agriculture at Curtis, Nebraska. One lot received no sup - plement and the other received the supplement mentioned in the report above. The test demonstrated strikingly the need for protein supplement. The average final weight of the pigs fed the supplement was 204 pounds but the pigs fed without the supplement averaged 126 pounds. Summer-feeding pigs on Sudan grass pasture. o—This0 —This test extended through 100 days. A. simple mineral mixture was provided to all lots. The addition of tankage to the ration of either corn or Sooner milo in - creased the daily feed consumption and the rate of gain, and reduced the 'Complete details are available in Cattle PtOßrcis Report 167, obtainable from the Department of Animal Husbandry. College of Agriculture. * The detailed results arc available in Hog Progress Report 265 by addressing the Animal Hus - bandry Department, College of Agriculture. ' Details of the experiment arc Riven in Hop Progress Report 268, obtainable from the Department of Animal Husbandry. College of Agriculture. </seg>
         <seg id="p037">i Fifty-second Annual Report amount of feed required for each unit of gain. The use of tankage in - creased the carrying capacity of the pasture and reduced rooting materially. Where corn alone was compared with Sooner milo without protein supplement, the milo proved to be 85 per cent as valuable as corn. Where corn and Sooner milo were both supplemented with tankage, the Sooner milo was found to be 90 per cent as valuable as corn. White kafir when supplemented with tankage was 87 per cent as valuable as corn similarly ¦ supplemented. . : \ : In this test cracked barley self-fed with tankage was found to be 84 1 per cent) as valuable as corn. With barley the consumption of tankage was unusually high. : .1 ' ' . The addition of shorts to a corn and tankage ration increased the total daily feed consumption and the rate of gain. The shorts practically re - placed an equal weight of corn and tankage. Skimmilk fed as a supplement with corn in place of tankage produced slightly larger gains. A pound of tankage replaced 2.72 gallons of milk ! in producing 100 pounds of gain. ! Hogging off grain sorghums 7 .—Two lots each of Day milo, Sooner milo, and early kalo were used in this test. In all of the lots fed good rations (including supplement) an average of 435 pounds of pork was produced per acre. It is probably necessary to restrict the range of pigs in order to get them to clean,up the grain properly. The use of good protein supplements is desirable to secure good utilization of the grain sorghums. . • . ". . •'..-¦ Sorghum grain for fattening lambs.—White kafir was used in lamb fattening rations during the ; winter of 1937-38. Several comparisons were made: (1) a shelled corn and whole white kafir comparison showed a little difference in favor of the corn; (2) a comparison of whole kafir and cracked kafir showed no advantage in cracking for lambs; (3) a com - parison of feeding whole kafir in a grain trough and feeding it mixed with cut alfalfa hay in a bunk ihowed no difference in rate or economy-of gain and there was no noticiable difference in palatability; (4) a compari - son of cracked kafir fed in i grain trough and cracked kafir mixed with cut alfalfa hay and fed in a bunk.showed no difference in rate of gain, economy of gain, or palatability. Whole alfalfa hay vs. cv alfalfa hay for fattening lambs.—The lambs receiving whole alfalfa hay consumed 1.29 pounds daily and refused 0.19 pound daily per lamb; Thfc cut alfalfa hay fed perday averaged 1.47 pounds. Calculated on the s mount of hay fed, 501 pounds of whole hay or 450 pounds of cut hay were required to produce 100 pounds of gain. DAIRY HUSBANDRY Growth studies.—The gathering of data on growth, a long-time project, has been continued and publications are being prepared on various phases 'Hos Progress Report 269, available from the Dfnarlmem of Animal Huibandrv, Collect of Agri - culture, containi the details of ihc experiment. </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of this work. One technical article was published during the year, "Rela - tion between Rate of Growth and Milk and Fat Production," by H P Davis and E. L. Willett, Jour, of Dairy Science 21: 637-42. Seventy-six Holstein females were studied in regard to rate of growth between birtii and two years as indicated by increase in weight, chest girth, and height at withers and also in regard to relationship of growth to subsequent production of milk and fat. The animals in this study were apparently normal in their rate of growth. There appeared to be little if any relation - ship between various measures of rates of growth and subsequent produc - tion. Studies of vitamins.—Research Bulletin 101, The Vitamin A Content of Soybean Silage and oj A.I. V., Molasses, and Common Corn Silages, and the Effect of Feeding these Materials upon the Vitamin A Content oj Milk., by I L. Hathaway, H. P. Davis, and J. C. Braver (16 pages), was published during the year. From the data obtained it is evident that under the conditions of the experiment various milks produced from cows receiv - ing A. I. V., molasses, or ordinary silage as the only roughage ranked in the same order of vitamin-A potency as did the silages. Molasses silage was approximately equal to A. I. V. silage as a source of vitamin A and both ucre slightly superior to soybean silage and ordinary silage as sources of vitamin A. Alfalfa hay was superior to all kinds of silage in this respect. The lactogen content of the pituitary glands of the lactating rat was studied, and a paper by R. P. Recce, I. L. Hathaway, and H. P. Davis was published in the Proc. Soc. Exper. Biol. and Med. 37: 293-94. This phase is cooperative with the New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station. Dairy manufacturing.—A study of the freezing of condensed milk as a means of preserving that material for use in ice-cream making was com - pleted and the results were published as follows: "A Comparison of Fresh and Frozen Condensed Skimmilk as a Source of Serum Solids in Ice Cream," by E. L. Reichart and Robert T. Corley, four. Dairy Sci. 21; JO9-J9. The method was found to be satisfactory for a period up to six months. After four months a gel was formed which did not prove objec - tionable, while after eight months there was some wheying off. There were no significant differences in the pH and titratable acidity of ice - cream mixes made from fresh condensed skimmilk and from those made from the frozen stored product. As compared with mixes containing freshly condensed skimmilk, mixes containing condensed milk that had been frozen and stored showed lowered whipping ability, a slightly longer time to reach a definite overrun during freezing, in some cases a slightly lower flavor, texture, and body score for the ice cream, and a more rapid melting of the ice cream. Shipments of frozen stored con - densed skimmilk can be made in the summer in non-refrigerated trucks for distances up to 150 miles with success. Continued studies have been made upon cream cheese with special reference to improving the keeping quality of the cheese. Hot packing and concentrating the ingredients are both being tried in this study. </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Fifty-second Annual Report Milk quality as influenced by the individual cow.—Since 1934 every case of udder infection (which showed evidence of streptococci has been isolated in an attempt to eliminate the continued mastitis infection. While there have been new cases of infection during that period, the incidence of infection has been greatly reduced. In this study, determinations have been made of the leucocyte count before and after incubation to study any changes which may occur. Weed flavor, particularly that caused by French weed, has been studied. Studies of reproduction.—Continued studies are being made upon the influence of wheat-germ! oil and prolan upon the number of services re - quired for conception in virgin dairy heifers.; The influence of gonad - stimulating substances such as prolan upon dairy bulls has been studied and it has been found that these substances increase the activity of the spermatozoa and the sex impulse of bulls. During the year Research Bulletin 104, Influence of Age of Dairy Cattle and Season 0} the Year on the Sex Ratio of Calves and Servicef Required for Conception, by R. F. Morgan and H, P. Davis (20 pages), was published. The records used covered 38 years on five breeds, Holsteins, Jerseys, Guernseys, Ayrshires, and milking Shorthorns. POULTRY HUSBANDRY Manganese requirements of growing poults—Recent research has in - dicated that the element; manganese is involved in the control of perosis in chicks. During the past year experimental work was conducted at the Nebraska station to determine the requirement of manganese for growing poults. For a basal ration a mixture (8-T4X) providing protein and vita - mins in sufficient amounts was used. Analyses showed that the basal mash contains 35 parts per million of manganese and this ration was used as a control. To this was added manganese carbonate and manganese sul - fate, each one at levelsfof 35 and 350. parts per million. Thus three levels were compared. No cases of perosis were found in any of the lots. This would indicate that the basal ration, 8-T4X, which is recommended by the Station and widely used, contains sufficient manganese to prevent perosis in poults. . . Use of complex minerals in poultry rations.—Formula 8 and formula 8S (with soybean oil meal) were used as bases in an effort to determine whether or not additional mineral mixtures containing small amounts of many elements would be helpful. A complex salt mixture containing small amounts of many salts and designated by the Mendel and Osborne laboratory at Yale University as No. 351 was'used at 3 per cent levels with each of the two rations mentioned above. While the data have not been completely analyzed, it is apparent that the complex mineral mixture is not effective in increasing weight and feathering. 1 Grain sorghums in chick rations.—ln the standard 8S ration, 31 per cent of the yellow cornm'eal was replaced by grain sorghum (white kafir). </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Results of the test indicate that white kafir is inferior to yellow corn, even with sufficient alfalfa meal to meet ordinary vitamin A requirements. Trials with Early Kalo, Wheatland milo, Atlas sorgo, and Orange cane were conducted to determine the vitamin-A values of these four varieties. It is apparent that none of these varieties contains enough vitamin A to maintain growth when fed at the 31 per cent level. Wheatland milo, one of the yellow-seeded varieties, proved slightly superior to the others. Fur - ther work is planned. Amount of salt in chick rations.—Formula 8, a widely used mash formula, calls for 1 per cent of salt. Comparative tests were made'to determine whether or not V 2 per cent of the salt in the mash would be sufficient. The data on growth indicate that 1 per cent should be used. Carotene content of poultry feedstuffs.—Some data were obtained on carotene content of first-cutting alfalfa, on the distribution of carotene in leaves and stems, and on the effect of storage conditions on the stability ot carotene in alfalfa meal. It was determined that leaves carry a relatively higher percentage of carotene in comparison with stems and that storage at low temperature (40° F.) is effective in preserving the carotene content. Application of heat to chick rations.—The object of several tests dur - ing the past year has been to determine whether or not heat applied in processing to various products such as meat meal, blood meal, fish meal, etc. causes the products to lose some of their original value. In the experimental trials, various percentages of the 8S chick ration were cooked in an autoclave for 2 hours at 15 pounds of pressure. The cooked and un - cooked portions were recombined and cod-liver oil added after the re - combination. That the growth-promoting value of this ration (8S) is reduced by heat treatment is shown by the experiment. Further work will be necessary in order to determine the factor that limits growth under such circumstances. RURAL ECONOMICS Cost of producing farm crops.—Cost-of-ptoduction information is useful to farmers in planning a production program. It is helpful to know not only the cost of producing each important crop on a farm, but the costs of production by different methods and in different areas. Blank forms are placed with farmers who are willing to cooperate and filled in during the year. These records show the number of hours of work performed by men, horses, and machines for each operation in seedbed preparation, planting, cultivation, and harvesting. During the past year 176 wheat records, 195 corn records, and 76 tractor records were secured. The tractor records will be tabulated to show the average hourly cost of operating tractors of various types. Cost of marketing corn and wheat in Nebraska by various methods. Bulletin 314, Operating Problems of Farmers' Elevators In Nebraska, by L. F. Garey, 32 pages, March, 1938, presents information collected in re - cent years in one phase of the work under this project. Data were </seg>
         <seg id="p041">! i : ¦ Fifty-second Annual Report '"¦¦..¦¦ i¦¦ ¦ ¦¦¦¦! ¦ : ¦¦¦•'-¦[' ; obtained ftorn annual audit reports of farmer-owned elevators for the ; years 1922-1935. In spite of, the sharp decline in prices which began in f the autumn of 1929 the group of elevators studied appeared to be in better : shape financially in 1931 than in 1922. Their condition decreased slightly • but not seriously from 1931 to 1935. This was due primarily to the de - i crease in volume of business which was a result of the series of dry years. The effects of grain prices, volume of grain handled, and volume of side - : lines on elevator prosperity were tabulated. The expenses of the elevators ¦}."¦ studied have, decreased since 1922. The items which showed the largest | decreases were interest, salaries, and wages. The average per-bushel cost ! of handling grain decreased as the volume handled increased. One of ¦' the most serious problems confronting grain elevators is the reduction : in the volume of grain jold by farmers. Wheat acreage in a considerable j ; part of the state has decreased since the elevators were built. The acreages I of corn and barley have increased, but the amount of corn marketed has decreased because of the;increase in the number of livestock, and in recent I years because of the prolonged drouth. Some of the elevators are trying '. to maintain dollar volume of business by handling mill feeds and other ; sidelines. i .-v..: : . ¦ .¦/¦¦'-''; ,:¦¦-. Farm organization and farm costs. — This is one of the oldest and most ¦ " important rural-economic projects. Information is secured from record f books kept by farmers.; For the year 1937 a total of 899 farm account I books were received and summarized. It is anticipated that fully as many i books will be submitted by farmers for 1938. : ! . Bulletin 319, Equipment Expense per Acre on Farms in Nebraska, I 1926-1910 and 1932-19361 30 pages, by A. W. Medlar was issued in Septem - j i .'.¦:, ber, 1938." The equipment expense per acre was higher in the earlier of the two periods studied. The cause was undoubtedly the adverse crop ! conditions and the price maladjustment which caused farmers to buy * less machinery and to reduce equipment expenses. Near the close of the .; period disease among horses and shortage of feed grain caused many farmers to turn to tractors for farm power. The expense per acre on small farms was materially, less than on large farms because the equipment : was not utilized as fully. : ' Farm real estate tax delinquencies and public expenditures in Nebraska. : —Research Bulletin 105,1 The Tax System of Nebraska with Special Refer - ; ence to its Relation to Agriculture, by L. B. Snyder, 84 pages, presents j tables and graphs covering assessments, levies, receipts, expenditures, and ¦ real property tax delinquencies for twelve selected counties for the period I '¦ 1928-1933. Figures are \reduced to per-capita and per-acre basis. Com - l parisons are made between supervisor and commissioner counties for each ' item. Expenditures were somewhat less in the commissioner counties than I', in the supervisor counties.. : .. : ; f Considerable progress has been made in tabulating data to show the j relationship between tax delinquency and type of soil, </seg>
         <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The measurement of Nebraska fanners* response to price in hog pro - duction and marketing.—Considerable progress has been made during 1938 in summarizing by counties the data for hogs shipped to the Omaha market from all points in Nebraska. Data are available for cattle and sheep. Over 30,000 reports are included in this study. Farm mortgage foreclosures in Nebraska.—Research Dulletin 107, Land Transfers in Twelve Counties in Nebraska, 1928-1933, 24 pages, by L. F. Garey, was recently issued. Sixty-four per cent of the land trans - fers during these six years were voluntary, 16 per cent were distress, and 20 per cent were gifts. Relatively less land was transferred because of distress during the earlier than during the latter part of the period. The assessed value and the sales value of the farms transferred voluntarily were approximately equal. The assessed value of the distress transfers was 90 per cent of the sale value. The assessed value of the land given away was higher than for that transferred in other ways. There was no evidence that high taxes were the direct cause of the distress transfers, although they may have been a contributing factor. For the distress transfers the amount of the claims against the land totaled 56 per cent of the sale price. It varied among the counties from as low as 1? per cent to as high as 145 per cent. In general, the percentage was highest in the counties where the price of land was highest. The pro - portion of the distress transfers in a county which consisted of relatively poor land was higher than the proportion of the lower grades of land with - in the county. Apparently poor land was overvalued during the high - price period to a greater extent than good land. From 1928 to 1933 the prices received by farmers for their commodities dropped over 50 per cent and during the same period the number of distress transfers increased over 150 per cent, which indicates that prices received by farmers play a very important part in the forced transfer of land. A study of adjustments in fanning by regions and type-of-fanning areas from the standpoint of agricultural adjustment and planning, includ - ing conservation. —Maps are being prepared showing the land use in each of twenty-five selected counties. These maps will serve as a base on which to build future plans in these counties. Other counties will be included as soon as conditions justify. Economic and social effects on farms of a definitely designed program of soil conservation.—This project is cooperative between the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station and the Soil Conservation Service and the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the U. S. Department of Agri - culture. Data for the years 1935, 1936, and 1937 have been collected from three areas, and the collecting of 1938 data is now in progress. Tabulation of the earlier years has been completed and a manuscript prepared and submitted to the Washington offices for approval. Economic studies in prices, volume of production, and purchasing power of farm products. —Work has been done during the past two years on a statistical study of price fixing by governments. A manuscript is in </seg>
         <seg id="p043">. Fifty-second Annual Report process of preparation and will probably be completed during 1939. Prices received by farmers for 24 commodities for the period 1912-1937 .have been obtained on a county basis. Maps are being constructed showing the geography of the price of each commodity. Seasonal prices are also being tabulated. ! UTILIZATION OF LAND County and area land-use planning.— The two land-utilization projects formerly carried on in cooperation, with; the Resettlement and Farm Secur - ity Administrations have been combined into one project and the enlarged project is being, continued cooperatively with the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, U. S. Department of Agriculture. One phase of the work has been published as Research Bulletin 98, A Proposed Method for Classifying and Evaluating Soils on the Basis of Productivity and Use Suitabilities, by Arthur Anderson, A. P. Nelson, F. A. Hayes, and I. D. Wood, May, 1938, 34 pages. It is pointed out that such analyses should be particularly valuable (1) in the development of use-suitability classifications for such purposes as taxation assessment, con - servation practices and programs, and individual farm analyses and plan - ning, (2) to public and private agencies and individuals for land purchase and loan purposes, and ((3) in general and specific programs of research, education, extension, and action designed to bring about more effective land-use practices. ! Preliminary use-suitability classification maps have been prepared and recommendations designed to bring about more effective land use have been made for eight counties. These maps and recommendations will be studied and revised in, accordance with additional factual information which is being assembled and with local opinions. This work will be ex - tended into additional bounties as rapidly as facilities will permit. An extensive WPA land-use survey project, which is being administered by the State Planning Board, is contributing materially to the basic informa - tion essential to such analyses. HOME ECONOMICS Gas stoves.—Experimental work on this study has been concluded and the final results are being prepared for publication. Briefly, the study of six stoves investigated shows that (1) The best average efficiency to be expected from the present types of cooking-top burners is about 47 per cent, j With pans having an 8-inch-diameter bottom, efficiencies may run as high as 55 per cent. ; (2) Excessive carbon monoxide may be found in the combustion products with burners that have grates and burner bowls that qause a smothcringjof the flame when a large pan is used. Only one of the five stoves analyzed for CO in the .combustion products was satis - factory according to A.G.A. requirements. One stove especially produced CO in a dangerous amount. (3) Automatic lighters could stand improve - ment in many instances. The ones investigated were not. entirely satis - factory. (4) The greater portion of the heat loss from ovens arises, from </seg>
         <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the conduction and radiation loss through the walls of the oven. A de - tailed calorimetric study of the heat loss from the flue of the oven showed that this loss was approximately 11 to 13 per cent of the total loss. The oven tests indicate that if the heat loss is to be reduced, the ovens must be better insulated. Steam pressure cookers.—The technical results of the investigation of pressure-cooker gauges used on domestic pressure cookers were published in May, 1938, as Research Bulletin 99, The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Household Steam Pressure Coolers, by Arnold E. Baragar, 18 pages. Facts about pressure cookers that would be of value to the public in general were published in Station Circular 57, Your Pressure Cooler, How to Choose it and How to Use it jor Canning, by Arnold E. Baragar, ]b pages. Gasoline stoves.—Because of an increased demand for information about the performance of pressure gasoline stoves a study has been started to secure information similar to that obtained on gas stoves. Tests will in - clude: efficiency ol cooking-top burners; analysis of combustion products for CO and CCX.; and heat capacity, rate of cooling, heat loss, temperature distribution inside, surface temperatures, and flue loss oi ovens. The hear of combustion of gasoline will be determined with the Parr bomb calori - meter. Also, the effect of volatility upon the heat of combustion will be observed during the storage of gasoline at room temperatures of 75° to S0 c F. This study has just been started and no data are as yet available. Small food mixers.—Because the present small food mixers do not per - form satisfactorily for some mixing and beating processes, an investigation has been started to determine the performance as: (1) a function of the r.p.m. of the beaters. (2) a function of the shape of the beaters, (3) a function of the shape of the bowl, (4) a function of the rotation of the bowl, and (5) a function of the load. As a part of the study, a test mixer is being built so that motor characteristics will vary only as a function of the load, and speed changes will be effected by interchanging gear boxes rather than by controlling speeds through the motor. Each'function will be studied as nearly independently of the others as possible:and then the results combined at the end of the study. Load tests are now being made with wood-flour and oil, but no results are ready for publication. The mineral and nitrogen metabolism of college women.—Twenty-five college girls have been studied in addition to the thirteen mentioned in the report of last year. All the food eaten by each girl for one week or ten days was weighed and samples were saved for analysis; also, the excreta were collected. The biological materials have been analyzed for calcium, phosphorus, iron, and nitrogen. The relationship between the intake and outgo of these elements provides evidence from which to determine the storage or maintenance requirements for these dietary essentials for girls of this age. Results available from this small group indicate that girls from 18 to 22 years are storing minerals and nitrogen when they are </seg>
         <seg id="p045">Fifty-second Annual Report supplied in amounts over and above the requirement for maintenance. X-rays of the wrists have been taken of fourteen of the girls in order to study the stage of maturation of the bones. These were accompanied by calcium and phosphorus determinations of the blood. Publications this yearj included: "Reliability of the Thiocyanate Method for the Determination of Iron in Acid Digests of Food and Feces," by Ruth M. Leverton, Jour. Home Economics, Vol. 30, April, 1938; "Com - parison of Food Intakes for Week Days and for Saturday and Sunday," by Ruth M. Leverton and Alice Marsh, Jour. Home Economics. A project on copper metabolism of young women was approved December 22, 1938, and the analytical work was begun immediately. , Results obtained by Nebraska homemakers in canning with pressure equipment—Additional (records are being collected concerning spoilage encountered^ jn home-canned goods. Continued drouth conditions have made it desirable to postpone work on a portion of the project as it was originally planned. ! ¦'¦--• . A'-study of comparative costs of certain home and commercially pre - pared foods, and of such foods prepared in the home with the use of different fuels.—The purpose of this study was to determine the compara - tive cost of home-produced and commercially produced white and whole - wheat bread and rolls. Costs of home-produced bread were estimated on the basis of cost of ingredients and fuel, plus time. These costs were com - pared to costs of commercially prepared bread available at retail. Nutritive value was considered in interpreting results. : The method used was a combination of survey and laboratory investi - gation. The survey included the collection of (1) information regarding the baking practice of families in Nebraska, (2) detailed records of amounts and costs of ingredients and fuels and time used in home baking of bread, and (3) kinds, 1 amounts, and costs of bread purchased over a two-weeks period. The laboratory investigation included the baking of bread by a standardized (formula with ovens heated by electric energy, natural gas, kerosene, and gasoline, with recorded amounts and costs of in - gredients and fuel. j Results of the study show the following: (1) Over 90 per cent of the women cooperating baked all or part of the bread used in the home. (2) The most frequent reasons listed for baking were economy and superior quality. The family preference was predominantly in favor of home - produced bread. (3) Approximately 70 per cent of the women cooperat - ing used cobs and wood I together or separately as fuel and 35 pet cent purchased all on part of the fuel. Seventy-one per cent used the stove for other purposes when baking bread. (4) With the ovens used in the lab - oratory, costs ofj fuel varied in the following descending order: electric energy, gasoline, kerosene.j natural gas. Fuel costs to the women cooperat - ing varied as follows: electric energy, natural gas, gasoline, coal, cobs, kerosene. (5) The total costs of home-produced bread per pound varied with the cost per pound of flour, proportion and kind of yeast used, kind </seg>
         <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of liquid (milk or water), and with the fuel used. Seventy-three per cent of the women reporting used water as liquid. (6) The savings from home production of white loaf bread, made with milk, to Nebraska home-makers is 3.55 cents per pound. Bread baked in the laboratory showed possible savings ranging from 2.48 cents per pound to 4.48 cents, depending upon, the variable factors. Similar savings resulted from home production of whole-wheat bread, but were somewhat less. Costs of ingredients of white rolls made by cooperators ranged from 3.6 cents to 18 cents per pound. The total cost of fancy rolls made in the laboratory did not exceed 11.8 cents per pound and ranged from 10.27 cents to 11.8 cents, j Costs of those purchased ranged from 10 to 29 cents per pound. (7) |The Nebraska homemaker's time is worth from 23 to 46 cents per hour for making bread, depending upon time required. (8) Information from commercial bakers regarding ingredients used in their bread products shows that they are not inferior in nutritive quality to home-produced bread and are fre - quently superior. (9) Household production of bread appears to be a sound economic practice. Economic necessity, market value of the time of the homemaker, family preference, availability of commercial products are factors in considering home-produced vs. commercial bread. Studies in family life.—A study of the nature and importance of the relationships between home environmental influences and the development ot certain selected traits of character and personality in children has been made. In order to obtain comparative data concerning three general types of home setting, i.e., the farm, small town, and the city, and concerning the "personality products of each, separate samples of young people from farm homes, town homes, and city homes were used as subjects. These groups ranged in size from 520 to 695 individuals and they were selected so as to represent adequately the adolescent population of the state. Research Bulletin 106, The Relation of Certain Factors in Farm Family Life to Personality Development in Adolescents, by L. H. Stott, published October, 1938, 46 pages, reports in detail the results from the farm group. Specific relationships between items of the home environment and the personality variables in children are shown. The indications were that the social aspects of the home environment, including family group and social activities and the person-to-person relationships, are most closely related to personality adjustments of farm children. Some items of the home environment were shown to differ in their importance to the two sexes. Adequacy of the personality adjustments of the children of a family was adopted as the criterion of "family success." From this point of view it was possible to compare the "success" of the three general types of home setting in terms of the young peoples' scores on the nine different aspects of character and personality selected for study. It was found that in general the city ranked highest, the farm second, and the small town lowest in "success" according to this criterion. The city group averaged slightly but reliably higher than the farm group in freedom from irrational and </seg>
         <seg id="p047">Fifty-second Annual Report emotionalized thought associations, adequacy of personal adjustment to life in general, in independence of judgment in regard to personal prob - lems, in resourcefulness in social situations, and in ethical judgment. The farm group was slightly superior to the city group in attitude toward work and attitude toward home life. The two groups were not significantly different in personal responsibility and honesty. The farm group was superior to the small-town group in all variables except resourcefulness in group situations, ethical judgment, and honesty, in which the town ranked somewhat higher. The town and the city groups averaged practically the same in these three traits, all of which involve initiative, judgment, or facility in social matters. Farm life apparently does not furnish as much experience and training conducive to the development ofi these particular aspects of personality as does life in town or city. ;.'.•'. A study of the data concerning the various items o£ the home environ - ment in each home setting and of their relation to the personality scores suggests that a greater frequency of confidential and affectional relation - ships between parent and child, more family group activities, better atti - tudes of parents toward the.child's friends, and attitudes favoring less strict and authoritative control over the activities of adolescent children (found in the data from the city group particularly, and also from the farm group) probably are responsible, at least in part, for the superiority of the city and farm groups in personality adjustment. .-¦.'. Final, reports"of the results of the project are being prepared for publi - cation. Work is soon to begin on a project entitled: A study of the family life of rural couples in reation to their similarities and differences in per - sonality and temperamenr. ¦¦.'.'•. NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION The general plan of work at the North Plane Substation was contin - ued. Major projects that are cooperative with the United States Depart - ment of Agriculture are those on dry-land crops and tillage and swine breeding. An additional tract of 240 acres has been obtained under a ten-year lease, and of this 30 acres have been subleased to; the Soil Conserva - tion Serviceior increase of native grass seed. The remainder willbe used for production of feed c-ops and as pasture lots for the swine breeding experiment. Total rainfall was above normal but unfavorably distributed, and crop yields were generally lower than would be expected. Dry-land crops and tillage.—Average crop yields were: winter wheat 14.9 bushels; spring wh|at 10.9 bushels; oats 26.5 bushels; barley 173 bushels; corn 6.4 bushels; Early Kalo 29.6 bushels;,and potatoes 49.1 bushels. The small grains generally made a good growth of straw but the soil moisture was exhausted before the grain was mature. ¦The sorghums were outstanding in comparisons with other crops. Forage sorghums made more than double the fodder yield of corn, and Early Kalo, a grain sorghum, made more than three times the grain yield .of corn. . :¦¦.'¦. ':¦;¦' ¦¦¦¦¦'. ¦¦¦; ¦'¦¦¦:¦ .-."' I :-... ¦ ¦¦.¦¦' </seg>
         <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Sorghums were the only crops that made a fair profit above cost of production. Differences between tillage practices were generally insignificant with the exception of fallow for certain crops. Potatoes were seriously affected, by psyllid yellows or "purple top." Yields of winter wheat and Early Kalo after fallow were double those on cropped land, but the response of spring grains to fallow was slight. Pump irrigation.—A summary of results obtained from the pump irrigation plant can be found in Bulletin 301, Pump Irrigation Results. During the year 1938 Sumac sorgo produced 16 tons of silage per acre. Because of poor stands and hail damage, corn yielded 9.3 tons per acre of fodder. Potatoes yielded 150 bushels per acre; the low yield was due to an attack of psyllids. . . ¦ .' About 83 acres of land were irrigated during die late fall of 1937 and early spring of 1938 for the purpose of creating moisture reserves. During 1938 an average discharge of 1130 gallons per minute was maintained by the pump. Water was applied to 102.7 acres, at an average rate of 11.33 inches per acre. The average operating cost for the season was 33.48 per acre. Testing crop varieties. —Cheyenne winter wheat, one of. the leading varieties for the past eight years, yielded 16.8 bushels per acre. Kawvale x Tenmarq yielded two bushels more but was poor in quality. Extension Circular 124 (mimeographed), "Varieties of Winter Wheat for Nebraska," discusses yields and other qualities. Of barley varieties, Velvon, a new introduction in these tests, yielded 37.9 bushels per acre. This was the highest yield. North Platte No. 1 has averaged highest over nine years. Ceres spring wheat yielding 14.2 bushels occupied first place for the eighth time in a 12-year period. Brunker, with a yield of 35.8 bushels, was highest among oat varieties for this season and for a 14-year average. Early Kalo, with yields of 22.0 bushels on cropped land and 36.6 bushels on fallow, was again the leading grain sorghum. Corn yields were very low. In a dry-land test of 60 hybrids and varieties, many produced no ears, and of those producing grain, the highest yield was made by native open-pollinated Substation White. Under irrigation, 18 of 21 hybrids out - yielded three open-pollinated varieties, and the average superiority of all hybrids over varieties was 16 per cent. Beef cattle. B —Kafir seed proved to be approximately 95 per cent as valuable as corn in tests with wintering and fattening calves. There was some indication that the higher die proportion of the two grains fed, the lower the value of kafir in comparison with corn. One ton of silage plus 68 pounds of cake and 5 pounds of ground limestone were equivalent in efficiency to approximately 850 pounds of 1 Several mimeographed progress report* of liveitock fettling ecus Jrc available at the North Platte Experiment Subitatioo, Vonh Platte. Nebraska. </seg>
         <seg id="p049">Fifty-second Annual Report alfalfa hay and 30 pounds of grain for wintering calves. These conclusions ate based on three comparisons. Each group was fed a limited amount of of (I) alfalfa hay, (2) prairie hay, and (3) silage (84 days) and alfalfa (remainder of period) were made with six lots of steers. Three lots were full-fed corn for 180 days and three were given half feed for half the period and full feed for the remainder. Trials were begun May 10. Cottonseed cakej was fed to all lots. All rations proved satisfac - tory; the deferred feeding: period reduced grain requirement but increased the requirement of hay. • The project on the development and maintenance or breeding came begun in 1933 was dosed.! The supplementing of prairie hay with steamed bone meal gave some indications that it was of value although differences were not striking. The addition of one pound of cottonseed cake pet day per head to a winter ration of prairie hay resulted in heavier cows with more flesh, in calves with heavier birth weight and weaning weight, and in a 100 per cent calf crop (third crop) in comparison with a 55 per cent crop from cows not receiving the supplement. Blood analyses gave no indication that differences in the ration affected the calcium level in the blood, but the addition of steamed bone meal or cottonseed cake re - sulted in higher phosphors levels at the close of the wintering period. . Swine.—Work in connection with the Regional Swine Breeding Labora - tory was continued. ¦¦' V ¦ , ¦-..,.¦. , In trials involving the use of whole kafir, whole milo, ground kafir, and ground milb in comparison with shelled corn for .fattening hogs, five lots of pigs with an average initial weight of 44 pounds were fed to a final weight of 220 pounds. Whole kafir was worth 90 per cent/ground kafir 91 pei cent, and ground rriilo 94 per cent as much as shelled corn. A mixed protein supplement was fed to all lots. Sheep.-No experimental feeding was done with sheep. Surplus lambs have been sold to 4-H cUs throughout the state. A small foundation of purebred Corriedales wai secured. ; Dairy.-The Holstein herd for the first year of twice-per-day milking averaged 406 pounds of fat for each cow in the herd. The herd was pas - tured during the summer on alfalfa pasture and on a number of cultivated grasses on which studies' are being made at the Substation. Poultry.-The Nebraska flock testing project work was continued in additions breeding worlc with White Rocks and Whtte Leghorn chickens and Mammoth Bronze tilrkeys.; . . frets, vegetables, and lawns.—Trials of trees, shrubs, and perennials are being continued with native species, and accessions.secured chiefly from the U. S. Department of Agriculture. New windbreaks of Chinese elm, Austrian pine, arbWvitae, cedar, and juniper have been set out. Tomato varietal trials indicate that high yield and earl,n«s have been secured in several varieties including Earliana, Bison, Denmark, and All </seg>
         <seg id="p050">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station I I; ' I Red, and two North Dakota Station selections. Some of these need further! improvement in quality and uniformity. Trials of native grasses for lawn! purposes have been continued. Some progress has been made in grub* and weed control by chemicals. . , SCOTTSBLUFF SUBSTATION The Scottsblufl Substation is conducted cooperatively by the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station and the Division of Western Irrigation Agriculture of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Rotations under irri - gation are the most important investigations. Feeding of lambs and dairy cattle is also important. During the year the Substation also conducted some corn and sorghum variety tests and some tests with the spacing of sugar beets. Other agencies conduct work here also. The Experiment Station at Lincoln is conducting some breeding experiments with beans, potatoes, and tomatoes, and variety tests with other vegetables. The Division of Sugar Plants of the L". S. D. A. is conducting variety tests, manure experiments, and breeding work with sugar beets. The Division of Irrigation of the 1. S. D. A. is conducting work on water requirements of crop plants and methods of handling irrigation water. The Division of Forage Crops and Diseases has continued its work with alfalfa. Precipitation for the growing season, April to September, amounted to 14.19 inches as compared with the 29-year mean of 1131 inches. In the watershed of the Pathfinder Dam, precipitation was above that of the drouth years and the mean delivery of water to farms amounted to 1.69 acre feet. Sufficient water was available for the needs of all crops. The growing season. May 8 to October 18, was the longest recorded at the station op to the present time. Hail reduced the yield of small grain approximately 50 per cent at the station. Otherwise weather conditions were favorable. Crop rotation.—The original rotations, concerned with alfalfa and manure, have been in operation since 1912 and rotations including sweet clover have been in operation since 1920. In 1931 rotations including beans were begun and in 1937 rotations were added for the study of phosphate fertilizers. Briefly the rotations cover the subjects of farm manure, alfalfa, and sweet clover as green manure crops, the pasturing of legumes, and commercial phosphate, in addition to crop sequence and the length of rotation. Generally speaking, manure has exerted a greater influence than alfalfa on the yield of sugar beets while alfalfa has increased the yield of potatoes and oats more than manure. Manure and alfalfa together in the same rotation have had the greatest stimulating effect on the yields of crops of any of the treatments involved in the rotation test. The difference in crop yields between the treated and untreated rotations in this respect are essen - tially the same for 1938 as for the 21-year average from 1918 to 1938. During the past year, Bulletin 318, The Value of a Ton of Manure in the </seg>
         <seg id="p051">.'-"•..¦ :¦ . FiFTr-sEcovD Annual Report North PJatte Valley, by Lionel Harris, 20 pages, was published. This bulletin discusses the rotations with special attention to the manure and the livestock population required to maintain profitable crop production. The records for 1938 for other rotation experiments substantiate con - clusions previously published. No conclusions have been reached on the phosphate-fertilizer tests. I": • '•-•."'•". .'. .' Hybrid field corn.— Experiments in 1938 include 31 hybrids and 3 open-pollinated varieties. Several of. the hybrids have promising character - istics. The highest yield was 88 bushels per acre for lowealth 258, but the' hybrid is of no value for this region because of its late maturity. Sorghum varieties.— Four forage varieties and five grain varieties were tested. Lecti produced the highest yield of forage; Sooner milo, Greeley, and Early Kalb are promising grain varieties. ''- ; Spacing sugar beets.— Commercial-stand planting was compared with 100 per cent stand in a series of plots of sugar beets. Ordinary methods of cultivation were used. The average stand in the commercial planting was 83 per cent. The results indicate that a perfect stand of sugar beets does not yield significantly more than an 83 per cent stand. VALENTINE SUBSTATION At the Valentine Substation the experiments that received most attention are those dealing with the wintering of range cattle. Some crop tests are conducted each year with corn, wheat, oats, barley, rye, and the sorghums. Attention is given also to poultry, dual-purpose cattle and other problems peculiar to the northern Nebraska area. Wintering range calves. 9 —The project comparing the relative value of cottonseed cake, soybean oil meal, and tankage as supplements to sandhill meadow hay was repeated. However, instead of feeding one pound, the amount of tankage was reduced to three-quarters of a pound daily so thai the protein intake would be approximately the same for each supplement. The winter gains for a 168-day period were as follows: cottonseed cake 186 pounds, soybean oil meal 148 pounds, and tankage 153 pounds. The three lots were run together on summer range for 105 days and made an average daily gain of 1.80, 1.70, and 1.83 pounds respectively. While the results of the two-years test with tankage show that it com - pares favorably with cottonseed cake and soybean oil meal in producing gain, the price differential will usually make it less profitable to use as a winter supplement. ¦ . ¦-''•. Dual-purpose cattle— Small herds of both milking Shorthorns and Red Polled catde are being maintained in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture. Data from only the dairy phase of the pro - ject are available.. The milk production shows some increase over last year. The average for the Shorthorns was 7,172.8 pounds of milk and * More detaili on ihc livestock work it Valentine on be obtained by writing; directly to the Sub - tution, at Valentine, Nebraska. : -. - - :-¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p052">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 294.6 pounds of fat and for the Red Polled 5,868-9 pounds of milk and 256.6 pounds of fat. Dnring the lactation period all cows were fed a 16 per cent protein concentrate mixture at the rate of one pound to four of milk. When not on grass the dry cows were fed one pound of cottonseed cake as a supple - ment to winter roughage. The loss in weight during Jactation was 24 pounds for the Red Polled and 32 pounds for the Shorthorns. The feed cost for the Shorthorns was enough greater than for the Red Polled to offset most of the advantage in production. It appears that in this region spring freshening is the more profitable with dual-purpose cattle. Poultry.—The turkey flock-testing project showed greater than in the previous years. Turkeys from a flock which was mated with toms from Oregon ranked first in dressed weight, length arid fullness of breast, and in percentage of prime birds. The lot dressing out the lightest was from an unimproved farm flock. There was a difference of 3.31 pounds in the average weight of the toms between the tivo lots and 3.80 pounds in the hens, fn length of breast the difference was 0.66 inch for the toms and 0.69 for the hens. Water level investigations.—The water level of the subirrigated meadow ;« the Substation dropped to a new low in the fall of 1937. However, with rainfall above normal in the spring of 1938 the water level in June was 18 inches higher than that in June the year before. BOX BUTTE EXPERIMENT FARM This farm, comprising 160 acres located northwest of Alliance, has been used during the past eight years for studies of farm crops adapted to the western portion of Nebraska. Potatoes constitute the major crop and good yields were obtained in 1938. The grain crops, consisting of winter wheat, spring grains, corn, soybeans, and sorghum all yielded well this year, thus allowing for very good comparisons of varieties and strains adapted to this locality. Three specific lines of work are conducted at this experimental farm. Foundation seed stocks.—The farm is used for the production of foundation seed potatoes in cooperation with the Nebraska Certified Potato Growers. Selected lines of seed are indexed in the greenhouse and grown in tuber unit plots on the farm. This high-quality seed is being dissemin - ated to farmers who increase it on a few selected seed farms, after which it is available to commercial growers. The seed potato industry is largely dependent on this source of seed stock for the replacement of growers' stocks that have become infected with virus diseases. Likewise, all of the grain produced on the farm is released to growers as seed stock. Rotation plots.—These plots provide a valuable study of the most ad - vantageous crop sequences for this locality. The study includes yield, quality, diseases, and soil factors. A good deal of valuable information </seg>
         <seg id="p053">Fifty-second Annual Report . . . ¦ &gt;: " ' ¦, '-¦ ¦ ••-. ' - ¦ ¦¦ ¦¦¦'¦'¦. has been obtained from these rotation experiments with reference to the effect of different crops upon the soil moisture content and thus upon the yield of. the next crop in the sequence. •'"¦ In addition, there are a large number of experiments being conducted with potatoes, small grains, and corn by representatives of the Experiment Station .at Lincoln. Other experiments in cooperation with the Office of Cereal investigations of the U. S. Department of Agriculture are in pro - gress. The farm thus offers an excellent site for many studies that must of necessity be carried out under the local conditions in that area if the results are to be of value to the farmers in western Nebraska. STATE SERUM PLANT The demand for serum in 1938 was less than last year. Although the price of hogs remained reasonably good throughout the year, there was very little cholera in the state. The State Serum Plant continued its policy of buying its supply of serum and of manufacturing its virus. Serum retailed at 70 cents per 100 cc, throughout the year. Virus re - tailed at 51.60 per 100 cc. . .-,¦'• Following is a report of the serum and virus sales by months and a financial statement showing the status of this activity at the dose of the calendar year 1938: Scrum on hand January I, 1938.... - -!.-....:........ Z,..... ..2,716,400 cc. Serum purchased in 1938...................... - v - : ¦- • i00.000.ee. Total handled for year........... .........,..,.._ .,2,816,400 cc. SERUM AND VIRUS SOLD BY MONTHS FOR 1938 Monti Serum Vims .'¦•¦.¦ . ¦ '.:":¦ ' ¦¦-. cc. . ¦;• cc. ¦¦¦'¦' January :.'. ...... ........... 7,375 ; ¦ 165 February • 1,625 135; March ...,..:..:....,....- 6&lt;&gt;00 April ;............ 17,000 2,530 May ............:... .81,500 6,840 ¦¦¦¦: &amp;~±±=:?gs :¦::;». /. Ktar ,....:.,..........-^5 3,900 Tour... :.:.. ..¦¦¦¦ ...760,725 57,905 Scrum for revaccinarion... 10,625 I Serum on hand January 1, 1939.........:.. -. • ¦ •.............. : - V .2,045,050 cc. I ¦ ¦ ¦ ."¦"¦.¦¦ ¦ ¦ -..¦."¦¦.¦' ... ¦¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Cash balance lanuary 1, 1939 $73,451.15 Reserve for special compensation S 1,584.24 Estimated value scrum stock 5M,315.35 Miscellaneous S 200.00 Total 589,550.74 Total gross sales from all soured . . 5 6,310.94 Money collected and receipted for 5 6,395.58 Number pigs used in making virus 74 Number of orders 581 Gallons gasoline consumed 362 Mileage 2,781. PUBLICATIONS OF THE CALENDAR YEAR 1938 ANNUAL REPORT Fifty-first Annual Report, presented to the Governor February 1, 1938. 1,500 copies. BULLETINS No. 314. Operating Problems of Farmers' Elevators in Nebraska. L. F. Garcy. March, 1938. f&gt;,ooo copies. No. 315. The Use oi Alfalfa and Native Grass Pasture in Producing Finished Cattle. Marvel L. Baker. April, 1938. 8,000 copies. No. 316. Grain ami Forage Sorghums in Nebraska. T. A. Kicssclkich, R. L. Cush - ing, and E. V. Frnlik. April, 1935. 15,000 copies. No. 31". Influence of Rotations under Irrigation on Potato Scab, Rhizoctonia, and Fusanum Wilt. R. W. (ioss and M. M. Afanasicv. May, 1938. 4,000 copies. No. 318. The Value ot a Ton of Farm Manure in the North Plattc Valley. Lionel Harris. May. 193 H. 5,1)01) copies. No. 319. Equipment Expense per Acre on Farms in Nebraska 1926-1930 and 1932- J9J6. Arthur W. Medlar. September, 193 X. 5,000 copies. No. 32D. The Use of Lard in Cake Making. Helen Bacdcr. October, I9jB. 5,000 copies. No. 321. Nebraska Trjctor Tests, 1920-1935. Hoard of Tractor Test Engineers, lanuary, 1939. 10,000 copies. RESEARCH BULLETINS No. 9H. A Proposed Method for Classifying and Evaluating Soils on the liasis of Productivity and Use Suitabilities. Arthur Anderson, A. P. Nelson, F. A. Hayes, and I. D. Wood. May, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 99. The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Household Steam Pressure Cookers. Arnold E. Baragar. May, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 100. The Utilization of Food Elements by Growing Chicks. V. A Comparison of Cottonseed Meal and Linseed Oil Meal as Portions of the Protein Concentrate. C. \V. Ackcrson, M. J. Blish, and F. E. Musschl. June, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 101. The Vitamin A Content of Soybean Silage and A.1.V., Molasses, and Common Corn Silages, and the Effect of Feeding These Materials upon the Vitamin A Content of Milk. I. L. Hathaway, H. P. Davis, and J. C. Braucr. June, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 102. Wound Healing in Potatoes (Triumph Variety) as Influenced by Type of Injury, Nature of Initial Exposure, and Storage Conditions. H. O. Werner. July, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 103. Studies on the Vitamin A Content of Cheese. I. L. Hathairay and H. P. Davis. July, 1938. 2,500 copies. </seg>
         <seg id="p055">Fifty-second Annual Report No. 104. Influence of Age of Dairy Cattle and Season of the Year on die Sex Ratio of Calves and Services Required for Conception. R. F. Morgan and H. V. Davis. August, 1938. 2,500 copies, i . . . No. 105. The Tax System of Nebraska with Special Reference to Its Relation to Agriculture. L. B. Snydcr. October, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 106. The Relation o£ Certain Factors in Farm Family Life to Personality Development in Adolescents. Leland H. Stott October, 1938. 2,500 copies. No. 107. Land Transfers in Twelve Counties in Nebraska, 1928-1933. L. F. Garcy, November, 1938. 2,500 copies. ; " '¦'&#132;. . CIRCULARS ' No. 40 (revised and reprinted). A Manual for Hog Raisers. Wm. j. Loefiel. October, 1938. 15,000 copies. .' No. 50 (revised and reprinted). Bindweed Eradication. F. D. Keim, D. L. Gross, and R. C. Kinch. March, 1938. 25,000 copies. No. 56. The Prevention of Anthrax. L. Van Es. February, 1938. 10,000 copies. No. 57. Your Pressure Cooker: How to Choose It and How to Use It for Canning. Arnold E. Baragar. June, 1938. 10,000 copies. ¦ : V.. No. 58. Feeding and Care of Calves. R. R. Thalman. August, 1938. 7,500 copies. No. 59. Common Native 'Grasses of Nebraska. A. 1. Frolik and F. D. Keim. December, 1938. 10,000 copies. </seg>
         <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND ¦ " Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, uisullment for the fiscal year ended /une JO, 1938 under act of Congress approved March 2, 1887. Total .. '. . 5 15,000.00 „ , Expenditures Forsalancs 515,000.00 ToQl $15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts RCC7 mt y u C Su'c,, Trasu «f. «*n is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June JO, 1938, under act of Congress approved March 16, 1906. Tool '. °'_ J lsi oo o oo Expenditures For "lan" 5/5,000.00 ToUl PURNF.U. FUN'W Receipts . , RCT V 1" I"" SlaK M TrasurCT- &gt;"ho » ¦¦'«• 'he treasurer of the University ..t Vcbraska. ,ns,ulln,cnt tor the fiscal year ended June 30, 1938 under act of G, nK rc« appromi February M, 1925. Total ... . . ' salar.es and wages E*v««i'"»« Regular employees 543.H9 19 Tem[)orary employees 5*667^9 SUPPLIES '"'¦'' 548.812.0S Office supplies s 550 - Laboratory supplies 3 0-17 31 Educational and recreational ' 37 65 Tanitor and barn supplies 3'cj Feeding stuffs ,„/- Agricultural supplies jg^j EXPENSE T°al 5 3,8-19.27 Office expense and postage 5 7" 61 Freight, express, and drayagc lQ2q Public printing, advertising, and photo supplies I 2-JI 44 Traveling expense 630 47 Rentals 6^-^ Special and temporary service 3 23169 Total 5 5,217.50 </seg>
         <seg id="p057">; Fifty-second Annual Report REPAIRS '. . . : :•¦.!•¦. ¦ Equipment i ....... .$ 117.57 . ...: ¦¦ T0ta1............................. S 147.57 ' EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures. $200.57 Apparatus, labor, and equipment 1,101.62 Machinery ..'.' 88.50 . Books, magazines, and maps. 45.39 T0ta1........'.. &#132;...'.;. $ 1,436.08 LANDS AND BUILDINGS ' Land impr0vement................. ........$ 50.64 Additions and improvements. 486.86 T0ta1......... S 537.50 ;-.'¦¦ GRAND T0TAL.;..;........,....,.... $60,000.00 ' : \ . ¦ BANKHEAD-JONES FUNDS i' ' ' ' ¦' .. ¦'¦.', ¦' " Receipts .. ._¦"'. ' ¦'¦•¦•'-:'¦ ! Received by the Slate Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University ! of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1938, under ! "act of Congress approved June 29, 1935. Total $29,082.45 Expenditures SALARIES AND WAGES . Regular emp10yee5......................... $21,470.09 i Temporary employees ../..]............. .... 1,312.50 ¦/¦¦¦¦ Total •..).,. ¦_. ¦...,....;-...;....' : . ¦!¦; $22,782.59 ':' SUPPLIES ¦ | '",:.¦¦-'¦ ¦ ' '. Office 5upp1ie5...........;..,....... .$ 48.00 Laboratory 5upp1ie5......].:.......... '... 291.83 Agricultural supplies... : 324.69 • T0ta1............................. $ 664.52 ' expense- ¦'.:' ¦..¦;¦. .'; - - : ¦;'¦ .'.:.- .¦. : :...-.: . ¦ Traveling expense.. r ... .$ 196.3") Special and temporary service. . ............ 1,103.42. '! T0ta1.......:;..,.,......,,....... : $1,299.76 \ REPAIRS Equipment .....,.% 61.87 Total..; $ 61.87 EQUIPMENT "....¦ ;'. :'¦'..- Apparatus, labor, and equipment.. ....:.,$ 2,345.07 Machinery ..,..,..,.....:.......... ;.... 621.87 Books, magazines, and maps.. ;.:... ;... .4.98 ; &gt;¦ T0ta1..:.!... v.;,.. ...... .-v... ; $2,971.92 </seg>
         <seg id="p058">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station lands and buildings Land improvements 5 1J4.89 Additions and improvements 1,166.90 Total $ 1,301.79 GRAND TOTAL $29,082A5 L. E GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary </seg>
         <seg id="p059">Fifty-second Annual Report FINANCIAL STATEMENT EXCLUSIVE OF FEDERAL FUNDS Statement of expenditures of the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year enduig June 30, 1938 (exclusive of Federal funds), including expenditures for central station at Lincoln and substations at North Plane, Scottsbluff, Valentine, Union, and Alliance. SALARIES AND WAGES ' Regular emp10yee5!.,......... ..$61,639.70 . ¦ Temporary employees ...J........ 6,150.85 ; , T0ta1..................... $67,790.55 SUPPLIES Office supplies ..,......:...$ 1,100.72 . Laboratory supplies ; ..: ......;........ 8,325.19 • • Fuel (c0a1)......... 1,167.42 . Foodstuffs 1,448.62. . A Educational and recreati0na1.................... 24.04 j Janitor and barn supplies.. ..1,211.24 . ( Feeding stuffs.... |.:............. 44,104.16 * Agricultural supplies;....:... .. 4,835.69 T0ta1....;..,.. ................. $62,217.08 EXPENSE ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦ ' ¦¦-'¦".' ' ¦' : '¦'.¦¦¦ - "¦ ¦'¦ Office expense and postage.... $2,135.78 Freight, express, and drayage 1,219.62 Water, heat, light, and pb\ycr........ ... 6,846.07 Public printing, advertising and photo supplies 3,353.64 Traveling expense 2,576.29 Rentals .................... 37730 Special and temporary seniccs... 28,829.31 Miscellaneous 621.76 . ¦ T0ta1.... .....^...../........:.. ; $45,959.77 REPAIRS ' : Buildings ................... ...............;$ 3,173.74 Lands .................... ..... ..... 658.96 Equipment 1........ 1..... 6,593.79 T0ta1......;.:.... $10,426.49 EQUIPMENT . '¦''¦:¦ ••¦¦; ¦¦¦;¦ Furniture and fixtures..... 7 $1,254.70 Apparatus, labor, and cquiimcnt.. , .4,963.68 Livestock ..........K... 15,106.21 Machinery 5,540.33 Books, magazines, and maps.. 236.73 ¦ .¦¦:•. Total.. :...J..V $27,101.65 LANDS AND BUILDINGS i ¦ . Land improvement.......! ..:...........$ 396.07 Additions and improvements.. 320.82 T0ta1.¦.¦•.:;................:..,: $ 716.89 . GRAND T0TALJ....,........;....... : $214,212.43 Lincoln, Nebraska i }.. L. E. GUNDERSON, j --".:'- -'¦¦- : ¦'¦; Finance Seaetary ..¦¦ ¦."¦¦¦ -k. •¦' ¦:.-, : .:¦ -: ¦¦¦¦¦¦¦¦.- ¦ (ikm) </seg>
         <seg id="p060"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>