<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A.  THE BLEACHING OF WHEAT FLOUR</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">A r 1 &amp; UHKTLTUKAL EXPERIMENT STATION Press Bulletin No. 24 Distributed February to. iqoq THE BLEACHING OF WHEAT FLOUR. BY K. J. Al.WAT. f high jinttle Nebraska wheat Hours have a more or less yellow len freshly milled. This color slowly fades when the flour is in ■ well lighted place, but even after several months is Btill mm times a yellow tint was considered desirable. r merchant demands the whitest possible Hour." This matter, which resembles a coal tar dye in many re- xeeediugly minute in quantity and is contained in the fat te flour, (waring the same relation to this that butter color i&gt; the pure fat of butter. The coloring matter is not an essen - nstituent of the fat. the latter being, when pure, colorless like and forming only about one per cent of the weight of th« flour. LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">The yellow flours becOBM wliiti&gt; when exposed in thin iu\- - bright sunlight or treated with liquids that are able to dissolve rh -uch as ether, chloroform and benzei on In- olor when ex to the suiishini'. These tuav be considered is, nitrogen peroxide, which electrical process, and in others by the decomposition of nit Accordingly, the effect of bleaching should which kind of apparatus is used ■otation is obtained wkicl </seg>
            <seg id="p003">) far been examined, as well as a have ace from two to eighteen months g in ag tained more or less bleached flour. These seven the bleached Hour- re &lt;&gt;l&gt; Of trier il pi .nd 16 from six mills t three were sent by a miller who that he used Ten samp!' i ten months, and of which lv examined fu •art II )ur be positively identified? Yes lent for nitrites gives a pink coloration with nil UK lve Im .ny change in the composition of be detected bv an ordinarv flour ubstance added to the flour during the &gt;ture is the small amount of nitrite that is nmierciallv bleached flours. The amount of i considered as sodium nitrite) in the Nebraska bleached flours roin A to 15 parts per million of flour. The average found in bleached by electrical processes is 4.53. and by chemical Fourth — Is nitrite present in bread made from bleached flour ? .iinihvd ami wvea live-pound sample* hich were obtained from 21 different mills cd. 12 were from four mills having n&lt;&gt; d flours from mills having bleach. .■n which were sent as an The other no coloration with unl&gt;l&lt; ■on stored beaide bleached flours for substance iiresent that could well be </seg>
            <seg id="p004">yields ;i bread showing no nitrite, in other cases about -5 us mucti ■ad seems to determine the amount nitrite. The method of making brt of nitrite remaining. Fifth- -Is the amount ■ I nitrite in bleached Hour, or in bread from bleached Hour, sufficient to be injurious? No. Nitrites 1 in the saliva, and usually in larger quantities than in bleached Sixth — Are the bread-making properties of dour injured by t No In order \o answer this question, loaves of bread wert Kfrom '_'l — plea of unbleached flours as well as frc iirs which had been bleached iu 13 different Nebraska writer weighed and measured the ingredients, while tht baking was done 1&gt;\ one of the be immercial bakers The loaves were accuratelv weighed and measured. Tht ture, odor, and taste of the two members of each of the 21 1 compared. In all cases the bleached ave the whiter loaf \ difference was detected iu odor or in taste. The text in both. The 21 loaves from bleached flours togetht no In some pairs the bleach* ,v iu others, the unbleached agreement as iu the weight. T amounted to 2.19i» cubic inches - the two loaves of a | As the result of the inv iii*: wheat flour whitens th&lt; &lt;&gt;z., while tbf l!l \onrta fron cubic inches In 11 pairs the bleach -mailer. ;md m one of &gt;sition. odor. t;isre. texrnr* </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>