<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00004.00002">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>npd.00004.00002</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FIFTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF REGENTS TO THE GOVERNOR, LAID BEFORE THE LEGISLATURE AT ITS TWENTY-SEVENTH SESSION, 1901</title>
		             <date value="1900">1900</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-26</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-31</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">L- SERIES 5, NO- 8 The University of Nebraska FIFTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Board of Regents TO THE GOVERNOR Laid Before the Legislature at its Twenty-Seventh Session, 1901 Lincoln The University Press December, 1900 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Part I The Board of Regents 3 Letter of transnnttal 4 4 Chancellor's letter to the Board of Regents 5 General survey by the Chancellor — Growth 8 Material prosperity — New law New law 6 Equipment .• 7 Attendance 8 I Internal change — Col leges 8 ( ouneil 9 9 Congregation 9 The Alumni. 9 9 Secondary technical schools 10 Department changes 10 Administrative officers 11 10 11 11 University extention 12 Resume 13 U The Regents' estimate for the biennium ■iMMVMi 14 Expenditures 14 Discussion of estimates 15 Reports of administrative officers — Report of the Dean of the Graduate School 18 Report of the Dean of College of Literature, Science and the Arts.. . . 19 is Report of the Dean of the Industrial College 20 Report of the Dean of the College of Law 21 Report of the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station 88 Report of the Director of the School of Agriculture Report of the Director of the School of Art Report of the Director of the School of Domestic Science Report of the Director of the School of Mechanic Arts Rc|M&gt;rt of the Director of the Affiliated School of Music 26 Report of the Acting Director of the Chemical Laboratories 26 Report of the Librarian 27 Report of the Curator of the State Museum -J» L Report of the Superintendent of Farmers' Institutes 31 Report of the Inspector of Accredited Schools :tj Report of the Registrar (tabulated statement) 85 iparative tables with other state universities 44 Diagrams showing increase in buildings, enrollment, growth of colleges and schools, and total appropriations 46 1'ART II Financial statement of the secretary, J. S. Dales Latter of transmittal •&gt; Temporary University fund — salaries and wages 3 General fund — State University 50 N Temporary University fund— current expenses 58 General fund— Mechanic Arts Hall Temporary University fund — permanent improveiaents 83 University cash fund — Morrill fund (United States) 108 Agricultural Experiment Station (United States) 118 Agricultural Experiment Station— farm cash rio </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 II "ti II. L. Goold, OgmlaJla Ten expires January, 1902 Bob. (lias. H. liorrill, Lincoln Term expires January, ISM Hun. E. v. Forell, Kearney . Term expires January. 1904 Boa. Geo. F. Kanower, Wlmr Term expires January, 1904 linn John L. Testers. Lincoln Term expires January, 1908 Hon. Kelson Rick, ( Imaha Term expires January, 1906 OFFICERS Hon. E. v. Forell, President. Kearney. J. Stuart Dales. Secretary, Lincoln. E. Benjamin Andrews Chancellor. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 the Fifteenth Biennial Report of the Board of Regents of The University of Nebraska for the Biennium ending November 30, 1900. In the Re - ports are included a general survey of the progress of the University by the Chancellor, the estimates by the Regents of its needs for the coming bienniurn, and rei&gt;orts of various officers, together with the financial state - ment of the Secretary -Treasurer. Very respectfully, your obediant servant. K v. Fokell. I President of the Board of Regents of The University of Nebraska. Unirerstty or Nebraska, offlcr of tbe Board or Regents. January I. 1901. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 OK THK KOARD OK REdENTS OF THK UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA TO THE GOVERNOR ITo the Hoaku of Regents: I have the honor to present herewith a :ral survey, based upon the reports of heads of college* and depart - ts, of the progress of the University during the biennium just closed. E. Hknj.vmis Andkews, Chancellor. January 1, 1901. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GROWTH IMF, Spirit uk PsXMWM. — 'I'lii* past hiennium has bew characterized l&gt;y sami' external ami internal growth that the University has enjoyed for tin* uli' preceding. In the headship of the University an interregnum of one ■ has existed. Demo Bcisey acting a* Chancellor from Chancellor Mac - »'i resignation in August, ls'.iit. until Chancellor AiuIitivs ammed tin' i's of the office in August, HKM). Notwithstanding this period of suspense lalt. no deterioration has ooeurred. The opening of the praaeal year ni all parts of the administration in the be~t of order ami all tit-part uients istruction prosperous, MATERIAL I'KOSl'KKITY Ikw l.vw -The most signal ante of University prosperity is the law led by the last legislature granting a one-mill levy on the grand assessmeul instead of a three -eighths mill levy From at I sources the University the liieiiniuin has received MM.000 asagainst :!u-j.ii&lt;io for the previous Men - n ami 1340,144 for the two years. L8B6-7. Sine. ■ the I'niversity did not \ e lienelits of the new law until January 1-t. ItWO, its full value has. a- \ .! cely been felt. Nevertheless, new buildings have been ereeteil and per - lent improrements been made both on the I'niversity Cansnaw and at the persity Farm. iithe( ainpus the I'niversity Soldiers' llemorial llallhas been completed is an addition to the west end of Grant Memorial Hall. It contains, '■■- - rooms in the basement, a large auditorium with a seating cap M. The haniNome pipe organ, reoently girea to the rniversity hy its mi. has been placed in this hall. It is planned that ultimately Grant lorial Hall and I'niversity Soldiers' Memorial Hall will Ik 1 used entire y lie Mil'tary and Physical Training Departments, sttf this cannot come to until a "University Auditorium" is provid *. I by the legislature. An addition of forty f ft in length lias been placed on the west en I of the l&lt;oil«*r lioii-e. a new chimney has been built, and two new boUanot 1M r each have been adde I to the power plant. This new i'i|uipineut will provide the Campus bnJIdings with ample steam hearing ami power for ser - eral years at least. imay be mentioned, incidentally, that the interior of Mechanic Arts Hall of the Koun.lry have been improved, the Campus has been beautilietl In - constant care of a gardener, new walks have bsM laid, and docks have n pla&lt;fd in the main corridors of all halls. Just south of Library Hall a ,nish War cannon, donated by the government to the city of Lincoln, has n mounted upon a pedestal and stands as a memorial of the late war. us now exist for ararting a memorial to Colonel Stotsenburg, who met death in the Philippines. The wind, rain and electrical storm of August did considerable damage to the grounds anil buildings, blowing in win- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 valuable trees. It 19 fortunate that the )o— was m« p.1— till, for the wind was of hurricane velocity, seventy-six miles an hour, an&lt;l the University ■ tin 1 path of its [rrslosl violence. tthe Slate Kami the new K\perimeiit Station Mkxmg has btN ti cosi of al&gt;oiit M5.000. Toig bailding furnishes accommodations for the •riment Station stall', and will also furnish temporary quarters for the Agricultural School. A steam beating anil power plant has been ei near by, anil a system of boiler works Installed, furnishing ample supply for the buildings, also for tin- protection and the needs of the feed yardl :irns. These latter improvements cost HO. 000 ii ii'mk.n r- —The University has increase, I its equipment in many general Library now number* 4",000 volumes, a,, increase of 10,006 1 during the bienniutn. lu greatest growth has been in the departmental ries. which now number eleven, with a seating capacity of 230. ral reading mom has lieen enlarged, now Mating 300 student-, i&gt;y Decimal System iscoaiplete in the entire Library and its department - ic publication of bulletin- and by cooperation with other libraries in the ■. the I'niversity Library is extending its iullucnce with remarkabl University's Mn-ram out til ha- grown steadily, both the Museu proper and the dcpartiiiental musenms having received rich accessions. I pan men ts draw upon the Museum for material used in illustration and in oth Eodsof instruction. Many of the collections have been donated tot 11m by private parties ( liief among ibesc are the geological eollectio Regent Charles H. Morrill, ami the archaeological collection of fo and Indian relies from different states donated by Dr. M. H. Kvei, •In. The University is ander the greatest obligation to both th. - tleineii. Perhaps the Agricultural Museum has enjoyed the 1110-t remarkab growth of all. This now illustrates the forestry of the State as represent* by timbers, shrubs, and Insects injurious to vegetables. It possesses em specimen -ets of grains, fruits, grasses and soils. Tae State Board c Agriculture take- an aetire interest in this department of the Museum and ■Wring much among the farmer- of the State to promote its value. The Historical Society's rooms in the basement of Library Hall are now completely tilled. Almost every available inch of the space that existed - ago is utilized. As a result of its activity the Societv many valuable collections, and its lilesof State newspaper- are recognized n - of great practical and historical worth. The Herbarium has grown until it at present contains 10(1,000 specin and is in itself large enough to take rank as a distinct part of the University. A marked advance in the nmnber and quality of University publieati. apparent, especially in -uch as relate to the administrative offices of the University and to the Experiment Station. Another number of the Uni - ty Stadies has been published. The Graduate Club has issued its first Graduate Magazine and several publications have appeared in print from certain classes in the Alumni Association. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 women's parlor ami rest room recently furnished, in better facilities against fire protection and in the fund for the care of the sick. This fund, it is hoped, is a nucleus from which will (trow a University Infirmary. A University station of the post otlice for the regular distribution and handling of the mail by government officials has been applied for and will probably be eitebliahad in the mm future. It is hoped that a direct street car line to the University Farm will soon bring the agricultural work into closer connection with the University. Attkndam K — The whole number of enrollments the past biennium lias been i,\V) as against 3. 56* during the preceding biennium: a gain of 16.3 per cent The whole number of students in lH'.tK. the last year of the pre - ceding biennium WM 1.915; in 190&lt;), 2.2»KI. a gain of IS,\ per cent. An in - -•' of 13J |&gt;er cent occurred in the two years of this biennium, that is from 1,94&lt;"&gt; in June. 1899, to 2.209 in June, 1900. The Graduate School slums a large increase in attendance: namely SI per cent, and in numl&gt;ers growing from in in 18M to 14H in 1900. During the biennium the Universr drawn from the same Mmber of counties as during the preceding biennium. although not the same counties. Some of these counties show a remaikable increase in the attendance. This is especially true of counties in the wttt and in the North l'iatte country Douglas county also shows a remarkable increase of over 100 per cent. IXTKKNAL CHANGE Important internal changes have taken place in the University. I affect principally the entrance requirements, the curricula, and the adminis - tration of the University. The developments along these lines i- a natural evolution of the institution toward the broad, harmonious University idea! of the middle u TllK OOUMD.- While Um entrance requirements have kWM raised by i«n credit pi&gt;iuts. they have at the same time l)een broadened so that instead of twenty-six points in required subjects Mag demanded, the requirements now call for seventeen point* in required subjects and eleven points in optional subject- These optionals are chosen from fifteen different subjects, covering a total of twenty-two credit points Hand in hand with the change in the entrance requirements the curricula of the University have been greatly broadened. In the (iraduate School more subjects are offered by the various departments than ever before, and twenty-four out of thirty departments in the University are now offering graduate instruction. The group system has been al&gt;olished in the College of Literature. Science and the Arts, in which, with the exception of his first year, the student now has free election of subjects The group system in the Industrial College is still maintained. In April, 1899. an important change in the government of the University occurred, affecting principally these two colleges. The General Faculty was dissolved, the University Senate revived, the faculties differentiated and given power to administer the affairs of their separate colleges. Memlwrship in the faculty of the Graduate School was ex - tended to the Dean and professors giving instruction. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 A reorganizition of the Law School also took place whereby the lecture 11 has been practically al&gt;aml&lt;&gt;neil ami more capful anil extended work demanded of students by the instructors As an earnest of the adv , ment of the Uw School and the need of widening its scope, the I'niv. Senate presented to the Supreme Court of Nebraska a memorial that tt (luirements for admission to the bar of the state l&gt;e raised to three JN work, in order that the College of Ijiw might advance its requirements for graduation to that term of residence. ImUm the revival of the University Senate and the division of the I lie-, still more important features, inaugurated at the same lime widened the Held of the University, brought it more closely into touch with the other colleges of the state and crowned it as the head of the educational system of Nebraska. Thk Council. — The University Council has been organized. This con - sists of the Chancellor. I he dean of all schools and colleges, the heads of de - partments and the Secretary of the Board of Regents of The University of Nebraska, the heads of departments in the College Union of Nebraska, the principals of accredited sehools. the (iovernor of the state, the Lieutenant (Jovernor. the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, the Speakerof the I: of Representatives. State Superintendent of Public Instruction and his deputy ami I ho I— pm Inr nl Accredited Schools This ( ouncil meets twice a year, on Charter Day and at Commencement, at which times it KM* (iiesiions concerning University policy as related to the educational interests of the state The Con&lt;;kk&lt;;atk&gt;v — The University Congregation has likewise beea in - stituted. Its purpose is to cement closely the variouselements which makeup the University life in its broadest sense. Its membership coiisiMs. of the Regents and the entire instructional force of the University, the Doctor! of I' ophy from this University and all graduates of three or more years standing who keep their names on the book of the Congregation by the payment of an annual fee. The Congregation also includes student delegates in each in each college and school of the University and in each permanent or - ganization. These various elements, bound together in the Congregation, meet twice a year, on Charter Day and at Commencement, toheai important aits of the Regents and Faculty and to engage in general d sion concerning the needs of the University. In these two organizations, the Council and the Congregation, not H organized in detail, are to be found the factors for a strong, generous mad far reaching influence favoring the University spirit and University ideals. Thk Au mm. — The alumni of the University now numlier 1,422. A large part of them still reside in Nebraska and herein is a tower of strength, lx&gt;th for the external and the internal development of the institution. More than ever the alumni are exerting their influence in the various affairs of the state religious, educational and political. But it is a pleasure to fee) that the alumni, as they become engaged in their life work, do not lose, but rather gain in affection and regard for their Alma Mater. During the past year the alumni of the College of Literature. Science and the Arts and the Indus - trial College and the alumni of the College of Law. until a year ago separate </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ill the ill i &gt; &gt;d feeling ami harmony of a nn- much for the -trength of Ihcimganiialinii - relation to t lie University. A pleasing recognition of the women graduates of the institution has lately comic in tin- form of their ad n National AsmK-imtiun of Collegiate Alumnae. A Motion of tlii- A - tion hat been formed at the I'niversity and is regarded as cine of the stronge-t ■ 11- in an organization granting membership only to the largest an. I -t institutiou of die country. UWDABI Tb iimi Al. Si HOOLM — The greatc-i possibility of the Inner • roiiilarv work of a practical nature, namely, in the iiiuie. Domestic Science and Mechanic Arts. Throughout the past twoyear- the work in the-e school- baa been augmented and in - • ■■I. tlie practical instruction ha- broadened ami the technical instrnc - become more comprehensive The eleven weeks' winter cour-e iii . b, now extended to cover two year*, ha- proved popular all over the - In fact it- success ha- created a demand for a similar course iii the School of anic Arts. Certificate* are bow granted to students completing the of these aecondary school*. An important step in their developi ha- been taken recently in the plans for the accredit ing of village and rural these practical secondary school- of the University. By thi - - student* from rural -elm., Is may enter ihe -el 1- of Agriculture. stic Science and Mechanic Arts without examination a- gradual' ilite&lt;l high schooli now enter the regular courses of the Univi Kiving to the advanced stage that -ugar culture has reached in the -tate sugar - .-hoo! ha- been di-continncd. although co-operative experiment - still carried on by the Department of Chemistry on the standard i lpany's lields mar Ames, Nel'ta-ka. intil a year and a half ago the School of Fine Arts was affiliated with the ver-ity in the -ame manner as the School of .Music i- at present atliliatcd ieptentber, l^'.Ki. however, the University as-nined control of the admin ition of the School of I'ine Arts. It is -till maintained as formerly by . but its growth ha- been -o favorable as to demand immediate attention plan- tor it- expansion. IBS affiliated School of Music ha- enjoyed unusual prosperity. Its attend ■ has steadily grown from WH to 4*.~&gt;. By the addition of new and highly ned instructors, by the equipment of the school with twenty-live new ids and by acquiring the use of the large alumni organ now in the L'ni ■ ity Soldier- Memorial Hall, the School of Mu-ic has greatly inci 'Pportnnitie- for general mu-ieal culture. The school ha- started in a II way a system of musical exten-ion by courses of lecture- given in iv of the small cities and towns of the state. Dki'autmkm (iiam.k-- Since the last biennial report four new depart Jin nt- have l&gt;een added, i. *., Linguistic Science and Sanscrit. Semitic Ijin - guagc. embracing Hebrew . As-yrian, Arabic: Bililiography for the evten-ion of Library Siience. and Animal Husbandry. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 te Departments &lt;&gt;f Kngli-h sad Knglish Literature hav- I. In time :i department of Sociology may evolve from tl res on that (abject given under llie auspice-; of the Association of I il &lt; harities. (the Department of Military Science no * 'g"*" army officer has yet detailed by the Government The reports of the government inspec - however. -how that the department under the sii|&gt;ervision of United • Volunteer otlicers has maintained its usual high and flourishing con - n. It is probably only a question of time before the detail of a regular ■ ollicer will l&gt;e secured. For the lirst time tlie system known as "CoBMhutg Department^' lias leoogaiaed. By this plan departments that are likely to be affected by any general action, as for iuMatice tho*e embraced in the term Engineering, the right of collective consultation ami may together report to the authorities. Ihmimsti! \ 1 1\ K Offk kk- With the growth of the Univer-ity the duties aining to the administration of the institution have become heavier, e involved and of wider scope. Daring the past two year» tlie-c execu - fiinction~. following along the wiae plain of Chancellor Macl.ean's illustration, have been more thoroughly differentiated, still maintaining long and centralized power in the Chancellor, more dignity and scope e been added to the office of Dean, and a large amount of details of goT - ment placed in the hands of those officers. An examining dean has been ointed. invested with all the authority pertaining to entrance reqnire - it-. a power which formerly rested in committees. Tbeofltoeof Recorder also licen created, in whoso custody the records of the (acuities, deaas, various committees arc centered. Kkks. The attendance of the University has -o far outgrown the resources that it has bean found necessary to institute some speeial fees a- a source of innniie. It il now a law that a student nniM matriculate for each degree for which he wishes to pur~ue work, except in the case of transfer of colleges within the University. A fee of iM per letcster is charged for (tndents in the Graduate school who are non-residents of Nebraska, but students who have taken the degree of Ph. 1&gt;. are allowed the freedom of the 1'iiiversity Beginning with next year it is intended to charge a special fee of $3 to all students who are not registered at the close of the sixth week-day of &gt;uch -icr. this fee to be remitted only by the Chancellor and only on pre-en - tation of good and sufficient reasons for such late regi&gt;tration or reregis - t ration. KKeussions of a plan to continue teaching thru the year, of the removal of the University to the State Farm with a view of larger Campus and hattsw facilities, of the question ••! internal revenue and of the possiblity of a per - manent Chancellor's residence have occurred at various meetings of the Board trents and the faculties All such discussions show a healthy condition, and point the direction of the University's growth. Eie lovalty and the industry shown by the teaching force of the Univer - are altogether exemplary Whenever required — which is oftener than it to be necessary — professors and instructors cheerfully labor long hours </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 t teach excessively large classes. Many are constantly engaged with oal work— creditable lx&gt;th to them and in the University. The behavior I students (luring t lie biennium has been, with scarcely iin exception, all could be desired. UN IVERSITY EXTENSION Im Experiment Station does not stand alone in prac ical ai d extended ; for tlie people. The University s work is almost ; s wide. At present ■stemati/.ed courses of lectures and instruction exist as in some other in - tions. The rapid growth of the University within itself has prevented The instructional force lias all that it can do without seeking to meet Icmand for outside appointments. Busy profes-ors. neverthele-s, tind formany lectures, especially baton Farmer-' and Teachers' institutes, schools, Woineiis' clubs and Agricultural societies. An increased deiu.ind for the use of the libraries, the museum, herbarium and oilier accessories of the University by the public, lias been gladly met. Publications of wider scope and greater variety have been circulated. Among may be mentioned Vol. IV of the University Studies, issued after an interval of several years Bulletins concerning the formation and use of libraries have proved ■&gt; popular means of arousing inteiest among clubs, rural and high schools, in this important branch of education. The Botani - cal Survey has been continued, its results taking form in the second edition of ■lVtogeography of Nebraska. just is-ued. It is al-o matter for congratu - i that the individual publications of the instructional force are almost as numerous this hiennium as last For the tirst time a catalogue of publication* has been compiled. It shows a list of works nearly all of which have acquired national renown and many international recognition. In widening this influence of the University the inspection of high schools has accomplished more than ever liefore. for this ins|&gt;ection has gradually applied to nearly all high schools in Nebraska and many in the trib - utary territory outside the state. Through the co-operation of the county superintendents it has extended even to rural and village schools. The extension spirit has developed along other broad lines. Fifty-one Farmers' Institutes were held last winter, covering all parts of Nebraska. Tin 1 professors in the Industrial College were the main workers andthfse in - stitutes were a potent factor in bringing the work of the University lief ore many rural districts. Many lecturers and workers not connected with the Uni - v. some of them l&gt;eing of national prominence, were secured. Insti - for this year have been planned on a much larger scale, from which correspondingly larger results are anticipated. I he University has continued and enlarged its work for teachers. The mier sessions for teachers have been well attended and productive of the t results. The committee on the appointment of University graduates to po - )iis has become extremely important as is recognized by the constant de - nd upon it for recommendation by school boards. Within fouryearsone ldred and MM teachers' certificates have lieen issued to graduates of the iversity taking their degrees of A. B. or B. Sc, which signify that these dent- have completed the requirements for the University Teachers' </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Irse. Thus the University is taking young people from the schools of the e and returning them to the schools thoroly trained for school work in r respective localities. The University is not only the head of the q in a way the center, its usefulness radiating outward. More and more iducational interests are gathered about it. The various stat - welcome and glad to accept the freedom of the University in holding r annual meetings. During ihe holidays hundreds of teachers attending meeting of the State Teacher* Association are upon the ground. The State ,rd of Agriculture. Horticulture. State Dairymen and Improved Stock ••ders' Associations are equally welcome guests of the University. 1 he sociological opportunity for extension work was recognized some years ago, but it has l&gt;een only during the past bienuium that this opportunity has been fully grasped and that it has found expression in the work of the Col - settlement and the Association of Associated Clmrr RESUME E viewing the two years, then, they have been eminently a perii&gt;d of Iv growth and progress. Financially, the commonwealth of Nebraska liberally recognized the need- of the institution. The University ha - d to its ctiiciciicy in buildings, equipment, improvements and strong ling. In attendance it has enjoyed more than a natural increase. Its nal evolution has l&gt;een along broad and natural lines of true University ■ncement. Finally it has widened its -phere of inlluenee, reaching out the most practical help to the remotest l&gt;orders of the state, yet al the ! time maintaining the highest ideals of scholarship and culture. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ENDING MARCH 81, 1903 KESOCBt'KS tinill tax &lt; .n grand aawament roll for liH)l 000,000.00 approximately) $17:5.000 00 rmil] tax on grand assessnien roll for I'M) hoO.CHkiuo approximately l?.-&gt;,000 00 i Illr:li ■!" leased and gold itwo rears) ii peimanent fund investments, C'niver 100.000 00 §-ity and Agricultural ( ollege (two years) Iry miscellaneous receipts two yea '•Murrill Fund " (U. s ,. two rears 12.000 00 r&gt;(K) 00 ."•o.ooti on jrieultural Experiment SUi"ion fond (U. S two rears t" University rash" fund, collections of fees and chargies f«»r all purposes and from all 3(1.0(10 0U sources, including lialanee in the hands of t'lx state treasurer '■:, March 31, l'.Kil. (two ycar- :.-&gt;(miii ihi M15 ."KMi i&gt;0 KXPKNDITLKKS &gt;,„ I/,,- Tewtporarg Umivtnitp Fund I the executive officers, tli teaching corps, and other employees, $144. iKHmmi unnu . 1 1 v . . m oo Itl current expenses, *:(:!. r.OO.o:) annually. including apparatus': books: departmental ex - -. rarmers' institutes: fuel, jras. water and light furniture: incidental e\|&gt;enses. printing, postage a. d stationery: state surreys (hot :ii.. (iT.OOO 00 I permanent improvement* and repairs.iorliiding new buildingand equipment: addition to heating apparatu-and tiiniiels; S eneral repairs and inain - \m ance: disposition of sewage at the farm: i and tire protection apparitus: electric lignl machines and wiring: roof for coal areas remodeling north wing of central building (law college : special rep Mrs to chemical laboratory and general science liuildings: sheds, fences and improvemeiits at the farm: ventilating ap - paratus for Grant Memorial Hall: equipment of Experiment Station building at the farm; rontingent expeaaes on works of improvement. 105.500 OH payable from the Temp. Tniversity Fund, carri. L'd forward $400,500 (10 I.Vniuls Mini intend nn Unirersity and Agriim </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Payable f rum the University Cash Fund. [Inclu - sive i if cash in state treasury Mar. 31. V.»)l : ■ services iu farm anil dairy schools: graduate school; summer school; school of line arts; fakW scl I; in labocmtor.es; and for farm expenses, stock and labor: books: iaw school expi laboratory expen-es and (applies; expenses in t ( several special schooll named above: out - standing indebtedness, and for all other pur - pose* for which fees and charges are collected by I he Ini veisity 75.000 00 Payable from the ••Morrill Fami" tuo finral years ending June .'in. 1MB, and June SO, 1908, respectively): ■ services, equipment, apparatus and facilities for instruction in the school and college of agri- culture and the mechanic aits, as required by ihe act of Congress approved Aug. 8U. 18!K) . .'. ."&gt;0, (KX) 00 Payable from the Agric. Fx/ier. Station Fund — U. S. ' For the two fiscal years ending June 19O3, and June -Hi. V.hiS. respectively): ■ services, equipment, apparatus, and the ex - penses of investigations and the publishing of results as required by the act of Congress ap - proved March -'. 1887 30.000 00 ( Grand total *r» 1 .1. .100 Oil Vlie above grand total the state supplies the one mill tax only, aggregating for the two years. $349,000 00 approximately I Lotted States land endowment, cash appropriations, interest i funds, and ca-h collected at the I plies the remainder United Stales in permanent niversity. sup- ■jor..-)00 oo M13.50O 00 KKMEMBER THK \BOVE ESTIMATES EB Board of Regents has made er-iiy and has determined to as will keep the institution up tional corps, and as will, on th a careful study of all the needs of the present to the legislature inch re.; on a high plane of efficiency as to its in- property side, mahitain the plant, pro- f books, apparatus and equipment and provide some additional building lieve overcrowded quarter!). Following the policy outlined two the Regents ask for no appropriations outside of the University fui; created by general .statutes state and national. i wo years ago the legislative grant for salaries and wages was J230.OO0.0O. Regents desired and needed considerably more. Had they been paying salaries according to rank and length of service, the sum granted would i' been insufficient fortbe bieniiiuin now closing. At present rates forsal - s it requires $180,000.00 annually, in round numbers, for their payment. r and above the specific c:k*h appropriations received from the XJnited es for special purposes. This means *-2(i0, 000.00 for the ensuing bieniiiuin. ch placed against the Regents' estimate of $288,000.00. leaves but 000.00 annually to provide for all iucreased demands — a sufficiently ,11 margin surely. U. S. (For the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 It so happened that the legislature of 1899 limited the amount which could be drawn from the University cash fund to $32,000.00 for the bieniiiurn end - ing March 81. 1901. Such an event was perhaps natural enough, taking into account the effect of the new statute passed at that session relating to the funds and finance administration of tin 1 University. But it was nevertheless unfortunate. By referring to the accompanying financial reports it will lie seen that from March 31, 1899, to the close of business on November 30, 1900, there was paid to the state treasurer by the secretary of the Board of Regents for the University fund, the sum of $35,4*1 50. This sum plus the cash Iwlance in the hands of the state treasurer on March 31, 1X9K, and plus the amount which will be collected at the University and paid into the state treasury from Now 30. l!»00. to March 81. 1901. makes a total of University Cash available for the bienniuni now closing approximating $48,500.00. The legislature's limit of $32,000.(10 simply forces the accumulation of a balance in the hands of the state treasurer and deprives the University of much needed revenue. To avoid seriously crippling of the work in certain departments the Regents have found it necessary to place a limited amount of advance orders for laboratory materials, supplies, live stock, and books against the cash accu - mulated in the treasury, and these transactions are covered by the "out - standing indebtedness" mentioned in the Regents' schedules. For the ensuing biennium the Kegents estimate the University cash, in - cluding the balance in the hands of ttie state treasurer on March 31. 1901, at $75,000.00. To avoi i the difficulty experiences during the past two years they ask that no smaller limit l&gt;e placed upon this fund. By general statute (see Conip Stat Neb. l*9!t. See. MM, Chap. 87) it is provided that 'no warrant shall lie issued against said fund unless there is money in the hands of the state treasurer sufficient to pay the same.'' It is therefore certain that the legislature can run no risk in placing a maximum instead of a min - imum limit upon the amount to be included in the general appropriation bill, payable from said fund. With twelve large buildings and a half dozen lesser structures constituting the property plant of the University, representing a half million dollars in value, it ought no longer o l&gt;e necessary to discuss the need of considerable expenditure for maintenance and repairs. The usual rule of one jht cent annual depreciation is barely sufficient to make good the actual loss from ordinary wear and tear upon the buildings themselves. The upkeep of ap - paratus and appliances for heating, light ing. ventilating, water and gas supply and fire protection is a steadily increasing item of expense, inde - pendent of tbe wear and tear upon the superstructure of buildings. The problem is no longer one of the expenditure of a few hundred dollars. It is a question of proper maintenance or ultimate destruction of property of much value. The Kegents regret to-day that for lack of more money for proper upkeep thev are now practicing ■ species of economy which in the long run is wasteful There is still great pressure and overcrowding in many departments The Regents propose to construct during the next bi nnium a building, or poMt - bly wings fo two buildings, for the better housing of departments now crowded into inconvenient and insufficient rooms. The two items— new buildings and upkeep of the property — absorb the greatr pa t of the total WKm which the Regents have .•■timated fo permanent improvements and repairs. There are a number of other important demands wheh the Regents have lieen obliged to defer to the future. A chancellor's residence should be pro - vided There is great need of an administration building, containing suitable and convenient executive and business offices, lire proof vaults, rooms for Board meetings. Faculty meetings, and committee rooms which might also ai commodate the business meetings of state societies co-operating with the I'niv rsity A Law College building cannot long lie deferred. ThrTB is great need of additional ground to accommodate th ■ military drill </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 :»nd to proride suitable athletic fields. New street paving will ba needet atound the I'niversiiy campus before the expiration of the ensuing biennium The legislature of 1899 passed an act requi ing tire escapes to be placed o public buildings. So far the Regents hare not had available fund- for tl purpose. It may indeed be questioned \vh ther the funds of the I'nivi set apart for instruction ml the facilities therefor should be used for &gt;uc purposes as street paying and tire escapes. That the state should provu lire escapes for all its buildings in which persons are kept in constant con tinement will not be denied. But none of the University buildings are o itipied at night: and during the day there is such constant activity about tl buildings and such use of every portion of them that is is practically impr sible fora lire to gain headway without discovery. The Regents submit, t 1 question of tire escapes particularly to the judgment of the legislature connection with the statute above cited. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 OK THE DEAN OK THE (JHAIHWTE st'HOOl To the Chancellor ami Board of Regents I have the honor to submit to yon the following report of the GradMfe School for the biennium 188H l'.KK)'. The number of graduate student! enrolled daring Lbete two yean bi . i « » : YEAR ■■■ Women, i ■&gt;9!t 7* 44 BOO «J1 67 My report for I8!i"-n* con tain- a statement of the gra naf attendance from rliesl beginning l* s - 83 . A comparison will show that the enrollment -i year was larger than thai &lt;&gt;f any preceding. Below is a table (based mainly on reports Furnished by the registrar of the attendance in different departments or leading sub History, American 14 It in I •noniy History, European 10 IS I I Botany « 14 Horticiil ure 1 Emistrv B •ution 1 Latin IT 20 Mathematics !i 11 1 Engineering, electrical "&gt; 1 Pedagogy 10 19 Engineering, civil 1 1 Philosophy 14 24 Engineering, mechanical 1 Physics... I 4 English 7 11 Phvsiology 1 English I.it.rature H Political Science 10 H 1 Entomology 1 \ Romance Langiiajfes .. is 82 Geology.... 4 4 i Sanskrit and Philog.... T M Germanic Language li 10 Sociology 1 Greek 9 14 Zoology 1" 1- 1 would reiterate here the recommendation made in my previous n of gradually, as circumstances allow. appointing teacnen for graduate instruction on the principle that such Instruction, and the furtherance ol ; i tii- investigation, shall !*• their chief work. Such a policy can 1 &gt;• 1 1 recommend itself to one familiar with the exacUngdemand* of graduate work and appreciative of the importance of promoting the advancement, and not alone tiie transmission, of knowledge. Respectfully submitted. A. H. EDGREN, Dean of the Graduate School </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 DKAN OK THE COLLEGE OK I.I TKKA'IVKE. SCIENCE AMD THE AliTs Tu the Chancellor and the Board of Reye)itx ■ beg to report that the enrollments in the College of literature. Science tin- Arts, for the year IflM l'.MK). bare been as follows: Matriculated Art and Music Students 5 4-J :;•.'.-&gt; tat To this list should lie :■&lt; lilt-il i In- ri&gt;&lt;!i-tr:itions in preparatory subjects carried by the teaching force of the College: men, US: women. 7!' Tin enrollment for the year, not including Mudents attending in the mati in, is 1,020 name-. The change in the requirements for admission to this College, whir adopted by the Faculty in April of the present year, ami approved l&gt;y the 1 of l!e&lt;rents. was put into effect in the September examinations. inta for admission t&gt;&gt; the ( 'lassical (troup have been heretofore re. • as firm ear Btndeatson satisfactory completion of twenty-four points, and .•ant- for admission to other jrroups, ol twenty livi- points. II First War pupils most nereaft r present evidence of having sm ■ completed twenty-eighl points. To counterbalance i« part thisim ie Dumber of points required for admission, credit i- allowed for o ects usually taught in hiirli schools, but hitherto nnrecognized by th&lt; of t li i~ College. Souh' further lil&gt; ralizing of the requirement* ission has lieen asked lor by the SuperintendeBts ami Principals of the I, and the University Senate, in a recent meeting, has agreed to 1 1 1 i — . -e revised requirements will undoubtedly Im&gt; accepted by the Faculty of College, ami their recommendations, it is hoped will be approved by the ncellor and the Board. tin- remits ol the elective system, which has been put into effect this r, are generally satisfactory. The abolition ol the grouse has relieved Enrollment Committee of intolerable burdens, and enabled the student rregular preparation to systematise hW work. There i~ great liberalising ie choice of subjects, vet there i- not much search for easy combinations, lanir lage departments are not neglected, as it was feared might lie lents of the Suphmore as well aa the of the Junior and the Seniot e been admitted to elective courses on condition of furnishing twenty - it point* of preparatory work. Nearly all student- of this College, paration affords the three additional points required by the new plan of ■ission. bare availed themselves of the opportunity to leave the groans. First V&gt;ar clam is large, and the general enrollment bids fair to . lerhaps a hundred names the total for last year Very respectfully submitted I. A. SHERMAN, Deaa of the College of Literatnre, Science and the Fourth year Third year Second year First year ( ollegiste Law Unclassified Irrej^'ilar .-&gt;4 r,T&gt; M :S! -,&gt;0 w &lt; » M r 47 lit! 190 l:&gt;7 :!0 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 I'KAN (&gt;1 'I'lIK IXDl'S'l I Al. ( I ll.l.Kl.l- i "f mt't flu' littirti t)f' 1 Inh .w &lt; lll.Lt which rciillir ii i I &gt;■ :ire ■ 1 ■ ■ - : _r . i i -I :i ~ &lt; ■ 'iiit.i1 Science, (ien- \ lt t ~ i &lt; ■ 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 &lt; ■ . Technical Agriculture. Agriculture and (neinistry. Botany iiiv and Zoology. ( ' i ■• - nt i—t i"&gt; ■ :im&lt; I I 'li \ ~i &lt;•-. Horticulture ii .\«i ( Itotauy. M n in'iii u ri ami I'nys :v anil Philosophy, ( 'lien &gt; ience. Civil Kiigiiieering V. ectrl -:i! Kngineeriii); and Median - ering 1 Miring ate year i hirty-live mrii and women lated from tlics.- lines ol study, recen iiiL r tilt* degree of Bachelor of I I icy an- prepared to take upp :i lically the scieotitic work relateil iculture ami the Mechanic Arts, and t'i the applications of Scien ■ TiiiL' Dii I! ra'lnatcd from 1 I I! l"ln-v an- prepar illv tin- -rii-iilitic work relate.! •ulturt" ami the Mechanic Arts, ami to tlie applications of Scienee i II Tue &gt;■ iioiii.-. with two-year anil three-year lines of study, in Am Mcrh;niic ArtH antl 1* ( » 'lire, atinii^iofi to which iuh ■ ■'i ilire»-tly Irom the. ]&gt;u!i -. (hi i-ompletion of thew lii the stuilenl is tr^cn :t ccri iticaic i&gt;1 proticieni'y. ami is prepan 1 *! to take il w. irk in um horticult mil. iiK'chanic.il antl do i j p;i 1 1 &lt; ■ n - . It' S4 lloiil.-. \\ ilh l u i»-vt»ar :ll idv. ii A n M Arts ami 1&gt;^ on i.i \\l h On n :l iiTI I to tak ; r.il . Ii III The Ai.kk i mi kai Kxi'KI.'Imkni Siaiiun. is a department of mentation anil iv. arch, the results of which are |iul)lis|i d for the ben i lie community at larjfc III Till" AtilCII I III HA I K.XI'KKIMKST SlAII.iN. is a il.')):trl llirnl of ii Ii. tilt" results of which arc publish &lt;l for X\w I in in u ii 1 1 \- ;ii lai I'm' aii.Mi.iaii.- ■ ..I — 1 1 1 ' 1 • - 1 1 1 -i in the [otlustrial ('o&gt;llose lias Blade a rapid lenU in the ludmtrial Collejte 1 ■ : i — Bade :i i-c iii the 1 lien niii :n Tne enrollment for the year IWW U u;i~ :i- folluwo nt'iit for vear 18UM a u ;l - a i »w m i- n ffimn M I- N W ■ t K :{():( 411 Mi 4 I ill of Agriculture '14 i til S-l I of Domestic Science 11 School of Mechanic Art« 52 Sugar School I .... i-&gt;\ I tfa year 1S&gt;I&lt;» 11KK) the enrollinenl « a- a- follows: Ii vear 1899 r.Miii tin- enrollnx in « a- a • i\\ NIKS VOUCH &lt; 'oil sic 358 ti-.' I ScIkmiI of Axriculture Ill I IhhiI of Aerifiiltur School of Dome-tic Science 11 school of Mechanic Arts 4:i Mechanic Ar 4i Suir:u School - ... Total* ■&gt;"'■&lt; »6 I. ill T»i Th lines of -in.lv com in in- to be detin tely la il down for each ye ir of the ut- ri'-iclcn ce. i -led ion living mainly i ontined to the choice of groans o( I'll lines of study ciiii i in ue to be ilelin telv la il ilown for each re ir of tin -tii.lie-. The latter have tieen cai-efullv arranire«l so as to rive the student's ■ necessary fore .iltli anil Imlanoe. In addition to the foregoing » entv-lil nt of the siinlies in the general groups are 'frei res," a n 1 1 in all irroii|»9 sunn 1 " free ■ let'tives " are oiTereJ [nilividua a il preferences may thus be (riven due consideration, while avoiding lanirer of an ill-cou»idereil tion of stii.lies liv uiifiuiilcil or ini-s •il stinient Very respeetfnlly submitted CHARLES E. HKSSKV. Dean of the Industrial College </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 DEAN &lt;&gt;! THE COLLEGE OK LAW nol Im'cii appropriated by I ■apart for the purchase of i ooka. have not Im'cii appropriated by the i e, has prevented u- from purchasing books necessary for present we. I Knnmfml that tb«' legislature be requested to so frame the appropriation o render tliis fuml available to the full extent of the money paid in. '1 lien' is now between *T00 ami *1.ikH) lying in the treasury which can be us.'.l for ■other purpose and which should be u&gt;.-,l at om-p in the purchase of much tried books There is m&gt; economy in holding the fuml on hand while the Inaml for its immediate u-. t is not deemed newsnary to repi two year- air" poncerning matt nre [refer to that report for a tre •at at the statements contained in my report ■r- wherein no change Iris Iveeii il neral statement of our plan of instrtu •tfullv submitted, Very respi M B. REESE. Deaa of the Collefn at Law. T« the Chancellor mid th* Boartl of KegenU: I have the honor to Mibniil to yon tin- following' report o« the I ■ ■ inv lasl report tin- scl 1 has shown an iniT :i-' j . I »» &gt;t l» in nu ii the interval taken by the students. The i;towtli of the i liiite satisfaetorv -in .,,'\iun- years. with but lliree exceptions. 1 sii\e the itatenient of 1 1 1&lt; - attendance fi»r each year since the open in 1*'.H: I I Ml 2 ,i ill I8M ■"&gt; 1HU5 I -' 18U6 7 l«!l'.l-l!l(HI IM llii~ ti c |)iT.inl"i- l-i there are 163 enrolled for the |&gt;n - anil live prospe»-u are that the total enrollmenl for the yea i I he plftn, recently a«lopteil. of (lis|H&gt;n&gt;inf( » iili the special leetiu ami tin' work of t Ik- »|&gt;ecial lecturers, aeems to work well. Thin p itbalilv require an increase of th«- resilient niemliers of the fan ilaiu-e Rrowg. lint -n&lt;-li inorease i- not now ret-onimen&lt;l&lt;tl. Our fa&lt; is now ur|(Hni/nl. is able to incel the present ilemamls. We an' iiu-n n, Iv of eases and shall continue to do so, sn long as it cm be done with- out prejudice toelass texl-btMik work. Since my hist report the aceoniino latious for the school have Inm iniproretl. lint the rapid increase in attendance will soon r ti.l.r the rooms now occupie t. The fact that our college course is given ■ instead of three, as in many other schools. t&lt;inl- to increase the at I The course will have to he' changed to three yean at aa earl v date, bat nui-h change is not now recommended. The income rona the paymeni of tuition and fees w ill soon be sufficient to rentier the college self supporting. Indee .at thepresent rate of sittem the tuition "ill prolwbly pay all theexpeiisen of instruction and the matricu- 11 and graduation fees will maintiin the Law Library, leaving only im-i- dental expenses tobe provided for. The fad that the fees, which are I) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 1 ' I 1 » I'.* I t M » I 'r 1 I I r . A t i li 1" I 1 . 11 1 » A I j r,\ I r. li I .\l r. N I SIAIHIN To the Chancellor ami the Board of Riyents I haw i lie honor to -ul unit tin- following brief report upon the organi; :iinl the work of the Agricultural Kx peri men! Si at ion for the two years i. niiiary 1. l'.toi. It has been a Batter for congratulation that so few ccurred in the peno»»et of the working staff, li is also for - tunate that while there have been several changes in the directorship of the ii there ha- been no change in the general line- of investigation. A- :i jiienee there ha- lieen less dissipation of energy than usual. There is an increasing degree of concentration of action, and fortunately perfect har - mony in the workiiii; part- A closer organisation is however desirable. The K\periinent Station building, for which an appropriation was made by the Legislature o l*!'!i in recognition of the services of Station lor the has lieen nearly completed. The location of the Station on the farm, the improved Facilities for investigation, and the bringing together of the working part- of the Station which the erection of this building accomplishes, result in a greatly increased efliciency. I here i- a markedly increasing temleucy for the farmers of the Male to . to t lie K\ peri i in "in Station for guidance This is indicated l»y the i nth of the bulletin mailing list, ami by the letters received. On I &gt; •'.i'.i. the number of persons in the Mate receiving bulletins was 4.4X1 i er 1. l'.Hki. it was T 800 These bulletins, relating the result." of exper into every county in the State They a e sent oul to persons ap - ng for them Bu lelin No. 61. oa "Hungarian Brorue Grass." roiiglil Station 6.VI re&lt; | Is tor the publication by persons in the State not pre ihe mailing ist. Bulletin No. .V.i. on "The Homemade Win. &lt;el&gt;rask:i. ' broughl s !i'.i re«|iiests from various part- of the country. correspondence of the Station now necessitate the writing of about "i letter- annually. The investigations of the Station continue along the same general line-. "luetiou ol plant- under limited rainfall, ami the pro. I net ion eat and milk from crop- adapted io tlii- region, together with tie known work of | lie station with animal clisea- h has Ueen done for agriculture by the introduction of certain foreign s which have proven then tier adapted to conditions of - aridity than the varieties grown in the I'nite I Man-- Sol able am ing these Hungarian brome-grass and Turkestan alfalfa. The former i- h cultivated pasture grass ever tried in this region. Sei at the Station has been distributed through all part- of the . and has proven generally successful. Through the efforts of the Station in securing hardy varieties, winter wheat ilt raised in localities where it- culture has not before been attera| ■ ■ar the Station distributed winter wheat in packages of twenty pounds awong Ml per-- ins living north of the Platte river or we-t of the lOiith merid- Murh information regarding the use of forage crops ami methods of llage ha- lieen disseminated Eie ex| iinent- with antitoxic serum in the treatment of lion cholera eon !■ to give fa\ oral ili' results. In the coarse of these experiments 2.000 hoes lifting to people in various part- of the State hive I u treated There ■ also been distributed in the past year 76.830 i loses of blackleg virus I Bong other work being carried on are experiments with windmill irriga- I, the growth of cover crop* for the protection of orchards, tin' eradica i of insect pests, the feeding of cattle and sheep, investigation of man) Dial disease-, etc. present Lhe Agricultural Experiment station i- supported entirely by funds appropriated by CongreKS. This appropriation is a specific annul &lt; &gt;K T11K </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 ii is to !&gt;&lt;■ increased it niiiM In- dune l&gt;v tinai from the Stale t" supplement the -mail (iovernmenl appropriation. Very respectfullj snbmitted, K. BENJAMIN ANDREWS. Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station. KKl'OUT ok mi; DIRECTOR Ol THE m IKHH. (IK Ai.ltH I'LTIRE To tin 1 Clianceilor amd the Board of l:&lt; K ginning with September. l s '.i s . the &gt;&gt;&lt;■! I of Agriculture was re-o the sessions being made concurrent with the regular L'niversiti Winter ( uiir-i' in Agr culture »a« not abandoned as it wan felt thai rears musl elapse before a great n amber of farmers)' turns » ill Im- ilis] tend a -eh' »il of agriculture except during the winter months Tin' regular course covers I hree years i»f work aail is growing steadily into favor. Any young man who completes the regular coarse has, besii nil in AgricuTtiire, a l""&gt;,I general i-dncation. l&gt;iinnir tin- year twenty two stutlentx were in the three years' rtwrse anil thirl • 'I themselves i&gt;f tin' a&lt;l vantages offered by tin' WinteH 'oorse. The 1900 saw a largely increa. &lt; &lt;e&lt;l attendance in both courses, there forty-nine in the three yai- course ami sixty-live in Winter Coarse. The school has Mice led in reaching the young men of at least ha!; «tai&lt;'. there being students from forty-five counties last year. The daii liave been especially generous in their support of agricultural educati«»o. M'hiMtl has grown steailily and during the winter course the Imi are greatly crowded. It is evident required. that another building «ill soon be ■Ik- groH tli of the school run lie sees number in attendance each year "f from tin 1 following table which shows it~ existence: 181I.V1XVHJ. 15 ttudents. The greatest need of the school at the present time N such an incr the teaching Force as will make it j&gt;&lt; &gt;-~i I &gt;!«• to offer instruction in Agricn Horticulture and kindred subjects in every term ol the year Ii i» iliat. if the L'niversity is t" develop* a real School of Agriculture, the &gt; : Tlie policy of the school lias always been t" seat] its students back t" the farm ami thus far no one can truthfully say that students arc lieing edw away from the farm. ' &gt;f the two hundreti and seventy studectn, who have attended the school, two hundred and fifty are at present engaged in branch "f faming or are -till pursuing their education. Evidently the uK liven here is inspiring students with a love fur the calliiiLr of culture. Very respectfully submitted. named :il«&gt;\ e must l&gt;e rnjule. A K. DAVISSON, Direct i&gt;r of the School of Agriculture N9U-1H07 . -".H ]S!»!I. . . --'.Ill -UK W I. :;:i stmlenik. ~&gt;1 students. '•' -llhliMll-. ...1H students. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 DIliKt Toll OK THK M llool. Of All I It somewhat disorganize I state. mi- ail -diool- in the «•: i — t and ill foundations. Wiili time it grew second ~.in ~i it foil m I it tiiiulv e I v ain-iv I students had left for • liuililinic up nf the school Itegan from n numbers, strength ami interest, am! -1 :&lt;l,i !-!,.■. I Bthe present lime, L*eceral»er I, ' rger than that of any ilate d-innir !KX). the number of students regi»tere«l I In' preceding year, ami inquiries con - iii. nearly every week from iiilTerenl « ha- douliletl ii- former uumhers. A a new feature which was ntartetl in an averaife attendanee r&gt;f twenty Ii &gt; •■. Kiiui; the depart nii'iil art* coming n&gt; in the stat". Theevening cla* - in illustration held oner a week &gt;Imt with three members, has now K genuine interest in this clan in proved when it i~ stated that i n itii'il n' In i has not fultille&lt;l the assinnnienl for the week. ■ n an matters given eaeh week, an 1 well attended mlinU an- earnest, hard-working, and enlhusia&lt;tie. There seems no ri' ison t" doubt that in time a -i-hm .^ni/i-il liy tin' oliler art school* their ranks. To achieve thi- siuhh- — . inu&lt;t In' ri'plrnishi'il Hni whi - ''in to justify tin 1 i'\|i N itioii n ill clu nun 1 of art ina.v I staltlished « hieh will if tin' count rj' a- worthy of a place in however, tin' ineafrre supplies of tin' e a fuller equipment i- neeessary tin' enditure. 'fhe re4*ntly ineorpoi-ateil Ii to further the cause of art in this iiiijci'i nf thi- society, which i~ the tn (five an annual exhibition 'if pic - -&lt;■&lt;■ k - to Iniihl up in connection witli ■iini nt line art- which -hall U' free in I ion of tlir country. The primary rrnu ih of tin' Hay. Inn An Club, i - ■s during the « in'cr holida ery nf tin 1 Inii ersity a mil* citizens nf the state. ■ ■ nf a permanent collection nf pictures, Htatuat I he art department «ill In' incalculable. It is ho iiiealin It i- hoped that every : may Ik' made in secure it Numlier "i students ai'tuallv rezistcn reftula Saturday hi; ,1a-- {oiitsiile pup 1 i paiutine 18 Verv rr-iic( \i;a s. haydkn Difl-rtnr nf till' Srhnnl nf Al IIKI'OUT ni i ii i i»ii:k( ion of the s«mK)L ok domkstic s&lt; ii:m k lUllii- Chancellor and the Board of Regent The -i-Iiimi' of Domestic Science was organized iu Sejitewber, 18H, with a ration of ten students. \- soon as the work was begun eollem 1 student* began to apply for per hi to register for domestic science. The request was granten Mid col ■ilit given for this work. ■&lt;&lt;■■ //or antl fin Hoard of Regents: •pelting "I th* 1 l'niv« j n*ity in Sej»u*ml»er. 1000, foiimj th»» s«-li&lt;i«»l of ,\ irom 1 &gt;.&gt;&gt;&gt;, •tl'iillv submitted </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 mr-tic "science classes. Tlie kitchen laboratory, when tilled to its u will accoinnio&lt;late only sixteen students. The great need i»l more ."in is therefore very evident to all who visit our crowded quarters Be wink is I rased on scientific principle!*, and is decidedly pra :il cooking i- clone. ( 'areful attention is given to the economy i»( iim. j KiiL'l'i :iml materials. Tin' rational 111:111 \' problems which liave to ih ii' nre studied. ivisiun &lt;&gt;( income is considered with tlif furnishmg and care of the In addition to tin' mm red student* referred to aliove, an ex - afternoons, lias recently licen ■ tension class, which meets Saturdi V t*v respectfully submitted KOSA KOI ION lor of Sclmoi n f Domestic Science l&gt; UKI'OKT Dllll.t l()i: (i| nil. "school OF MECHANIC ARTS To Ilif Chancellor ami the Boanl of Regent Diirin 1 11 i 1.1 111 little has l&gt;een done t" advertise tlic Si Mechanic Arts, vet this year the first vear class i- larger than thai &lt;■ The niiinlicr in id year i»f the course - probably due primarily t&lt;&gt; tbe fact that we are still Una the work ol the -ecoml vear. The average age ol all stmlentH in the vln»il ■olid year. I lie averaKt* age ol all student* in the - ttween nineteen ami twenty vear-. a short course in pnwtii-.il mechaiiii lil lie of value to a class ol y ; in l"hi- indicates (as was pn and tin' elements of eni/ii n of somewhal mature years ■xtensive preparation ne bad found it imno — ible to serin I. enter the regular engineering coiir Many »l the young men lca\ ing th ■ ■n- in some line ol mechainca ■ 11-. paying from $8 r month, ami in one ler month. Theae results are encouraging, particularly when \\ . sider that much of the work in the -ecoml vear of the course canm tii- vear the large increase in attemlanee in the -hop courses in Mechan- Kngiueering makes ii nece— arv t« &lt;s ve the -hop work for the Scb lianic Arts in the forenoon- fcven with this change to relieve the after- inundate all of the student- reg :il».n' conditions, it i- probable thai ■mi periods, we were unable to ae the shop courses. In view of tl during the nexl hienniurn ii will be neeessarv in some way to limit t ; teinlam-c in the School of Mechanic Arts, miles- more room, eutiipmeal inei are pro\ iilcil. The work in thi- school mnsi not Id' allowed to in- Eere with regular work in engineering. ■ should it Ih- allowed t^&gt; be irden to the departments giving instruction in the school. I'nlet k 1:111 l&gt;e properly taken .are of. it should be abandoned altogether Eis desirable that the students in thi- coarse be given a small amonnl of I'tical laboratory work in steam engineering ami also in electrics ring. There is a great demand for such work, but little can be done more assistants in the two departments. Last vear. for the first time, certificates were iri\en those stiulents in the tool who had satisfactorily finished ml to 1 e eligible for the honor the required work. Two men watt ■ctfully submitted. Very re»| C. I! RICHARDS. Director of the School of Mechanic &gt;i-ln«il hrtve lui'i. -iicc-i— — t" « 1 1 in obtaining work. A nmulier »l the i»l&lt;l stu&lt;li'Dts ren until the shops aiv fully t'&lt;|iii| </seg>
            <seg id="p026">l ■i f ;i. 26 r Till- DIRECTOR OF TIIK AFFILIATED SCHOOL OF MUSIC To the Chancellor mxl the Bonn I of Regent Thf sixtli year of the Srlioo] of Music as an organized and fully equipped onservalorv. closed June 20. l'.Kiti. Previous t" 1W4 music had been taught in the I'niversitv liv two or thr Kuctors, Imt offered no definite u natiil. Since the above date tin Hlli'll I : urses from which stikfenu niiixlit li following is a brief record of it~ &lt;!• To the Cli me llor and the Board •&gt;/' Re&lt;jenl Durinn the la-t biennium there have lieen under the control ami in nn-iii ot the l)irect€&gt;r the following laboratories: The Ih-par) ntal l^alxiraton at the University. Experiment Station L*lx&gt;ratory at the Farm. The Aifriiullural Si-hoo] Laboratory at tin' Farm Kthe Departmental laboratory, tl ction. In tin- graduate ami undei uiMitv courses of instruction lia\ •tlv chemical in character. • principal work ha- been thai graduate schools comlnned an arenun Ih'i'm iriven, exclusive of several no Km' registration in the ilepartment biennium amounts to a tota omit, are from the Industrial I'ol ege, not counting those in the ixra ilnriiifr three of the four st'in 1 students, of whom approximately B lii."' *0 per I'i'ni. from the Acailem luaii 1 school. Bni-i' the la&gt;i report, tl»' following n place: changes in the instructional MalT liav Professor Avery resigned about tin hit \va- appointed in his stead: the vai »tatT by Mr Hiltner's promotion w her. Professor Nicholson, lias Mi&gt;~ Fossler iM'insr appointed to -- "V Nicholson's aJ»sence. miililli' of August, )S9ti. and Mr. II It Micy created in the Experimenl Statioi I n absent on leave since January 1 as-i-t in the work of instruction durini \( TIM; |)IKK( lOi: &lt;&gt;1 THE ( IIKMH Al. LAHOKATOUIF The IV-ci Sugar lalMiralorv at Ann-- Nebraska ■ancy created in the Kxpenmenl Station as iilli'd by the appointment cif Mr It 1 1; i — ;i total attendai &gt;f over three hu ti&lt; In-i I regular students, hi uni.luan'il twenty-three from it- four ami ) i v » ■ year courses, ol which thi teen candidates hare bwn presented in tlie last two years. Tin' i-tMimi' uli'ui- building erected for its use has for two years been t&lt; in afconinKHlate those u ho applied fi&gt;r resilience in it- dormitory, am liinnir which period it- force of instructors lias increased from fifteen I nttuence, the most successful military band lias been built u in the history of the l'ni\ entity, awl each year one of the standard oral '•n performed with a large chortia and orchestra, drawu from the &gt;ti ■»ly. It no« offers :i tun years' i-oarse in harmony and theory, and Hve -in all branches of applied music; which are of etjual standard wii - -tin H il- « i the coiml rv \Ci\ respectfully submitted, WILLAR1) KIMBALL. Director of tin- School of Mu&gt;ir REPOKT or mi. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 rese tor several yean. The principal lines of work an K\ study of sugar licet development, including •election of mother s for seeds Secon&lt;l.- -Experiments in the line of licet seed cultim Third Seed variation, experiment* upon wheat, corn, oats and rye. in injunction with the Agricultural 1&gt;' Fourth. — Soil moisture determinmt Kiftli. — Analysis of soils. ■art men t of tin- University &gt;u Sixth. A study of foragi parlini'ii I-venth. — ( imperative work with mists, a study of analytical meth Ivsi- of milk. Ik Association of Official Agricultural i*ed in beel sugar work and in the Kisrhth. — Miscellaneous analy »tr cholera remedies, water, i mprising analyses "t feeding &gt;tulT*. ler, coal, several :tna with cast The Laboratory of the K\ peri men &lt;|Uarters in t Ik* new Expcriineul Si nave not vet been fnllv equipped ow ation has recently lieen moved inti n building at the Farm. Inn then ;u-k of fund |lll|iped OW n rlie Laborat new Imilcli leulture likewise occupies a room in ■n titled np. In onse .|Ueiiie of the has lieeu better svsteinixed. - Airr reorganizat further in n work instead of those who are ■■found" or supplied at short notice and up &gt;n small pav The registration for (hem hool was. duriiiif tli 18WI l'.KK'. twen nt eight are taking this work. :lt Al It' Sllcral made becai w years of its existence, the sehool had ] essary. in order that it might &gt;ly enlarged &gt;N|iiipmenl should tn- wa mi U- pro. v provided for. fun ng. It was therefor thought l»--t w n nts with Mr. Allen, manager of tin experiments in sngar lieel culture. ■bniska, for several years, inig Standard Cattle C'oinuanv. wherebv th which have been contliicted :ti Ames, N iiueil According to the arraugem ilysis, furnishes a laboratory and lent to the work. The department for experimental purposes and for ai n rects the work and plans the experin •nts. The chief nature of this work ivaiion of twcts lor seed proilnction nt. About « UOU analv-e- hn\r the ill inent of the sugar cont made of inotln lected for fill lire seed production Very respectfully submitted. KKI'OKT F 1 II h \. I H I! A 1! 1 A N To the Chancellor and Board of Regent* 1 have the honor to sulmiit the following report on the University Library. corering the two year-- ending November 1. l'.KX), showing its growth duriiiif that time- njuiiotiim with the Aitricnltural !&gt;■■ il of Regents held \n-{ April, npon my rvcont- ivaa iliscontimied. This rccnmnieiMiation wms ither than attempt i&lt;&gt; carry it The resents 1:M war made aruMjreiu nt Mr. Allen now provides a • 1 1 1 1 1 &gt; 1 1 1&lt; 1 1 1 . anil pays a 'luring the |&gt;:i-r - JOHN WHITE, Ac; inir Director n( the Chemical l^altoratoriesi </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 definite |miiiy early formed an»i constantly maintained i&gt;f separate ■riinrin- nl pure and applied science, seem* hi make "k- cm iln&gt;c subjects most available and presents n&lt;i serious adminis - liis plan costs the most tn properly administer ii no ;iii. r ii!iM-n! if ii lie surely the be»l plan, bin the ideal ami ulti - iit-i of I he system ca impetenl attendant with each collec - &gt;ksand foi . 1 1 .- 1 1 ■ &gt; &lt;r i &lt; ■ for each ilepartmental library which Hi' lor- the general catalogue :il the central kepi in laiml in making library appropria- B&lt; been an evolution and in tin' pa«l two re policy have have l«een newly empha- IA t ■ • 1 1 1 ! &lt; • 1 1 1 - ; iart iinut a ■ libraries unduly even in closely I'd sill &gt;v the consolidation of the collections on Hor - ture Agricultun y. Animal Pathology and the Kxper - ■! the department!) ol Mat hematics rin;; departments have been similar!; united an&lt;l to i iniL'ln well In- added pan ol the Astronomical lilirarv now inadequately i'il in an unsafe buildiun Tin- union of the libraries of the iMologii'al rtiueuts. ot coursM- in charite of a coni}&gt;etenl attemlant. seems desirable lever fund- u and when these departments -hall In- perma- • k^ peri* h lir:i - :i in { publications of learneil societies which are &lt; if ire that they cannot justly be assigned to any one iii'iil shall I"' kept :ii the central library. ■ :i charge upon each department wherever - kept :i departmental libi K'l'lh- Library Board has ruled that when department libraries become 'i~ thai i oi- ili'-iri'il by the department concerned, anj liooks in - •h department may In 1 transferred to tin' central livt* crcrj student free access to all books. Tin- actual loss iirv. ia no larger than in some similar insti - nis when 1 I k- mu\ In- used only under restrictions. Ii seems certain :i \ i -_r i . : 1 1 1 1 administration ami a very few safeguard* will reiluce the an - a minimum ot inexpensive Itooks. STAKK I that there has Iteen no change in our -t a IT. luring the bien - i Ke&lt; a ruiting mir force, at we are yel obliged to do, from almost wholly ained material, it is true that in this department more than M others, changes in staff mean a ilistincl sacrifice in efficient administration, the l»— i results the salaries paid should !"■ enough to commaml trained ami i- n&gt; to permit new assistants to learn their work in trast - betin f students and faculty It gives me pleasure to testify to the uni earnest ami intelligent work ol the prewnl MalT EX I i;.\— I MVEIISl I 1 I M. EL'niver»ily libran is a reference library for the wl inain - with the people's money, ami so far a« possible itaeverj' resource is \&gt; tin 1 I'niverwity is the bead of the state educational -i&gt; tlic University library, more than any other. i» the center of the interests of the state. The many ami increasing deinauds made I &gt;y other libraries, by communities starting new libraries, by teach - th in person ami by correspondence, by study clubs, by non-fesidenl ts and citizens, constitute an obligation which we cheerfully recognize ullv discharge to tin- utmost lint ;&gt;i with tin- claims of our M it II'-IHY. Ml S1IKI.\ I ■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 Band diploma tees, has I n. daring the pa-t three or four year*, about i j&gt; t :i n 11 ii i ii 1'ni- has Iwt-n supplemented liy your :n l&lt; I i t i- &gt;n:il irt:iu t !.. 100 annually from the ilirvri legislative appropriation, making a total i | about *,".outi each year. Against thi- sum arc annual Bxed charges This leave* t4.:'(N) in be divided among thirty recognixed department*, or an average' &lt;&gt;f 1140 each. This sum does no serve tn keep up with i he car - renl literature in most depart in-, ami entirely inadequate to build tip :i \ complete t'tiottgh in any department fi»r advanced s inly ami re - i, Nothing will i -e effectually add to our renown or help us to re- I he greatest I'niversity in this region than a liberal treatment of our By common ioiim'iii our present • • &lt; &gt; 1 1 &lt; ■ • ■ i i ■ &gt; 1 1 contains little waste Iter. ami has I n ma«ie with can 1 ami skill, but it is far too small In - rl of 13.000 volume*, there Hhoulil lie IVi.nn i viliinn--: mi r income should 15.000. nol *;.im&gt; If the I &gt;&lt;--t n are i" !«■ 1 ■!-• »• i «rl ■ t hereaml kept here, library must afford them means t" k&gt;v|i their work abreast of tin- times. Iheir coining to the west, far fn»ni the larger libraries, must it« »t mean the suicide of creative sch&lt;ilar«hip. STUDY AMI -KMIN \l: !;• » 'M- The I'nlveraitv library should In- more than :i \&gt;&lt;»&lt;k room ami :i |rreal reatl- iiMiin. where books are dealt oul to the mas* o! readers. Ii ihoohl :i!s&gt;&gt; • :i- :i lalioratory, for faculty as well a- students, ol tin we sciences « hose * chiefly to be obtained from l»"&gt;k-;. Kor thU osa, there should be ral -mailer seminar nniiiw where members &gt;&gt;( the faculty may work out interruption: where they may leave I k- or papers for an hour or v. and where they may bring small classes to consult li»&gt;ks. There i\\ no such place available for any bill the history department*. There ild !"• other provided, certainly one al least for a general faculty work i I recommend thai one or tw.. ro ius in tic library building suitable lii- purpose ami now occupied by other departments be vacated for iv use :i- -'"Mi a- |n.~- Very respectfully submitted .1 1 \\ VKK. Librarian REPORT OK THE rl'KATOR ol THE STATE M1SKI.M To Hi- ( haneellor and Board of Regntt: Ii- ( -orator is able to re:&gt;orl kn«l even remarkable growth in tin' inn considering it- overcrow«le«l condition. It now contains so much rative ami educational material that it is drawn upon daily by the as - ted departments in the I'niversity. l&gt;onatio«s are constantly receired citizens throitghoal the state from liberal &gt;\ &gt;rs and patrons in Lin - ami other towns, fn&gt;m estatei and froas many unexpected source* be - the state It has alre uly ac»juireil recognition as tin- repository of the nonwealth in which should be stored for ready reference not only the ral resource- ami -oils, but also ' agricultural, industrial, ami art Ilic fact that the present building which offer* temporary quarter! :1 » follow* ilicals ( '••Hi in nation iwdero (books i--n.il one vol. al a lime, annuals 4ihi rig periodical* anil iiiri'-tiry rcliiniling 1.000 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 more thai. w 1 1 rii condition. Prospective donors frankly avow their intei i ben the time pomes iin&gt;- \ ide suitable and safe buildings in \\ hich to store valuable private collections In tin- meantime the donation! are with-held and not infrequently drift away, and ir&lt; &gt; Hnallv to enrich the .abim-i- ol neighboring states. The il, paleontological. zoological, and entomological collections have ifrow n I y and no* contain all thai is of lirst importance, and even much thai e and unusual. The agricultural museum, which li:i- been fostered liv urator since 1801. has enjoyed a more important growth than was then predicted and when present plan can be carried into effect this will constitute the utosl impressive and important display in the state museum. The uirr cultural miiseuin already contains the woods, uoois. -oils. Uirds. mamma •■. -, -.in-, e. luiiiiaia -. reptiles, injurious and lieneKcial insect*, fruits and many of the eer »and (trasses of the state. The collections of soils, timbers and surpass those of elder stabs*. A large importation of i:i — ware make ■tsiblcto prepare large a Lints of agricultural material for exhibition nnseum ha- also made rapid train during the past liienniuin. i&gt;ne can look forward to the time when it will become an important i-nce collection for tin' artisan, citizen and student. ESTIMATE!! VALUES &lt;&gt;1 T1IK &lt; ()I.I.K&lt; lIONs AND I'ROPKRTY BE l.o.M.IM, TO THE STATE MUSEUM j'u-al and Ethnological * Addition- from the State (ieological Survey and the Morrill Geological Expeilition the past bienuiiini, consistiug of building -lone-, clays. cements, sand, gravel, etc mtological collection added past biennium consisting of 4.CK.K1 1 n- Dakota cretacious ' 'i.tioO 1 specimens carlxiniferous . rossils Morrill (i«&gt;ologifal Expedition pa-t biennium, including sand- ) in rystals, 1.200 Wyoming and Nebraska fossils \\ yoming and Nebraska fossils -j;,ci Thurston County. Mastodon 7.-, t-t Zoological l.x.V) 2~M tishes of Nebraska 1-50 litio Hsbes of the I'. S Osteologica! tlditions past liiennium. Bryan alligator, etc Idition from Moirill l.eo]o'irii-al Expedition -J."&gt; ■j:, r.utoiuological 4.500 Mi-i-elleneon-. including l)tic-a brae inn &lt; oin-. medals, • Entomological iltural 1.IKHI Woods 1,3*0 Wools 2B0 Fruits ami cereals -joo Miscellaneous 250 ere 2.5M J.:!(H) ctions made prior to 1*81 4. (KM) - locks and shelving prior to is'.U :;.(HKI I map mm Total probable value MS.060 Very lespectfully submitted. E. II BAKBOUR, Curator of the State Museum. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 or the SUPERINTENDENT OK FARMERS' INSTITUTES To the Chancellor and tin- llmtril of Reijents: The Fanners' Institutes for the year l*!t!i 1900 closed March 81. Fifty-one Institutes hare been held this year, all of which have 1 ■ rae- cesful. except possibly three. Attwo points the storm was very were, which prevented large attendance, an. I at the third a variety of causes reduced the interest and attendance. All regular Institutes were live sessions in length. lint foursp-cial points were. ailed for one session only. These were at points where Dr. Peters lectured &lt;&gt;n prevention of blackleg and hog cholera. The average attendance may be sakl to range from thirty to littv at noon session!) lifty to three hundred at afternoon sessions, and one' hundred to live hundred at evening sessions We have expended the one thousand live hundred ninety-three dollars and fifteen cents allowed for Institute as follows 11.509 15 Re expense of the Institute this year would indicate that we should have i-l two thousand dollars for the next year's work and si Mask the legislature for at least Bve thousand dollars per year for the next biennium. The amount of Institute work performed during the la-t three years would not have been possible but for the generous cooperation of various railroads which have furnished an aggregate of forty thousand miles for the year 1900, a sum equal to the entire expense of the work outside of the i|Uestioao superintendence. It is apparent that the Institute work can only continue upon its present appropriation with the continual cooperation of the road-. As the work of the Farmers 1 Institute i- purely alons; the line of indu - development. it i» to lie believed thai the courtesies and support of the rail - roads will continue, even when the Slate comes to our aid with a larger ap - propriation than i- now available. Judging from the standpoint of what had previously been accomplished, I am informed by all the Institute workers who have been some yean in the lield. that the Institute- ha\ e been a decided improvement over previous in the perfectness of organization, general interest aroused ami the uniformly good work done by the speaker! Thirty -eight different men have been sen! on; by the central office to - at fifty-one different Institute points. The regular Institute force cons of four Experiment station workers, who received expenses only, and eight other men and women, who were paid a per diem and expenses. Several I niver-ity professors assisted the workbygiringevening lecturesat Institute points, and a large number of men gave assistance for a few days, receiving expenses only, which accounts for the apparent large number ol men on the Institute lecture force. We do not need more men but more rigid selection in order that I he of work may be raised. Most of our speakers should !»• successful farmers who themselves have large businesx interests which they have built up from meagre beginnings through approved methods and business insight. We must have mean- sullicient to command the time and thought of the best Superintendent'! salary $,"&gt;0(l iH) &lt; )lliic help, printing, stationery, portage Emergency railroad tare .",7 4s Per diem for lecturers outside the University 4110 mi Kxpense for all lecturer* on the road ' 4111 H K\|&gt;cn-r for charts ami lantern slide* 4."&gt; iki K\|i(mim' for stereopticon lantern 110 OU </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 mi -n who »|H-ak from an Institute platform should thomlv Im n the farm in a good |&gt;laee to live. ;i jr.i.id plac-e t,&gt; retire to, a good phi,-, N her men w y successful unless ii In; in tin- disci phi. few technical subje&lt; A f:trmiT -aid t" iii' ■ ifi-i-ntly. 'I learned more alxuil the E\pet 1 iniHT said to me iceently. ■• I learned more abonl the Experimei &gt;l of Airriculiuiv from our stereopticon lecture than In ■n \cai-' residence in the state, ami attendance :ii three previo Institutes.' Another farmer said. -The talk an feeding h&lt;&gt;| i I heard la-! year, was worth two hundred dollars in mv feeding oim iinl School of Agriculture from one stereouticon lecture llian f 11 year*' residence in the state, ami attendance al three nrevioi rs" Institutes." Another farmer said. -The talk on t. ■•■ I i 1 1 ir ln&gt;" us this year." A sttx-k man in the western part of the state said. ilmtioii c.l lihi.-kli'i; \ini- through the Experiment Station lias sa\ mds of cattle in Sheridan. ( 'Merry and a Ijoining i nl in in formed liv |&gt;roiniuenl stockmen thai the blackleg vaccine distr: through the office ol the Kviierinient Station lias s:i veil many thc.usa (heiel»y increasing the tin iiilu-i- of cattle availalile for the feed-vai A stock man in the western part uf the state sail I. \\ lit mils of cattle in Sheridan. I'herrv and a Ijoiuil I an, itioii ha- nl t !•• ava - aujrliter house, an, I for breeding |&gt;ui|«&gt;»e». The Kxperiinent Stati striluitetl during tlie pa-t year, twenty thousand doses of I. hi lie. and live thousand do-.'- of hog cholera serum, which han effective in reducing these diseases among the animals to which thej applied 'I'lic Fanner-' Institute. Io... may fairly claim a -hare of this I tiiroiigh its efforts to disseniinal ■ this information regarding the* ml in spre.i I iliis inform ition which ha« enabled the stix-kmen to antage nl enVctM c remedies. i .11 lie -i -' liisiiim,. could be in id.- sti in ire effective 1&gt;\ increa-ing the to the purpose. Minnesota. Wisconsin and Iowa devote i. 01 1 per year to Institute work. Ne« Vork devotes (25. (NN) nil. and tin - aiiL'lii'-r •lniii« &gt; . and for breeding purposes. The l\\p past year, twenty thou-and lie. ami live thousand di&gt;ses of hog cholera serum, wit noiijt th'- annuals in which they i. in :i -liar moil u Inch h if caablcl ' the purp i-c Minues - of Michigan. Olio Indiana approximate abonl $5,000.00 annually tti These suing permit more thoro organization. Dctter speakers ■' Michiirau, Olio Indiana apn the publication of Institute Annuals which are of great assistance n furthering tin- work Very respectfully submitted. K A BrRNETT, Superintendant of l'armcr-' In-titutc. Very resjiei I K A HI KNKTI UK PORT &lt;&gt;K I III. • » INSPECTOR OF ACCREDITED SCHOOLS INSI'Kl TOI! OK At KEDITK1.1 SCHOOLS ( Hcellm- mi./ the I; &gt;&lt;ifl I take pleasure in Miltmitting my a~ka high uohiMils. I have To tin Chancellor amt tlie Board til' l:e / nix: re in submitting my second biennial report of the inspection Nebraska high schools. I have given my entire time during the Behoo to the work uf inspection, visiting frtmi three to live schools a week sits for the year is'.ili I WU0 were as follows: t lie. i nl oimI biennial report of the inspection n my entire time durius the school X to the work of inspection, visiting from three to five schools a week Biaita for the year I HUB l'.MKt were as follows: her of hiirh -chooN \ i-iteil 1mm' of hiifh schools \ i-itet) twice NuiiiU'r of high schools visited Nu ml mm' of high schools visited twice ; Numlier of high schools visited three times Number of hi^'h schools visited three t mis Number of academies visited a lier of accredited schools not visited 7 Number of academies visited 4 &gt; Number of normal schools visited Numlter of colleges visited Educational conventions attended 10 Number of schools accepted for the accredited list Iii inspecting a school I follow as far a- circumstance* permit, the follow inn ptao: (1) Spend « '»H day in the school g) Visit each instructor during </seg>
            <seg id="p033">:i th-grade classes H ( itnfer wilh4he in \ w troctor*. i I'onsull with tin 1 superintendent. 8 Meel with the boari Hisult w in ducalion. Daring t li *- last two years h jili school conditions hare pereeptiblj i Schools have gained mil only in |&gt;oint of enrollment, strenicl During the la- i i\ i nt. strength ■•nir-i— nf -tmly. ami scholarship of instructors. Inn progress I'* 8 I m - • - 1 1 n i&gt;iuiii&lt;Mliti&lt;&gt;ns, scienlitic equipment and library facilities TIm 1 imii'iit and library facilities Tin 1 li rliiHil I'liriiilmi'iit &lt;if the accredited scl Is a at least twenty per thai "t two years r&lt;«r&lt; &gt;. ami i h&lt;- total nnmber of graduates a ;u least twentv per Km' thai ol tw« years ago, and i h&lt;- total number of graduati ufiily per cent higher. The niurwt i&gt;1 study hare been streugthi . 1 1 i 1 1 ir mil tli- Ihsh &lt; — t-iii i :i 1 branches ami giving additional tin er cent liiirlicr. The courses i&gt;f study have licen strengthen* In- more essential Board* of &lt;■ lucation "i accn ;li:m rrer (.Imii' in the selection i»f their teachen for hip iuhjects. They practically d**mand :i »*&lt;&gt;. «-^f fluration as the iiiiiiiuiniii ri'iiienl of nigh school iiisirnctors in all i«ir heal -■■! la V her ol lower seho arship i. it is either i«:ui-r of verj experience, or because mi suitable graduate is availali now in' practice to ( -i only college graduates, and only such a- an iicaiiiMi aa ilii' minimum i iim-iit of high school instructors in all i&gt;ur l&gt;cst schools V :ui-r of v ery mm ible graduate is available. It is now I tic practice to ( -t only college graduates, and only such a- arc i in i mi 1 1 or a|i|&gt;rn\ ■ 1 1 by tlir l'niver»itjr. Kxpekienck. Wlii i'. iii the "election "i instroctim*, there has Front tin- standpoint of scholarship, there has been some li«s fron point iif experien«*e. In many cases a collea« prraduate without e has taken tin' pla&gt;"e of an px|&gt;erienced tea«'her of lower scholars v tin 1 change has prored lieneticial. eren thoajfh the new eti ■ I iir aupruvitl I &gt;v tin- I'niveisitv KxreKiEM k. \VI instructor!*, there Iki- lieen from tin* standiMiiul of scholarship, there li:i&gt; l&gt;een ~"inc !•&gt;&lt;■. from standpoint of experieniv. In many cases a college graduate without exi I ~ 1 1 ; i 1 v the chaiiKC has prove&lt;l lieneticial. even though the new c« naii- ha» sometimes failed to grasp, :ii oni'i'. high *i*honl conditions. M ion shows thai these instructors of higher scholarship do not n enough in a place. Then* :iri* few college graduates wlm hare hail ex - ice in teachiug. ami who desire liitjli ~.-ln&gt;ul positions, racancii - i largely, by graduates without experience. At tin' la-i election '•! icrs ii was easily -i 1 "!! thai more than tin 1 iimihI attention wan given in rienee. which resulted in I ries in inanv schools. A mon demand for college graduates of experience, will gire a correspoi talaries. which "ill im-an teachers fora longer term "i In; "»i "I'ki.mn i KM&gt;K\ i Tlie sehiMils of the state are under efficient i ti ion shows tlial theoe iiMtrnctora of higher ncholar^hip &lt;ln not r - eiiough in a place. There are few college graduates wImi have had ex- \vs ||i:i w hii^li scIiikiI po \perience. At tin 1 la~t election tellers ii was easily seen that more than the usual attention was given rience. which resulted in lietter salaries in many schools. A win ■al demand for college graduates of experience, will iri\e a corresponding n salaries, which will mean teachers fora lunger term "i year-. in I'll; SlTKKIM I h.NUh.N I I the state are under eHicieiil 111:111- ageiuenl al the presenl time Mosi superintendents are men of scholarship executive ability, and well qiialilied for the positons they holil. I hare M it turn K executive anility, and w d. howe\ er, that th'V ai Her s.-| U the superinti mistake mi the part ol 1 found, however, that th"y are forcwl to teach too many branches In i !■•■ U the Miperintemleul ~li&gt; »n 1&gt; 1 teach a few clashes, but I to teach too many branches In the lioulil tearh a few :&lt;l I'm- mistake mi tin' part ol the board "»f education t" allow insnnicienl tpervising the wiirk below the lii'/li schiH»l. In a number of the - reakness in th ■ (rrades is directly traceable to a lark of proper - a This means wi-akm'— ia the liisrh school in a few years. Oeeasion - i board nf education advocates getting along without a superiuteniieat. of education to allow insufficient time 11 ■l\i school. In a number of tin- schools Bsuper\ i-111^ tin 1 work licli weakness in th ■ grades i - &gt;n. This means wcakne - a hoard of education ad i\ iMe to a lack of proper - hisfh -.choid in :t few veal- (• h nir along without a superintendent. Inn tin' number holding thai opinion is rapidly decreasing In mosl rapidly decreasing In mosl where tin' superinlendeucv has lieen almlishcii fur a year, or where i iliiilishe.i for a year, or where perintemleui ha- lieen required to devote all his time to tin' high school, it le vote all his time to the high sel 1. it lion of the district, rather than I" a has lieen due to the financial condition of tin' • I i — 1 1- i « • t . rather than hi ■ has I m ■&lt; - 11 due to the financial euni ol appreciation ol the services of llciiiiii- iif Kim 1 a niiN —My ol ■ it appreciati&lt;Hi of tin- serrices of a ;_' I superintendent Buakus i if Kim i a 1 1 1 in —My ol i-.it v at ion fails to justify iln- crilicism 1 :it ii &gt;ii fails to justify the criticism made thai '-members of the board of education are men unlit for anv othef idiication arc nun unlit for any other See." As a rule I rind them to lie the leading luis ness men ami most influ- ential professional men ol the town. The &lt;\ tion ol party politics oc church affiliation very seldom enters into the election and dismissal of high schoolteachers. In these matters lioardi act largely upon the :n l\ ■'■'■■■ ........ ........ ...._ their superintendent. It is the common practice, also, to write the Insp lor confidential information al t the applicants. In only a few instance! have boards elected teachers where this confidential information would not warrant such action. It may Ii" added that less care is taken in the -election </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 K...I IPMI i ii&lt; i with 111.- I l|lli|imi«l ol t 1 IH'M' 1 1 1 t! ' 1 \ A X 1 1 ' '* ' ■ I 1 1 it I 1 1 *l I 1 ' • I IMIL dS Mlllt'll 1 1 M 'll''\ 111 »i]*| J .'iI»lMl** "1 1 J ' 1 reference 'nooks, daring the last yemr. us the financial condition o( the dis - trict would justify. Many time* 1 hare considered it necessary to caution ;- against going beyond their means. It very seldom ocean thai a rec - ommendation of the University is not met promptly by tin' board of educa - tion, even where tin 1 outlay amounts to several hundred dollars. It is our desire to use this influence of the University very cautiously, ami to recom - mend only what i- absolutely necessary for work ami no more than is -lent with tin' si/r of the school and iis financial condition. CoL'ESES or Stuim —Not only accredited schools but the smaller graded school* conform their courses of study to the standard courses recom - mended l&gt;y the Mate Department of Kilucatiou ami the University, given as much uniformity a- i- desirable. The high school courses of the 'talc are as near the suggestive si ate com-es a- local conditions will warrant The adoption ot entrance requirements, based on what Is actual v done in thi' Ik'si nigh schools instead of what is required for entrance to other colleges, is the most important action ever taken by the University in matters pertain ing to the secondary schools. It i- a formal recognition by the University that this institution i- a part of the great public school system of this This action, al once. &lt;-lo-c- the gap that has heretofore existed between the high school and the I'niversity. .a Bad Tkvukv i The strong desire of high schools to affiliate closely with the I'niversitv, while on the whole beneficial, has produced an unfor - tunate tendency among the -mailer scl Is to carry heavier high school study than i- consistent with thesixe of the town This gives over led programs and over worked teachers It gives a top-heavy course of study. It means, that if the high school work is well done, the work of the grades i- neglected. Mill worse, it means a reaction in the school senti - ment of the community in a few years, which will place the standard as much too low as it i- now too high. The L'niversity has advised againsl these heavy courses, and vet University influence i- responsible, in a measure, for this tendency. The influence comes from the announcement ■thai certain studies usually called "preparatory" now carried by the University will be dropped in a short time. The high schools expect, each year, this action of the l'niversity to take place tl lowing year, whereas they may be sun that no change so Important will 1m - made without ample notice. They prepare for it by making a four-years course of study to fit their graduates for freshman classes. Fully half of the high schrolsof this Mate carrying four-years ought to carry only three This would permit paying better salaries, which would mean retaining stronger ■T- ll would enable district- to have better laboratory Bad library facilities, and assure more thoro and efficient work. Eierc an- twenty-five or thirty high school- in the Slate large enough, and •ugh financially, to carry four years' work: there are sixty or nty thai could safely attempt three years. It would be unwise to limit our accredited schools to the twenty-live ready to do four years' work, be - cause thai would place certain portions of the State at a disadvantage. It seem- to me iliat it would lie equally unwise to force the sixty or seventy weaker places to go beyond their means in order to reach the University by including these, utmost every county would be provided with a school whose graduate- could enter the University. In other words, tin- conditions in thi- Stale are such that the l'niversity ought for many years to continue to receive the graduates of good three year high school- and to arrange the courses in the University so that -uch students can graduate in due time Graduates of three-year courses enter now. bin the announcement thai the r-iiy will, in the near future, drop all so-called preparatory work i - doiag harm If it could be announced officially that the University has no </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Mt intenli f plaiinu the minimum entrance mpsirMMMti Ml of -•liooK and that jtraduates from ~mh •choo mi I" '. :i n t :itr&gt; ■ "" cntiTiiiii.it would greatly lessen the tendency t" top hea\y eoarssa among the smaller accredited scnoo this btaqaestion thai should receive careful attention on the part of the ( 'hanee lor and the Board ol Kegents. The past Menniuai ha- been a period of quiet, persistent work, with uu enc raraging improveisenl in the high school conditions, and I belter* a tfen- UMnta in Hcholanaip, both in teachers and high school graduates. The biennium ends with the most cordial relations possible between the UniviT- -it _v :ind accredited hinli nchools. In conclusion I desire to recognize the uniform courtesy of your Board :ind the kind personal reception accorded to ineliv the schools of the State Very respectfully submitted. .1. VV CRABTREE. Inspector of Accredited S. REPORT OF THE REGISTRAR SUMMARY OF STUDEHTH MW-18M »»»» The (iraduate School TH 4-1 US The College of Literature, Science and the Arts. 4th year .V! 43 Sdyear is M in 3d year 87 Till i»»i 1st year si; 9:! ITil M 9:! 179 Collegiate Law If 0 1« tnclassitied students f] 141 1(58 Total :!47 444 7!tl Industrial College, 4th year 3-i I 37 3.1 year ."&gt;' 7 .&gt; '.M vear 41 8 49 ir 116 17 M Collegiate Medical . . .'. 11 0 12 Unclassified Students 11) . 9 ,' s Total 36(1 4« IW Law School, ".'il year "i'i Unclassified 1 '• 1 Law School, 1st year ■ 0 GS Total 111! I 11* Scl 1 of Domestic Scienee 0 11 11 School of Agriculture i&gt;4 J 66 Sogar School I u 2 School of Mechanic Arts, 'id year 12 U 12 1st year 40 0 40 40 0 40 Total 118 13 131 School of Art and Musi.- Art 13 56 69 Mu-ic 52 215 M Total t&gt;5 SM </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Total 1-40 iKS •-•:!&lt;; Siiiinii r School 114 1M 849 Grand total* llliO l(X)7 -iVu Deduct for repeated name* M 12* |«j| Total registration .. KtiiT 871 1!'16 SUMMARY OK THE STUDENTS 1HM-1M3 M V N w i &gt; M I N TOT » L. The Graduate School m SI 14 s The College ol Literature. Science and I hi- Aits. 4th year :(H M * I year " 54 47 101 id year M M 131 latywu* ms iao M6 Collegiate Law r&gt;4 oo I'nilassilieil :il 157 Total .too «n 74- Preparatory % 711 17". Urand Total :«»•; 5-J7 W8 The Industrial College, 4th year :id c, :«•, 3d year 54 10 M M year imi u 71 1st year 101 15 11« Pre-Medical 11 l ij rnclassilieil 17 7 M Total 27:! HO SI Preparatory HO 19 M The School of Domestic Science 00 11 11 The School of Agriculture Ill :{ 114 The Sugar School a 0 '.' The School of Mechanic Arts 43 0 43 Total 156 14 170 Grand Total SM 7&lt;i 5«5 The College of Law. Id year 71 0 71 1st year M 11 !ki Total 1C1 0 ltil School of Art 14 &lt;!7 -I School of .Music 41 24H Total bb tu an Summer Session 114 16* Grand Total* ISM 1141 211:7 Deduct for repeated names &lt;I5 M Total registration .. TJ31 178 SM </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 \rkanMS I Mini..- 9 ■ rnia 6 Missouri Canada. •i Montana 9 Central America 1 Nebraska Colorado 18 New Jersey i New Mexico l Connecticut 1 England 1 New York 15 (ierraanv "2 1. 1. ill. i •&gt; •&gt; North Dakota 1 Idaho Ohio 1'2 Illinois :S3 Oklahoma India 1 Oregon "1 Indiana 11 Pennsylvania 11 Iowa IS1 KhoiU- Island 1 Japan 1 South Dakota 31 Kansas 35 Texas 2 Kentucky •&gt; Utah I Maine 3 Washington 3 Massachusetts 3 Wisconsin Michigan 4 Wyoming V RESIDENCE IN NEBRASKA BY COUNTIES Adamv -7 Frontier 2 Otoe "■■ Anti'lope 13 FnnUM "21 Pawnee IV e M tinge liT 1' rkii.s... 1 BoxBnttt- 1 (iartield 1 Paelps Brown 4 (ireetey t» Pierce Buffalo li Hall.." '2:. I'latte V&gt; Hurt V&gt; Mamillon 21 I'olk Butler :!:( Harlan !&gt; Kid Willow 9 ( a-s ."i9 Harrison i Richardson Cedar ti Haves '2 Saline Chase 3 Hitchcock I Sarpv 0 Cherry ti Holt 10 Saunden 94 Cheyenne it Howard 7 Scot is Bluff ( 'lay 43 Jefferson Hi Seward 80 Colfax II Johnxon J7 Sheridan Caming '.".I Kearney ■-"•• Sherinan Coster 8 Keith '.' Sioux 1 Dakota 1(1 Kami Hi Stanton I Dawes I Lancaster Til Thayer 37 Dawson 'Ml Lincoln '21 Thurston 1 Duel .'t l^oup ... 1 Union 1 Dixon 14 Madison '24 Valla* Dodge 47 Merrick 14 Waxbington "21 Douglas 19 Name 13 Wayne 1U Killmore -j:! Nen.aha '27 Webster 18 Franklin H Nnckolls 17 York SS </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 1- years g 85 years j» W vear&gt; 1 at yean l'l IBjrwn 4 S? yearn l (i years in % yean ■ 17 y«»W G&lt;i 39 year- ... : , ' 8 years 197 40 V.'ar- r! 19 years 275 II years.... 4 30 years 300 4 -,» \,,. u .^ ,, " • «-« ■»- .war- &lt;l -il years a»4 4M year- 5 5 y**™ 278 44 yean '.'..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'. I U ye.tis m 4:i year- 5 - v '' al - 278 44 yean &gt;, id years -J44 4.-, ;,..„.. , 1 -* yars is:, M years.... -i 25 yean 138 47 yean »• years 114 48 year* '-'7 years s'.i 4* yean 28 yean 77 .Vi years *• ye»" 77 ~&gt;:\ yean 9 •,".t yean :!(l vears 4y 54 yean 7 •*» u-t vemra £ y^ 1 "'- :i4 57 year- ..........'."! •'- &gt;'"»•- 33 M yean I'LACE OK KIKTII Arkansa- 1 Nebraska. iV'-" 1 ' 1 !• Netherlatnls 1 Hiilifinia 5 New Brtinnwink ."» Hew BniDAwick California 8 New Hampshire Canada 2' Now J.iJ&gt; ., 2-J New Jersey ;p Colorado Colorado 11 New Mexico 1 Connecticut r&gt; New York Delaware 1 Norway Denmark 12 Nova Scotia District of Columbia 1 Ohio ' 115 England^ it Oregoii!.'!!!!.'!!"!!!!".""""; 1 English Channel 1 Pennsylvania.!! nil Germany 28 Rhode Island! 1 Waho 1 Russia ■ Illinois :t4(i Central America . 1 Indiana gg Scotland \ l"»:i ..'til South Dakota 11 3M Central America ! 1 ■M South Dakota .........'...'. 14 Ireland g South Wale* •J :l l&gt;an 3 Sweden.... |g Jiitlaml 1 SwirxArUnH ■) Jutland 1 Switzerland ■( Kansas M Tpnnmuuu. 1 ")»i Teiinesst'e 4 Kentucky '.".'.'.I! 17 Texas ! 4 Jj 1 ' 1 '" 1 8 rtah !!!!!!!!!!!! JJaryUad !!!!!!!!!! 1 Vermont !!.!!!!!!!!!'!!!.!'! ■1 — j " &gt; enuoni - Massachiisetta Hi Virginia I'l'igan 3-j West Virsrinia. 11 Minnesota 2, Wisconsin. ' ,14 Missouri HVnmin. ■ W yoming </seg>
            <seg id="p039">1 Mail Service . 10 '■'i Manufacturer* I Marble Dealers I Architect J Maaoaa r»' l Mechanic*. . -ji I "i rs :i Merchants M Auctioneers 2 Mil era ... •&gt; 7'.i Millwright *■ - Miners . . : -mitli- »mitli« Hi Minister*.... Bookkeepers »«'&lt;'l»«''" s 11 Music Dealer . 11 Music Dealer.. 1 10 Name *s 10 Hum 1 Business Manager ess Managers in Nurserymen " 1 19 Nurserymen 14 Butcher -I Notaries Public I'arpenterH and Cabinet Make inters ami Cabinet Makers.. 53 Paper Hanger llis ' s 5 Painters : rimmw 1 IVtt.Tii Maker re Trimmer 1 Trttcni Maker 1 s Pensioner 1 H Pensioner 1 County A State Officers. .. 8N Photograpbera ;!s Photographer! :i 11 Physicians T:( Knjriiif.Ts 11 Physicians - and Salesmen - I'hi-terer. 1 1*1 II 111 ' it-. 1 I ( '&lt;&gt;! lectors Police 1 tioner 3 Politician. 1 ■-'« Pork Packen S ractar I i "in i ai i\n . . , . .... &lt;s 1 Potter l '-' Printer* 7 1 I'rofessors 17 . &lt; lour) Reporter men J&gt; Provision Store •' l'liiiip Dealer 1 1 Railroad Employees 4"&gt; -•"» Ranchmen lo I' 1 Heal Ksiate I Engineers 20 Receiver 1 Executor 1 Registrar n Deed* 1 Expressmen : t Sirrelaric- . . .1 '■''- &gt;s Shoemakers. " ■-. Kanner 1 Sign Writer. 1 Sign Writer 1 ' Soldiers * '- Stationer 1 89 Steward 1 Furrier (iardner (.rain Dealer 1 25 stock Dealer*!.'.'.".'.'.'.'.". .'..'.'.'.'. 84 Stone ( utter 1 Hardware Dealer- 1 Harness Makers 1 Stone (Quarry 1 Horseman w w * - • Superintendents &lt;&gt;f Sol I-. ... 5 1- Surveyors 0 H Tailor- « ■" Teacher* 46 Proprietors nent Dealer Insurance 4.1 5! Telegraph Operator* Theater Proprietor 1 Journalists - Traveling Salesmen 45 1(1 Undertaker* 3 Laborer l.aii'1 Commissioners r V s. Aimv ( Mlieers 7 133 Veterinary Surgeon 1 . irian! ...'.'..'.".'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'. .'.' Watchman 1 l.i\ervnien l.uinlier Dealers Wellmaker* . 2 28 Not iriven l-,'4 ■• 1M ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 gea ;inil I'nivi-i &gt;iiii's 401 Graduates 14(1 Graduates. In Nebraska In other states X'2 rit graduates ".'til In Nebraska Ult In Nebraska. In other states US dited High Schools 1014 Graduates m Graduates Not (iradnatos '.'s4 Other High Schools 47"&gt; Graduate* :s:i'.i Uradiiatet In Nebraska -"-Jl In other states 1 is Not Gnu! nates 130 In Nebraska *7 In other States 4!t tirades and l)i&lt;uict Schools In Nebraska lH(i In other states 2"J hers Normal- Mi (iradnates !MI In Nebraska .".8 In other states K! RELIGIOUS STATISTICS. VOLUNTARILY GIVEN, L89H L899 MEN. CHtMU'H i H1K« II N« I I MEPAUTMKNT MKMHKKS ADHBKBV1H ADIKUKff TOTAL Graduate U-J IB 5 Industrial IM !•"&gt;&lt;« 31 3«i4 IS 4M 14 110 •. ! y -''J? 1 4.") I* M School of Agriculture M 30 0 M 54^ :tK9 ■ m • it Graduates IN In Nebraska 148 In (&gt;t lit-r slates "&gt;1 Academies 77 Business Colleges 'J7 Foreign Schools U Institutes 8 Latin Schools 15 Military Schools r&gt; Preparatory Schools 84 l'rivati' Schools 13 Professional Schools 7 Seminaries . . . . . 18 Training Schools. - No! given "J </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 WOMEN Graduate :S4 !&gt; 1 44 Industrial ■ •_".» 4 89 l.i« 0. 1 1 2 ry 42fi 12-J r&gt; 5o:i School of Agriculture 0 2 o I 509 M ii 683 SUMMARY M.n and Women). Graduate M 21 n 126 1 iMlustrial 23.-, lsr. mi; 44f. l*w 5.! 44 15 113 Literary G."&gt;3 207 31 943 School of Agriculture 20 :S2 0 -Vj 52 1067 .'&gt;52 71 1«7!» DISTRIBUTION AMONG THK RELIGIOUS DENOMI NATIONS ("HI'RCII H MHEHS AUHKHI.VT- T"T M Baptist Ill 44 l.V. Hrcl hren 1 1 I United Brethern 1 1 1 Buddist 1 o l Kiiuian Catholic M 4 tiO Christian or Disciples sip 20 Km Christian Science 1 ii 7 I'oMrogational 134 Ha 220 Dnnkard 1 0 1 Protestant Episcopal «4 H 101 ETannlical I 3 7 thinker ll 1 1 Krici.ils 5 1 •&gt; Jewish 12 3 Lutheran 4* 33 70 Ifennonite 0 1 1 Methodist -JS4 174 45* Mission 1 0 1 Presbyterian 3W M ."»•-• L'nmberland Presbyterian 2 0 2 Kiki\ Presbyterian 1 ti 1 B tad Presbyterian 22 :i 25 inn ( 'hurch 2 0 2 2 0 2 Seventh Day Adventi-ts 4 (t 4 I'nitarian 12 13 25 Bon , 1 1 vt'isalist 3 12 14 1 1 Universalist Any Protestant Church 0 27 27 lOr.T 5.VJ 16U9 N"t member* or adherent- M 11 7(t Total 11 Hi 1'!7:p </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 RELIGIOUS STATISTICS. VOLUNTARILY GIVEN I«!i9 l'.MKI MEN h i ». 'i i if rm'ii n&lt; n ■ •■PAKTV HBHBBK4 AIIHKKKNI- ADHEKCN TH 1 1 &gt;l A I IIIPAKTMKNT HBHUEK4 A IIH »:Kh N I » ADHKKCN *&lt;-li'M&gt;] of Agriculture 4i&gt; 5T :i Hxi Art 1 i: (I s s&lt;-Iicm&gt;] ol Agriculture 4i&gt; 5T :! 1ih&gt; An i; 0 An -J ii 0 ite 7:i Hi 4 M ».r:i.lu:il.- 7:i Hi 4 N Industrial XM 19:. -.'1 4-j:&gt; Industrial $0» 19:. -.'1 4-j:» Imm ... Tii N ■"■&gt; 166 Law Til N ■"■&gt; 166 -J41 IM 17 414 -J41 1M 17 414 f»41 510 Ml 510 30 I ,'(11 50 1201 WOMKN WOMKN ill Agriculture 'J 1 (I Airiiruitun- I 1 (t :; Art X 7 0 4.' An :s^ 7 0 4- Graduate -17 13 n N Uraduate 47 13 n N Industrial imi f] 4 !il [ndnstrial M -&gt;7 4 ill Literary 402 14:&lt; 4 60» l.it.taiy 402 IVi 4 60!&gt; (MMi 19(1 S S04 S04 sr.MMAKV- M.ii mm! Women uf Agriculture.. .. 4- IH KKi I SJ i:; o on • I AKricultiire 4- IH KKi 1IBI i 33 ia o on Graduate 131 t 193 Uradomte 1-Jd t 193 Indusl rial Ml 228 2-"&gt; 51« rial Ml 28J 25 5lii l.:i» 7(1 M •'» 106 l.:i« 7(1 M •'» 106 y 7(i:i ■.'it'.i II IO2S j 7(i:i ■.".Mi n UBM Ii47 TiMi IM&lt; TiMi W MM W -'iK)r. DISTRIBUTION AM&lt;)N(iTHE BIUOIOU8 DENOMINATIONS DISTRIBUTION AMOXli THE RELIGIOUS DENOMINATIONS C'HI'liCH imin AMCBKHTil TOTAL C'HI'liCH MKMIIKUv AOBKBKHTS TOTAL IH H 171 Baptist 1 ii 1 Kretlm-n :i » :! 1'niif.l Brethren 4 »&gt; 10 Hinl.lisi 1 0 I Rosmm Catholic I m ChriMtian H :t7 1^:; &lt; "hristian Science 1 M Congregational tW 110 -2-4 Dankard i l 3 .» 1 3 l&gt;al M 44 109 itelical '.i I M Thinker (I 1 1 7 1 1 sh 1 I 8 Latheran (Kic., &lt;■&lt;■!■ . Swetl.. ami Nor.) "ii 7!i lUtEpbcopal Mt »M 5« :«:; an .vi-j </seg>
            <seg id="p043">New Jerusalem I 0 People's Independent | (, | Presbyterian o ; j[ yr\ m Cumberland Presbyterian 3 0 I'nited Presbyterian '• as 7 Progressive Brethren 1 0 1 Reformed u j 7 Seventh l&gt;:i\Ailventist 4 1 5 Union. \ 0 1 1 Unitarian 13 kj 29 rniversulist 1 n 12 Any Protestant Church 0 M 31 1-J4T TOO 1»47 Not Members or Adherents ."&gt;0 58 Total UVJ 708 '.tHl </seg>
            <seg id="p044">r. r- 5 s i t X 5 ej &lt;- D o *o O ' gajj '2-fi?r £ 5S £ g!i^^2 8|fUIg2S :5 a i / I || 1^1 |l2§§3|§o||s| HI j j !J|S|I | 5 I -\ 7i . i. »i _; Ji B , s x &lt;- rf * 2 .2 = 5 . = S -2 2g-gg -§-§„ = = _2 = =-~ | | ■ i as -^ t:i- 31 55 ?&gt; ■y- M ~ d nj, s , :i 3aun|. P.~ S S ~ 2 9fl | »5 £ § 2 .i.i.inj MIU] ftlliq.liMl "r. J iij snuiiTppY' ■ * S mH-nwoo 88 § 88 S §S. S SS gjl a ■ ij iQOpippV a W\* oj )so.) ubO JtHl { l : 1 1 1 1 ii \ ll k^ H — ' : — ' »~— « ao-r «-• Ig 2 - ua .aaqo^wooK R8 | 5 2 R §| C S9 | *{j •^ho^j,,,^ §5 | 3 2 g I SI! ghjj T» 112 s,n al .n, S ,o ,, M II | | | § || | g£ J|Jj WP«njiou I?- f 5 § S 5i i SS 5 ii 3 3 2 S S SS 2-' 82 Sill ii r&lt; ac o»C •suoi}BU(l(M&lt;l(h: =oi.o csc=i_= 55 a agg. ; suoi}BU(l(M&lt;l(li: =oi.o Cbcoa.s =2 B 99 O. S •&gt;jt:js innnui: .10 ~.-.t'i.~. 52&gt;..S - s;S 38 S *8 - t.8 K&amp;S t j .tjrjs iBiiaut: .10 =="^5 32_&gt;.§"^= S3 S t-§"i_S B&amp;S '*** X1:) ??; i £^ -t §53 1§ 8'i §' .-'?' i ES 2ls ranuun 10 iii»i 1 !"5(i,S ti c - ?» _ ~ - t - - 5; «i S =.?i | S £■•- __! * ' ' - A I mr KtJ bx '- ~ '*• m o = ;1 i! S ■ § § sl 1. n 1S1 7- C_ TSSy&amp;i 2- S - S - 38 5 M 8 sH t.3 1 f.ss ,wpnno; u,,i (A \ || | f J f || f || | |*| ■c IS I I S i &amp;1 5 §S 5 as - ii i ■ * x Ty * 3Eao Ss-c iwpano; n,»q A \ \ — r — it " " 1 1 il " 7\ '■ i i-i i— si I «J I? 3 I! i I : 1 1I ■ II I 1 M Ii I Ii !i /. Sfi) j. $ sliecf I W 5!S -S I BS5; &lt; &lt;~ : * </seg>
            <seg id="p045">the cost i&gt;f its buildings: (b) that it is also the lowest except two in the amount of annual state aid received: (c that lint four of the institutions named exceed it in attendance of students— at least three of them having schools of medicine, pharmacy, dentistry, etc. which the University of Ne - braska has not: d that lint three of the institutions named have a smaller teaching force; (e) that the average salary rate is as low in the University of Nebraska as in any of the institutions named with possibly two exceptions: (f) that the annual per capita coat to the state is much lower in Nebraska than in any other slate Basted. The per capita eoat argument is a popular and often a delusive one for estimating the efficiency of an educational institution. For example, taking the iglliea of the table as they stand for Nebraska and dividing the state aid by the number of students the per capita cost result is $77.7:2. B it the law school and the school of line arts are practically self-supporting. Therefore the '-'4-2 students in these schools should be. for the present purpose, deducted from the total attendance for the last year, reducing the figures to 1967. Dividing the revenue from the state by this latter numl&gt;er gives the per capita rale shown in the table This i- exact if it be assumed that the entire tax levied in the one year is collected and becomes available— a condition which is never quite realized Tne per capita cost to the state as thus calculated is as nearly correct ■ it could be stated under existing conditions. Other interesting deductions favorable to the University of Nebraska are to be drawn from a careful study of the table. The relative size of the Uni - versity library is noticeable among the younger institutions. The struggle of the I'niversity to meet the demands ol the state with moderate material equipment anil with only a small addition to the teaching force is very clearly shown. A little study of this table alone must convince any one that the needs of the University are great and that the requests of the Regents are both conservative and justifiable if the University of Nebraska i&gt; to hold its place in the educational move.nent of the time and successfully meet the wants of the people of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">1895 K.ni hool DIAGRAM [.— Saownra m ucuam in koikiwoi m &lt;ami-i OH THE UNIVKRSm KAItM CAIPt FARM I. I'm i versify Hall. - Chemical Laboratory 3. Grant Memorial Hall, L899 1 in ii i p™^ Knlarjrcment A ■ : ""' LTel.Cl'a 5. Nebraska Hall 5. Boiler House. (i. Electrical Laboratory. 7. Carpenter Shop. 8. North Wing of Library t±_*j j °r-. H rrSr '.». Plant Houst 10. Slh 1895 11. School of Musi T2. Library. 1894 L^^i g IS. Astronomii-al Observatoi-y 14. Wing of Mechanic Arts Hall. 15. Soldiers' Memorial Hall. a 1892 ■ ft No m, M j Additions 10. OKI Stone House remodeled in for Agricultural Chemical Lai torv. 1891 1890 17. New Farm House 18. Barn. 1MS8 lit. Shed M. Animal Hou» 1885 21. Pathobiolofical Laboratory ■. Dairy Hall. 1875 •23. Irrigating Pond and Mill 24. Grow. _J 1874 A J 25. Forestry Experiment 20 Experimental Plots. 1869 A 27. Experiment station and FanaSo Buildiinr. H. Water Tower 29. Heatiuj; Plant 1868 1 898 A ■ uu&lt;l genera] ism a !■■ 1S»6 AM; -.• </seg>
            <seg id="p047">i I M DlA'iRAM II -Showing the total enrollment &lt;&gt;k studests IM7-M 1898 » </seg>
            <seg id="p048">I. HUM A IK SCHOOL 3 Proportion ol Men II*. &lt;'.! OOUJOI O» LlTKKATIKK I'roportion of J'ronortion of Uollbui OF Law [■DD*TB1AL COLI.COI Proportion of Men M'-n Women and Women ■ -- 1 Proportion of \\ omen . 3 7- Ta </seg>
            <seg id="p049">PKKP STrDBNTN iK"H\ikhi.v Latin Kthooi Mrsn ■■ - i UK ■■ - i UK . - - / ; ;/ \- - - r4a The relative proportion of mt*n The relative proportion of m«-n 1-rr 7- - - - / ' '/ \- - - uu and women is to be shown by tb- and women is to be shown by tb- IX7&amp;-77 - - - -vi— 4— — &gt; - - - 198 IICft-77 - - - ■ v i ■ 1 N 1»8 - - -\ .A / . - - 13rt - - .\'\ / - - - 13rt &gt;• tippled area for tbe men, the white area Tor tbe men, the white .... \iJz . flu area for the woiufn. area for the women. 1S73-74- -.-.-. M-. - » 1«71 K .' ' .' ' &lt;-~ r \~ . 1 110 - VRsni I O - SCBOOLOP *^ : I IN ABSENTIA f. SHtiHl CUUHHK 1M83-M _ « . n5 •*-« . _\ /. ■ :«; s, ii.i.L or OtHJJKsi or Schomi. or Mlsn MtDlC NE AKT- AI.HIirl.TlRK ■— IWH.IMl AttTUfi ' ' . .. M \ / ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p050">DIACiKAM V # — Showing tiik. mm state: i w . ami ihk United States Inivkk-h WrUol'HI ATIKN KOI! i iik Biennium Appropriation of ending the state (tax. Appropriations of the l"nited Slates 1. 1901. $33J.OIHI $80,000 —The income from the t.'niieil States endowment lands and the entire University ~h fund are not included for the bitnnium ending March SI. IWil. To avoid confus - iiui this table from this point forward will snow strictly state aiil (appropriations of le tax) and United Slates a'd [&gt;$ direct money grants. The income from endowment lands and the University cash fun), omitted here aggregate for the bieanlum ending March 31. IW)I. approximately MMM. </seg>
         </p>
       </body>
  </text>
</TEI.2>