<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00057.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00057.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Warden of the State Penitentiary Lincoln, NE</title>
               <date value="1923">1923</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Biennial Report OF THE Warden OF THE State Penitentiary LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions For the Period Ending June 30, 1923 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOREWORD To His Excellency, the Governor : The Board of Control herewith transmits the Fifth Biennial Report of the State Institutions of Nebraska for the period ending June 30, 1923. The biennium formerly ended on November 30 of each even-numbered year, but this date was changed by an act of the legislature, so that this report really covers a period of thirty-one months from December 1, 1920, to June 30, 1923. During the period, no change has occurred in the personnel of the Board, but several changes have been made in the chief officers of institutions. Dr. Beverly A. Finklc, superintendent of the Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska, resigned to enter private practice, and was succeeded on August 23, 1921, by Dr. J. H. Matthai. Miss Amy V. Stevens, who had been superintendent of the Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska, for a number of years, resigned on July 5, 1922, being succeeded by her sister, Miss Nellie Stevens. The latter served until February 19, 1923, when her resignation was received, and Miss Lena Driever was appointed to the position. We call attention with pride and pleasure to the fact that the report shows the institutions to have gone through the bien - nium without incurring any deficiencies; although the cost of living, and consequently the cost of supporting the state's depen - dents, has certainly not decreased since the appropriations were made for the biennium. Sume improvements tif a permament character have been made at the various institutions during the period covered by this report. A hospital building, bakery and scullery have been erected at the Nebraska Institution for feeble Minded, Beatrice, Nebraska) a cottage for girls at the Girls' Training School, Geneva, Nebraska j a fms|iii;tf iiHiMiug At the Soldiers and Sailors' Hume, Htirkett, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska; a gymnasium building at the State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska ; a farm house and a barn at the Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska; a warehouse at the State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska; a hospital building at the Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska; a kitchen building at the Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk, Nebraska ; a main building at the State Reformatory for Women, York, Nebraska. These buildings were badly needed, and they will have to be followed by others in the very near future if our wards are to be properly, efficiently and economically cared for. The legislature just past made provision for two or three buildings, but failed to •ee the necessity for several others that were urgently requested. Brief mention was made in the last report of the establishment of the Reformatory for Men at Lincoln, but the importance of the institution calls, we believe, for rather more extended notice. Thifc iiiktitiilKin was etitabliHhed as a result, primarily, of a wide recognition of the need of segregating young first-term offenders from more mature criminal*, The legislature of 1921 authorized ili«* fkUliluliHiriii, therefore, of Midi an institution, making an initial appropriation of $.HX),(XX). &lt; &gt;t thin sum the Board ex - pended $A7,MM for 10 wren uiul a brick building known as the Hayward Military Academy, later buying about 152 acres of Hrtriitfumiii land for thr Mini of $49,531 J5, Thin land in used for UrmiiiK, »i&lt;m It raUiug, dairying, and intensive gardening. Various trod** mm- Ijuight muli mm tailoring, that repairing, carpentry and ji Hurry, lirit'k laying, electricity, autmtiobili repairing, launder - ing, run him ing, firing, Hitd tutrbrrlng. The manual labor nbout iltr iM*iiiit(i"ti in, tif i-imrnt!, ptrfofttMd by the intnati*, of which time Ufa Hi (hi* time IM-i, Mr, A, W, Miller, thr. superintendent, i» (U»i»tt um : U »i»ii"»tuit live work with the young ttiett &lt; ommttinl (A hi* riwn#, »h4 we bulU've the iiistitiiilon Is amply justifying flMtt Th# dllMVwUy lit PHIploytiiH tin- pciiilriif mt v infflftUl »it fiuittlbl« l#bor fli»t (Um mi vwifttet too much with the prerogative* of tbr fr«^ workers of unr litHte, Ims Ijp*i» pretty well twewime. The Hsu siili npfc-ruu-b tin- lihcf furniture luxury which Has been «t the prison tor some years, »nd has aUu estftblished relatioris with the Olieriiiau Company by whii h blurt.-, are made and disposed of with » minimum of competition with free labor, </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 JKMATB POPULATION There are seventeen institutions under the control "' i'"-- Board, and at this time (July 1, 1923) the inmate population is 5917, as compared witli an average of -fWO for the biennimn ending in 1921, and 4907 for the biennium just prior to that. The following table will l&gt;e found of interest as showing the population of the different institutions during the past two biennia : (a) 19 months (1921, &gt;) months ichool; 1''22, 10 months achool.) (b) Open only 21 month'.; staiinl Ortobpr I, 1921. EXPENDITURES The following IjiI.Ic mvijiIs the expenditures at the various institutions for the |..p t biennium, the item of salaries and wages being included under Maintenance in all instances excepting trig first. Capital outlay represent* permanent improvements to the realty and equipment, ieftfd tti Control, lAtitmUt Maintenance ............ 1 JiUS i vm*) Sdiarie» rfiid W«kc« J(i»iituti«n itif Feeble --Minded, Beiiirifee espjtat Q^ mm w mmm , mmmmmmmmummm . vijmMt mmw M»iflten»t»€i ,,,,,,,,,,.„„„„„„„„»„„„.::,„„„.„„„„.„„,„ 111^4I#^7 c»»h ,„„„ '™r:;:r;;:;;:z;;™:zzz: 4^.20 CifHtol 6illir_n. — — . .-»»... 42^00^0 151,772^7 ash ; zzr:~ :; rzrzzz #,iiMf Girts' Training Sehoet, G#nev&amp;= Institutions (With "Key" Letters) Av. pop. Av. pop. Largest biennium hiennium number ending ending at any one lunr.iii, June 3D, time past 1921 1923 two yean A — Institution for Feeble- Minded B — Girls' Training School C — Soldiers and Sailors' Hume D — Hastings State Hospital E — State industrial School F — Hospital for Tuberculous G — Lincoln State Hospital H— Orthopedic Hospital — State I Vnili-iil iary —Nebraska Industrial Hume L— Soldiers anil Sailors' Home M— School for the Blind (a) N— Norfolk State Hospital P— School for tin; LVuf (a) R — Stute Ki-lm maioi v for Women S — Home for Impendent Children T— State Reformatory for Men (b) .. 607 725 756 lui. 17.) 189 409 353 412 1152 I I'M 121" 217 214 241 78 102 106 8.17 971 995 64 88 102 363 586 5% 73 K6 W 148 162 195 47 53 57 646 733 768 171 178 187 9 18 28 53 91 107 Not open 150 192 Total 4980 5876 6249 II </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Burkett — Maintenance 176,14828 Cash _ 67,846.61 Capital Outlay 115,000.00 358,994.89 Hastings State Hospital, Ingleside — Maintenance 501,184.46 Cash 99,853.78 Capital Outlay 38,850.25 639,888.49 State Industrial School, Kearney — Maintenance 161,200.06 Cash 26,345.72 Capital Outlay 43,440.24 230,986.02 Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney — Maintenance 106,076.45 Cash 30,794.13 Capital Outlay , 117,826.18 254,696.76 Lincoln State Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 375,095,50 Cash 89,072.43 Capital Outlay 74,803.84 538,971.77 Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln — Maintenance 122,286.28 Cash _ 25,627.53 Capital Outlay ;. 4,490.17 152,403.98 State Penitentiary, Lincoln — Maintenance 2293)5.92 Cash 161 ,633.02 Capital Outlay 390,838.94 Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford — Maintenance _ 61,306.38 Cash 2,578.26 Capital Outlay 63,884.64 Soldiers and Sailors' Home, Milford — Maintenance 94,406.99 Cash 29,700.29 29,700.29 Capital Outlay 15,934.10 140,041.38 School for the Blind, Nebraska City- Maintenance 57,82522 Cash „ _ 3,989.06 Capital Outlay 3,952.01 65.76629 Norfolk State Hospital, Norfolk- Maintenance 321.060.71 Cash 50,535.76 Capital Outlay... 59,999.01 431,595.48 School for the Deaf, Omaha — Maintenance ..._ _.... 137,695.55 Cash _ 16,819.16 Capital Outlay 4,500.00 159,014.71 State Reformatory for Women, York — Maintenance _ 28,489.38 Cash 2.733.39 2,733.39 Capital Outlay _„ _ 46,996.15 78218.92 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln — Capital Outlay 300,000.00 379,147.91 Grand Total 4,538,783.65 At its various institutions the state owns something over 4000 acres of land, of which in excess of 3500 are in farm and garden. About 800 acres are rented in addition. Details of operation are given in the reports from the several superintendents which are appended hereto. The health of the inmate population has been generally good during the past biennium. We are pleased to be able to report that no epidemic has broken out at any of the institutions, and our medical men have been able to cope with such sporadic cases of contagious disease as have appeared. In conclusion we wish to express our appreciation of the efforts of the officers and employees of the various institutions in striving to bring about a betterment of the living conditions of the wards under their care. We wish also to thank the Governor for his manifestations of interest and for his assistance in the work of this department, and we trust that he will continue his efforts to help us provide better means of caring for the wards of the state. Board of Control, KATHERINE F. WORLEY, Chairman, A. E. ALLYN, L. C. OBERLIES. Attest : E. B. FAIRFIELD, Secretary. Maintenance Cash Capital Outlay 65,026.59 7,584.94 72,611.53 itate Reformatory for Men, Lincoln — Maintenance Cash 72,188.46 6,959.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AVERAGE DAILY POPULATION STATE INSTITUTIONS OF TOTAL POPULATION 5,876 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 EXPENDITURES FOR 1921-1922 SALARIES and WAGES OPERATION and MAINTENANCE 2,27£,H65.M6 FURNITURE and EQUIPMENT I96,O93.9M NEW BUILDINGS 6O3.6H9.60 LAND ' 48.748.08 FIXED CHARGES and STATE AID 6,848.53 PERMANENT IMP. TO BUILDINGS and GROUNDS 1 1 1 ,02570 TOTAL 4,491,10225 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 INCOME FOR 1021 - 1922 3,841,348.13 598,304.90 66,960.00 48,100.56 4,554,713.59 STATE FUNDS CASH FUNDS FEDERAL FUNDS TRUST FUNDS TOTAL * UNEXPENDED BALANCE OF CASH , FEDERAL AND TRUST FUNO (clothing funo,institute for feebleminded) rebppropriateo </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 (a) Opened October 1, 1921. 21 months. LAUA..E/O, O1A July 1, 19; !1 to June 30, 1 institution for Feeble-Minded jirls' Training School soldiers' Home, Burkett...- Hastings State Hospital state Industrial School rlospital for Tuberculous Jncoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital . state Penitentiary. Nebraska Industrial Home soldiers' Home, Milford school for the Blind ..._.- Norfolk State Hospital school for the Deaf. _ state Reformatory for Women.... 3ome for Dependent Children state Reformatory for Men (a) * 89,737.78 31,660.01 77,410,19 226,534.52 60,739.65 45 281.20 178,107.10 56,464.88 93,39320 19294.61 35,009.08 32,444.05 137,841.88 77242.53 9,137.15 19,53925 52,439.86 Salaries and Wages $ Operation and Maintenance 186,411.64 82,797.68 155,19827 351,306.24 120,474.65 87,490.63 269,172.04 89,805.58 288,86020 42,879.03 88,144.78 28,007.41 229,413.66 74,549.12 19,058.85 49,977.47 108,91821 Furniture and Equipment $ 25,232.79 9,782.66 8,110.35 15,447.16 10,568.22 16,452.47 16.898.41 4,786.04 4,309.18 520.59 5,468.85 676.87 38,443.00 7,223.06 3,470.00 1,003.35 27,700.94 Permanent Improvements to Bldgs. and Grounds $236.00 16.08 150.50 8,557.31 10.72 2,124.19 28,624.45 1,347.48 3,776.36 1,165.66 10,552.41 685.95 3,634.66 $72,778.39 34,512.84 118,115.58 37,872.07 39,192.78 103,348.27 45,077.86 New Buildings ..... immnHi^m Land $871,27 3.40 10.00 171.19 Fixed and State Aid Charges I 375,267,87 158,772.67 358,994.89 639,888.49 230,986.02 254,696.76 538,971.77 152,403.98 390,838,94 63,884.64 140,041.38 65,76629 431,595.48 139,014.71 78218192 72,611.53 379,147.91 Total for Biennium Per Cent 8.3 3.5 8.0 142 5.1 5.7 12.0 3.4 8.7 1.4 3.1 1.4 10.0 3.5 1.7 1.6 8.4 i/msi ■""84726" 500.00 24.75 19.00 3,952.01 200.00 22,66228"" 7,500.00 2,091.46 50,552.47 '39,052.92" 90,789.35 48,747.08 ■" Total $1,242,276.94 $2,272,465.46 $196,093.94 $121,025.70 $603,649.60 $48,747.08 $6,843.53 $4,491,102.25 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 POPULATION AND PSS CAPITA REPORT OF STATE INSTITUTIONS July 1, 1921, to June 30, 1923 Number of Inmates June 30, 1923 Average number Inmates during Biennium Number of employees June 30, 1923, Average number employees during Biennium Average number Inmates to each employee Average per Capita Cost for Hiennium Average per Capita Cost per month Average amount Pay Roll per month Institution for Feeble-Minded Girls' Training School _ Soldiers' Home, Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School _ Hospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital — Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary. Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford Nebraska School for the Blind (a).... Norfolk State Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf (a) Stats Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men (b) 747 183 301 1,200 207 103 981 93 579 63 154 53 767 187 25 87 187 725 173 353 1,193 214 102 971 88 586 86 162 53 733 178 18 91 150 66 20 72 160 40 36 132 49 55 11 32 24 90 49 7 14 26 61 19 62 ,158 38 35 131 48 53 11 31 24 88 48 6 13 25 12 9 6 7 5 3 7 2 11 8 5 2 8 4 3 7 6 $ 380.89 661.60 659.00 48427 846.80 1,301.68 460.63 1,662.16 652.31 722.95 760.20 1,140.59 501.03 852.76 1,566.44 763.92 1,075.72 $ 15.87 27.57 27.46 20.18 35.28 54.23 19.19 6925 27.18 30.12 31.67 47.52 20.87 35.53 65.27 31.83 51.22 $ 3,562.47 1,319.17 3,225.42 9,438.94 2,530.82 1,886.72 7,421.13 2,352.70 3,891.47 803.94 1,458.71 1,351.84 5,743.41 3,218.44 380.01 814.14 2,497.13 Total 5,917 5,876 851 $ 598.15 $ 24.92 $51,896.46 (a) Average during school year. (b) Open&lt; :d October 1, 1921 — 21 months. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">AGE OF THOSE AD MI' TED FOB IRST TIME Period Ending June 30, 19 Under 5 years 5 to 9 yrs. inc. 10 to 14 yrs. inc. 15 to 17 yrs. inc. 18 to 24 yrs. inc. 25 to 34 yrs. inc. 35 to 44 yrs. inc. 45 to 49 yrs:. inc. 50 to 59 yrs. inc. 60 to 69 yrs. inc. 70 to 79 yrs. inc. 80 to 90 yrs. inc. Over 90 years Unascer- tained Total nstitution for Feeble-Minded jirls' Training School Soldiers' Home, Burkett. Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School — .. iospital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Drthopedic Hospital state Penitentiary. Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' Home, Milford. _ Nebraska School for the Blind. Norfolk SUte Hospital Nebraska School for the Deaf. State Reformatory for Women - Home for Dependent Children State Reformatory for Men 15 67 70 28 38 134 33 11 6 6 ... 246 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 369 92 125 21 344 35 62 238 241 13 204 18 17 57 13 59 33 41 60 54 41 37 31 112 80 1 36 9 59 16 58 79 61 30 15 2 3 t 17 9 65 14 63 185 17 223 28 135 10 61 .... 16 50 3 18 12 70 8 43 I i 1 m ioo 89 31 _... 2 14 3 7 1 4 3 12 2 8 6 15 4 27 1 39 i ... , 6 15 ■•• 66 «" 4 7 80 74 36 41 38 i 2 26 34 121 67 44 6 5 3 i _ 180 ... 46 Total...- 211 393 324 599 581 743 399 172 212 181 271 76 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 ITTED FOR FIRST TIME Bie: inium F.ndin [ June 30, 1923. In-UtuUon PMbto Waded dirts' aiding School Soldiers andStUors' Home Barkett Hastings sutT" Hospital State Induitrial School Hoepital for Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital Orthopedic Hospital State Penitentiary Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers and Sailors 1 Home Mllfuru Nebraska School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital Nchntfiku School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory for Men Total . i 7 7 20 12 3 28 1 18 24 2x 3 6 95 7 1 4 21 4 6 1 22 1 1929 1 4 14 30 1 8 1 2 1 2 44 6 1 1564 124 30 *v*-M*HCMA(_l | I,, , i -T..T,T. ............. ..I ~ 2 ~ 5 ... _____ 6 i 14 Austria ._ ri — ! n..i_^. _ 2 2 i £•_«£• — - M _. 7 r 12 3 i Canada n._.. — 1 cam Caecfco-Slovakia Enctaad ..II~""ZIZZ"Z Finland 9t ..Z — Greece W°U-«i Hungary Ireland Italy 1Z'.ZZ.~.L. Moravia _.. Nebraska Netherlands Norway Poland Rdftia _.. Saxony Scotland _ Seria Servia ..... siciiia :; Spain ■'Wmill Switzerland „. Turkey _ V. S. other than Nebraska. &gt; 'nkiiiiwn Other Countries 1 7 6 i i n 17 8 6 2 4 5 1 2 27 ■■■■ ~i "l | T~ 2 i &gt; 2 "~ ~5 1 19 1 i 2 2 32" 1 1 3 2 1 1 i 2 1 2 — "'" 5 """ i" 3 7 i 3 1 i i 3 2~i 1 ..._ ~™ 4 2 - _ ._. 1 1 119 1 3 i n 2 l 209 98 " 2 157"" ' m 201 339 74 66 l 12 103" 26 30 232 '"" 72 :. 2 3 8 1 1 2 1 2 5 _ i 2 l r 4 "1 10 2 i, M 1 _ _... 1 4 i ~" 2 i I _ ' 2 1 I ... 2 2 13 2 .4 2 9 i " " l 13 i 32" 56 4 119 205 26 137 """76 209 42 4 42 i 256 5 20 1 116 8 129 9 29 5 1 116 45 26 Tot.-,! 246 162 135 472 333 220 586 384 36') 02 12? 21 344 35 62 4074 238 241 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 CLASSIFICATION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR FIRST TIME Biennium Ending June 30, 1923. County Is-HI-Hon Girls' Training School Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Burkett Hastings State Hospital State Industrial School I Hospital (or | Tuberculous Lincoln State Hospital j Orthopedic | State Hospital Penitentiary I I I Nebraska Industrial Home Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford Nebraska School for the Blind Norfolk State Hospital ! Neurauka School for the Deaf Reformatory for Women Home for Dependent Children Reformatory for Men ToUl Brown , Buffalo Bait Batter Cms Cedar Chase Cherry v-ocy wmc _....-.»..■.......-..—■■ Clay Coilax Coming Caster Dakota Oawes Dawsoa Deuel Dixon Dodge Douglas Dandy ................................. Fill more . _ , Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage Garden Garfield Gosper Grant Greeley Hall . Hamilton , ,, Harlan Hayes .................. Hitchcock Holt Hooker Howard , _... Jefferson Johnson ; _.._ Kearney __.... Keith ..._ Keya Paha Kimball " Knox _ I-ancaster Lincoln Loup Madison _ IfcPherson Merrkfc Nebraska Industrial Home Morrili .._ Nance Nemaha Nuckolls _ . Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps Pierce Platte. Polk Red Wfllow .. Richardson _________ Rock . „„ Saline __ Sarpy Sannders _„_ „ Scotts Bluff. Sew and Sheridan Sherman Sioux Stanton Thayer Thomas .•Metope mhur , tanner . llaine 8 1 """ 3 2 4 1 5 3 7 4 2 2 4 2 2 1 16 2 4 2 1 2 32 3 2" 12 3 1 2 2 1 3 2 1 2 6 ...„ 1 3 2 ""4 1 1 I " 2 44 2 1 3 1 "l 1 10 "' " l" l 6 i " T _ 4 7 a 6 _ _ _____ " 1 _.._ 32 5 i 1 1 3 2 43 1 1 1 " 7 25~ To 4 ~ 9 16 19 10 - 4 5 4 17 13 5 9 3 1 4 5 25 12 10 2 5 " 8 11 5 1 4 1 12 1 4 4 4 3 4 '3 3 ... 7 109 1 2 1 2 7 1 2 ~ 6 3 3 3 1 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 62 3 8 3 i" i l 9 3 2 1 1 2 2 2 4 1 4 4 68 1 1 2 2 S 1 "~~~ 5 2 2 1 3 2 2 2 1 19 I I i" 2 6 1 is 211 1 1 1 56 1 f 1 9 l 3 1 5 2 1 1 2 3 1 2 1 3 2 2 2 2 6 1 3 S 2 1 8 3 3 1 3 1 4 1 3 2 4 3 4 1 3 5 6 1 4 1 6 ■ 9 2 1 2 1 6 2 6 1 2 13 125 "i i 4 3 11 5 1 1 3 5 1 3 6 2 i i i i i i i i 4 2 6 4 1 2 8 i i" l i i i i 2 2 1 2 i l i' 3 » 27 3 1 2 8 i "a 3 i ZZZZZ 20 1 **""*"' *~ 8 1 1 12 3 9 16 1 1 6 I 2 7 14 2 12 3 1 "™ i 1 5 76 _ I „ 1 1 i ~ 1 ZZZZZ "is i I ! I 1 1 1 I I » 7 2 1 i' 2 1 i 2 2 • 1 i i i' l i i i i&gt; i i '3 i ... 1 . 9 5 2 2 5 10 6 3 s i "a l i 2 I . i" 6 "i 6 2 5 _ 3 4 7 2 2 3 1 2 1 6 1 8 | i'o 6 68 2 4 2 8 2 4 ] 2 2 2 " ... ... 97 35 1 2 2 2o 20 27 19 85 31 38 40 38 14 19 51 32 19 2C 74 2.3 26 46 8 13 58 810 9 36 27 14 27 110 7 9 5 1 12 112 39 22 4 18 31 5 22 29 11 30 14 8 12 29 726 46 3 37 7 19 1 29 21 43 33 49 20 16 21 20 40 12 39 68 8 38 11 39 44 53 28 27 7 17 32 16 25 1 43 19 16 19 1 1 55 F 12 ' 4, 7 _____ i ... 1 1 4 24 5 1 "==■- * i i i 1 2 1 2 2 3 25 3 1 1 214 1 3 1 12 14 1 1 16 2 1 "49 " 3 3 4 1 145 1 "" 38 :=:H * . 2 2 I i ! 1S io2 14 9 4 1 3 1 1 2 3 4 3 4 2 ... . 2 4 3 1 2 i' 21 i "~ 4 8 1 3 I i i 2 I Ti _ ™ 6 1 4 1 7 3 1 2 — •- I 1 20 1 1 2 1 3 1 5 1 4 3 1 1 is 4 3 2 7 1 2 1 6 1 „ 8 _ 6 1 » - 1 i i _ 2 ■ 2 3 t ■" is 9 1 1 1 i ; s ! 1 3 4 8 2 i ■ 2 1 1 1 2 2 _ 1 zzz 10 10 2 2 M 1 » 1 5 7 1 i' 3 12 ... i 9 14 1 1 i 2 S 1 s ~3 6 rr= 3 7 1 i 18 4 3 2 s 2 ........ z?i 1 : ■-■ _ 3 2 i 4 5 15 1 1 1 . 3 .. 17 6 19 4 2 i 1 3 1 7 3 2 4 "2 i 1 3 3 1 4 1 7 1 4 6 s I i 2 1 2 "6 3 5 if 2 1 2 3 ~"~ . 1 8 5 1 _ 9 6 6 11 7 2 "To 2 2 zzzzzz 8 2 2 zzzz__ s 6 2 n 1 1 4 2'"' 1 ~\7 1 2 2 i 1 3 2 1 1 2 1 — 2 6 "i 2 4 _. . 16 " 7 .ZZZZZ ii 1 Unknown Valley Washington Wayne Webster ««— — «__ _ 7 _ 2 ""■■"]■ 2 2 1 i 7 ™ i xi [ . 1 2" 1 2 _ ~2 zzzzz: s 10 1 _... _.._.._ i ■ I— ■■■■»■ !....»»....... . 1 "" "T" 1 1 1 11 _ ... I '■' ' ' Wheeler » .zzzzzzzzzz I ~—\ — I ■ ■- i 4 "■■"■ j „.. is 8 " 7 1 . - _____ Total 162 135 472 333 229 586 384 125 21 35 241 4074 </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATE PENITENTIARY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA OFFICERS W. T. FENTOM Warden D. G. KAVANAUGH Deputy Warden MRS. FRONA LOCKARD WILLIAM KIRBY Matron Steward Chief Clerk and Principal Physician Manager, Handcraft Furniture Company Miscellaneous Statement Established 1869 Number of employees 55 Number of inmates June 30, 1923 579 Highest number of inmates 586 Per capita cost per month 27.18 Number of acres 416 j Number of acres rented 260 Number of acres under cultivatiion 607 Value of land and buildings $545,909.13 Principal industries : manufacture of work shirts and fibre furniture, farm, gardening, and stock raising. Visiting days : every day except Sunday and holidays, 8 :00 to 12 :00 and 1 :30 to 4 :00 p. m. Commitment by District Judge. Persons committed to the Reformatory for Men and the Reformatory for Women for felony, may be transferred to the Penitentiary on order of the Board of Control. All transfers, however, from the Penitentiary to either Reformatory emanate from the Board of Pardons and Paroles. JAMES O'CONNELL B. A. FINKLE, M. D. L. M. EASTMAN </seg>
            <seg id="p018">• </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 To the Governor and the Board of Control of State Institutions, Lincoln, Nebraska. I present to you my report of the Nebraska State Penitentiary, together with tables showing the general income, etc., for the period ending June 30, 1923. At this time our population is five hundred fifty-six males, and eleven females, making a total of five hundred sixty-seven. There are now employed three hundred men in the manufacture of work shirts; eighty men manufacturing fiber furniture; fifty men farming, stock raising, gardening ; the balance of the number, who are physically fit to work, are employed as firemen, engineers, cell house runners, waiters, cooks and at other lines of work necessary to carry on the work of the institution. At the present time we have a very crowded condition here, as four hundred fifty is about our capacity. We expected some relief from the Legislature but in this we were disappointed as no appropriation which would guarantee us more room was provided. There are at least one hundred men in the county jails under sentence which we are unable to accommodate. Ii will be necessary that they be held until our population is reduced in some way, or more room provided. I would recommend that a building be erected outside the walls for all trusties, such as farmers, stock raisers, dairy men and others working on the outside. This would relieve our crowded condition on the inside. I would also recommend a cold storage building, something we have been badly in need of for many years, as our old one has become too small for so large a population. Our large dining room is badly in need of a new floor. I hope this improvement can be made soon. Our inmate kitchen is too small for the number we are required to care for, and I believe some improvement should be made on same. Our dairy barn is badly in need of some improvement. With the increase of our prison population, in my judgment it will be necessary in the near future to provide more cell house </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 room, but as this institution is located where the flood waters fill our basement and sometimes two or three feet of water in our cell houses, I would not recommend that any more expensive cell houses be built in this location. Our new ware house, which was built back of the walls last year, has proven a great help to us in making more shop room, as all our extra supplies are kept in this ware house, where the chances of destruction from fire is much less than if those materials were kept inside. Our prison night school has been well attended ; about one hundred fifty are enrolled at the present time. Our prison library is cared for by one of the boys and is well patronized by the men. Chaplain Maxwell and our Voluntary Chaplain Reverend McKenna are looking after the spiritual welfare of the men. A number of the good people of Lincoln are looking after the Sunday School work each Sunday. In conclusion, I wish to thank the Honorable Board, Ex- Governor McKelvie, and his Excellency, Governor Bryan, for their kind cooperation in the administration of the affairs of the institution, and I appreciate the good work of my Deputy, Mr. Kavanaugh, and all my co-workers for their loyalty and grateful consideration of the affairs of the institution. Very respectfully submitted W. T. FENTON, Warden. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Period Ending June .30, 1923 M. F. T, 622 6 628 For first time Readmitted Returned parole or furlough Returned escape Returned transferred Returned remanded .. 21 0 21 1 0 1 548 13 561 550 10 560 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. 352 17 369 67 0 67 26 0 26 9 0 9 1 0 1 1,008 23 1,121 8 0 8 90 4 94 10 0 10 3 0 3 147 1 148 288 8 296 1 0 1 M. F. T. Sixteen and under eighteen 13 0 13 Eighteen and under twenty-one 34 3 37 Twenty-one and under twenty-five 90 8 98 Twenty-five and under thirty 71 3 ,74 Thirty and under thirty-five SO 1 51 Thirty-five and under forty 38 1 39 Forty and under forty-five 22 0 22 Forty-five and under fifty 17 1 18 Fifty and under fifty-live 8 0 8 Fifty-five and under sixty 6 0 6 Sixty and under sixty-five 2 0 2 Sixty-five and over 1 0 1 Total 352 17 369 •n hand beginning of period . fimiHpri • Total received 1,008 Released : Escaped Discharged Died ...: Order of court Transferred Paroled Executed Pardoned 8 90 10 3 147 288 1 1 Total released 548 Remaining at end of period 550 TABLE II— AGE OF THOSE COMMITTED T Peri&lt; June M. Sixteen and under eighteen Eighteen and under twenty-one Twenty-one and under twenty-five Twentv-five and under thirty .. 13 34 90 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 TABLE III— RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF THOSE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. United States: Alabama 4 0 4 Arizona 10 1 Arkansas 9 0 9 California 3 0 3 Colorado | 6 17 Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. White Negro Indian 294 52 (i 14 3 0 308 55 6 Total 352 17 369 TABLE IV— EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. 1-. T. None Primar&gt; Common school High school College or university 13 36 216 82 5 2 0 8 6 1 15 36 224 88 6 Total _ 352 17 369 TABLE V— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Single Married Widowed Divorced Unknown 184 15.5 9 4 2 5 10 2 0 0 189 163 11 4 2 Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 TABLE VI— NATIVITY OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T Georgia Illinois Indiana Iowa ... 1 0 1 23 1 24 4 0 4 44 3 47 Kansas 18 2 20 Kentucky Louisiana Michigan 7 1 8 6 0 6 3 0 3 Massachusetts Minnesota 2 0 2 5 0 5 Missouri 26 2 28 Mississippi Montana . 1 0 1 1 0 1 Nebraska . New York Nevada 68 6 74 14 0 14 1 0 1 North Carolina North Dakota .. Ohio 4 0 4 1 0 1 6 0 6 Oklahoma 11 0 11 Pennsylvania South Dakota Tennessee 6 0 6 4 0 4 3 0 3 Texas Utah 11 1 12 2 0 2 Virginia 6 0 6 West Virginia Wisconsin 1 0 1 9 0 9 Wyoming 2 0 2 Total 313 17 330 Other Countries : Austria 1 0 1 Bulgaria Canada . France . 2 0 2 2 0 2 1 0 1 Germany Greece . 3 0 .&gt; 2 0 2 Holland Ireland Italy ... 1 0 1 3 0 .3 1 0 1 Macedonia Mexico 1 0 1 11 0 11 Norway Poland 1 0 1 2 0 2 Seria 1 0 1 Switzerland Turkey 1 0 1 1 0 1 Unknown 5 0 5 Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 TABLE VII— COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Adams 3 0 3 Antelope 2 0 2 4 Boone 0 4 Box Butte. 3 0 3 Bovd 4 0 4 Brown 1 0 1 Buffalo 3 0 3 s Burt 0 5 Butler 6 0 6 Cass 1 0 1 Cedar 4 0 4 Chase 1 0 1 Cherry r&gt; 0 6 Cheyenne 8 1 9 Clav 1 0 2 Colfax 1 0 1 Cuming 2 0 2 Custer 1 0 1 Dakota 6 0 6 Dawes 0 2 Dawson Deuel 6 0 6 1 0 1 Dixon 2 0 2 Dodge 13 0 13 Douglas Fillmore 120 S 125 3 0 3 Furnas 1 0 1 Gage 4 0 4 Garfield 3 0 3 Hall 11 0 11 Hamilton 5 0 5 I l.irlan 1 0 1 Hayes 1 0 1 Hitchcock Holt 3 0 3 4 1 S Johnson Kearney 1 0 1 3 0 3 Keith 6 0 6 Kimball : ZZZZZZZIZI Knox 3 0 3 1 0 1 Lancaster Lincoln &lt;J 3 12 13 1 14 McPherson 1 0 1 Madison 3 0 3 Merrick 2 0 2 Morrill ZZZZZZZZZZZZIZZ Nance 6 0 6 1 0 1 Nemaha ZZI! Nuckolls 4 0 4 1 0 1 Otoe 7 0 7 Pawnee Perkins 3 0 3 1 0 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 June 30, 1923 M. F. T. 1 0 1 5 0 5 1 0 1 6 0 6 9 0 9 6 0 6 2 0 2 3 0 3 1 0 1 1 0 1 5 0 5 1 0 1 18 0 18 7 0 7 4 0 4 10 0 10 2 0 2 0 1 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 4 0 4 4 0 4 69 0 69 TABLE VII— COUNTY FR on 1 :inue Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Phelps Platte Red Willow Richardson Rock Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff Seward Sheridan Sioux Stanton Thomas - Thurston Wayne York 2 1 4 3 2 1 7 3 2 4 2 2 2 6 2 1 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 6 2 1 4 3 2 1 7 3 2 4 2 2 2 6 2 7 Total 352 17 369 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF T OSE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending Artist Auto mechanic Actor - Barber Banker Butcher Blacksmith Bookkeeper Baker Bricklayer Boiler-maker Cabinet maker Cook Clerk Carpenter Chauffeur and truck driver Base ball player Domestic ~ Doctor Draftsman _.. Druggist Engineer Electrician Farmer </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 TABLE VIII— PREVIOUS OCCUPATION OF THOSE COMMITTED (Continued) Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Fireman 7 0 7 Foundry worker 1 0 1 Harness maker 1 0 1 Hospital attendent 2 0 2 Housewife 0 9 9 Iron moulder Jockey 2 0 2 1 0 1 Laborer 65 0 65 Lawyer 1 0 1 Miner 2 0 2 Machinist Mechanic 7 0 7 28 0 28 Merchant 1 0 1 Musician 4 0 4 Missionary 1 0 1 Painter 6 0 6 Plumber 1 0 1 Porter 9 0 9 Plasterer 1 0 1 Photo engraver Printer 2 0 2 1 0 1 Ranchman 9 0 9 Railroad man Roofer 6 0 6 1 0 1 Salesman Saleslady 7 0 7 0 1 1 Saddler 1 0 1 Sailor 0 2 Sheet metal 1 0 1 Shoemaker 1 0 1 Stenographer 0 1 1 Stockbroker Steeple jack 1 0 1 1 0 1 Teamster 5 0 5 Typist 0 1 1 Tailor 2 0 2 Telegrapher and telephone operator 4 1 5 Waitress Waiter '0 3 3 5 0 5 Wrestler 1 0 1 Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. General health : Sound Diseased Mental state : Sane Feeble-minded Insane Diseased, General Diseases: Syphilis Gonorrhea Diseases of the Nervous System Diseases of the Respiratory System Diseases of the Digestive System Hernia Asthma Fibroid Uterus Defects, injuries, amputations : Arm Finger 267 85 345 6 1 27 17 1 10 4 11 3 0 5 12 17 0 0 5 4 0 2 0 0 u 1 272 97 362 6 1 32 21 1 12 4 11 3 1 8 1 10 0 0 0 o 1 10 •ye TABLE X— RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE OF TH &gt;SE COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T. Protestant Catholic Greek Mormon Not reported 225 88 3 1 35 11 4 0 0 2 236 92 3 1 37 Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 TABLE XI— CRIME FOR WHICH COMMITTED Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923 M. F. T Attempt to steal auto 1 0 1 6 0 6 2 0 2 10 0 10 Assault to rape Assault to rob Assault to injure Arson 1 0 1 22 0 22 1 0 1 29 0 29 Auto stealing Assault to murder Burglary Breaking and entering 35 0 35 Bigamy 1 0 1 Bank robbery 4 0 4 Carrying concealed weapons. 2 0 2 Chicken stealing 2 0 2 Conspiracy to defraud 3 0 3 Embezzlement 10 0 10 Escape from custody 5 6 11 Forgery 55 2 57 Grand larceny Hog stealing .-....*. 30 2 32 3 0 3 Horse stealing Incest 1 0 1 3 0 3 4 0 4 4 0 4 2 0 2 9 3 12 12 0 12 11 1 12 Kidnapping Larceny as bailee Mayhem Manslaughter Murder Murder 2nd degree. Larceny from person 7 0 7 8 1 9 2 0 2 2 0 2 1 0 1 1 0 1 25 0 25 3 0 3 Larceny Obtaining money false pretense Pandering Perjury Procuring abortion by murder Robberv Rape _..."!Z"ZZ"! Receiving stolen property 5 0 5 Shoot to kill SOS Statutory rape 4 0 4 Selling mortgage property 1 0 1 Stab to wound 3 1 4 Sale of intoxicating liquor Wife and family desertion 3 0 3 7 0 7 Killing stock 1 0 1 False reports to Board of Trade and Commerce and deceiving Bank Examiner 4 0 4 1 0 1 1 1 2 Sodomy Check "No Funds" Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 TABLE XII— TERM OF SENTENCE O FOR FIRST TIME Sentence Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. ~M. F. TT Death Life 20 years 50 years 25 years 17 years 15 years 10 vears 8 years 7 years 6 years 5 years 4 years 3 years 2 years 1 year 12 months to 14 months 12 months to 18 months 1 day to 1 year 1 year to 2 years 1 year to 3 years 1 year to 4 years 1 year to 5 years 1 year to 7 years 1 year to 10 years 1 year to 20 years 2 years to 15 years 3 years to 7 years 3 years to 15 years 3 years to 20 years 3 years to 4 years 3 years to 5 years 3 years to 6 years 3 years to 10 years 2 years to 3 years 2 years to 4 years 2 years to 5 years 2 years to 7 years ./■. 4 years to 7 years .\ 4 years to 10 years 5 years to 7 years 5 years to 8 years 5 years to 10 years 6 years to 15 years 10 years to 15 years 10 years to 20 years 9 years to 10 years 6 months 15 months 18 months 18 years 1 year to 6 years 1 year to 21 years 3 8 2 1 2 1 2 20 1 1 2 9 s 16 11 If) 1 2 3 15 29 3 22 40 44 12 2 4 5 1 1 10 1 6 6 7 S 1 .5 1 1 1 5 2 1 1 1 1 1 5 1 1 1 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 0 1 2 0 () I) (I 0 0 2 0 1 3 1 0 0 0 8- 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 3 ■■!■ 2 1 2 1 2 21 1 1 2 9 6 18 11 22 1 2 3 15 31 3 23 43 45 12 -&gt; 4 5 1 1 II) 1 (i 6 7 5 1 3 5 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 TABLE XII— TERM OF SENTENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED FOR FIRST TIME (Continued) Total for Period Ending June 30, 1923. M. F. T. 2 years to 6 months 3 years to 6 months 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 1 0 1 (3) 6 years to 10 years ... (6) 1 year to 7 years ... Indeterminate sentence. 12 years Total 352 17 369 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 •a . 5rvS to o c u 3 poioopo o &lt;tj o o *o •—I 5 in J u _3 I \n o s CO 5! ■x 6 2 tJ- Q O VO O CM "&lt;3 o u u 3 2 °8 tsio u 5 u "3 8. ! |$ I ! 8 I 8" I I - — i ; I «— I • •»■ i ■ I i 8 8 Si 88 \n o 5- — 3 — _3 d 2 0 C/3 J &gt; 8 ! ! j I? § 1 1 Mi &gt;O | i ■ :") I i | is 5 » w H O &amp; Q O « a. 13 a 2 98 H H ■&lt; 3 N 3 -4 &lt; H 5 9 H i-l S3 o Q S5 M o O H w W &gt; 5 y. 0 U 6 15 38 i j :H 0 s 00 ■ • O s i I K U~) ; ; ; «—4 ! i : s a H i-) 1=&gt; O a, d 2 Q 2! •a U 3 p S.»o : 1 8 f*^in oo : ; op o to ft a 3 o &lt; 6 13 n o _3 88 1882 inn :rN»c\io\ » | — " f^O i t^ O C*J vo o ; »-&lt; to o oo 3C in o H d j : I t i i I ' ! | 3 ■ &lt;"■■•:■ O g c* ' ! H qj r; x fl&gt; '^ cfl -C SO 3 * O </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 i 5 — S c c •5 o H _3 8 si 8 •a . 8sf O 3 Si 3 &lt;si a o s Si 3 rt o 2 8 c ■a CJ G C. ■3 o &gt; S8885S8SS t^*\OoocNr^P5— tm r-H o" 6^ u •o £ 8 8 Si 3 irjoQ00?P&gt;no»ri'^ o V 3 I 88883888?? 10 o O © *T *^5 ©'©'«—&lt; t^ 25 Oj **} *O J""^ t*N 00 00 o w H U O o d4 -a I C. •a c 3 o O : o u 3 0 s Q « M « O "2 5 _3 "3 |8||8 ||8 | | : 5 : 1) 3 in a ioooo !»oo • cn cn en on -C en cn^S o &lt;n cnJZ gsggssggs 1 I | | I I I'd i : .X : i '• '■ '■ i :"o3 4 *» i ! i S i jjllollll "3 o H U u u U U 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 til •5 ■ § § .2 "Co" -- •a c C 3 5r s o o 8 si U g o o_ &lt;5 "&lt;5 88888888888888888888 «O(Crt r *^. l/^ *~ ifOO 1^ i^to^H OlO't § 8 5^ o 5 W&gt; m U ||§i§|88|S||8||88S88 "cd 8888338888888 8388888 S8SSS?g'g?SSK8 8^888^ »-• On \O ri r^ 1/3 **"* f^lfim O O - 8 -a v o I 0&gt; u Ui 3 in re cj 5= I re 8o 8 S S fe a •3 C re o s 3 id a °- nntninuiuiuiuiminiftmtn in « w U) m in « |-i ||-i § 1 1| § § §■« § § § s § § g salt rfl : =ll§»;|||^|1|i 5 3 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>