<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Secretary of State OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1910 TO THE GOVERNOR</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">)F THE Secretary of State f)F THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1910 TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">nor to resent herewith my biennial report lniuni ending November is Sprrptarv nf Ktntp fo r the bi&lt; t of all 1 received by this ottic ippropr: itions for, and the expenditures of ons filing articles during the last t L:_ _ i i-iorai ±^-M *V it m iDears jl d certi n^iinr he Banking \ imitted The contracts made and entered intn Kv- tho 1 toard of Pill Lands and Buildings for repairs and im - itate Institutions I have also omitted, to- »r fuel and supplies, as the same will appeal issioner of Public Lands and Buildings. Comr In this rpnnrt endeavored to include only such matters ai IH ' ■ ■■!■!■ tn tViic- .-*( Lincoln. Nebrask 'o His Excellency, Ash ton C. Shallenberger, Governor of the State of Var Sir- — I havp thp which contains a statem* This r*»Tw^rt rnntninR Th&lt;» rpiifii and school bonds approved by me is oinii n the report of the Auditor of Public Ac i 01 approved DanKs, as mis usi Board. List of notary commis- provement8 at the severs gether with the contracts in t\\t* rprtnrt nf thct Cr\mr ectfully submitte&lt; GEO. C. JUNKIN, Secretary of Stati </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">ERRITORIAL. «k n /**, homas B. Cuming, Auk. U, I8M, to Mar. 12, . Sterling Morton, July 12, ISM, to May 6, 1861. leernon S. Paddock. Mav 861, to Feb. 21, ltd 5TATE. ». Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1S«7, to Jan. in, itTL 5. Wm. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 13, 1873. to Jan. 1 \t-iiiiK, uuvciiiui, iiuiu juiic *, i ■» « i , iu Jan. io, ioio. Fohn J. GoSDer. from Jan. 13. 1873. to Jan. 11. 1875. to Jan. 11, 18 .JVJllll .1 . IIUBJI' I , Dftinn Tio/ihilf.U mo Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. !t. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879, to Jan. 4, 1883. .lward p. RoRgen. from Jan. 4, 1 8,s:{, to Jan. •, It Albert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1S87, to Nov. M, 1 igned to fill unexpir'_'d term in Congress caused by the death c\f lamAfi I -i t i'i I Benjamin R. C'owdry, from No' to Jan. i Appointed by Governor Thayei to fill vacancy caus ru uj i tion of Cilhert I, Iji^ ohn C. Allen, from Jan. 8, II oel A. Piper, from Jan. 3. It , to Jan. 3, 18: to Jan. 7, 189' tjoei a. ri(jer, Irani jail. .}, William F. Porter, from Jai George W. Marsh, from Jai , to Jan. 5, 191 Vcting Governor, from June k William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1H!»7, to Jan. 3, 190 George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. fi, 19fl A. (lidusha, from Jan. %, IMS, to Jan. 3, 1907. Geo. C. Junkin. from Jan. 3. l!t»7. to Jan. 5. 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE TERRITORY. Territory of Nebraska was organized May loth, lv"4 The Territory was a part of the Louisiana Purchase ceded by France to the United States in 1X03. First Territorial Legislature held at Omaha commencing January 15th, 1*55, consisting of 13 Councilman and 25 Representatives and the 12th and last session convened al Omaha January 19th, 1867. The seat of Government was permanently located at Lancaster, the present site of Lincoln. July 29th, 1.HG7. The Territory sent 3,157 men to the Union armits during the Civil \\ THE STATE Eebraska was admitted to the Union as a State March :?■ t of Congress passed February 9th, 1867, and by Proclamation is by President Andrew Johnson and attested by Hon. William H ■d. Secretary of State, and dated March 1st of that year. The first State Legislature was held in Lincoln January 7th The present Constitution was adopted November 1st, 1875. The extreme length of the State east and west is 412 n IU greatest breadth north and south is 208 miles. Its area is 76,895 square miles or 4!t,iML &gt; ,iM&gt;0 acre Number of votes cast in 1868—9,77.' Kiber of votes cast in 1908—271 491 ulation in 1M0 was 1j Kraska's population in 1910, 1.1H2.214. i in last decade, 125,914. Gain percentage, 11.8. Counties showing net loss, 21 Counties showing net gain, 71 Counties losing in First district, 6 of 7. Counties losing in Second district, 1 of 3. Counties losing in Third district, 3 of 15. Counties losing in Fourth district, I of 12 Counties losing in Fifth district, I of It. Counties losing in Sixth district, none. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">OFFICE FORCE OF DEPARTMENT OF STATE Secretary of State Geo. C. Junkin, Smithfield, Neb Deputy Secretary of State Addison Wait, Syracuse, Neb Bookkeeper T. W. Smith, University Place, Neb Corporation Clerk Walker Smith, Elwood, Nab Clerk Adair Galusha, Red Cloud, Neb Recorder Nellie M. Leach, Lincoln, Neb Stenographer . \i jirv F M ol l&amp;nd X^incol n </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 NEBRASKA STATE GOVERNMENT THE FOLLOWING ARE THE OFFICERS OF THE STATE AS SHOWN »BY THE RECORDS OF THIS OFFICE. THE TERMS OF THE EXECUTIVE OFFICERS EXPRIES ON JANUARY 5, 1911. Governor. Hon. A. C. Shallenberger Hon. M. R. Hopewell Lieutenant Governor Secretary of State. . Treasurer . Hon. Geo. C. Junkin Hon. L. Q. Brian Auditor of Public Accounts. . Hon. Silas R. Barton Commissioner of Public Lands and Bi ildings... Eon. Edward B. Cowles Attorney General Hon. Arthur Mull Superintendent of Public Instruction .Hon. E. C. Bishop OFFICERS-ELECT WHOSE TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRES JANUARY, 1913. Governor Lieutenant Governor. Secretary of State . . . Hon. Addison Wait Hon. Walter A. Georg Hon. Silas R. Barton Treasurer. Auditor of Public Account Commissioner of Public Lands and Bu Attorney General Idings... Hon. Edward B. Cowit Hon. Grant O. Martin Hon. James II. Crabtre* Superintendent of Public Instruction FEDERAL DEPARTMENT United States Senator ...Hon. Elmer J. Burkett, l'.Hl United States Senator. Hon. N'orris Brown, 191 United States Senator-Elect Hon. Gilbert M. Hitchcock, 101 CONGRESSMEN WHOSE TERMS EXPIRE MARCH 4, 1911 First District Hon. John A. Maguir Second District. Hon. Gilbert M. Hitchcock Third District Hon. James P. Latta Fourth District Fifth District. Sixth District. Hon. Edmund H. Hinshaw Hon. George W. Xorris CONGRESSMEN-ELECT WHOSE TERM OF OFFICE EXPIRE MARCH 4, 1913. First District .Hon. John A. Maguire Hon. C. O. Lobeck .Hon. James P. Latta .Hon. Charles W. Sloan Second District. Third District. . Fourth District. Fifth District. . Hon. George W. Norris Hon. Chester A. Aldrich Hon. M. K. Hopewell Hon. Moses P. Kinkaid </seg>
            <seg id="p009">;po RT )F THK 8ECRI PATH FUDICIARY DEPARTMENT SUPREME COURT. ,'hiet Justice — Hon. M. B Reese, Lincoln. i nuel H. Sedgwick, litli on. J. B. Barnes, Norfolk, UK L. Root, Plattsmouth, 1! in B. Rose, Lincoln, l'.Hl DISTRICT COURTS. n ev District — Leander M. i'emb»&gt;rton, lieatrice; John B. Uaper, l'a\v i Platl i rhirH I il District -A. J. Cornish, Lincoln; V.\ B, St. -wart. Lincoln; Lincoln Frost. Lincoln \. Da Omaha; Howard y, Jr., Omaha; William A. Keduick, Omaha; Wiliis G Tek:miMh' 4brBham I. button HMaka- \ i., ■*..,,,!..». &lt;* "t»«.... Ol nder C. Troup ran, Yorn xth District- Conrad Hollenbeck, Fr,&gt;n,ont ; Ceo. II. Thoin .. I) • i C.ra\ rict — A Welch, Wayi h District— James K. Hann. Paul, Si ■&gt; () II k&lt; "hirtetntli District H. M. .Irinies, North strict -J. J. HarriiiKton. O'Neill; Wm. 11. West STENOGRAPHERS Supreme Court Stenographer; 1. Do (' I.. Hohhs . Norfoll . Lincoli Lincoh . Lincoli B. Johns rie L. V nrwu i »^-_ F . . \\ esten . . . Lincoli B. Lettoa, Uncoil Ion. Jacob Fawcett, Omaha, C.ood, Wahoo Illliil. ll;ii'\ M c-C'ooli </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 10 District Judges' Stenographers. First District Ernest J. Brown, Beatrice J. A. O'Keefe, Beatrice Second District Earl R. Travis, Plattsmouth Third District Myron E. Wheeler, Lincoln Arthur R. Richardson, Lincoln E. R. Mockett, Lincoln Fourth District W. S. Heller, Omaha Thos. P. Wilson, Omaha W. J Fawcett, Omaha H. M. Waring, Omaha Frank A. Smith, Omaha Sidney M. Smith, Omaha C. C. Valentine, Omaha Fifth District A. P. Sprague, Aurora O. P. Heald, Wahoo Sixth District Blake Maher, Platte Center W. I. Speice, Columbus Seventh District Daisy Williams, Geneva Eighth District J. B. Rossister, Walthill Ninth District W. H. Powers, Norfolk Tenth District O. M. Baird, Wilcox Eleventh District O. A. Abbott, Grand Island H. J. Paul, St. Paul Twelfth District T. Hermanson, Kearney Erteenth District rteenth District eenth District. . E. A. Cary, North Platle L. W. Stayner, McCook C. B. Scott, O'Neill J. D. Scott, Rushville SUBORDINATE STATE OFFICERS Adjutant General, N. N. G John C. Hartigan Banking Board E. Royse, Secretary Board of Irrigation E. C. Simmons, Secretary Board of Charities and Corrections Joel A. Piper Deputy Labor Commissioner W. M. Maupin Deputy Game and Fish Warden Dan Geilus Deputy State Food Commissioner S. L. Mains Deputy State Veterinarian Paul Juckiness Chief Oil Inspector Francis Calfer Printing Board H*arry Thomas, Secretary Agricultural Society W. R. Mellor, Secretary Horticultural Society C. G. Marshall, Secretary Board of Equalization Henry Seymour, Secretary Dairymen's Association S. C. Bassett, Secretary Poultry Association A. H. Smith, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 STATE UNIVERSITY REGENTS. Hon. George Coupland 1914 Hon. Charles S. Allen 1916 Hon. C. B. Anderson 1914 Hon. William G. Whitmore. . . 1916 r. F. L. Haller 1912 Hon. V. G. Lyford 1912 The following officers are appointed, their terms expiring at the pleasure of the appointive power; the officers being as follows: Kversity of Nebraska, Lincoln te Normal School, Peru Samuel P. Avery, Chancellor I). \V. Hayes, Principal Nebraska Hospital for Insane, Asylum.. D. S. Woodard, Superintendent Hastings Insane Asylum, Ingleside W. M. Baxter, Superintendent Norfolk Asylum for Insane, Norfolk .... J. P. Percival, Superintendent Home for Friendless, Lincoln Amy V. Stevens, Supt. Soldiers &amp; Sailors Home, Grand Island. Eli A. Barnes, Commandant Soldiers &amp; Sailors Home, Milford.. State Penitentiary, Lancaster Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln Institute for Feeble Minded Youth, D. C. Rowden, Commandant T. W. Smith, Warden Dr. J. P. Lord, Supt., Omaha Beatrice G. L. Roe, Superintendent C. B. Manuel, Superintendent Lyda J. McMahon, Supt. Lena E. Ward, Superintendent Boys' Industrial School, Kearney- Girls' Industrial School, Geneva Industrial Home, Milford Institute for Deaf and Dumb, Omaha... R. E. Stewart, Superintendent Institute for Blind, Nebraska City N. C. Abbott, Superintendent Abbott, Superintendent STATE INSTITUTIONS The following officers are appointed, their terms expiring at the pleasure of the appointive power, the officers being as follows: BOARDS The Secretary of State, by virtue of his office, is a member of the following boards: Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Public Lands and Buildings Board of Educational Lands and Funds Board of Purchase and Supplies Printing Board Board of Pharmacy Board of Canvassers Board to Approve Depository Bonds Board of Prison Inspectors Voting Machine Commission Board of Veterinary Medicine Following is a list of the various State Boards, and the members </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF Till TARY OF STATE BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Meets first Monday of each month Eard B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands &amp; Buildings. . .President C. Junkin, Secretary of State Secretary son G. Brian, State Treasurer Arthur Mullen, Attorney General. BOARD OF EDUCATIONAL LANDS AND BUILDINGS Meets second Tuesday of each month Slton C. Shallenberger, Governor Chairman ward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands &amp; Buildings. . .Secretary Lawson G. Brian, State Treasurer Kge C. Junkin, Secretary of Stat&lt; - ur Mullen, Attorney General.... BOARD OF PURCHASE &amp;. SUPPLIES Meets first working day of January, April, July and October Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor Chairman nl B. Cowles, Commissioner Public I^anils &amp; Buildings. .. Secretary BOARD OF ASSESSMENT &amp; EQUALIZATION Meets for assessment first Monday in May Meets for equalization third Monday in July Geo. C. Junkin, Secretary of State Lawson G. Brian, State Treasurer Silas R. Barton, State Auditor Kdward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands &amp; Buildin Ash ton C. Shallenberger, Governor Chairmai Geo. C. Junkin, Secretary of State Lawson G. Brian, State Treasurer Arthur Mullen, Attorney General BOARD OF PHARMACY Meets second Wednesday of February, May, August and November Silas R. Barton, Auditor Chairman Edward B. C'owles, Commissioner Public Lands Ai Buildings. . .Secretary Geo. C. Junkin, Secretary of State Arthur Mullen, Attorney General Lawson G. Brian, State Treasurer DEPOSITORY BONDS BOARD Called Meetings Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor Chairman George C. Junkin, Secret-iry of Btafc Arthur Mullen, Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 PRINTING Meets 1st to 5th and 15th to 20th of each month A&gt; rman Junkin R. B&lt; Auditor H. ('.. Thomas, Expect and Secretary to Boar BOARD OF CANVASSERS Meets second Tuesday in September and fourth Monday in November Ashton ('. Shallenberger, Governor Chairman Lawson &lt;;. Brian, State Treasurer Silas R. Barton \u000dr deorge C. Jur retary of Statt Attorney General. . . . Mul BOARD OF EDUCATION Lawson G. Br K. C. Bishop, tate Treasurer ate Superintendent Dr. B. L. Shell X. P. McDonah J. J. Tool&gt; orn. . . . President, Term expires 1912 expires 1913 expires 1914 expirtv - expires 1911 'resident. Term Term I. r. Roach. L. P. Ludden Term Secretary, Term PRISON INSPECTORS Lands &amp; Buildings VOTING MACHINE COMMISSION Called Meetings Chairman BOARD OF VETERINARY MEDICINE Called Meetings Rton C. Shal Junl Chairman Silas R. Barton, State Auditor Paul Jucki State Veterinarian BOARD OF HEALTH Called Meetings Ashton C. Shal Bishop, £ Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor. George C. Junkin, Secretary oi Silas R. Barton, Auditor enberger. Governor. in, Secretary of Stat llenberger, Governor State Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE BOARD OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS Meets third Tuesday of January. April, July and October Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor Ch Chairman E. C. Bishop, State Superintendent Edward B. Cowles, Commissioner Public Lands &amp; Buildin Joel A. Piper Chief Clerk TRANSACTIONS OF BOARDS The report of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds will be found in the report of the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings, which will also contain the transactions of the Board of Purchase and Kie action of the Board of Equalization and Assessment will be in the report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, which will also i the transactions of the Board to Approve Depository Bonds. The Board of Canvassers has canvassed the vote on the Constitu tional Amendment, the latter having failed of the required majority vote The Board of Prison Inspectors will be included in the report of the Warden of the State Penitentiary. The Secretary of State is secretary of the Printing Board, and a» itemized statement of its business will be found in the report, which is published herewith, by its secretary, Harry Thomas. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p015">LEGISLATIVE RECOMMENDATIONS Corporations corporation law of 1H C .»7, which provides for the filing of arti - of all corporations with the Secretary of State, based the filing fee the authorized capital stock. This law remained unchanged until legislature of 1*07, when an amendment was passed increasing the filing fee from ten cents to fifty cents per thousand. When this bill was drawn the word "authorized" was omitted, which was a clerical error, as the party who drew the measure informed me that it was not intentionally left out, and as the laws of other states, which we have examined, specify that the fee should be based on the "authorized" capital stock, I would recommend to the Legislature that the present law be changed so that the fee will be based on the "authorized" capi - tal stock instead of "capital stock." The law created two years ago imposing an annual tax upon all corporations, both domestic and foreign, has demonstrated the fact that the same is not perfect, and a few amendments should be made to that law. I would recommend that the fee be a per centum based upon the "paid up" and "subscribed" capital foreign corporations doing busines: quired to pay upon such proportion erty located or used in this State property and capital outside of the i stock of the corporation, and that in this State should only be re- of their capital stock as their prop - bears to the total amount of their ;tate. Permanent School Investment Fund. I want to join with the other members of the Board of Educational Lands and Funds, which Board has the investing of the permanent school fund in Nebraska in a request that the Legislature make pro - vision for the disposing of State bonds of other states held by this State for this investment fund, when such bonds can be sold at par without any loss whatever to the State, and the money so derived for said bonds can then be re-invested in municipal and school bonds in this State. At present there are between three and four million dollars invested in state securities outside of Nebraska, which are drawing in - terest from three and a quarter to four per cent. These bonds could be disposed of and the money brought home and invested in Nebraska securities at four and four and one-half per cent, which would be a saving in the rate that is being paid at present by the issuers of the bonds, and also increase the income of the school fund from one-half to one per cent, and I believe that the funds invested in these securities </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Eld be safer than having it Invested in long time bonds of some of states that are in a class which will require years before they are to pay any on the principal. Pie Board has within the last jremr and a half refused something million dollars in bonds which luive been offered by school dis - and municipalities in this State, and this should not be tfc Nebraska has money Invested in securities of other States. I respectfulh I that the correction herein reconunendet icorporated into law. Metal Fixtures in Vault. I would recommend, and do most earnestly hope the Legislature will make an appropriation for supplying metal fixtures for at least one of the two vaults in this Department. These vaults at present are sup - plied with nothing but combustible material, and in case of fire it is ■ loubtful but that all the records would be destroyed. These vaults are filled with Legislative Records dating from the first session to the present time, all the original manuscript of laws, contracts for all work or material, bonds of state officers, notarial records, election records and a great many other documents that could not be replaced. Automobiles E years ago when I assumed control of this Department there istered ten hundred and eighty-seven automobiles. At the pres - there are over fifteen thousand on record. The original law for the issuing of a license, but in I!iu7 the Legislature amended it so that the licenses are now issued annually. It is the cus - tom of this department, the first of every month, to notify all automo - bile owners whose license expires during that month of the fact, and as this requires the sending out of fifteen thousand notifications, and an equal amount in remitting the license, together with the issuing of licenses for new machines, (which amounts to upward of five thousand per year) the work has become so great in its proportions that it re - quires almost the entire time of one person. Therefore we have asked in our appropriation for office expenses sufficient to cover the salary of one clerk for at least twelve months during the biennium, which will be absolutely necessary if we are to give the prompt service that is expected of a state department. Increased Office Expenses. The biennium preceding the time that we assumed charge this De - partment collected in fees $22,463.10, with an office appropriation of $20,180.00. During this biennium we have turned into the state treas - ury fees collected to the amount of 1322,686.81 on an office appropria - tion of $25,280. It will be apparent, with this increased labor thrown on the office of Secretary of State in collecting this large amount of funds, that the office appropriations are not in keeping with the increase in fees. During the last two years this office has been compelled to </seg>
            <seg id="p017">RKPORT OF TH1 1ARY OF STATK 17 withhold a great deal of information, which, though legally we are not compelled to give, yet would have been of great advantage to those having business to perform with this Department, solely on account of not having sufficient money to pay for stationery and stamps and extra clerical hire in getting the work out, and we believe that it is a bad practice for the State not to give all information and aid possible to our citizens. Such, however, cannot be done unless the Legislature makes sufficient appropriation to do so. Therefore we have asked for an appropriation for office expenses that will allow this Department to give good service to the public, and we trust that the Legislature will recognize the large increase in the 'Cted thru this Department, which has necessarily demanded a much larger amount of labor, and be willing to return at least a small portion of it to help put the laws into operation, and render proper and efficient service to the public. Respectfully submitted Secretary of State. OFFICE EXPENSES. For preparing session laws for printer, copying, comparing and indexing same, stationery, books, blanks, printing, binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, tele - phone, shipment of laws and journals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographieal help as may be necessary for the recording and licensing of corporations and other office expenses $ 4,500 . 00 For registering letters, blank applications, blank records, seals, issuing licenses for automobiles and one clerk not to exceed twelve months during the biennium $ 2,100.00 For steel fixtures in vault where legislative records are kept.$ 3,500.00 tio.m.M SALARIES. Estimated expenses for the Office of the Secretary of State for the Biennium commencing April 1, 1911 Secretary of State — Salary, two thousand dollars Four thousand dollars for the biennium $4,000.00 Salary for Deputy, eighteen hundred dollars Thrpp t hniKMTid sit h 1 1 n ii faH Hnll a fs for t h c* hi Ann i 11 tn t *\ * GEO. C. JUNKIN, Total appropriation for the bienniutn $1,SOO.OO </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE REPORT OF STATE PRINTING BOARD During the biennium ending November 30th, 1910, the State Print - ing Board has secured bids upon and awarded contracts for approxi - mately ft;_ vorth of printing and sationery supplies for the ous departments and institutions of the state. Of this sum approxi - mately $23 luta been expended for the publication of the annual and semi-annual reports of the State Officers, Supreme Court Reports and the Journals of the Senate and House of Representatives of the Session of 1!&lt; The volume of business handled by the State Printing Board makes it impracticable to give a detailed statement of each transaction. How - ever, the numerous small items have been purchased at prices which have been fair to the state, and at the same time giving a reasonable profit to the successful bidder. During the biennium five meetings of the Printing Board have been held for awarding contracts for work for the various state offices and institutions. For each letting a tabulated schedule is prepared giv - ing full information regarding the work on which bids are askeO. the names of the bidders, amounts of the bids and the name of the success - ful bidder; the schedules being bound as a part of the records of the board. At each of the five lettings competition has been keen and as a result the work has been distributed among various printing estab - lishments of the state. The number of bidders at each letting has averaged from three to nineteen. For several years the State Printing Board has been equipped with a set of paper testing devices, including testers for strength, thickness and weight, the value of these instruments to the state has been set forth in full in previous reports from this department. A great number of contracts for emergency printing have been during the past biennium, which have, in every case, been let by e bidding to the lowest bidder Salary of Bookkeeper, fifteen hundred dollars Three thousand dollars for the biennium o ...$1,: ...$3,000.00 Salary of Corporation Clerk, fifteen hundred dollars.. Three thousand dollars for the biennium ...$1.:. ..J3.000.00 Salary of Recorder, twelve hundred dollars ...$1,200.00 Twenty-four hundred dollars for the biennium ...$2,400.00 Salary of one clerk, twelve hundred dollars - - $1.- Twenty-four hundred dollars for the biennium . ..$2.i Salary of Stenographer, eight hundred and forty dollars . ..$ 840.00 Sixteen hundred and eight dollars for the biennium... ...$1,680.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">r\ Ri I O i\ 1 ( ) I* 1 HI I AK l \J f 1 A 1 h 19 Contracts Awarded in 1909-1910. During the biennium ending November 30th, 1910, the State Print - ng Board has held five meetings for the purpose of awarding printing, ind for which contracts have been made. The following list shows he most important contracts. In addition to this the Board has, during he biennium, contracted for numerous smaller items of printing and supplies for the various departments and institutions, which, owing to :he large number, are not shown here, it being the aim to report only terns of the most importance. April 26th 1909. Nebraska Newspaper Union copies Session Laws $2 . t&gt;~ per page Clafiin Printing Co 1000 copies House Journal at $1 . 63 per page 500 copies report Building &amp; Loan Association 1.43 per page 1604 copies report of Department of Banking 1.46 per page 8000 copies School Laws 3.37 per page it copies report State Board of Horticulture 3.52 per page '•opies report of State Railway Commission 1.45 per page York Blank Book C&lt; copies Senate oJurnal $ .96 per page copies report of Nebraska Constitutional Con ventior 1.73 per page 13 per page of Legislative Ex $145 per page copies Insurancy Summary . 2.00 per page State Journal ( copies report of State Board of Agriculture. . .$3.40 per page July 12th, 1909 York Blank Book Co blanks Engineering Department State Railway $230.00 Comissic September 25, 1909 State Journal ( Volumes 85 to 94 Supreme Court Reports $1 52 per page York Blank Book Co copies Laws of Nebraska Relating to Railroads roads and other Common Carriers $1.49 per pagfe December 13th, 1909 State Journal ( copies Volumes 4 and 5 Supreme Court Reprints. $ .65 per page blSOO copies Dairyman's Report Quiz— 1000 copies Auditor's Report penses </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE April 30th, 1910. Claflin Printing Co. — 10O0 reports Commissioner Public Lands and Build ings |1.23 per page 1000 copies report Secretary of State 2.75 per page 1000 copies report of Auditor 2.10 per page 1000 copies report of Bureau of Labor. . 1000 copies report of Board of Irrigation 1.68 per page 1 . 62 per page 1000 copies report of Railway Commission 1600 copies report of Banking Department 1.40 per page 1 .55 per page 2500 copies Insurance Summary 2.40 per page York Blank Book Co. — R copies report of Attorney General copies report of Superintendent of Public In 1.35J per page struction 1.64 per page 500 copies report of Adjutant General 1.30 per page 500 copies report of Librarian 1.30 per page 1000 copies report of Food, Dairy and Drug Commis- sion 1.20 per page 3500 copies Session Laws 2.71 per page 500 copies report of Building &amp; Loan Association... 1.45 per page 1200 copies Dairyman's Report 2.44 per page Huse Publishing Co. — 1000 copies report of State Treasurer 2.40 per page Jacob North &amp; Co. — 5000 copies report State Board of Agriculture 3.35 per page 5000 copies report State Board of Horticulture 3.47 per page EXPENDITURES. Following is a statement of the amounts expended from funds which are wholly under control of the State Printing Board Laws and Journals. Balance November 30th, 1908 $ 7,818 . 13 Apropriation, Session of 1909 18,000.00 Total $25,818.13 Expended Nebraska Newspaper Union $ 3,779 . 23 J. W. Brewster 15.00 Harry Porter 34.55 Gillespie &amp; Phillips 51.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 21 Woodruff-Collins Printing Co 1,900.90 York Blank Book Co 3,033 . 72 J. G. Gill 5 . 00 H. G. Thomas 60.00 Eric Morrell 183 . 20 State Journal Co 7,913. M Nebraska Telephone Co 5.80 Rough Notes Co 36 . 00 R. H. Gillespie 7.50 Adams Express Co 25 . 55 American Express Co 11 . 29 Underwood Typewriter Co 52 . 75 Globe Delivery Cod J. E. Cobbey 184 . 80 Claflin Printing Co 3,170.82 Bee Publishing Co 6 . 00 Cornell Engraving Co 44 . 25 Olga I. Whiteman 15.00 Hammond Printing Co 16.00 W. M. Benton 11.00 Jacob North &amp; Co 2,435 . 56 Smith Premier Typewriter Co 6 . 00 Lou W. Frazier 10.00 Total $23,200.85 Balance November 30th, 1910 % 2,617 . 28 REVENUE BOOKS AND BLANKS Balance November 30th, 1908 % 1,151.43 Appropriated, session of 1909 $ 5,000. 00 Total $ 6,151 . 48 Expended Woodruff Banknote Co $ 75 . 00 Gillespie &amp; Phillips 65.60 Claflin Printing Co 121.50 York Blank Book Co 222.79 Pacific Express Co 6 . 32 Columbus Printing &amp; Specialty Co 317.30 Omaha Printing Co 725.51 R. H. Gillespie 150.70 Woodruff-Collins Printing Co 14 -o </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF BTATE Adams Express Co Klopp &amp; Bartlett Co 35 . 00 Adams Express Co 16 . 70 Benton Bros 65.00 W. W. Haskell 40.50 M. H. Seymour 9.00 Nebraska Paper &amp; Bag Co I.M T. J. Farrell 1M Harry Porter Revenue Books &amp; Blanks 9.00 George A. Hearn 200.00 State Journal Co 683 . 10 Globe Delivery Co 3.15 Henry Seymour 230.00 Lincoln Paper Box Co 6 . 0( George Brothers 39 . 50 Columbus Tribune 15 . oo Amount lapsed, appropriation iyc-7 189.38 Total Balance November 30th, 191( $ 2,683.01 SUPREME COURT REPORTS Appropriated, Session of 1909 $12,000 Expended (State Journal Co.) $ll,385.0i Balance November 30th, 19 H&gt; 1,716. « SALARY OF PRINTING EXPERT. R.nce November 30th, 1908 ropriation, session of 1909 $ Expended : L. W. Frazier, salary Dec. 1st, 1908 to March 31st 1909 $ :: H. G. Thomas, salary April 1st, 1909, to Oct. 31st, 1910 1,582 Total $ 1,916. 69 Balance November 30th, 1910 $ 416.6 Respectfully submitted, H. G. THOMAS Secretary to the Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Ltihg the rgeistrution and licei use and operation upon the high - ons 140, 141, 142, 143, 144, 145. regulating their of motor ways and nd to repeal 147, 148, 149, 150 and 151 of Ch braska. ( 'om piled - of Xt Be it ena •liiturt sction 1. The words and phr ses used in this act shall, for th nlv, be constr follow 1. "Motor Vt hall inc power other than r ng such motor vehic I r power run only on rai tracks, providing that nothing herein contained hall apply to traction engines or road rollers: 2. "closely build (t) ui portions,' sh n the territory of a city, town or v ill ntiguous a. public highway devoted to business or where for not than one-fourth :i mile the dwelling houses on such highway avera not more tt mndred et apart Fee One Dollar Per Year. Sec. 2. Every owner of a motor vehicle shall, for every such vehicle owned by him, file in the office of the Secretary c: statement of his name and address, with a brief description cf the vehicle to be registered, on a blank prepared and furnished by such Secretary for that purpose. The fee shall be fl.io per year, and must accompany the application for registration and license; subsequent pay - ments must be made on, or before the date of expiration of said regis - tration and license, which is for one year from date thereof. For regis - tering change of ownership the fee shall be $l.i- rtified copy of the bill of sale must accompany such application. Sec. 3. The secretary of state shall thereupon file such a state - ment in his office, register such motor vehicle in a book to be kept for that purpose and assign it a number beginning with number one (1) and so on in the order of filing. File Application. Sec. 4. Every person acquiring a motor vehicle shall file a like statement with the secretary of the state and such secretary of the state shall, in like manner, file such statement. h vehicle and assign it a number. Assignments. If the vehicle has previously been registered, and such fact and For an Act requiring and regul ] Nebraaki purix ude all vehicles propelled by any </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE number assigned it shall be set forth in the statement, and the previous registration shall be cancelled; but the number of such previous regis - tration may be assigned under the new registration. Sec. 5. The secretary of state shall forthwith on such registration and without other fee, issue and deliver to the owner of such motor, vehicle, a seal of aluminum or other suitable metal which shall be circular in form, not over two (2) inches in diameter, and have stamped thereon the words "Registered in the office of the Secretary of State for the State of Nebraska" under the motor law Xo with the registration number inserted therein; which seal shall thereafter at all times be conspicuously displayed on the motor vehicle to which such number has been assigned. Must Display Number and Neb. ESec. 6. Every motor vehicle shall also at all times have the num - assigned to it by the Secretary of State displayed on the back of motor vehicle in such a manner as to be plainly visible, the num - ber to be Arabian numerals, each not less than three (3) inches in height and each stroke to be of a width not less than one-half (&gt; 2 ) inch and also as a part of such number the abbreviated letters of the State Ei viz: Neb., such letters to be not less than two (2) inches in t- Non-Residents. &gt; r5ec. 7. The provisions of section two (2) to five inclusive shall apply to motor vehicles owned and operated by non-residents of this state, provided the owners thereof have complied with any law re - quiring the registration of owners of motor vehicles in force in the state, territor} or federal district of their residence, and the registra - tion number showing the initials of such state, territory or federal dis - trict shall bedisplayed on such vehicles substantially as providt;&lt;l by sec - tion six (6) of this act. Rate of Speed Sec. 8. No person shall operate a motor vehicle on a public high - way at a rate of speed greater than is reasonable and proper ha\ing regard to the traffic and use of the highway, or so as to endanger the life or limb of any person, or in tbe event in the close built up por - tions of a city, town or village, at a greater riite than one (1) mile in six minutes, or elsewhere in a city, town or village, at a greater rate than (1) mile in four (4) minutes, or elsewhere outside of the city, town or village, at a greater rate than twenty miles per hour, subject, however, to the other provisions of this section. Upon aproaching a crossing of intersecting public highways, or a bridge, or a sharp curve, or a steep descent, and also in traveling such crossings, bridges, curves, or descent, a person operating a motor vehicle shall have it under con - trol and operated at a rate of speed less than heretofore specified, and in no event greater than is reasonable and proper, having regard to the traffic then on such highways and the safety of the public. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THK I ARY OF STATE 25 c Sec. 9. Any person operating a motor vehicle shall at request or n signal by putting up the hand, from a person riding or driving a restive horse or other draught or domestic animal, bring such motor vehicle immediately to a stop, and, if traveling in the opposite direc - tion remain stationary so long as may be reasonable to allow such horse or animal to pass, and if traveling in the same direction, use reasonable caution in passing such horse or animals, and the operator of any motor vehicle shall render necessary assistance to the party having in charge such a horse or other draught animal in so passing. Signals. Sec. 10. Every motor vehicle while in use on a public highway shall be provided with good and sufficient brakes, and also with a suit - able bell, horn or other signal, and be so constructed as to exhibit dur- ng the period from o _• (1) hour after sunset to one (1) hour before sunrise, one or more lamps showing white lights visible wiihin a reason- able distance toward which such a vehicle is proceeding, and also red light visible in the reverse direction. Cities and Towns. Sec. 11. Cities and towns have no power to pass, enforce or main - tain any ordinance, rule or regulation requiring o fany owner or oper - ator of a motor vehicle any license or permit to use the public high - way or exclude or prohibit any motor vehicle whose owner has com - plied with section two (2) or section four (4) of this act from the free use of such highways, and all such ordinances, rules or regulations now in force, are hereby declared to be of no validity or effect; provided that nothing in this act shall be construed as limiting the power of local authorities to make and force and maintain an ordinance, rules or regulations, in addition to the provisions of this act, affecting motor vehicles which are offered to the public for hire. Publish List of Registrations. Sec. 12. The secretary of state may, at his discretion publish in pamphlet form the names of owners of motor vehicles who have reg - istered and pay the expense from the office expense fund of his depart - ment, providing such publication may be sold for not les than $1.00 per copy. The proceeds of said sale to be paid to the state treasurer foi - the general fund and miscellaneous fees. Penalty for Violation Sec. 13. The violation of a-.iy of the provisions of this act, shall b« deemed a misdemeanor, punishable by fine not exceeding twenty-flTe ($25.00) for the first offense, and punishable by a fine of not less than ($25.00) nor more than fifty dollars ($5000) or imprisonment not ex - ceeding thirty days (30) in the county jail for a second or subsequent offense. Passed and approved April 3rd, II </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE FEES The fees received by this Office for services performed during the past two years from December 1, 1908, to November 30, 1910, inclusive. are as follows: For filing and recording Articles of Incorporation $169,273.96 For affixing Great Seal of State and forwarding Notarial Commissions 1 ,787 For filing and allowing Live Stock Brands 1,019.7 For Motor Vehicle Licenses 18,617.23 For Certificates and Transcripts 1,413 . 95 For Trade Marks 56 . 00 For Corporation Permits 122,012.15 For Corporation Penalties 8,490 . 00 From all other sources 15.60 Total $322,685 .81 APPROPRIATIONS AND EXPENDITURES The Legislature of 1909 made the following appropriations for this Office for the purposes named below Secretary of State Salary (per annum $2,000) $ 4,000 Expended 3 Balance November 30, 1910. 1,'" Deputy. Salary (per annum $1,800) $ 3,600.00 Expended : 2 Balance November 30, 1910. Bookkeeper. Salary (per annum $1,500) $ 3,000.00 Expended no Balance November 30, 1910 $ • Recorder. Salary (per annum $1,200) $ 2,400.00 Expended 1,900.00 B&amp;1&amp;I1C6 Vovemb^r 30 1910 $ 500 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Clerk Salary (per annum $1,000) Expended 00 Balance .November 30, 191( i Stenographer. Salary (per annum $84( Expended Balance November 30, 19K $ For preparing Session Laws for printer, copying, comparing and indexing same, stationery, books, blanks, printing, binding, lithographing, express, freight, telegraph, telephone, ship - ment of laws and journals, furniture, repairs, postage, such clerical and stenographic help may t sary for the recording and licensing of corporations and other office ex - penses $ 7 ■ Expended 6,218.77 1 1 $ 1 r registering letters, copies of brand laws, blank applications, blank record book, seal, issuing licenses for automobiles and one brand clerk not to exceed four months during biennium. $1,200. Expended 1,191 Balance November 30, 191 * For advertising relative to corporation and occu - pation tax laws $ l j(Hi Expended 999.50 t Balance November 30, 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 28 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS Kind of Author- Author- (OKI'oRATi: SAMI Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Place of ized Business Capital When Filed Stock Stock Hardware Co r Grain ( Amend' Fairfield $ 10,000 Dec. 17 1908 Amend Fairfield Dec. Jan. $ 10,000 300,000 IT 11 190S Articles Minneapis, M 300,000 Jan. 11 1909 Minneap'is, M Articles 19O.I Alexandria Light &amp; Water Articles Alexandria .... 10,000 Jan. 14 1909 Alexandria 10,000 Jan. 14 1 'JO'.l American Carbolite Sales Co Articles Duluth, Min... 50,000 Feb. 2 1909 Omaha 200,000 Feb. 2 1909 Duluth, Min... 50,000 Feb. 2 1909 American Telephone &amp; Tele - graph Company of Xebr.... Omaha Omaha 200,000 60,000 100,000 Feb. Feb. Feb. 1909 Alamo Engine 8c Supply Co. W. H.) Companv Anderson Lumber &lt;S: Con- Articles Omaha 60,000 Feb. 4 1909 Articles Articles 4 1909 Articles Columbus 100,000 Feb. 5 1909 Columbus 1909 struction Co Articles Gothenburg 20,000 Mar. 9 1909 Articles Articles Gothenburg Axtell 20,000 10,000 Mar. Mar. B 1909 Articles Axtell 10,000 Mar. 13 1909 Axtell Investment Co 13 l'.»09 Aurora Business College As - itiofl Amend't Aurora 25,000 Apr. 9 1909 Aurora Apr. Amend't Articles Amend't Amend't Amend't Amend't 25,000 9 1909 Articles Alma 10,000 May 21 1909 Alma 10,000 May 21 1909 Alma Produce Co Arlington State Bank Ansley Telephone Co.. Amend't Arlington 50,000 June 23 1909 Arlington June 50,000 23 1909 Amend't Ansley _ June 25 1909 Ansley June 2:. l'HXi Anchor Realty &amp; Securities American Safe Deposit Cr&gt; .... American Safe Deposit \- Amend't Lincoln 25,000 June 29 1909 Lincoln 25,000 June 1909 29 Amend't Lincoln 10,000 June 30 1909 Lincoln June 10,000 :io 1909 Trust Co Amend't Lincoln 10,000 June 30 1909 Lincoln June Amend't 10,000 :to 1909 Alumni Ass'n of Xebr. of the Delta Tau Delta Frater - nity Articles Lincoln 15,000 July 3 1909 Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Lincoln Alliance Alma .... 1.1.000 July 1909 Alliance Valley Club Alma State Bank Articles Alliance 1,000 July 1 1909 July 1,000 1 1909 Articles Alma 50,000 July 13 1909 .10,000 July 13 v.m Albion Electric Light Co Ashland Park Co Articles Albion 30,000 July 15 1909 Albion Omaha Alda .. 30,000 July IS 1909 Articles Omaha 10,000 Aug. 13 1909 10,000 Aug. 13 1009 Alda State Bank Articles Alda 15,000 Aug. 31 1909 15,000 Aug. 31 1909 Avoca Supply Co. of Avoca Automatic Switch Co Articles Avoca 10,000 Sep. 8 1909 Avoca Lincoln Omaha 10,000 Sep. s 1 909 Articles Lincoln .110,000 Sep. 13 1909 200,000 Sep. 13 I'.iOO Adcrofters Articles Omaha 250,000 Sep. 25 1909 250,000 Sep. American Music Hall Com - pany of Xebraska Articles Amend't Omaha 100,000 Oct. 1909 American Exchange Bank Ainsworth (The) Light and Elm v. Oct. 11 1909 Articles Ainsworth 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THK SECRETARY OF STATE 29 ngCKLLANMUi &lt; OKI'OKATIO&gt;S (( oi:tim i .1 Kin- Author- corih.katk NAMK I n s' Place of ized When ment 1 Busine^ , tal Filed Stock Alliance Electric Co Amend't Denver, Alliance E Amend't Denver, Col \ Aurora (The) Electric Co Vmend'l Aurora 00,0«n N'nv. 27 1 Aurora (The) Electric Co Vmend'l Aurora 60,000 Nov. 27 1909 Aurora (The) Artificial Ice Co. \i- Aurora (The) A \r Atkinson and Saratoga Tele - phone Co Arl tkinaon ...imhi [). Atk ind Saratoga Te ph&lt; \r Atkinson 100,000 Dec. American Realty Co Article* Omaha loo.ooo I). Am R \r Omaha n American Trade Promoting Corporation Articles Omaha 10,000 fan. fi U' Arti Omaha 10,000 Tan. Agee Land and Live Stock Co Articles Douglas Co Arti Douglas Audit (The) Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Feb. 24 1 Audit (Tr Articles 10,000 Feb. 2) Aero Club of Nebraska Article* Omaha KUMOjMar. ;t l Aero Club of Nebraska Arti Omaha '.o.ooo Mar. :; American Bottling Co Articles Fremont 10,000 Apr. 14 l American Bottl Arti 10,000 Apr. 14 lino (The) Abbott-Fitch Co Articles Omaha ■.-.I.oon Apr. IS 1 The) Abbott-Fi 7 itch Co Articles Omaha -'.^.OOO Apr. Amboy Telephone Co Articles Red K) Apr. :«) l Amboy Telephone Co Articles R- J,000 Apr. :&gt; Automatic Passenger Reg - ister Co Article? Lincoln 100,000 May IT Automatic Passenger Re g ister C Arti Lincoln 100,000 May 17 Alamito Sanitarv Dairy Co Amend't Omaha .100,000 Ma Alamito Sanitarv Dairv Co Amend't Omaha iOO.OOO May 27 utio Allen State Bank Amend' Allen June 14 Amf Allc June 14 l'.no Alliance Union Club Ar' Alliance 1,000 Ju! Alliance Union Club Ar Alliance 1,000 July Alda Lumber Co Article- Akta io.ooo Aug. io Alda Arti 10,000 Aug. 10 Anderson (The) Politi. and Social Asssociation ... Articles Grand Island 100 Aug. it; Grand Islam Arti 100 Aug. If, American Brotherhood (The) Articles West Lincoln :&gt;.000A,;. West Lincolr Artii 10,000 Sep. 1 Abie State Bank Amend't Albi, 10,000 Sej Abie State Ban Amenr Albie t American (The) Brother - hood Articles Emerald -&gt;,ooo Sep. 2 l Emeralr Article 2,000 Sep. American Heating ,\ Plumbing Co Articles Omaha 1,000 Sep. 19 l Plumbing \rt 1,000 Sep. 19 Anderson Land, Lumber, Construction and Material Co Articles Gothenburg 25,000 Oct. 24 1 Anderson Land, Lumber, Construction and Mate Art Gothenburg 25,000 Oct. 50,000 Nov. l no, ooo \ov M 17 American Printing Co Articles Lincoln 50,000 Nov. 17 l American Printing Co Arti Lincoln Aurora Electric Co Amend't Aurora 100,000 Nov. 30 i Aurora Electric C Amen Battle Creek Valley Bank ... Amend't Battle Creek Battle Creek Vallev Bank Battle Creek Dec. Buchanan Co Articles North Platte 10,000 Dt Artu North Platte :; Box Elder Telephone Co Articles Ansley !.~&gt;000l&gt; Artii Ansl </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 1 Kind of Instru - ment CORPORATK HAJU Place Busines Belvidere Grain &amp; Coal Co (formrly Farmers &amp; Mer chants Elevator A Amend'tl Belvider Bull Mountain Trading Co. . Articles o ma ha 50,000 Jan. 15 l« Bingenheimer-Evans Co, (formerly The Creighton Lumber Co. I Articles Creighton Jan. 19 190! Big Horn Timber Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Jan. 20 190! Articles Amend't Articles- Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Begole, Van Arsdale, Bardin Bank of Palmyra Beatrice Palmvra . r )0,000 Jan. Feb. Baldwin (The) Co i Bruning Telephone ( Bank of Commerce Benson &amp; Myers C Bvron Lumber Co. (The) Byron Ragan . Lincoln 10 Bank of Ragan 11 Baker Hardware C 21 Bridgeport Independent Telephone Co Articles Amend't Articles Articles Bridgeport Omaha 2i Brown Truck C( Baldwin Lumber C&lt; Crete 1 Bakaska Construction Co Omaha Betz &amp; Crawford Invest - ment Co Lincoln Beatrice Brick Works Articles Beatrice Barr (C. C.) Lumber Co Amendt' Benkelman Broadwater Bank Broadwate 14 Brown Truck Co Amend't Omaha 10 Bank of Glenville Boyles College Beatrice Poultry &amp; Cold Storage Co Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Beatrice Omaha Lincoln Beatrice 100.00C Apr. 20,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. Boyd System (The) Builders Supply Co Beatrice Automobile ( Baca Grant Development Co )1 100,000 Apr Birdsell Mfg. Co. of Nebr 10,000 May Bethany Commercial Club MISCELLANEOUS ( oKIMMt \TIO&gt;s M Ontiiiiit-d i Author- ized Wht Capital File Stock Cincinnati, 0 Bruning Louisville Omaha .... Amend't Articles Amend't Glenville 20.000 Apr. 22 1 Articles ' Omaha ■.•.1.000 Apr. 23 I ■ 30 1909 IS Col. Spgs, ( Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p031">M I'OKT OF TIIK Si ATK 31 H8CKLLAHIMT8 ( OKI'OKA Kind of IIO&gt;S &lt;( ontimud) Author- oououn«A)u Instru . Flaceiif ized When ment Busines tal Filed Baylor (C. W.I A I A r ticks Plattsmouth | MOO Mav i ,V.i &amp; ■ Brunswick Bank Amend'1 Brunswick wick Bar Amend't Brunswick ,000 June " Bank of Keyst. Articles Keystoi hk) Tune : Keyst Articles Keystone ,000 June 7 190U Burgess Shirt Ml&gt;. Articles Omaha hi June 8 1909 Mfe Bank of Roger- Arnend't Rogers 10,000 June l Hooth Fisheri. Articles Lime. In -'".,000 June 1 ' Bank of Seneca Articles Senaca 10,000 June 15 1909 m Articles Senaca Bank of Brock Amend't Brock June 18 1909 Bank of Vutan Amend't Vutan ;iU*&gt;0june 18 1909 Bank of Douglas Amend't Douglas JuneL 1 ; Brown Park Mineral Sprin. Park Min Articles Omaha 75,000 Tune SI Butler County State Bank.... Articles David Cil 3^00ttJtme 29 1909 nty State Bank Articles Anoka 1. "..000 Tune 30 Bar B Brandstreet and Clemens Co. Articles Grand Island 75,000 Tuly Bank of Xorden... Articles Vorden n».O'H&gt; [;: Battle Creek Telephone Co.... Amend't Battle Creek llMMMjnl Butte Hall Associaticm Articles Butte 10,00oijul Butte Hall Associatior Brandies Real! Amend't ( )maha 1. .'00,000 July 1 Brandies R Brooke, T. ('., A Sons I tckson, Mich .-.0,000 July 1. H Bank (Thel of Waverly Amend't Waverl-. -.'."..OOO Aug. I afield Drug C Articles Bloomfield . 7.000 Aug. S Bow Electric Light Bank iTht- i field Drug Articles j Bloomfie 7.000 Aug. Broken Bow El Articles Broken Bow 2'.. 000 Aug. 0 itMW 25,000 Aug. [) Bank of Phillips Amend't Phillips tdwell-Roberta Co. (for - merly Broadwell-Rich Coal Co Amend'1 South Omaha 10 Broadwell-R \mt-. h Omaha Brewster State Bank (for merly International State Bank of Brewster) Amend- "0 Aug. 19 1909 B B B ' Aug. HP Bolte (The) Manufacturing M Articles Kearnev 50,000 Aug. 2 " Aug. 10.000 Aug. um.ooo Aug. .•(i s Baker Manufacturing Co Articles Omaha 10.000 Au. M Baker Construction Articles Omaha 100,000 Aug. 23 Bank of Bayard Amend't Bayard Aug. ?,o los. F. Sons. Articles Omaha !5,00OSe] Aug. !0 Articles Omaha 25,000 Sep. 1. ".,000 Sep. 10 Sep. Butler Electri, Articles David City 1 1.OOO Sep. i: Articl, [&lt;■ x Butte County Fair Assa Articles ' Alliance 25.000 Sen Butte Countv Fair A </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 REPORT OF THK SKi'KKTARY OF STATK MIS&lt; U I. WKOI S I ■OHI'OHV IIuns .roitiniMdi Kind c Instn ment Author CORPORA'!! (The) BakerForbes Paint (formerly National Oil ft Paint Company of Omaha Amen Artici t On :.»O.(KK) S 10.000 S&lt; Bergers Automobile C Om Beaton Realty C&lt; Article Amend Amend Amend Article Omaha ,IMK) St Bradley &amp; Vrooman C h, 11 t t t 150,000 s Alrr Bank of Alma Oct Burke (The) Mercantile C&lt; entr 30,000 O 10,000 0 -t Bankers Investment C Omar Buffalo County Corn Show and Agricultural Ass'n Article Kea 10.000 Oi (The) Brule Land and Loan Co. Articles Hrul 25.000 ( Article Burt County Telephone Bank of Commerce Articles j Geneva ;o Article Amend't N'ebr. Citj ) Amend t Business Men's Clut Brooks. W. R., Coal C&lt; Articles Petersburg Bank of Petersburg Bank of Petersburg III Amend't P .i) Beaver Vallev Land ( Articles Mind Articles Fair Bank of Fairmont Brandies Annex Building Bader Br Baker Bros. Engraving ( Bank of Avoca Briggs, Arthur Hat C( Bank of Bovd Countv Omaha Butte Amend't 50,000 Jan. 19 1910 Boyer-Van Kuran Lbr. &amp; Coal Co 50,000 Jan 5,000 Jan. 25,000 Feb. i Burleigh Glove Co. of Omaha Beck Christensen Realt 31 1 Bruno State Bank Feb Burgess &amp; Woodward The ater Co Articles Omaha 20.000 Feb. Bartholomew (The) Real 15 (MX 11 Place of ized Whe Busim pital File 100,000 Oct. 75,00 I :;.-).(KMi Xov ■MM Xov Vov Bank of Cheney. Bartling Grain C Ban) Articles 'raw Articles Lin&lt;&lt; 15,000 X r'l.iMKi X 50,000 X 90,000 D 35,000 D Articles Omaha 100.000 Dec. Amenrit' Fremont .".0.000 Jan. SO 1910 Amend't Omaha .''..ooo Jan. Amenrl't Avoca i."&gt;,000 Jan. 1 Articles Omaha .1.000 Jan. 2 Articles Ofnaha Articles Omaha Articles Omaha Amend't Bruno </seg>
            <seg id="p033">IBPORT OF THE SECRETARY OK STATK .uthor- ..kim.katk xamk lnstru- Place of ized When 11 ei n I '.I Ml Lmend lmen.: Uar. lmen. tiend t Murdock 15,000 Mar. 3 Article- Mar. Vn K nend t; kearne\ 10,000 Mar. t Vmend't Ke Mar. A f \rtii-l. 100,000 Mar. I \men end t Hvr..n 20,000 Mar. 12 Artkl. &lt;■'•. 25,080 Mar. R 1 I Articles South Omaha .'0,000 Mar. u Articli .'«Xi Mar. A TI 40,000 Apr. 4 Blue 1 Burge Articles {Omaha S0.M U Articles j Beaver Cr'si'g |0 111(1 \i E Articles Sutherland .1,000 May Bu Be R., Amend'tK'mah.i 1 5,000; M A RpT-tr Wi Articles Omah., 10,000 July 5 19U Amend't Brewster [uly 20 19K Brewster State I Jul mil Amend't' i IISCKM. IMKOI'S rOKI'OK\TIO&gt;S i ( i.ttiiiurdi iusim ital File( Lmen Hi Articles Ralst Articles Lincoln t'.. Articles Lincoln Articles St. Jose'h. Amend't Omaha 100,000 May Amend't Crawford Articles Bostwiik tSjMMM Bostv Hirrlu Articles I Omaha \! .1.000 June 3 l!&gt;lf Amenrl't Bristow 100,000 June 13 19K Baker Ire Ifi Larson-B, </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE Kind of Author- CORPORATE NAMK Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock Bagley-Woodruff Lumber Co. Bank of Graf $25,000 July 2:, I '.i 10 10,000 July 26 l'.tlO Bowen Investment Co Barnes Jewelry Co 50,000 Aug 20,000 Aug 9 1!)1O Bank of Gretna 50,000. Aug 11 l'JIO Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks of the Unit - ed States of America Articles North Platte Aug Bridgeport Electric Light &amp; Power Co Bridgeport Bradshaw Palmyra .... Bradshaw Lumber Co Bank of Palmyra Burns, Jay (The) Baking Co. (The) Board of Directors of the Congregational Con - ference of Nebraska Lincoln Ong Oct. 12 l'.tlO Bank of Commerce Bank of Sprague.. Bank of Miller 25,000 Oct. 10,000 Oct. Sprague Miller . Oct. Blue River Power Co Capital Drug Co Seward Lincoln 100,000 Oct. 100,000 Dec. Club House Cigar &amp; News Co Articles Articles Articles Articles Lincoln .. Fairbury Lincoln .. Albion .. 8,000 Dec. 50,000 Dec. 10,000 Dec. 20,000 Dec. I MM Collier-Axtell Co Capital Publishing Co... Citizens State Bank Chapman Co-operative Amend't Articles Chapman Tavlor ... 10,000 Dec. 10,000 Dec. Carlson-Xordstedt Clothing Co Articles Central City Campbell Bros. Consolidated Shows Creamery Package Mfg. Co. Columbus Mercantile Co Chanute Refining Co Chicago, 111.. Columbus Chanute, Kas 25,000 Jan. 50,000 Jan. Corey &amp; MeKenzie Printing Co. (formerly Beckworth- Corey Printing Co.) Amend't Omaha 10,000 Jan. Carvers-Axtell Co Articles MIS&lt; KLLANEOI S &lt; OKI'OKATIONS (( ontinucdi Articles Ashland .... Amend't Graf Articles Scottsbluff Articles Alliance .... Articles Gretna Art | c es Bridge, Artlcles Bradsh Amend t pa , mvr Artules Omaha 25,000 Sep. 10 1910 50,000 Sep. 12 1910 Sep. 15 1910 100,000 Sep. 15 1910 Articles Artic'v Articles Amend't Articles Articles IE Creamery Assn Cash Store Co 171908 17 1908 20,000 Dec. Articles Fairbury Amend't Chicago, Articles Columbu Articles rhan.itP 100,000 Dec Jan 7 IMS Jan. 8 1909 Jan. 13 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">■I8CELLAXE0US &lt; OKI'OKATIOXS M ontinuedi Kind o Instru ment CURPORATI Place of Business r Lumber Co. (former Axtell ( Amend Article SO^OOMan. 10,000 Jan. JO 1 amp Dewey Telephon Amend 30,000 Feb. hris Jensen &amp; Sons Relty Article Amend Amend Amend Article 40,000 Feb. 1. -.,000 Feb. t I Citizens State Ba Carvers Elevator Feb. iva (The) State Bank State Bank ,000 Feb. ,000 Feb. in Milwaukee ad Canal ( Arti Wis li l.i h- 1909 2, r.00 Mar 10,000 Mar. I Mar. 19 I 0 Mar, 10,000 Mar. 2.-..000 Mar. Lincoln Cc 200 Mar Amend Article t 100,000 Mar 2.1,000 Apr. 20 z I'ni. Plac Article Article Hnldrej Lincoln Apr r,.(MM) Apr. VI Operative Grain Article Amend Article Article Rockvilb Omaha _ 21,000 Apr. 300,000 Apr. 50,000 Apr. 18,000 Ma v 16 1T i rn Exchange Ban t Bri mbus Ohiowa 200,000 May 10,000 May °,7.ooo Mav t s 10 Amend't Amend't Articles 2;-»,000 Mav Broken Bow Author- ized When Capital Filed Stock t Pairbui lams ite Ba i,'hton ( &gt;maha t Wood River t &lt; )maha &gt;lumbia Fire Agen. j Articles Lincoln irtland Farmers Grain A Coal Articles CortUnd ty Driving Park Assn \rticles Indianda mtral Tire &amp; Rubber Co ... Articles Omaha llbertson Bank \rticles Culbert- &gt;nsolidated Fuel O \rticles Fremnrr rde Hill Telephone Co \rticles Ellis Sc'l H( Light. Heat &amp; Power Co aflin Printing Co iristian (The) Orphar &gt;lumbu Estate ltizens C tk Suppl CoatesTanner Lumber C, Articles Ohiowa Chernv ft Watson Lumber Co. Articlei North Bend The Central Lumber Co Articles Downs, Kas Citizens (The) Telephone Co. Articles Malm" Charity Organization city of City of Lincoln Amend't Lincoln Citizens State Bank of Peru Amend't Peru ... May 13 1909 May 10 1909 uster State Bank </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE • I I I I I MISCELLANEOUS COKI'OKATIOMS (( 'ontinurd i Kind of Kind of Instru - ment Author- niKiiHiATK xamk Instru- . Place of ized When Place of Business roRlitRATI i ment Business Capital Filed Stock Commercial Investment C IfoniU, Nebraska Articles Morrill .... * 1O.IXM) Mav 19 I'M)' Commercial Investment Co. \lorrill, Nebraska Campl&gt;ell (S. West Articles Omaha 10,000 May 19 1901 Campbell ft West Central National Life Assn. Amend't Lincoln \!., :.'() I'M* Central National Life Citi/ens State Bank Citizens State Bank Articles Havclock ■.•"..(tOOMay '.' (The) Trust and Sav ings Bank Articles David City .10.000 May 23 1901 2.-..000 May City (The) Trust and Sav ings Bank Articles Articles Amend't Amend't Amend't Articles Articles David City Benkelman Cowh :&gt;o.(hki May 22 19© Citizens State Bank Articles Benkelman :_&gt;o.oo&lt;&gt; M 20,000 Mav 25 1&lt;KV Cowles (The) Bank Amend't Cowles 1.1,000 Mav 29 I'.hk. 15,000 Mav 29 I9O Commercial State Bank Amend't Clay Center 100,000 June 1(»0,000 Tune ■ Citizens State Bank Amend't Chadron 100,000 June S 1901 ■erative Reference Co Articles Omaha .1.000 May 27 1901 100,000 June 5 .,000 Mav 27 190 Citizens Telephone Articles Paxton .000 June I ,000 June I Callaway (The) Telephone Articles Gallaw.o 12.000 June 17 I'.MK 12.000 June Tune IT Carpenter Paptr Co Amend't Omaha i&gt;2 .1.000 June tS I'M) 1 . 62:&gt;,000 Callaway Electric Light \ Power C Articles Callawav 1"&gt;,(KK) June :: id (The) Mutual Tele - phone Co Articles Cosad me 28 100*. June 1. 1,000 June June June 28 Continental Land Co Artie'' O'Neill CallahanPeterson Co Articles Omaha 1.1,000 June 3d l(«i'. i.-.,ooo .10 Church of St. John the Baptist Articles Crawford .... July ad Safe Deposit July City Trust and Safe Deposit .Amend't Omaha 100,000 July I Omaha Cairo . 100,000 July 7 Cairo State Bank Amend't Cairo . .' .000 July I Cairo State Bank (Thei Cook SI, (Thel Cook SI, Articles Omaha 7,000 July l'.l l'.tO". Omaha ... Cadams . Coleridge 7,000 July 19 1W Cadams Alfalfa Milling Co Arti&lt; les Cadami 1 :&gt;,()00 July 20 1901 Cadams Alfalfa Milling Commercial State Bank Crab Orchard Telephone 15.000 July 20 V.KY Commercial State Bank Amend't Coleridge ui.ixxi [ul'. 21 1W. 30,000 Julv 27 1W Crab Orchard Telephone Svstem Articles Crab Orchard 20,000 Aug. 11 190t Articles Articles Crab Orchard Omaha 20,000 10,000 Aug Aug 11 Consumers Ice and Coal Co. Articles Omaha 10,000 Aug. l Consumers Ice and Coal Co. iThel Commonwealth Life I!) iThel Commonwealth Life Insurance Co. of Nebraska Articles Chicago, 111.... «i, 000,000 Aug. :.'■ Insurance Co. of Nebraska Chicago Great Western Rail- Chicago, 111 rc.uoo.oon Aug. 26 Chicago Great Western Rail - r a " Articles Omaha 1,000,0(X) Aug. :r road Omaha Aug. City National Bank Build Cit\ National Bank Build - in^ ( " Articles Omaha l.JiMl.OOO Sep. 1 |«0l ing Co Articles Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THK SECRETARY OF STATE 37 ( Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATl Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Articles Articles K,. rdvce rawford Social Club.. onference Claimant's Asso - ciation of N'orth Nebraska Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Ch'ch ( rawford "),000 Sep. 3 1909 Articles Articles I incoln 100.000 Sep. Articles Amend't Articles Agree- ( happell happell ( he Sacred Heart Shelton ttral Trust Company of ew York and The Chicago ment of Condi- and Pacific Rail tional Sale Oct. Br Articles Articles \ Lincoln Curtis terv A Apartment House Omaha .-.o.imio N s i w.i Amend't Articles. Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Amend't Omaha 100,0&lt;« 100,000 Dec. 10 Dec. •«&gt; Jan. Campbell Columbus Chadron .. Mullen State Bank Electric ( Lincoln Lincoln 50,000 Jan Articles Articles Omaha Omaha 4,000 Jan Articles Articles Amend't Amend't Articles Articles :.(&gt;,(KH) Jan '..•4,000 Jan 15,000 Jan. 18 1910 ircle Investment Falls City Callaway Omaha Jan 29 1910 « Feb. oFeb. 8 1910 MISCELLAMKOl'S &lt;OKPOKATIO\S &lt; ( ontlnued) Church of St. John the Baptist Sep. 16 1909 Sep. 39 1909 in Motor Worl tppell (The) Telephone (change 10,000 : 1909 2O,(XM 1909 Oel I 1909 ial (The), Bank Vrti fornia Farm Products Nov. 10 1909 Nov. 15 1909 Dec. 6 1909 Dec. I I Jan. Jan. Jan. 1 ampbell Mercantile ( itizens Bar IterSmith Compar rk Lumber Co &gt;mcil Bluffs &amp; Omaha ransfer Co lahan Realtv Co.... 100,000 Tan irlson. The G. L., 1 1 or Breedine ( Norfolk iway State Bank Crane ' ■ .indFlyin ins Creai. Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (rontlnuedi Kind of Instru - ment ♦•Author CORPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock 'itizens State Bank (former - lv Bank of Plainview) Feb. Amend't Plainview 10 The C. B. S. Pole &amp; Keck Yoke Mfg. Co 2.»,000 Feb. 25,000 Feb. 11 s (The) C.C 10 ".,000 Feb. Chain Reference Bible Co ell Lumber &amp; Grain Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Citizens State Bank Central Telephone Co The Castle-Rock Land Co Columbus Baseball Club Callahan Bros., Munn &amp; Winnetoon . Merriman ... South Omah olumbus Omaha Reise Articles E) Church of the Assump - n of the Blessed Virgin Point Amend't I The) Cotesfield Farmers Grain and Supply Co Articles Articles Cotesfield Omaha ... Cheney, Street &amp; Heffern Co. i The) Contractors Supply &amp; Equipment Co The Concord State Bank. Coleridge State Bank Citizens State Bank Central Loan &amp; Trust Cc Citizens State Bank Wood River Lincoln 25,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. Chester Farmers Elevator Co. Articles Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Chester Chppell Lincoln Omaha 12,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 24,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 40,000 May 100,000 May 26 1910 Commercial Bank Capital Oil &amp; Gas Co Carter Sheet Metal Works Clearwater Elevator Co Cochrane, Thomas, Grain Co. Crawford Social Club 30 1910 30 1910 3 1910 Clearwater Lincoln Articles Brady . Amend't York ... Articles ' Lincoln t Amend't Omaha i Belt Realty Co Articles Wolbach r Creek Irrigation Co Articles Lewellen tinental Trust Co Amend't Dundee tral-West Investment Amend't Dundee Feb. 26 1910 50,000 Mar. 3 1910 500 Mar. 5 1910 10,000 Mar. 11 1910 Articles Omaha ... Amend't Concord . Amend't Coleridge Amend't Wood Ri Articles Lincoln ... Amend't Albion ... </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 T Kind of Instru - ment CORPORATI urtis .-.,000 Mav 11 I'.HO 1 Ir al &amp; Invest t Arti 500,000 May 10,000 May -'.-.000 May The) D Article Amend State Bank The) Land I Article ( )maha 40,000 May 2.-.,000 Mav i Articles Omaha The \V. G. Drug Article Article Amend Article Article La &gt;ridge (The) Sew al Novel tv Co 'PI Malleab Rang Article Amend Article ( )maha )rchard )maha 50,000 June 50,000 June 20,000 July The) State Ban t C 30 1910 ( n Lumber Co. (formerly The Mclntush Lumh Amend t uniata ntral National Life Ass&lt; Ban Amend't Crawford Oct. 25 1910 ["he i Colon Grain &amp; Stock G 10 (Wi Ott 29 1910 MISCELLANEOUS &lt; ORFOR ATIO&gt;S (( ontlnuedl Author- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Curtis &amp; Foxcreek Telephone Co ... Article 5 Omaha . I Oilier ... t Ravenna t Co... Resta s Omaha 100,000 June 1 1910 ■ ' 30,000 June M ■'•Ojune 2\ nibridge .... 10,000 June 27 1010 s Lincoln 10,000 June 27 1910 ster State Bank Fig Orchar ciation Amend 1 ! Lincoln July 12 1910 Co-Operative Orchard Co Articles Omaha 100,000 July M 1910 Crook. Spence Opera Co, Ltd. Articles Falls City .-.00 July 27 1910 Creedon Improvement Co Articles Omaha 10,000 July 30 1910 Custer Electric Co Articles Broken Bow 2.^000 Aug. 1 1910 Clark &amp; Levi Co ... Articles Lincoln 10,000 Aug. 8 1910 Colfax County Bank Amend't Howells Aug 9 1910 Citizens State Bank Amend't Archer 10,000 Aug! 27 1910 C. E. Coon (The) Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Sep. 9 1910 Crist Chapman Co Articles Omaha 50,000 Sep. 9 1910 Clay County Rural Phone Co. Amend't Harvard Sep. 10 1910 Chase, E. M., Co Amend't Lincoln Sep. 16 1910 Chaulk &amp; Birdsall Articles Chadron 5,000 Oct. 14 1910 Cheney Lumber &amp; Coal Co.... Amend't Lincoln 2."&gt;,000 Oct. 17 1910 Cummings, If. T. Grain Co Articles Lincoln 40,000 Oct. 24 1910 (The 1 Commercial State </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 MIS&lt; KLI.ANKOI S 4 OKI'OKATIONS (( ontinued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATI Place of Business ized When 'apital Filed Stock Culp-Langworthy Co.... . H. F. Lumber Co olidated Sales Co.. is Realty C« $25,000 Nov. 2 l'.UO 10,000 Nov. 10,000 Nov. 17 Clarkson State Bank'. Nov. £ Blow Advertising Agency armerly C. D. Thompson Ivertising Agency) Jan. 4 Cedar Bluffs South Omah Beatrice 25,000 Jan. 10,000 Jan. 10,000 Feb. \2 18 12 Kiam \: Dunham (now) rbv Woolen Mills Omaha Diller Feb. l Diller Mercantiler Co 35,000 Mar. 5 ■ton Co-Operative Society fns, P.1L, Co Dalton Lincoln Dorsev 39*000 Apr. r, 15,000 Apr. 11 Telephone Co 3,000 May -h Brotherhood Hall Amend't Elba 3,000 Ma v 21 Dailey James H. Estate Amend't Lincoln Dmiiphan Grain Co Doniphan Drummond Electrical Co Diehl (The) Chemical Co Lincoln Articles Omaha Dawson (The) Bank Amend't Dawson Articles Emerson is (The) Fullc tl) Doctor Egbert H..s tal and Sanitarium 10,000 Aug. 100,000 Sep. i The) Dutch Flats Telephone Articles Articles Morrill Dorsev 7400 Sep. 10,000 Sep. ].'» i The) Dorsev Trust ( If, K) Dutton Miller Hard Lincoln Duncan Articles Articles Amend't Articles Amend't Articles Articles Articles 10,000 Sep. 16 Duncan State Bank 10,000 Sep. 27 Duff Gran Xebr. City Denton 350,000 Oct. T 10,000 Nov. 20 Den ton C reamer v Co Drexel Shoe Co Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha 25,000 N'ov. 27 Diamond Bar Cattle Co 125,000 Nov. 28 100,000 Tan. 7 1910 Articles Omaha _ Amend't Omaha _ Articles Omaha . Articles Omaha Amenri't Clarlnoo 250,000 Nov Amend't Omaha Articles Cedar Articles South &lt; Articles Beatrk eVun&gt;. r Smith Cc C. P.. Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles May 24 l.-&gt;,000 May _•:. 10,000 June 8 2.1,000 July 10 25,000 Jui 2.-..000 Aug. 4 Articles Articles Articles Hastings Articles Omaha .. Davis Coal Co.. L. G. Co.. 65,000 Jan. 24 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">tKPORT OF THE SECRKTARY OF STATE 1 Kind of ori-okati. namk Instru- Place Author- &gt;in Mercantile ( Articles uster Mill Manufaetur- Vmend't Beatric ,000,00*) Mai Diers (The) and Carlson Co. Articles Fullerton l.VMK) Mar. I Mar. »1 I! i I' I L' '11 iphan Lumber Co Article! Doniphan Davenoort \ Kiowa Tele phone i Arti. los Davenport rson Lumlwr I Articles &lt; &gt;,, la h Dorchester drain &amp; Lumlicr iu run , Articles Dorchester DimockLwrnlH. Articles South Omah :.&gt;,uuu i u r u Luft ft Diers Broi Amend't Scott: mntv Hank Amead't | | Iltin/l\-(\inrt»»r A fl^j ■■■■■■ (' \,., !'♦ T» , Aug. ■_•■ i t !!• .. 0,000 &lt; let \ Ay County Abstr.i -ienkelmar tor Tavlor MeHiial ("om- .VKX) ( )ct. n \ titutc Articles ( )maha 2,0011 25,001 Douglas County Mill Producers Association Arti Omaha 50,000 Nov. 25 Drainage District No. -'" Articles Rich'dt Articles ; Dakota «e District No. 1". Articles Johnson &gt; Aug 1 ISM age District No. I Article! l'av Ar- NX) De - Articles Eldorac Amend't Lincoll i'b Amen(l' Realty Co Articles jOmah; Enterprise Planing Mill Co ... Articles iLincol] K.lcrin Articles Elgii II Tl \ Articles j Lincoli Equitable (The) Land Co Amend't Hasting Edgar Telephone I Articles Edga , y T til v IIS&lt; Kl.LANKOI S &lt; OKI'OKVTIONn tinucd) 15,000 Mar. I Apr. May Distr "Drainafl District No. 2". Amend' t Dakta C r»_..: i,: ..: . ■ &lt; .- i Omahs 2,00 I \'Mtr 700,000 Jan. 1,00 OOJJmn. a •no Jan. 28 1901 10,000 Apr. ll),0(K) Apr. t 40,000 June - 100,000 June :.'■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Articles Amend't Amend't Amend't Articles Articles Omaha Electric Garage Co Elevator Roller Mills Co.... Enevoldsen Land Co Elkhorn Valley Bank Elite (The) Amusement Co Elvria State Bank Columbus St. Paul... Tilden Lincoln Elvria . 15 hi in Eagle Independent Tele - phone Co Eagle 10,000 Feb. The Enterprise Publishing Articles Articles Lincoln 10,000 Feb. 50,000 Feb. Columbu Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Eldorado . Chadron . Emerson . Springfield Lincoln ... 20,000 Mar. 500 Mar. 7,500 Mar. 21 1910 Elk Valley Telephone Co Elwell Peters Co 25,000 Mar. 25,000 Mar. 10,000 Apr. 26 1910 30 1910 25 1910 Bjire Lumber Co.... pse Electrical Co Lincoln Kingelical Luthern Concor - a School of the Unaltered ugsburg Confession Hall County Grand Island Omaha Articles Articles May :% Edholm. Albert 25,000 June Eriison Telephone Exchange Articles Articles Articles Ericson 600 June 2,000 June 15 1910 23 1910 2 1910 E! Omaha People's Club.... wood Park Association, ern Nebraska Telephone East Omaha Elmwood .... Sep. Co. Wisner . Omaha . Omaha . Fremont 10,000 Oct. 10,000 Oct. 10,000 Nov. 100,000 Dec. Eaton-Rohrberg Co.. Eckles Stoneware Co Fremont Granite Brick Co... Fredrickson (H. E.) Automo bile Company Articles Amend't Articles Amend't Omaha Scribner Merna .. 100,000 Jan. 14 1909 18 1909 19 1909 22 1909 Eers Grain &amp; Stock Co.... ers Bank of Merna ers ft Merchants Bank ers Co-Operative Grain Jan. 25,000 Jan. Elmcreek Jan. apply Co Amend't Ashton 24,000 Jan. n itM Farmers Mutual Telephone $30,000 Aug. 9 1909 50,000 Aug. 11 1909 10,000 Aug. 26 1909 Aug. 28 1909 / 0,000 Dec. 3 1909 ■&gt;. r &gt;,000 Jan. Amend't 12 H&gt;10 14 19.0 28 1910 Itt, Speice, Echols Co rado Lumber &amp; Grain Eli Game Club Articles Articles Artices Articles iZ SET </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THK SKfRKTARY OF STATE 43 MISCELLANEOUS &lt; 'ORPOHATIOMS- (( onUn«e«) Kind of Instru - ment Author- \ AMI Place of ized When Business Capital Filed HIRA Stock Farmers ft Merchants Bank Articles Deshler armers &amp; Merchants Bank Articles Deshler - :.1,000 Feb. 3 1909 armers State Bank Amend't Shubert ,'0,000 Feb. 4 1909 i BanV Amend t Shubert armers A Merchants Batik Art; .! 25,000 Feb. 5 1905 Ba"nk Article Morrill 1 reeland Brothers-Ashley Co. Articles Omaha -'.-,,000 Feb. 13 1909 Freeland Brothers- Ashley Co. Articles Omaha ( 'armers ft Merchants Bank Articles Walton .'.-,,000 Feb. 22 1909 Bank Article Walton r ant armers State Bank Articles Oberton 25,MMMar. 4 1909 I Ban Article ( tberton Sta Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Articles I Oakland 'armers &amp; Merchants Bank Articles Oakland -.0,000 Mar. 8 1909 'orimont Lumber Co Art rmont 16,000 Mar. 11 1909 Fairmont r L Arti m r 'oster Grain Company Amend't Lincoln &gt;"&gt;,oooMar. 11 ter (irain Company Amend't Lincoln 'armers ft Merchants Bank (Thei Articles Shickley 25,000 Mar. 12 1909 mers &amp; Merchants Bank n Article 25,000 Mar. 12 1909 'remont Cement Product! Co Articles Fremont 25,000 Mar. 13 1909 P ts Article Fremont 25,000 Mar. r 'armers (The) Bank Amend't Kearnev Mar. IT Kearney Mar. Tht H Farmers State Bank Articles Florence 'armers State Bank Articles Florence 25,000 25,000 1 "irst Trust &amp; Saving Bank Articles Beatrio i 00,000 Mar. 24 1909 Trust A Banl 100,000 Mar. 20,000 Apr. 10 1909 'irst State Bank. Articles Tecumseh 20,000 Apr. 8 1909 ite B£ i "irst State Bank. Amend't Hemingford Apr. 10 1909 hi Hemingford Apr. -ranklin Volunteer Fire De - partment Articles Franklin Apr. 10 10O0 Franklin Volunteer Fire D« Arti Franklin Apr. t Farmers Grain ft Live Stock &amp; tCM 1 Articles Hadar 5,000 Apr. 14 1909 Arti Hadar 5,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 14 1909 I Fisher McGill Co. Article! South Omaha 10,000 Apr. 14 1909 ish M&gt; Arti South Omaha 14 1909 Farnam Lumber Co Articles Farnam 10,000 Apr. 15 1909 m Lumlier Co Articles Farnam I I.u IS 1 '.«&gt;'.» First Bank of Miller Amend't; Miller First Bank of Miller Amend't Miller ... Apr. 19 1909 Apr, 19 MM Farmers State Bank Articles Rosalie 20,000 Apr. H B Arti Rosalie 20,000 Apr. it First Trust ft Savings Bank (The) Articles Crete 50,000 Apr. 28 1909 Trust ft Banl T Article 50,000 Apr, M 1 '.'"■&gt; rete Farmers Independent Tele - phone Co . Articles Crawford 30,000 May 14 1909 Farmers Independent Tele Article Crawford 30,000 May 10,000 May 14,909 Fralick-Geddes Co Articles Grand Island 10,000 M. Arti Grand Island Fraternity Building Associa - tion of Hastings Articles Hastings 25,000 May 19 1909 Fraternity Building A Article 25,000 May 50,000 May Hast Hastings 19 1909 M 19O.» Farmers State Bank Amend't Craig | 50,000 May 26 1909 mers State Bank Amend'tl Craig Farmers \- Merchants State Bank Articles Trenton 25,000 June 1 1909 State Ba Article Trenton 25,000 June 1 1909 25,000 June 1 1909 Farmers Lumber Co Articles Unadilla 25,000 June 11909 irmers Lumber Co Articles Unadilla L First (The) Trust and Sav - ings Bank Articles Friend 25,000 June 1 1909 Pirs The) Trust Sav Farmers (The) Elevator Co Vmend't Burr Tune 2 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 c I I REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE HIS(KLLA\KOIS roKI'HKATIOXS- &lt; Continued) Kind of Author CORPORATK NAMK ized When Capital Filed Fremont (Thei Meat ( Farmers State Bant Farmers Shipping Assn Articles Broken Bow Farmers Mutual Canal Cu Articles Soottshlnff Franklin State Bank Farmers State Bank 11 June 30 190! Farmers Manufacturing Co. Articles Beemer .".o.ooo Aug Hallam 5,000 Aug 4 I'M* Fairbur\ 10,000 Sep. 10 iwc Farmers Mutual Telephone North Platte 5,000 Sep. :.'o.oon Sep. 20,000 Oct. imstot Fairburv Farmers Bank (now Farm Oct. 20,000 Nov. Farmers Independent Tele phone ( Article Fontein Brothers Pianc Article lumbu 2 ."1.000 Dec. 2 1909 Fremont Stock Yards iV Land Co Amend t Fremont De 4 1901 »iers Elevator Company Hubbard, Xebr Article Hubbard 20,000 De. 1909 Farmers Mutual Telephone Instru- p ]ace of ment Business Articles Fremont 186^ June 5 n«c Articles Pleasanton _ 1,200 June Articles Broken B. .1)00 June 10 IW Articles Scottsbluff j une ■&gt;:, ,.„,. Amend't Franklin .--,.000 June 25 i&lt;hm Aurora Articles Aurora Fremont Canal and Ron Amemlt Fremont Farmers State Hank Articles Glenvillc Fremont Stock Yards and Lam Amen.lt Fremont Farm Land Co Amend't Omaha . Fleury. \V. C, Co. I formerly -rsFleury Co Amend't Omaha Aug Farmers Telephone Co Amend't Fairburv Cloak and Suit Co. Articles Article Farmers &amp; Merchants Hank Article Fairbury Laundry I Article |&gt;O I "»,(., 15 1909 State Bank. Amend't Adams Frenchman Land A Live Articles Imperial Farmers State Hank Amen.lt Eustis Farmers' Cooperative Assn. Amend't Cedar Bluffs rtmry iThei Alfalfa Mill in S Co Articles Fairburv .-.0.000 Oct. 30 Nov. in i Nov. in North Platte 2,000 Dec. Manufacturing C&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF 45 MIS&lt; KM. \\H»I S (MKI'OKUIONh (outinuedi Kind Author OOWOBATX HAMI Instru- PU, ized W hen Inst When ment H l: ta l Filed ment Bu tal Fil Stock ck Farmers iThei Tru Articles Beatrice $100,0(1 Articles Be Articles \' f *ioo,o»&gt;o I)t Frontier (Thei Hotel Co Articles \elir. I I !S,OOOJD 2.1,000 Dt Franciscan (The) Sisterhood Xfliraska Amend' On) ah Ian. Farmers State Hank Article* Helvi .' '.&lt;mmi (an. 2:i,000 [ Fair (Tin- Amend't Gordoi JO.0O0 Ian. ■ .Vi.000 la Fir&lt;t Trust Articles Omaha IMUMOjan. i&gt; Articles Omaha 1110,000 Jan. II Farmers iThei dram Co Articles U'althill Articles Wai thill Farmers iThei Grain Co Articles Auburn Articles I Auburn 10,000 fan. Farmers State Hank Amend't \\ f a . Amend't W Jan. ■_■ Farmers Mutual Telephone \i Articles Litchfield Articli -itchfield JO.OOOFeb. II Frontier (The Articles Grand Island rt.ooo FeJ&gt;. 1 Articles Grand Island fi.000 Feb. n Farmers Grain. Coal &amp; Live Stock Association Articles Annemlale \ iation Articles Annendale Farmers Grain \ Supph Co. Articles Hasting! irmers Grain &amp; Supph Co. Arti Farmers Mcrcanti Articles Cartel Friend Commercial Club.... ..Articles Friend Articles i Friend 25,000 ! Farmers Elevator I Articles Stockham 20,000 Mar. Articles I Stockham 20,000 Mar. Farmers Grain Articles 15,000 Mar. Articles ■ Bellw. 1.-..000 Mar. Farmers iThei (irain and Supply Company of EH Nehrask Articles Elba 20.000 Mar. U 1 El Articles Elba tOfltt Mar. Farmers Ban; Articles Sutherland 1.M0 M The Farm Bank Articles Rel^ra'! a,000 M Fremont Granite Brick Co. Amend ■ I IO0u9OftMs Amendt Fremont 100,000 Mi Franklin ('reamer Articles Franklin mi Apr. ! Articles Franklin 25,000 Apr Farmers Protective Elevator ociation Articles Alexandria O.fiOO Apr. 1 - 1' irrr iation .... Arti&lt; li Alexandria 0,600 Apr. a Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Amend't Sterling H&gt;.WiOiA|ji. i Farmers &amp; Merchants Hank Amend't .Sterling 50,000 Apr. ! ar F. J. Harrington ,\ Articles Omaha 1 0,000, Apr. IS P. J. Harrington A Co Articles Omaha 1 0,000, Apr. IS Fender Patent Burner Co. . Articles Lincoln OoJApr. IS Fender Patent Burner Co Articles Lin ncoln tO.000 Apr. I- Farmers Grail Arti. ■ Arti&lt; « Apr Farmers State Hank Articles Bloomington -.' MW|A] Farmers State Bank Articles I Bloomington •.'. iOO A; Farmers State Bank Articles Obeii \! Farmers Elevator ■ Articles Palmyra 25,000 May II Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Amend't Imperial Farmers (The) Creamery Co. Articles Burton Farmers iThei Telephone Co. An </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE (OKI'OKATIONS (Continued) Author- MIS&lt; KI.I.AXKOl S ! Kind of Kind of Author ookporate NAME Instru- Place of ized When CORPORATK KAMI Instru- Place of ized When merit Business Capital Filed . ment Business Capital Filed 1 Stock Farmers (The) Grain Co Articles Pierce $ 50.000 June 4 I'.tlO Farmers (The) Grain Co Articles Pierce $ 50.000 June 4 Farmers (The) Mutual Tele- Farmers (The) Mutual Tele - phone Co Amend't Seward 10,000 June 25 1'tlO phone Co Amend't Seward 10,000 June 915 Farmers Grain &amp; Live Stock Farmers Grain &amp; Live Stock Articles Wvnot Articles Wynot 20,000 June 20 1910 20,000 June 20 1910 Farmers (The) Bank Amend't Chester 25.000 June 30 1910 Amend't 25,000 Tune .10 1010 Farmers (The) Bank Chest Farmers Lumber Co Amend't Cook 30,000 July 9 1910 Farmers Lumber Co Amend't Cook 30,000 Tulv 9 1910 Farmers State Bank Amend't Emerson 40,000 July IS 1010 Farmers State Bank Amend't Emerson 40,000 July Li 1910 Farmers State Bank Articles Platte Center 50,000 July 18 1910 Farmers State Bank Articles Platte Center Frv-Rosenzweig Co Articles Omaha 75,000 July 28 1910 Omaha 75,000 July 28 HMO Farmers Social Club Articles Martell .... 300 July 29 1010 Farmers Social Club Articles Martell Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Amend't Milligan 16,000 Aug. 1 1910 Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Amend't Milligan 16,000 Aug. 1 1910 Farmers State Bank Articles Sargent ... "•..oooAug. 3 lino Farmers State Bank Articles Sargent 25,000 Aug. 3 Farmers State Bank Articles Cairo 25,000 Aug. 90 loio Farmers State Bank Articles Cairo 25,000 Aug. 30 1910 Farmers State Bank Articles Cortand 30.000 Sep. 1 IM0 Farmers State Bank Articles Cortand 30,000 Sep 1 1910 Farmers Elevator Co Articles N'eligh 50,000 Sep. 13 1*10 Farmers Elevator Co Articles N'eligh 50,000 Sep. 13 1910 First State Bank Amend't Kenesaw £5,060 Sep. 10 IM0 First State Bank Amend't Kenesaw Farmers State Bank Amend't Smithfield ISgOOOjSep. 21 l'.no Farmers State Bank Smithfield Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Articles Springview 20.000 Sep. 22 1910 Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Springview Federal Trust Co Articles Omaha tSjMOOct a loin Federal Trust Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Oct. 22 l'.lin (The) Field Automobi'a Manufacturing Co Articles Lincoln 200,000 Oct. M 1910 (The) Field Automobi'a Manufacturing Co Articles Lincoln 200.000 Oct (The) Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Articles Wymore MyMO'Nov. (The) Farmers &amp; Merchants Bank Wvmore Fremont Ice &amp; Sand Co. merly Fremont Ice Co.) Amend't Fremont Nov. 11 1910 Fremont Ice &amp; Sand Co. i former! v Fremont Ice Co.) Amend't Fremont \ 11 First State Bank of Winne- First State Bank of Winne Amend't Winnetoon 100.000 \&lt;i\ •. - Amend't toon Winnet' ton 1(X).(HMI \(,y Gray-Benzing &amp; Miller Cigar Co. Articles Beatrii ■&lt; 25,000 Dec. 1 1908 Gray-Benzing &amp; Miller Cigar Co. Articles Beatrice 25,000 Dec. 25.000 Dec. 100.000 Dec. Golden West Land Co Golden West Land Co Articles Omaha 25.000 Dec. 12 1908 Articles Omaha German Fire Ins. Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Dec. 1- German Fire Ins. Co Articles Omaha German Evangelical Luth - eran Trinity Congregation of the Unaltered Angsburg On Elk Creek Confession Articles an d vicinity Dec. 2 German Evangelical Luth - eran Trinity Congregation of the Unaltered Angsburg On Elk Creek Confession and vicinitv Grantham Townsite Co Grantham Townsite Co Articles Grantham ■ »00 Dec. 30 1008 Articles Grantham Gothenburg Hardware Co ... Articles Gothenburg 25,000 Jan. 11 Gothenburg Hardware Co Articles Gothenburg Golden West Land C. Amend't Omaha 100,000 Jan. 13 1909 Golden West Lani 100,000 Jan. Omaha Great Western Xovelt 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 ( ( ( Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATK HAMI Place of , ized When Business Capital Filed 100,000 Mar. 6 1909 15,000 Mar. 16 1909 Articles Articles Artlices Articles Articles Articles Amend't ion ( Omaha Omaha York _ 10,000 Apr. 14 1909 50,000 Apr. 21 1909 25,000 Apr. 30 25,000 If a 10,000 Mav 11 10,000 May 15 1909 Lincoln Grand Island South Omaha Cheyenne, \V. oshen Hole Irrigation Co.... ermania (The) Land and Lumber Co 500 Mav 20 Columbus 100,000 June I Articles Articles Articles Articles Omaha Gilead 40,000 June 3 1909 4,000 June 15 1909 Grand Island Grand Island 10,000. Tune 18 1900 25,000 June 28 1909 El County Gas, Light &amp; wer Co. (formerly Beat - e Gas &amp; Power Co Amend't Beatrice ( Lincoln MISCELLANEOUS COKI'ORATIOMS- -(Continued) Gaines Lumber Co irport Gothenburg Irrigation Co.... Articles Milw'uke Greer (The) &amp; Trimble Mer- cantile Co Kearney German (The) Evangelical Lutheran District Synod of Nebraska, and other States Articles Gospel (The) Army Work- ers of Nebraska Articles German-American State Bk. Articles Glenville &amp; Inland Tele- phone Co Articles Gothenburg Light &amp; Power Cerf Clothing Co Articles Gage County Independent Telephone Co Amend't Grav-Kirkandall Construct- 25,000 Apr. 2 1909 I-vin Bros Id Lumber Co stlinger &amp; Co nd Island Saddlery Co.... Ifrey, E. B., Incorporated ;hen Hole Irrigation Co.... B umber Co Articles :e City Land &amp; Invest- lent Co Articles E) Gilead Townsite C( hel-Douglass (.'■ , Harrison Co 2:&gt;O.ltOO Tune 29 1909 Milling &lt;S: Elevatoi </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE *IS&lt; hl.l.A\KOl S ( OKI'OKATIONS ( ( ontimu d i CORPORATE NAMK Article Article 35,000 July :. Oretna Lumber ( retna Grand Island Specials Grand Island Storage and Grand Island 10.000 Ju l.i Grand Islan 20,0(10 I Forwarding C Article Kd Island Hotel rmerly McClintock Ho Co.) Amend Article Article t (jraml Island Lincoln liO.OOO lulv 26 191 Grand Grocer Green Mercantile Cc 10.000 Aug. t DeWitt 10.000 Aug. fi ■e) Gleason Pneumatic alve ( ''■ Articles Havelocl 5,000 Sep. 11 1909 Article Omaha Ht.lMHI Sep. 17 Articles Line 30,000 St; Kan. Citv, M Gabel. J. S. Lumber C&lt;. Grayson A Townsend, Inc b, Herbert K .. i The I Grand Dry Goods Co. (The) Grand Prairie and fio.ooo Nov. 15 Omaha l.oon N Lincoln Article Grand Island Article Atkinson (The) Gardner Memorial Parish House Association Articles Amend'1 Articles Articles Articles Omaha Kearne Beatric Omaha (Thel Gilcrest Lumbe; i The l Globe Clothing Gate City Construction Cc Ginn, White ft Schlat • es, J. H., Lumber ( t Tar 10,000 Jan. .-.(1.000 Jan. 30,000 Feb. 2-1 E N'orth Platte E rmerly The Pathfinder mber Amend't Feb. :.' (Thel Great Western Nov eltv Co Amend't Amend't Omaha Mar 1 i z (The) Grand Dry Goodl (The) Grand Island Base Grand Island I.Vi.OOO Mar Eill Association .. :va State Bank oway Milling C&lt; Article Grand Island Geneva 3,000 Mar fiO.OOO Mar .-.0.000 Mar in Amend't Articles 24 Oakdale :so lino Greater Omaha Athletic Club Articles Omaha 10,000 Apr. Gering (The) Lumber &amp; Grain Co Gering 50,000 Apr. Kind of Author- Insti Place of ized Wht ment Business Capital File Stock Guarantee Laundry C&lt; frugenheim Co Articles Articles Am end' t 75,000 X 100,000 Nov. 29 Emmet Telephone C&lt; 2..VK) Tan -bluff </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 MISCELLANEOUS &lt; OKPOK ATIOXS (( ontlnuedi Kind of Author- CORPORATK NAME Instru- Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock ment Gering (The) Henry R., Co (Formerly Porter-Ryerson lloobler Co.' Hoobler Co. I Amend't Omaha &lt;ljlM«KiMav 10 Amend Article Article Article Grant Telephone Co Articles Grant 4,000 M Gayety Theater Articles Omaha 3,000 June 3 1910 i.OOOjune 3 1910 Gayety Realty Co Articles Omaha ".000 June 3 1910 5,000 June (The) Grand Department Store Articles Lincoln 100,000 June 11 1910 The! Grand Department Store 100,000 [une 11 1010 Gymnastic Sokol Society Fugner Tver- Articles South Omaha June 14 1910 Gvmnastic Sokol Society Fugner Tyers Articles South Orr .ih f une 14 1910 Grocers Specialties Com - pany of Omaha Articles Omaha 2.-,,0OOjuly 6 1910 Grocers Specialtie pany of Omaha Articles Omaha Gregory Coal Co Articles Lincoln ::..'**) July 20 1910 Gregory Coal Co Articles Lincoln Gas Engine Starter Co Articles Omaha !3,000{J&lt;lly 31 1910 Gas Engine Starter Co ..Articles Omaha Gem Laundry Articles Crete 10,000 Aug. 1 1910 Gem Laundry Articles Crete Gamble &lt;S: Perryman, Inc.— Articles o r rl 10,000 Aug. 3 amble ft Perryman, Inc Articles Grand Island Telephone Co. Amend't Grand Island 100,000 Aug. 9 1910 Grand Island Telephone Co. Amend't Grand Is ;in Grand (The) River Valley Improvement Co Articles Omaha 23,000 Sep. 5 1910 Improvement Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Sep. 50,000 Sep. Gresham State Bank Articles Gresham 50,000 Sep. 23 1910 Gresham State Bank Articles Gresharr 23 1910 German-American Life In - surance Co Amend't Omaha Oci German-American Life In ranee Co Amend't i Omaha 17 1910 Gorsuch Lumber Co Articles Hastings .-.o.ihhi Oct. 17 1910 Gorsuch Lumber Co Articles Hastings :.0,000 Oct. 100,01m 10.00 - l .-»,orx 25,OO&lt; I 200,00* 100,000 Dec. Goodrich Bros. Banking Co. Amend't Fairbury lOO.ix Bros. Banking Co. Amend't 1 Fairburv Golden Rod Co Articles Alliance 10.000 Oct. 31 1910 Golden Rod Co Articles Alliance 31 1910 (The) Gresham Grain Co Articles Gresham l.-»,000 N'ov. 3 1910 The) Gresham Grain Co Articles Gresham (The) Grain Belt Co Articles Omaha 35,OOOlNov. 7 1910 The) Grain Belt Co Articles Omaha Griswold Seed Co Articles Lincoln 200,000 Nov. r Griswold Seed Co Articles Lincoln Home Builders Co. (The) Articles Columbus 100,000 Dec. 5 1908 Home Builders Co. iThei Articles Columbu Hastings Cement Burial Vault Co Articles Hasting 5,000 Dec. 8 1908 Hastings Cement Burial Vault Co Articles Hastings 5,000 Dec. 10,000 Dec. fi.OOO Jan. Hastings Security Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Dec. 9 1908 Hastings Security Co Articles Omaha Hub (The) Clothing Co Articles Merna 6,000 Jan. 4 1909 Hub (The) Clothing Co Articles Merna Hoffnungs Free Reform Ger- man Church Articles Sutton Jan. 9 1909 Herald Co. (The i nerlv The Perkins-Howard Co.) Amend't Fremont Jan. IS 1909 Hershey Hook Co Articles Lincoln 30,000 Jan. -..000 Jan. Hershey Telephone Co Articles I Hershev 28 1909 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE ■ 1 MISCELLANEOUS &lt; OK1'OKATIO\S (( ontinu* d) Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORFOBATE NAME Place of ized When Capital Filed Business Stock Articles -Stamford 10,000 Feb :so,ooo Feb. Ksch Lumlier and Coal Co. tings Foundry &amp; Iron Articles Uni. Pla« 16 10f Hasting 60,000 Feb Bluffs, la 2.-),000 Feb le Inning Produce Co me Savings Bank rdy Bank le pen Article Amend Columbi Hardv t Holdreg 25,000 Apr 1 I l'.to Article Article Article Article Wood River Hazard § tings Bottling Works le (The l Savings Bank (The) Independent Tele Hastings Wilber \lav 8 190" 2.-..000 May 2:. 1 10,000 Mai 2.-..000 Tun l.Vt.ooo June 21 Home (The) Interstate Tele phon Co Amend t Spem 2.Y0O0 I Humphrev Electric Light &amp; Telephone Co ■vutoo Tu 200,000 Tu 25^00 July i) Tniv mow Hastings Fuel Hastings 12,000 July 2; ""£ Co Amend't! Co. Bluffs. la. s Electric Manufactur- 40.000 Aug A y-+ ||-.1 a 75,000 Aug. 1 190!) Highline Mutual Telephone E'irks Amend't .•key (The) Glove Manu- turing Co Articles 18 19O Highland Telephone Com- pany of the State of Xebr. Arti Henning Produce Co Arti 2,100 Feb. ■&gt;0.000 Mar ."&gt;( i.ooo Mar. Apr. Klenbeck Manufacturing Article iipt'in Luml» al i. \w;..i« 25,000 Apr. 21 1M 10,000 Apr. 23 ]W rd Telephone ( P h "ne Co Articles N'iobrars Hubbell Bank Articles Hubbell Irege (The) Lighting Amend't IJolrlregt lele t )hoii Amendt Humphre rd Stove Works Articles Ralston (The) Hubbell Farmers Ele- Articles Hubbell 'The) Holdrege Lumber Co. Articles Holdrege Harvey, K. A.. Lumber Co Articles Bruning 'ings Fuel and Ice Com- i :&gt;,ooo T KAmend't The) Glove Manu- ring Co Amend't </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 \ l .11. 1 r. l.l, \&gt;r. IM &gt; Kil IfMCIOKVrlON** &lt;( " lit i nurd &gt; Author- Author .ratkximk In .. Place of ized When merit Bus Aa\ Filed OOBPORATE HAMI Instru- j Place of ized When apital Filed M ilding and Loan - Al " ;&gt;. 7 1909 Auto and Gar- Ar^' 3 1900 \l Aut 1 7 1909 Arti ,, g 1909 I T ewing Company ;ka \ ler Mutual f'anal Articles Haigler Sep. 23 1900 \r P luntv Teleph- Ai 100.000 Sep. r Millinery Co Artict Sa\ injjs &amp; I.. 1'aul 100.000 Sep. 27 1909 10.0(1. \r ( t. II 1909 11 1909 n and Trust Articli J.'i,O(m- 1900 e Bank Artici 25,000 Nov. S3 1909 \r iKs Hank Articles Grand Island :sn,ooo Dec. 1 1909 Articles Omaha W.OOO Dec. 1 1909 Artick 100.000 Dec. 3 1909 \r and .10,000 Dec. 1 1909 Articles Omaha W.000 Dec. 1 1909 Vrticle lOO.oooDec. 3 1909 Wachiiw ' 100,000 Dec. 9 1909 A1 l.-i.OOO Dec. 9 1909 100,000 Dec. 9 1909 15,000 Dec. 9 1909 ; eourit Articles Omah 00 Dec. 13 1909 Articles Omaha n.oooDec. 13 1900 he) Electr '-tides Harvard : .000 Dec. 23 1909 Articles I Harvard : .000 Dec. 23 1909 attle Co Articl&lt; 100,000 D Pairbur&gt;* - Amend't Fairbnry 100.000 Jan. 1 Articl. 100.000 O rlmr\- .. Amend t Fairbury 100,000 Tan. 11 1910 Amend noo Tan. 1 \i i.-.0.000 Tan. 13 Realt&gt; Articles Omaha 100,000 Jan. S! \r 100,000 Jan. 25 1910 sundry and It Amend't Hastings 100,000 Jan. ::■ Am Am Art Art • Bank Amend't Ohion DOO Feb. 3 1910 nan C Artici, r.DOOFeb. 1 \r Articles Omaha Feb. 1 Articles Hemingford 10.000 1'. 10.000 Fer 24 1910 r. 11 1910 Art </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 MISCELLANEOUS ( 'OKI'OK \TIO\S (&lt;'»ntinu« d i r«)KI1)RATE NAME Place of Business Hastings Base Ball Assn H. A M. Clothing Co Hastings Independent Tele- Articles Articles Hastings ridge :&gt;,000 Mar 10,000 Mar :::::; phone Co Apr z Hamilton County Grain Co. Hendley (The) Switchboard 20,000 Apr Co Articles Articles Hendlev 3,000 Apr. 20.000 Apr. 11 ;;:;:: Hampton Grain Co Hampton is (The) Hamm-Weller Mercan - tile Co Articles Scottsbluff 2.-),000 Apr Hastings (The) Equity Grain Bin Manufacturing Co Articles Articles Articles Hastings York 25,000 Apr. 100,000 May -.'.".fXHi May 21 Harrison Nursery Cc Home (The) Bank Articles Articles York 25,000 Ma\ 1,000 May :::: Havelock (The) Club Havel oik Home Publishing Company (formerly The Topical Bible Publishing Co. Amend't Lincoln .■iO.OOO Ma\ !1 Highland Lateral Company Number Tw Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Scottsbluff Omaha 3,000 June E Hancock-Epstein ( 100,000 June 20.000 Tune i:( Hogan Linotyping Co. Home Casualty ('■ Holmquist Elevator C Hull &amp; Daggett Omaha Omaha Omaha Lincoln 100,000 Aug .-•0.000 Aug :::: 12 Hydroro (The) Foreign Pat - ent Holding Co Lincoln 8,000 Aug 19 Hartington Knights of Co - lumbus Home 25,000 Sep. 100,000 Sep. 100,000 Sep. l I Hokombe Cattle Co Hennington Produce Co Hall County Grain Co Hastings College Athletic If, :o 7.500 Sep Association Articles Hastings 5.000 Oct. Herndon Railway — Joint Chair Co Articles Omaha 200.000 Oct. 19 (The) House of Dahlman Articles Hastings Kind of Instru- ment Author- ized When Capital Filed Stock I Amend't Hastings Articles Aun Elw&lt; Harrison's (C. S.) Select N'urserv Co !■■&gt; Aug. 1 Articles Articles Hartinton Articles Maxwell . Amend't Superior ... Articles Doniphan </seg>
            <seg id="p053">EPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE iaCILLAHI«Vf CORPORATIONS- (Continued) -IP I1T V1HC ( irticli irticli irticl i'a i,\nxi i hi. •l_-\ TJ s )m ha JU,UIK&gt; in ha ij.uuu .\c rt )« a i»u,uuu uei nrmpriv KeMntre Harvf tin ; \i ,(«ai,uuu jan. 100,000 Jan. n^r^l Milling imen' imeni Vrtitl lill^i] iui .uiiiiii^ \_/vj Ideal Cement Stone Co [dlewild Farm Co Instantaneous Freezer Indestructible Loose Le t na rei !00,000 Ml nt &amp; Arti&lt; ( &gt;u t \nxt .^p i: \rti' &lt; iii,i»hj cnay t Articles Huroi ._ .■".m hi may ■ iww Ord r ws Buildi IK ' Articl n, ; ai .t t \nnj j ._ Articl Articl I r,,«... iTui o,;i, n ,j ,.),I«J*I A I P La r Amend't Cedar R'ds, ,\OV. 18 VJW Arti iu,mm .\ov. .;'.i ia»f Articles Spence II nterstate Brewii r»anv of Articles ()mah 1U,UUO Ui IO,OOOiJa .. Art () . Amend't Stuai :i ' Li iihi,ixx) re .. Articles Red i,."Hiu »-\pr. o in i 3. Artie' O nar - 1" I Ar n; . 1 ... Articles Oma i , .Apr. ind of Author- nstru- Place of ized When nent Business Capital Filed ck a rvpstpi sta, Me &lt;&gt;: raska •ewin? Coi 1U,UUU Lit Inters The Ir : Auto Rec miu »-\pr. 1 1&lt; i,)U,uuuApr. iu i»j ... Amend't Stuai ... Amend't Omal </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 MISCELLANEOUS &lt; OKIOK VT1OW . ( ontiniu-d i Kind of Author- CORPORATK NAME ized \V Independent Lumber Co Article 0 1 50,000 M Independent Telephone Co Article International Railroa Auto matic Safety Pipe Coup ling Co Artid. .'oo.ooo Independent Cand Arti&lt; 5,000 A Independent Co-operative ,000 A Amend't Omaha 100,000 Mar. 12 ( Jefferson County Ban Apr Ks Merry Mixer A; Nuv r Co Articles South Omaha 100,000 M 1 Articles () m aha .. "..000 Tulv tnal-Stockman Co s-Gettier Motor Co.... ) Journal-Tribunal Articles Line &gt;ln .'VOOO D Printing Cc Articles Tecumseh 75,000 D&lt; 1 Johnson &amp; Lau Company Articles i Omaha 10,000 Feb. Johnson Grain Co Articles Johnson &gt;.000 Mar. Freytag \- Co... . Articles Odell ISJMMJ Johnson Lamp Co Article? Omaha IfluOOOA Johnstown Lumber Co Articles Johnstown .'..000 A James Coal Co Articles Omaha '30,000 0 Joslin-Axtell Lumber Co Articles Pairbun 50,000 Nov. 21 1 Katz-Craig Construction Co. Kauf &amp; Rinderspacher Co... Klinzman (The) Manufactur 60,000 I :,o.(hmi I ing Co Articles Kearney .'",.000 Feb. Kilgore State Bank Articles Kilgore 30,000 Feb. 2" Katz-Craig Construction Co. (now Katz-Craig Con tracting I Amend't Omaha Mar. I ne Irrigation Co : &gt;&lt;)• Instru- Plac ment ; Bull tCo... Articles j S ational Pineapple Sy- Co Eston Electric Co. (for- rly Western Electrical - baon ft Furen Co Article* South Omaha 25,000 Mar. Amend't; [) a Johnson, L. A., C( Auto (/■ Amend' t Bet Amend't Sou Articli Ar*icl&lt; ; * one Lumber Co Amend' t LouuCitv l *&gt;Q 000 \Iar </seg>
            <seg id="p055">• :. I1S( H.LWtOI S (UKFUKATIONS i ( ontinued) Cind Vutho .■i.nroRATE XAMK Ins: Place of ized \Y1 nent Ru 'apital Ciplinger &amp; Doherty Co Articles 00 Ms 'he) Artie 00,000 Ms Kearney Lumber &amp; Coal Co. Articles K. 0,000 Ap Irti Kilpatrick Brc k'limfnt Mprr: Vr «O A\ Vn IK),(MK) .\\ " (.500 l)t \m !.V).000 l)e Vrticles West Point.. 30,000 De :.,000 l)e Tplpnhnne Co Articles M &gt; r The i Kean Hardware Co Articles Ravenn.i 15,000 Pel i t I) Articles Keith To 1.400 I At .\ &lt;m Ma i.', Articles Nebr. (V u 1 Art Kennedy Investment Co Articles i A Cearnev Baseball &amp; At! i Articles Kearney !■ i. Ar i. \ V i \ Articles j Bloomington ISO July 1"&gt; It ISO " k'pv-c l.iimhpr i \ , A 25,000 Articles | Omaha 10,000 Juh Kimball Laundry Co Articles Omaha "0.000 Aug. 4 II Knaoo Grain Co Arti Articles - Mt. Clan :.-.,000 Apr. July Vrti&lt; &gt;0,000 A I \ I. fv \rti IK) A 10,000 M Kent &amp; Burke Co Articles Geaoa VtO,000 July Kimball, F. J. ft Co Amend't Omaha Aug. 4 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 MISOELLANEOl'S ('OKI'OKATIOMS— (Continued) T Kind of Author- CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed ment Stock Klopp &amp; Redfield Building Co Articles Omaha $100,000 Nov. 18 1910 250,000 Dec. 2 1908 100,000 Dec. 8 1908 25,000 Dec. 17 1908 50,000;Dec. 21 1908 1,000 Dec. 20 1908 5,000|Dec. 23 1908 1 Lion Bonding &amp; Surety Co. Amend't Omaha Lungren, G. E., Co Articles Wausa Limited Lyceum Bureau Articles Lincoln Lisco Mercantile Co Articles Gowanda Lost Creek Telephone Co Kansas Leo. Baroch, Inc Articles Omaha Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele- graph Co Articles Lincoln 2,500,000 Jan. 2 1909 100,000 Jan. 4 1909 25,000;Jan. 6 1909 25,OOOj Jan. 18 1909 50,000 Jan. 18 1909 50,000 Jan. 19 1909 Jan. 28 1909 100,000 Feb. 9 1909 Feb. 20 MM 100,00(1 Feb. :.'(i MM 1,000 Feb. 20 1909 Feb. 26 1909 25,000 Mar. I 100,000 May If) l'.*&gt;9 lO.OOOjApr. 7 1909 3,000|Apr. 10 1909 10,000 Apr. 12 190(1 25,000 Apr. 17 MM 10,000 Apr. 24 1909 10,000,May 10 1909 1,000 June 10 1909 June 17 1909 25,000 June 20 1909 15,000 June 26 1909 2,500,000 Jan. 100,000 Jan. S La Tour Land &amp; Cattle Co.... Articles Deuel County 4 Loretto State Bank Articles I Loretto 25,000 Jan. Lincoln Barb Wire Wire Reel Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Jan. 50,000 Jan. 50,000 Jan. is is in M n I Lincoln Lister &amp; Plow Co.... Articles Lincoln Lawrence State Bank Articles i Lawrence l.aflin Drug Co Amend't VVymore Liver (C. B.) &amp; Co., Inc Articles Omaha Loup City State Bank Amend't Loup City M Lamoreaux &amp; Peterson Co .... Articles Omaha Lincoln (The) Cleaning and Dye Works Articles Lincoln 20 Liver (C. B.) &amp; Co., Inc., (now Liver, C. B., &amp; Co.). Amend't M I z Long Pine Investment Co Articles Long Pine Lincoln Implement &amp; Trans- fer Co Amend't Lincoln 16 Laurel Mutual Telephone Co Articles Laurel 10,000 Apr. 3,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 10,000Mav 1,000 June Latin (The) Co Articles Omaha 10 Lincoln Base Ball Club Articles Lincoln 12 Lisco State Bank Articles Lisco IT Land Title Co Articles I Omaha 24 Lodge Pole Telephone Co Articles Lodge Pole Law (The) and Order League Articles Smithfield 10 10 Lueben-Baler Co Amend't Beatrice June 17 Lyons Independent Tele- phone Co Articles Lyons 25,000 June 15,000 June LeBlanc Mercantile Co Articles Oxford Leo Grotte Manufacturing vsO. Articles v/iii diici • </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 57 MISCELLAXKOI'S ( OHI'OlM Tl»»\s ( i.ntinued) Kind of Instru - ment Author CORPORATE KAMI Place of ized When Business Capital Filer! Stock Luther Academy er College) (now Luth- Amend't VVahoo Amend't Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Waho I Lynch &amp; Co Amend't Omaha 20.000 Aug. n Omaha Lincoln Lincoln Grain Exchange Articles Lincoln -2r,,mu) Aug. 2.1 1909 (The) A. C. Lederman Co Articles Grand Island 10.000 Sep. 1 Grand Island Lincoln . Lincoln Securities Co Articles Lincoln IS^MI N Lincoln Transfer Co Articles Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Transfer &amp; Storage Co. (formerly Lincoln Transfer Co.) Amend't Lincoln .-,0,000 \ toln Transfer &amp; Storage (formerly Lincoln ansfer Co.) Amen t Lincoln 50,000 N'ov Lincoln (The) Spreader Man - ufacturing Co Articles Lincoln .-,0,000 V 50,000 Nov. Lincoln, Capital Beach Milford Railway Co Articles Lincoln .... .•-,. \ 25,000 N'ov 20 Louisiana (The) Coloniza tion Co Articles Central City 1 -.0,000 Dec. 4 1909 150,000 Dec. 4 z Lithuanian Home Society, \rticles South Omaha Dec 7 1909 Dec (The) Lodge Pole Telephom Co Vrticles Lodge Pole 10.000 Dec. 29 1909 10.000 Dec. 25,000 Dec. 20.000 Feb. 30,000 Feb. 20 LoveHaskell Co. Articles Omaha .-.itOODec. ::■■ 30 Lisco Irrigation Co Article- .'o.ooo Feb. |i II) 15 (The) Lindahl Mercantile Co. Articles Oakland o.iMtO Feb. ! Es) Lindahl Mercantile Co. oln (The) Commercial ub Building Assn Lincoln (The) Commercial Club Building Assn Articles Lincoln 1 :&gt;O,ono Feb. 17 1910 Articles Articles Lincoln Gretna 150,000 Feb. 25,000 Feb. 17 l'.l Langdon &amp; Stahl Co Articles Gretna . 'no Feb. 1 Lexington Co-operative Creamery &amp; Cold Storage Co Articles Lexington 10,000 Feb. I Lexington 10,000 Feb. Long Pine and Southern Telephone Co Articles Long Pine 10,000 Mar. H Articles Articles Long Pine Hastings 10,000 Mar. 25,000 Apr. 31 z Lawson, C. K., Hardware Co. Articles Hasting- HiJUtO Apr. I awson, C. K., Hardware Co. incoln Typewriter Ex - change Co incoln Hardware Co.... incoln Accident Insurance 12 Lincoln Typewriter B change Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Apr. 13 1910 L Articles Articles Lincoln Lincoln z Lincoln Hardware Co Articles Lincoln. : , r . u l'HO I Lincoln Accident Insurance Co Articles Lincoln "■".""" Apr. 23 1910 Articles Articles Articles Lincoln Omaha Land Holding Co Articles Omaha IMHApr. 30 1910 Long Pine Land ft Stock Co. Articles Long Pine __. 25,000 May 3 1910 Land A S 11 (The) Hotel C Long Pine Lincoln Lindell (The) Hotel Articles Lincoln 300,000 May 26 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF THK SECRETARY OF STATK Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Lincoln Live Stock &amp; Land Co Lincoln Lincoln f .VUMK) May Lincoln Land Co June Leshara Farmers Elevator Co. Articles Articles Articles Leshara Leigh ... 10,00» June 50,000 June 50,000 June 15 i Leigh State Bank Loxseal Barrel Head Co Lincoln Telephone &amp; Tele Amend't Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Lincoln graph Co 2,500,000 June 20 1010 Lakeside Ranch Co Lincoln Crockery Co Central City Lincoln 25,000 July 12 1910 Lost Creek Telephone Co..._ Lincoln Investment Co Lincoln Steam Bakery Lincoln Commission Co (The) Lincoln Steam Paste Lincoln Lincoln 25,000 Oct Co. Lincoln Lincoln 25,000 Nov. 500,000 Xov. 3 % Lincoln Paint &amp; Color Co.... Live Stock Loan &amp; Trust 12 Co. Mark Hansen Realty Co. Masonic Temple Craft McCoun (L. B.) Co Midway Gas Co Maverick Loan &amp; Trust Co. Maiden Investment Co Morrill Countv Reservoir Co. Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Mercedes Plaiter Co Marsh A Marsh Morningside Land Co Marsland State Bank MeCook (The) Brick Co Martin Luther College of the Western District of the Evangelical-Lutheran Sy - nod of Iowa, and other states, at Sterling, N'ebr .. Mutual Interest Club (The) E MISCELLANEOUS ('OKrOKATH»K— (Continued) Amend't Amend't 11 1010 Fremont 100,000 Aug. 17 1910 Hloomington 1,000 Sep. 13 1910 Lincoln io,oooSep. 2 Lincoln 25,000 Oct. 13 1910 Amend't Amend't Articles South Omaha 25,000 Nov. 30 1910 Articles Omah;i 1 :&gt;0,000 Dec. .1 I '.mis Amend't McCook 45,000 Dec. 10 1MB Amend't Omaha Dec. 17 1908 Articles Kearney 7"i,000 Dec. :.'() l'.xi- Amend't Rushville Dec. » Articles Omaha ."&gt;&lt; 1,000 Dec. v Bridgeport 2.1.000 Jan. 0 10(»".i Grand Island 10,000 Jan. 13 1909 Omaha 10,000 Feb. Omaha .-.0.000 Feb. Marsland .... 10.000 Feb. 16 1909 ■2.1.000 Feb. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">1 OF THK SKCKKTARY OF . REPOR MIS( -ELLA&gt;i:oi S I Ol:i OIMIIONS Mc.nUnu.d Kind of I Autho Instru- Place of ized Whei Instru- Place of Wr merit Bu Fi! I \f:ir -, KK&gt; / • A AS! I ir. fi 1001 Paint Co Ar Arti. Martin ft Martin, Printers. . Amend') :ite Tungsten Lamp C^ •s-Oberhes D&lt; Articles Rethanv ln.iifHi Ma and Telephone O Articles Chappell 'I .tthew-Littell Co. Artii Mattnew ■Tlintock Hotel Co Article! , r . ; ioo.oooM key Milling Co Amend't Elkhorn JCOOCTMar. 31 Articles Omaha \or. l loo-.i M i Articles Red Cloi; v ooo Apr M .\i Assn. Articles Central City -&gt;0.000 Apr. - v Exchange Bank Amend't Minden SO.OOOiApr. 18 1909 \l Bond &amp; \rticles Omaha mi.ikm) Apr. 23 1909 \rticles (&gt;• kit -\pr. : Vmend't Lincoln V)0,00( Apr. ' ■ Pai Articles Omaha l 1909 Morns Hri Articles Blair 1909 Vn Articles Bridgeport "i.OfK) Tune l it u- arquette Elevator Co Articles I Marque tti » ii Jiddle West Elevator Co Articles Omaha Lrticles Malcolm t.ixin Aug. INN) An* ,i TT •0 maha Seo. 10 1MB imend't Lrticles lrticles articles • •:■: .000 ?«D. 21 1909 1' UMMM\f:ir ". IMMI M.iv 14 IMS </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE ■I8CELLANEOU8 ( ORI'OR ATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When Business Capital Filed ment Stock Modern Woodmen of Amer- Articles ica Amend't Rk. Island 111 Oct. (The) Marsh-Burke Co Amend't Lincoln Oct. IS IMS (The) Melcher-Schmidt Drug Co Articles Omaha 25,000. Oct. 12 (The) Motorist Publishing Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Oct. 2" Mountain Timber Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Oct. 20 1909 Melcher (The) Drug Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Nov. 10 1909 McSweeney (The) Land Co. Articles Ainsworth ... 10,000 Mov. :.'4 1908 Manhattan Oil Company of Nebraska ..: Articles Omaha 100,000 Xov. 2". Mockett (E. E.) Automobile Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Dec. 21 Marsh (W. W.) Estate and Trust Co Articles Omaha '. 25,000 Dec. 311900 Mountain Timber Co Amend't Omaha 500,000 Jan. 11 nun McCoun (B. L.) Co Amend't Omaha 30,000 Jan. 14 1910 The Milan Medical Co Articles Omaha 1,000 Jan. 15 1010 Merchants State Bank Amend't Winside Ijan. 17 1910 Martell Telephone Co Articles Martell 1 "..000. Jan. 19 1910 (The) McCook Telephone Co. Articles McCook 10,000 Jan. 28 1910 Mitchell Alfalfa Milling &amp; Light Co Amend't Mitchell 30,000 Jan. 311910 The Marsland Club Articles Marsland 600 Feb. 7 1910 The Farmers Mutual Insur ante Co. (now Mutual In surance Co.i jAmend't Aurora Feb. 11 HH0 McLaughlin Bros, (formerly Nebraska Lumber and Coal Co.) Amend't Lincoln |Feb. lfi kmo Monroe-Lilly Engine Co Articles i Omaha 100,000:Feb. 2r. 1910 *&gt;.-. (The) Midwest Printing Co Articles I York 10,000 Mar. 23 1910 (The) Masonic Temple Craft Assn Articles Callaway j 10,000|Mar. 25 1910 McAllister Bros Articles Cairo 50,000Mar. 29 1910 McCaffrey Bros. Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Mar. 29 1910 Meadow Grove State Bank. ...Amend't Meadow G've Apr. 7 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THK ShX'HETARY OF STATE 61 USCELLANEOUS (MUI'OK \ I IONS i ( «mtiiiii&lt; d . Kindo Instru ment Author ORPOBATE NAMF Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Amend Article Friend Lincoln t Merchants Supply C Articl Alliance 30,000 Apr Blring (The) Rosa Live ock Co Amend Article Article Article Amend Article Article t Alliance Lewellen Omaha . .10,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. 20,000 May Meeker Ditch Mansfield Mercantile ( Winnebago Mason Cit; Omaha t Marvel Manufacturing Crawford Ainsworth Lincoln .10,000 May- t ' .10,000 June t Omaha Amend Article Article Article Article t Omaha 200,000 July 10.000 July 10.000 July Mid-West Aviation Meet Omaha « Murphy . Omaha .. Omaha E&gt;hy Lumber &amp; Coal Co suri Valley Elevator Co iam A Millard C hants Syndicate Cata 200.000 Aug. 100,000 Aug. Articles Articles Articles Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Lincoln Mullen Omaha Murphy Did It 'rist Publishing C Meier Drug Co Kens Business Men's Club I Mutual Club Bra ska City Speed ( thwestern Fruit C Merchants &amp; Farmers Bank $ :u&gt;.oo&lt;) Apr. -'"i.ixhi Apr. Kring (The) Rosa Live &gt;ck Co Miiler-Cooper &amp; in Citv Banking ( May 50,000 May T.1,000 May Kison Lumber Co Arti son (The) &amp; Howe Mer cantile Co Arti Miller &amp; Paine Amend't l.ooo.ooo May IfcCook Irrigation &amp; Water Power Co Amend Melcher (C. A.) Drug C (formerly Melcher-Schmidt Drug Co.) Amend Miller. Stewart &amp; Beaton &gt;rmerlv Miller, Stew r Beaton Carpet &amp; Furniture Co.) 55 """ log( 50.000 Aug. 11 10,000 Nov. I 1 1.1.0O0 \'ov. 17 1910 83,00 2"&gt;.000 \'"- 1.000 N'ov. If .VK),000 No 10,000 Dec. 1 1906 100.000 Dec. 1 1908 Marion Automobi Xebr. City Omaha . National Lumber, Box &amp; Parka (re Co Articles </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 CORPORA']! Place of Business National Reference and In - vestment Co Omah $100.0(K, Dc Nebraska Home Building &amp; Loan Assn Articles Articles Beatrice Oxford . 200,000 Feb 19 \W Norman Mercanti! 10,000 Feb. 23 l'JO 1 Nebraska Conference Associ - ation of the Seventh-day Adventists Amend't Hasting Nebraska Trust &amp; Savings Bank Waho North Clear Creek Telephone Co Articles Articles Ansle Nebraska Kennel Club Omaha North Platte Gas &amp; Electric Co Articles North PI itte North Platte Chautauqua Co Articles North PI atte Nebraska Live Stock Owners Protective Assn Articles Nebraska Association Public Accountants... Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Omah Nebraska Lumber &amp; Coal Co. 1 Nebrska Stone Co Omaha Lincoln Nenzel Nebraska Trust Co Nenzel Mutual Telephone Co. 1,000 Apr North Bend Cement Tile Mfg. Co Articles Articles Articles 10,000 Apr. 20,000 May 100,000 Mav New Ideal Laundrv Ct North Platte Telephone Co. North Platte Mill and Grain Co Articles Articles Articles North PI Norfolk Sioux F'l ,000 Ma atte Norfolk (The) Countrv Club 15,000 June 20 1!X 25,000 June 20 VM Northwestern Electric Co SD ?o Nebraska Furniture &amp; Car - pet Co Articles Articles Omaha 100,000 June 24 190* 45,000 July 14 1W Nebraska City Gas Cc Nebr. Cit News-Herald (The) Publish ing Co Articles Articles Plattsmouth Omah: ,000 July ,000 Julv National Brokerage C Nebraska Culvert and Manu Waho&lt; 31 MISCELLANEOUS ( OKPOKATIONS (( ontinuedt Kind of Instru- ment Author- ized When Capital Filed Stock Articles Articles Xorfolk North Bend. Lincoln Xorth Platte </seg>
            
            <seg id="p063">MISCELLANEOUS COBPOBATIOW8 -(( ontinnedi Kind of Kind of Instru - ment Author CORPORATK nwmk Instru Place of ized When CORPORATK NAM I Place ment i Business Capital Filed Busines Stock Cew Hope Association of General Baptists Articles Rock and New Hope Association Bapt Article Rock and neighboring counties, neighboring counties, Nebrask Nebraska K western (The) Invest t and Trust Co Northwestern (The) Invest - ment and Trust Co Articles Aurora "&gt; Aug. 17 1909 "i Aug Arti Aurora 17 1909 \orth Western Construction Wahpeton, Company of Dakota Articles N. I) .'.-..imhi A:. h We mpar ist Dakota Arti Nebraska Business Men's Assn. Articles Omaha Aug. 26 1909 Men 1 H Omaha 26 1909 Assn Article I The) Nebraska Buick Auto - mobile Co Articles Lincoln 100,000 Sep. 14 19O9 Buick Auto The) NeV Articles Lincoln Telephone Co. Articles Atkinson 100,000 Sep. ») Sep. H1909 21 1909 mob Northwestern Telephone Co. Articles Atkinson -.'..ioo Sep. 21 1909 Northw Nebraska Cream Co. (for - mrly Edmunds Cream Co.) Amend't Central I 1909 r tly Edmunds Cream Co.) Amend't Centra oik Ice Cream and Cone 29 1 '.HW N'orfolk Ice Cream and Cone Co Articles Norfolk 10,0 '.1909 Ik Mutual Relief Assn. Articles Norfolk ka Investment Co Articles Mason City. 100.000 Nov. I Articles N 25 1909 Kolk Mutual Relief Assn. Articles Norfolk aska Investment Co Articles Mason City 100.0O' Nebraska Concrete Re-inforc - ing Co. (now Nebraska Re-infor w Nebraska Amend't I Omaha Martin.. Article? Omaha Nebraska Drain Tile Co Articles Tekamah 7.-.,000 Nov. 16 1909 Drain Tile Co Articles I Tekamah North Nebraska Annual inference of the Metho dist Episcopl Church Articles I 1 ■aska (The) Puncture ,f Co Articles ! Omaha 'r..ooo P North Nebraska Annual ch Articl Puncture ,f Co Articles Omaha e Niemann, Carl J. &amp; Bros, (formerly Krage-Elliott emann, Carl T. &amp; Bro Amend't Omaha 100,000 Jan. 1 Nebraska Farmer Co Amend't Lincoln 100,000 Jan. ■ Newcastle and Dixon Tele - phone Co Articles Newcastle 2,000 Feb. Nebrska Suspender Factory Articles Kearnev l ,.000 Feb. 2» 1910 v Turner Co Articles Omaha MM** th Platte Valley Chau- </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS ( OKPORATIO\S ■-(( ontinuedi Kind of Author- CoKI'oRATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock Articles Lincoln .. Northwestern Coal Co $25,000 Mar. 28 lino National Reliable Commod - ities Co Articles Omaha ... ,000 Mar. 31 1910 Neal Institute Company of Nebraska Articles Omaha ... Articles 100,000 Apr. North (The) Star, Sheridan and Curtis Telephone Co.... Articles Curtis 10,000 Apr. 11 1910 Nebraska (The) Isle of Pines Co Articles Grand Is Articles Articles Grand Island Omaha 100,000 Apr. 15,000 May 20 lino 2 1910 National Corn Assn Articles Omaha ... Nebraska (The) Managers Assn. Articles Tekamah 1,000 Mav 11 1910 National Printing Co Amend't Omaha ... .-.,000 May 5,000 ' n i9io Articles Hastings National Perch Co. (Inc.). Northwestern State Bank u loin Amend't Hay Spri Hay Springs 50,000 May 26 I ii 10 Nebraska Portland Cement Co Articles Superior ,200,000 J une 1 Nebraska Brick and Tile Co. Articles Tekamah Articles Articles 300,000 June ,200,000 1 une 4 1910 Niobrara Investment Co Articles Omaha 1 10 1010 Nebraska City Base Ball Club Articles Xebr. Cii Articles Articles Nebr. City Lincoln 5,000 June 10,000 June 20 1910 28 1910 Nebrska (The) Silo Co Articles Lincoln .. Nebraska Hardwood Timber Co Articles Lincoln .. Articles 25,000 Julv 22 1010 Nebraska (The) Co-Opera tive Mercantile Assn Articles South Or Articles Articles South Omaha Belgrade 10,000 July 200,000 July Nebraska Land &amp;• Cattle Co. Articles Belgrade 28 1910 Nellie Fontaine Memorial Methodist Episcopal Church Articles Articles Bertrand Aug. : s Naponee State Bank Amend't Amend't Xaponee 25,000 Aug. Norfolk Oil &amp; Chemical Works Articles Articles Norfolk 25,000 Aug. 50,000 Aug. 1,000 Aug. 10 1910 National Fur &amp; Taning Co. Articles Articles Omaha _ North Pole Club Articles Articles Omaha „ 30 1910 14 ,010 20 1010 Niobrara Investment Co Amend't Amend't Omaha Sep. Northwestern Securities Co. Articles Articles Omaha .. 100,000 Sep. Nebraska Hydraulic Stone p_ . ... </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 65 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued I Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Nebraska (The) Sanitarium and Benevolent Assn Amend't College Vie Amend Article t College View Lincoln Oct. Nebraska Medical College ... Articles Lincoln Nebraska Medical College... Nebraska Macaroni Manu 10,000 Oct. 17 Nebraska Macaroni Manu - facturing &amp; Selling Co Articles Omaha Article Omaha 10.000 Oc t Nebraska Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church Articles Uni. PI Nebraska Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Chun Uni. Plac« Oct. Oct. Nebraska Telephone Co Amend't .Omah.: Nebraska Telephone Co Amend't. Omaha 31 (The) North Bend Automo - bile Co Articles North Benc The) North Bend Au Arti North Bend 000 Oct. Nebraska Tire Apparatus Co Articles Omah, Nebraska Tire Apparatu Arti Omaha Nebraska Drain Tile Co.... Dissolu- ebraska Drain Tile Co.... Dissolt tion Tekamah .... Nemaha Valley Drainage District \emaha Cc Jan. 28 S Odell Lumber Co Articles Odell 15,000 Dec. 150,000,Dec. Omaha Brick Co Amend't Omah. ; 4 Omaha Heavy Hardware Co Articles Omaru. Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Omaha Omaha Omaha 100,000 Dec. .10,000 Jan. 10,000 Jan. 25.000 Feb. 10,000 Feb. 18 Omaha Trunk Factory Articles Omaha taha Trunk Factory aha Lighting Fixture Co. OstranSmith Lumber Co Omaha Wrecking Co Omaha Lumber and Coal Omaha Lighting Fixture Co. Articles Omah,! Ostran-Smith Lumber Co Articles Havel Havelock Omaha ... Omaha Wrecking Co Articles Omaha * Omaha Lumber and Coal Co _. Articles Omah . Omaha 100,000 Feb. is Omaha Bridge &amp; Terminal Co Amend't Omah. Omaha Bridge &amp; Terminal Mar. Omaha Ord 13 Ord Milling Co Articles Ord 25.000 Mar 13 Omaha Electrical Exposi - tion Articles Omah. 5,000 Mar S Kaha Automobile Co..._ Amend't Omaha aha Elks Building Co Amend't Omaha adi Co-operative Grain Apr. B 110,000 Apr. 12 Articles Articles Articles Articles Homer Omaha Omaha Omaha 10,000 May :»,000 July 40,000 July 100,000 July 2fi I Raha Railway Club, aha Wall Paper Cc Orchard ft Wilhelm C Oberton Mercantile C&lt; 12 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 66 MISCELL.WEOUS (ORrOKATIO&gt;S— (Continued) Kind of Author CORPORATE NAME j Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock Omaha Alfalfa Milling Co Articles Omaha $100,000 Aug M Omaha (The) Mutual Realty Co : Articles Omaha Omaha t&amp;JBOO Sep ? 5,001 1 Omaha Warehouse Co Amend't (The) Omaha Plaining Mill Co Articles Omaha l :&gt;.ooo Oct. 12 Osceola Construction Co Articles Lincoln 300,000 Oct. "I, ":,.0&gt;" ( let. -M \&lt;&gt;v. H Oakland State Bank Articles Oakland Overton (The) State Bank .Amend't Overton Omaha Omaha Stove Repair Works Amend't Omaha Safe Deposit &amp; Trust Co Amend't Omaha H0O.0O0 Nov. lfi 2.5(K) N I 10.000 Dei-. 14 800.000 N'OV ir&gt; Omaha Automobile Show Assn Articles Omaha 2,500 Xov Omaha Saengerfest Associa- tion Articles Omaha Omaha Omaha (The) Ink Co (Articles 35,000 De. Orleans Electric Light &amp; Power Co i Articles Orleans 10,000 Dec. O'Malley-Gallagher Hard ware Co Articles Greelev C"nt'r 20.000 Jan. Omaha Rendering &amp; Feed Co Articles Omaha 150.000 Jan. Omaha Yeast and Vinegar Manufacturing Co Articles Omaha 2.»,000 Jan. 20 Omaha Cement &amp; Paving Co. (formerly Beebe Ce- ment &amp; Paving Co.) Amend't Omaha Lincoln Omaha Feb. 0 E Orcutt, J. C. &amp; Co Articles 10.000 Feb. 0 Omaha Theatrical Club Articles Mar Omaha Posten Publication Co j Amend't Omaha Mar Osmond (The) Farmers Grain and Livestock Assn.Articles Osmond 25,000 Mar Octavia Lumber &amp; Grain Co Articles Octavia 20.000 Mar § Olson Photo Machine Co....) Articles Plattsmouth 25,000 Apr. •&gt; Orchard (The) Homes Co lArticles Lincoln 10,000 Apr. Oshkosh (The) Social Club. JArticles Oshkosh 500 Apr. lfi </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 67 MIS&lt; KLLANEOUS Kind of CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME ORATENAME Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Piled Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Stock Omaha Automatic Shoe Shining Co Automatic Shoe Do Articles Omaha $ Apr. 20 1910 Articles Articles Articles Omaha Omaha Omaha I Apr. 10,000 Apr. 100,000 Apr. 20,9,0 28 1910 30 ,9,0 Omaha (The) Can C le) Can Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Apr. 28 1910 Orcutt, F. H. &amp; Son, Co H. &amp; Son, Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Apr. 30 1910 Omaha Secret Service Detec - tive Agency ret Service Detec- ncy Articles Omaha Articles Amend't Omaha Omaha May 24 1910 Omaha Grain Exchange ain Exchange Amend't Omaha ;i)0,000 May 24 1910 200,000 May Biha (The) Traction and anufacturing Co ie) Traction and uring Co Articles Douglas Co., Articles Douglas Co, Omaha Omaha .. Omaha _ Omaha 100,000 June 2 1910 100,000 June 25,000 July 200,000 July 10,000 July 8 1910 Eha Speedway Co.... ski Motor Car Co ha Motor Club ha Senic Company edway Co Articles Omaha 25,000 July 7 1910 Articles Articles Articles Articles &gt;tor Car Co Articles Omaha 200,000 July 8 1910 tor Club Articles Omaha 10,000 July 14 1010 Omaha Omaha 22 1910 ic Company Articles Omaha 6,000 July 22 1910 6,000 July Omaha (The) Street Sweep - ing and Cleaning Machine ie) Street Sweep- cleaning Machine Articles Omaha 200,000 Aug. 5 1910 Articles Omaha 200,000 Aug. 5 19,0 Omaha Rod &amp; Gun Club, &gt;d &amp; Gun Club, Amend't Omaha Aug. 8 1910 Amend't Omaha Aug. 8 1910 Kha (The) Automatic y Stacker and Imple - nt Co Fhe) Automatic cker and Imple- Articles Omaha 200,000 Aug. 30 1910 200,000 Aug. antile Co Amend't Obert Aug. 31 1910 Kt Mercantile Co to State Bank ite Bank Amend't Oconto 25,000 Sep. 7 1910 25,000 Sep. DSten Publishing Amend't Omaha !0,000Sep. 13 1910 Omaha Posten Publishing Cr Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha 10,000 Sep. 20.000 Oct. 10,000 N'ov. 50,000 Nov. ■; s Eha Machine Works ha Corrugated Box Co. ha Base Ball Club ha Wholesale Grocery .chine Works Articles Omaha 20,000 Oct. 1 rrugated Box Co. Articles Omaha 10,000 Nov. 7 1910 se Ball Club Articles Omaha 50,000 Nov. 7 1910 holesale Grocery : Articles Omaha 5,000 Nov. 14 1910 Co. Articles Omaha 5,000 Nov. 14 ,910 Omaha Taxicab &amp; Auto Liv - ery Co cicab &amp; Auto Liv- Articles Omaha M,000:N&lt;n ti Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha H. &amp; Son, Co Amend't Omaha 150,000 Nov. 24 1910 Co Articles Omaha 75.000 Nov. 30 1910 Orcutt, F. H. &amp; Son, Co Omaha Oil Co t Factorv Articles Omaha r.,000Nov. 29 1910 Kha Hat Factory eer Realtv Co altv Co Amend't Omaha Dec. 19 1908 Kte Valley Alfalfa Mill f Co Articles Articles Brule 25,000 Dec. 3, ,908 PhelanShirley Co Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Co. (now Partridge-Thomp - son Co.) Amend't Articles Omaha Omaha July Peters-Edholm Co 100.000 July Pinkerton Manufacturing Co. (now Queen Incubator Co.) Amend't Articles Lincoln 100,000 Aug. 25,000 Aug. :s Pool Stock C Broadwater 19 Parlin &amp; Orendorff Plow Company of Omaha \rticles I Omaha lOOOOOSpn ° iqoq o ■ REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued Kind of Author- CORPOBATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When ! ment Business Capital Filed Stock Powell Supply Co. (formerly Powell Automobile Co.)... Amend't Omaha - Ian. 14 IMt Palmer Wheelock Enter- P rise c ' Articles Beatrice io.ooo Tan. M UN Pierce County Bank Amend't pi erce :tO,OOOjan. M People State Bank Articles y e nang.. 10,000 Jan. 2S Pettit Cabinet &amp; Fixture Co. Amend't Lincoln 15,000 Feb Power-Heafey Coal Co. (formerly Omaha Coal &amp; Building Supply Co.) Amend't Omaha ! .)&gt;. 2 1909 Peoples Ice &amp; Coal Co. (now Peoples Ice ft Cold Storage Co - Amend't Omaha Mar. 4 MM Platte Valley Cattle Co Articles Gothenburg :(00.000 Apr. 24 1909 Pantel Realty Co Articles Omaha 10.000 Apr. "- Peoples Telephone Exchange Articles Gordon 4,(HKtMay l MM Perfection Harness &amp; Tug Buckle Co Articles Blair 10,000 Platte (The) Real Estate Co. Articles Omaha 25,000 May 22 1909 Parker-Shaw (The) Co Amend't Omaha M Peoples State Bank Articles Arnold .-..iK)0june I Platte Long Distance Co Articles Schuyler 100.000 June I Parlor Furniture ft Mat- tress C- Amend't Fremont 25.OOO June 28 1909 Platte County Independent Telephone Co Amend't Platte Co 100,000 July 5 MM Parkway Real Estate Co Amend't Omaha 10,000 July I Provident Real Estate Co. ... Amend't Omaha 10,000 July 6 1909 Peoples Saving Bank Articles Hartington :&gt;0.000 July 6 1909 Prudential Real Estate Co.. . Amend't 10,000 July 6 1909 Partridge, Shelly, Thompson ,::= </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 69 MISCELLANEOUS COKI'ORATIOSS— (Continued. Kindo Instru ment Author CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Piled Stock Co. (for nt Health Amend Lincoln Sep 13 ash Arti Hasting 13 e (The) B s M Article Shelton 25,000 Sep. 21 Amend Article Article t Omaha . Palisade I Hemingford Omah Arti Platte Long D n A Suth Amend t .i T Columbus Paxt Oct. Article phor 5.000 ( )ct. Platte Countv Agricultura Arti Humphrey Omaha _ 0 N'nv 12,000 Nov 1 s Article Artilce Bn Amusement ;te Center Mil ton and Elsie Platte Center 23 ing Telephone Article Amend Pax ton Omaha 5,000 Nov 300,000 Dec. 29 s Peters, M. C, Mi Producers Cons t 13 ited Oil Article Article Lincoln . Lincoln . Kimhall 500,000 Dec. Phoenix (The) Brotherhood 1,000 Dec. 5,000 Jan. Pioneer Land ( Article Payne, Bostwick &amp; Slater rmerly Pavne. Bostwick Amend' Article . Jan. wick A is z Peru State Bank 25,000 Feb. B mt Store Article Amend 50,000 Feb. 25,000 Feb. 11 Z IS Peoples Telephone Exchange 8,000 Feb. 17 1910 Assn Amend' Amend Article Amend t 20,000 Feb Eeer (The) Lumber C( rsnn Brothers &amp; C( iles Bank of Xaper Tessive Club t Coleridge Aurora ... 18 1910 25,000 Feb. Feb 28 1910 t Xaper Ieer Insuran&lt; rly Endown Accident Asi Krs Burglar I k Co. tile Co Patton-Bowman Hardware Sep. 24 15,00. •_&gt;.-&gt;.i&gt;00 Oct. 1 io,oon.Oct. 9 Bsae Lumber ( &gt;les (The) Bai lam Co 18 .«• 20 1909 nun t ( imaha Kles Depar ipbell ; &gt;er . ... !es Bank of Xaper </seg>
            <seg id="p070">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 70 MIS&lt; ELLANEOIS ( Kind of ORPORATIONS— (( ontinnrdl Author- Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME iBATE name Instru- pi aC e of ized ment Business Capital Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Stock : Bank Amend't Pierce $ Pierce State Bank $ Mar E Polk County Telephone Co.... Pythian Building Co Paxton-Eckman Chemical f Telephone Co.... Amend't Stromsburg ] Mar. 10 ilding Co Amend't Lincoln I Mar. 12 man Chemical Amend't South Omaha I Amend't Amend't Amend't Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Articles Amend't Amend't Articles Amend't Co. Mar 30 Phelps. R. S., Cigar Co. ... Proudfit, R. S., Lumber Co Platte Valley State Bank Phillips Grain Co v, Cigar Co Amend't Fremont 10,000 i 10,000 Apr. 200,000 Apr. 20,000 Apr. 20,000 Apr. 20,000 Apr. 4 S., Lumber Co Amend't Lincoln 200,000 i 4 sy State Bank Amend't Central City.. 20,000 i 0 iin Co Articles Phillips ..._ 20,000 i 12 Peterson Grain Co ■ain Co Articles Phillips 20,000 j IS Phoenix (The) Brotherhood Peru Canning Company he) Brotherhood Amend't Lincoln j Apr. 26 ig Company Articles Peru 10,000. Club Amend't Crawford ] 10,000 Apr. 29 Progressive Club Mav 11 Payne Investment Co itment Co Amend't Omaha 200,000 ! 200,000 May 15,000 May 13 Peoples (The) Mercantile Co. Progressive Club (2 Am'd'ts) Press and College Leagueof e) Mercantile Co. Articles Wakefield 15,000 1 17 Club (2 Am'd'ts) Amend't Crawford Mav 21 College Leagueof of America a. Articles Omaha 25,000 ! 25,000 Mav :so Philleo (The) &amp; Von Seggern Lumber Co :) &amp; Von Seggern 'o Articles Wayne 25,000 25,000 June 50,000 Tune M .in 1 Peoples (The) Bank e) Bank Amend't Red Cloud 50,000 Red Cloud Paine Fishburn Granite Co... Patent (The) Holding Co Pope Trunk &amp; Leather Goods urn Granite Co... Articles Grand Island 100,000 Grand Island Lincoln 100,000 Tuly 10,000 Aug. 1? ) Holding Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 , 23 &amp; Leather Goods Amend't Omaha Co. Sep. 21 £ i Realty Co Articles '■ Plattsmouth | 10.000&lt; Plattsmouth Realty Co Payne &amp; Slater Co. (former- 10.000 Oct. 20 ater Co. (former- ly Payne, Bostwick &amp; Sla - ter) Bostwick &amp; Sla- Amend't Omaha ... ( Amend't Articles Articles Amend't Articles Articles Articles Oct. 28 Pioneer Land &amp; Cattle Co Pence, J. A. &amp; Son d &amp; Cattle Co.... Articles Alliance 120,000 ! &amp; Son Articles Madison 25,000 1 120,000 Nov. 25,000 Nov. 40,000 Dec. 20,000 Dec. 25,000 Dec. 50,000 Dec. 11 10 Reimers- Kaufman Roberts Grain Co.. Rayo Incubator Co Rowley Land Co.... ufman Amend't Lincoln 40,000 1 »in Co Articles Omaha 20,000 1 o itor Co Articles Blair 25.0001 17 id Co Articles Omaha .. :&gt;0.000 1 20 Rowland Lumber &amp; Coal Co. (formerly Turner Lumber i rain Co.) Realty Improvement Co </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 71 MI8CEU1AHEOU8 (UKPOKVT1O&gt;S— ((onUnned) Kind of Instru - ment Author- &gt;RPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock Rough &amp; Ready Co Horseshoe Articles Homer $100,000 Jan. 26 1909 Homer $100,000 Tan. 26 1909 Roseland Grain &amp; Supply Co Articles Roseland 5,000 Mar. 8 1909 Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Amend't Amend't Roseland 5,000 Mar. 10,000 Mar. 300,000 Mar. 10,000 May Randolph Ink &amp; Bottle Co. Articles .... 10,000 Mar. 13 1909 Randolph Ink &amp; Bottl Ralston Car Works Ralston Amusement C&lt; Robertson Furniture C( Ralston Car Works Articles Omaha 300,000 Mar. 31 1909 Omaha Omaha Lincoln Ruskin Omaha 31 Ralston Amusement Co Articles Omaha 10,000 M.. Robertson Furniture Co Articles Lincoln June 8 1909 June s moit Ruskin State Bank.. Amend't Ruskin 10,000 June H 1909 10,000 June 10,000 June 11 Reed Brothers Amend't Omaha 10,000 June 9 Reed Brothers (The) Roundup Coal Mining :to (The) Roundup Coal Mining Co Amend't Omaha July 1 1 Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Omaha . Omaha . Bethany Omaha . Omaha . Omaha . July IS Raphel-Pred Co Articles Omaha 25,000 July 22 1909 25,000 July 12,000 July 25,000 July 100,000 Aug. 10,000 Sep. 10,000 Sep. 10,000 Oct. 23,000 Nov. Reporter Publishing Co Articles Bethanv 12,000 July 27 1909 Reporter Publishing Ralston Realty Co Articles Omaha 25,000 July 29 1909 Ralston Improvement Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Aug. 11 1909 11 (The) Rollers Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Sep. 2 1909 Rippeteau C. L. Co Articles Clay Center. 10,000 Sep. Clay Center Ruskin Ruskin Grain and Coal Co.. Articles Ruskin 10,000 Oct. Ruskin Grain and Coal Co.... Ryan, Geo. W. &amp; Sons Co Ryan Jewelry Co. (formerly 1 Ryan, Geo. \V. &amp; Sons Co Articles Omaha SS.MeJNov. Omaha Ryan Jewelry Co. (formerly Ryan, Geo. W. &amp; Sons Co.) Amend't Omaha Ryan, Geo. W. &amp; Sons ( Rogers Motor Car Co Riverview Farms Co Nov. I Rogers Motor Car Co Articles Ralston 250,000 Dec. 13 1909 250,000 Dec. 80,000 Dec. 10,000 Jan. 25,000 Jan. 13 ia u Riverview Farms Co Articles Omaha 80,000 Dec. 18 1909 Rich &amp; Falconer Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Jan. 14 MM Rich &amp; Falconer Co Roberts, F. T. &amp; Co Omaha Roberts, F. T. &amp; Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Jan. _•' Articles Omaha Radium Medical and Surgical Institute (formerly North- Western Medical and Sur - gical Institute) Amend't Omaha 10,000 Jan. 28 1910 Radium Medical and Surgical Institute (formerly North- Western Medical and Sur - gical Institute) Omaha Omaha Lisco .. 10,000 Jan. 100,000 Mar. 50,000 Mar. 30,000 Apr. 88 I Royal Indemnity Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Mar. 1 1910 Royal Indemnity Co (The) Remick-Duer Co Ross (The) Investment Co... Rocky (The) Mountain Wa 1 (The) Remick-Duer Co Articles Lisco 50,000 Mar. 2.'&gt; 1910 Ross (The) Investment Co ... Articles Grand Island 30,000 Apr. 4 1910 Grand Island t Rocky (The) Mountain Wa - ter Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Apr. 4 1910 Omaha Lincoln ter ( Articles Articles Regal Auto Sales Co Articles Lincoln 15,000 Apr. 19 1910 Regal Auto Sales Red (The) Men Building Assn Articles Omaha 2.i,000 Dec. 14 1909 Red (The) Men Building Assn Omaha 25,000 Dec. 14 Rock Creek Corporate Tele Articles Riverton </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS ( OKPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Rubel Furniture Co Articles Omaha Omaha *100,000 May 6 1910 6,000 May 11 1910 Reynols, E. \\\, Manufactur ing Co Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Roca Grain &amp; Coal Co Rosedale Telephone (."• Red Cloud Base Ball Assn Rambler Motor Co Rota 10,000 May 17 1910 5,000 June 17 1910 3,000 June 22 1910 Hershev Red Cloud Omaha 25,000 July I.") HI 10 Regal Drug Co Omaha 500,000 July 21 1910 Rhodes-Montgomery Co. (for - merly Mi-Call Insurance Agency | Omaha Realty Investment Co Raymondville Orchard C Rhea Clothing Co Grand Island Omaha .. 100,000 Aug. 75,000 Oct. 25,000 Oct. Holdrege Robstown Fig &amp; Orchard Co Lincoln Sidney Bartlev Sidney Mercantile Co.. State Bank of Bartlev Standard Metallic Packing Co Articles Omaha 1 00,000 De Swedish Building Assn. (for - merly The Wasa Hall A Building Assn.). Omaha . Omaha . Xorfolk Lincoln . Chappell 50,000 Jan. 500,000 Jan. 9 1909 Smith iM. E.) \ Co.... Sturgeon Music Co Samuels Clothing Co sen &amp; Ritchev Co.. 10,000 Jan. 10.000 Jan. io.ooo Jan. Stanton Independent Tele - phoe Co Stanton Stella 15,000 Feb. 50,000 Feb. 100,000 Feb. 50.000 Feb. 1 1909 State (The) Bank Saeger &amp; Sons Fremont Aurora Schrandt &amp; Miller Co. 12 1909 Southside Mutual Telephone Co Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles North Platte Omaha 5,000 Feb. 16 1909 IT MM Sanitary Hand Laundr Shull (The) Land Co Stansberry Lumber Co Stein Brothers Clothing Co.. Scofield, O. K., Cloak &amp; Suit 6,000 Feb. 100,000 Feb. 25,000 Feb. 25,000 Mar. Omaha M.Cook Hastings Co. (now Orkin Bros.) Amend't Articles Artie-Its Articles Aug. 20 1910 Aug. 31 1910 Dct. 18 1910 3d. 26 HI 10 Articles Articles Amend't 25,000 Nov :&gt;o,OOO Dec. :.&gt;:,,i)00 Dec. Amend't Amend't Articles Articles Articles ?0 HtO9 Articles Amend't Articles Articles </seg>
            <seg id="p073">BKILLA1IWI &lt; Kind of ORPOB.VTHLNS— (Continued) Author- Kind of Instru - ment Author- OORPORATE name Instru- Place of ized CORPORATE NAME Place of : ized , When Business Capital Filed ment Business Capital St. Stock Stein Bros. Co Amend't :in Bros. Co Amend't Omaha »; ".0,000 Omaha Omaha Omaha $150,000 Mar. 11 i edish Hospital Assn Amend't Omaha Swedish Hospital Assn Amend't Mar. 16 Scates Motor Car Co . Articles ites Motor Car Co Articles Omaha 1,000 1,000 Mar. 2:»,000 Apr. Smith, Geo. A. &amp; Son Articles ith, Geo. A. &amp; Son Articles Long Pine 21,000 Long Pine Sioux City Bill Posting Ad ux City Bill Posting Ad vertising Co Articles ertising Co Articles So. Sioux City City Kearney Apr. »; I Standard Printing Co. Articles ndard Printing Co Articles Kearney 10,000 10,000 Apr. If. Sunlight Sanitarium Amend't light Sanitarium Amend't Lincoln Lincoln Apr. 17 Sheets Lumber Co Artdes Bets Lumber Co Artdes Beaver &lt; -o,000 crest Fruit Farm Articles Lincoln 10,000 Anthony (The) ft Dak Beaver Cit Lincoln K«),000 Apr. 10,000 Apr. -H Sum-rest Fruit Farm Articles :« St. Anthony (The) &amp; Dakota Elevaor Co Articles ilevaor Co Articles Minn'pl'is, M. 1.000,000 Minn'pl'is, Shell fcf. 1 ,000,000 May 13 s slby State Bank Articles Shelby . i."&gt;,000 Shelbv State Bank Articles 000 May 12 State Insurance Compan ite Insurance Company of Nebraska Amend't Nebraska Amend't Omaha 'iK),000 Omaha Shelbv 200,000 May 12,000 Mav s Bby (The) Mercantile Co. Articles The) D. V. Building elby (The) Mercantile Co. Articles Shelb- r.'.OOO oles (The) D. V. Building :o Articles Omaha ;:.,000 Omaha ,000 Mav Supreme Forest Woodmen preme Forest Woodmen Circle Amend't Omaha le Amend't Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Amend't Omaha Elkhorn Oak Mav I State Bank of Elkhorn Scroggin &amp; Co. Bank. State Bank of Endicof Shell Creek Valley Bank Superior Commercial Club... Sutherland Telephone ( Stevenson, J. R., Roofing »te Bank of Elkhorn Articles Elkhorn .10.000 June 25,000 June 10,000 June :&gt;0,000 J une 10,000 June 10,000 June .i roggin &amp; Co. Bank Articles () a k HjMS lrt M It 21) ate Bank of Endicott Articles Endk-ott 10,000 ell Creek Valley Bank Articles Newman G've .V),000 perior Commercial Club... Articles Superior 10,000 therland Telephone Co Amend't Sutherland 10,000 evenson, J. R., Roofing "o Articles Omaha 10,000 Articles Articles Omaha 10,000 June 50,000 [une 20 s ottsbluff State Bank Articles Scottsbluff .. 50,000 sbluff 21 vereign Camp of the Imen of the World Amend't Omaha Eoodmen of the World .... th Manufacturing Co th-Hultin-Andersons Co ?art (The) Stoker Co Amend't Articles Articles Articles Amend't Aricles Articles Articles June 26 1909 -lith Manufacturing Co Articles Chicago, 111... 10,000 10,000 June 26 1909 60,000 June 26 1909 hi June 26 1909 10,000 June 30 1909 16,000 July 3 1909 50,000 July 6 1909 nith-Hultin-Andersons Co. Articles Wahoo 60,000 Omaha _ Lincoln ... Omaha . Superior Hastings Sawyer Investment Sivley-Omaha Excursion Co. Superior Electric Light Co... Stanton (C. C.) Lumber Co </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued) Kind of Author- CORPOBATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When Business Capital; Filed ment Stock Smith Brick Co Amend't Omaha $200,000 July 26 1909 Sharp Automatic Tool Works Articles Omaha j 5,000 July 21 1900 (The) Scottsbluff Sugar Co. Articles Denver 1,000,000 Aug. 7 1909 South Omaha Commercial Club Articles South Omaha 10,000 Aug. 14 1909 State Oil Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Aug. 15 1900 Statute Law Book Co Dissolu- tion Omaha Aug. 20 1909 Shelby Progressive Club Articles Shelby 500iAug. 23 1909 Scottsbluff Investment Co.... Articles Scottsbluff .... 50,000 Aug. 26 1909 Stamford Bank Amend't Stamford 100,000|Sep. 3 1909 St. Joseph &amp; Grand Island Ry. Co., St. Joseph, Mo. and First Trust &amp; Savings Bank, Chicago, 111 Agrem't Sep. 17 1909 Stromsburg Sewer Co Articles Stromsburg 15,000lOct. 1 1909 Sweet-Edwards Automobile Co Articles Omaha 20,000 Oct. 11 1909 Square Deal Sales Co Amend't Surety (The) Investment Co. Articles Lincoln 60,000 Oct. 14 1300 David City... 100,000 Oct. 15 13i»0 Security Orchards Co Articles Lincoln lO.OOOOct. 27 1000 Starr Club Articles Crawford Nov. 10 1009 Sheridan Realty Co Articles Hay Springs 10,000 Nov, 20 1P09 Sioux County Agricultural Society Articles Harrison 10,000 Dec. 7 1900 Scottsbluff Land Co Articles Scottsbluff 20,000 Dec. 23 1900 Sidles Garage Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Jan. 6 Uiii Southern Cottonseed Meal &amp; Feed Co Articles South Omaha 10.000 Jan. 8 1910 (The) Stephens-Schmitt Mer cantile Co _ Articles Ulysses Omaha 25,000 Jan. 10,00o!jan. 15,©00jan. 20 1910 22 1910 Sterling Land Co Articles Sweetwater State Bank Articles Sweetwater Sidney (The) Electric Service Co. Amnd't Sidney 50,000 Jan. 40,000jjan. 25,000 Jan. 50,000 Jan. 29 1910 Security (The) Bank Amend't Creighton Creighton Omaha .... 29 1910 Security (The) Bank Articles 29 1910 Shook Manufacturing Co Amend't 31 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 75 MISCELLANEOUS Kind of CORPORATIONS—(Coatine*) Author Kind of Instru - ment Author CORPORATE name i ns tru- Place of ized Whe CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed merit Business Capital File&lt; Stock St. Standard (The) Automobile Standard (The) Automobile Co Articles Omaha S 75,000 Feb. 3 C&lt; Articles Omaha $ 75,000 Feb. Swan Lake Land &amp; Cattle Co Articles Omaha 50,000 Feb. 4 Swan Lake Land &amp; Cattle Co J Articles Omaha 50,000 Feb. 4 1910 South Omaha Auto Co Articles South Omaha 5,000 Feb. 7 South Omaha Auto C Articles South Omaha 5,000 Feb. 7 The Sweetwater Elevator Co Articles Sweetwater ..! 10,000 Feb. 15 The Sweetwater Elevator Articles Articles Sweetwater Vebr. City 10,000 Feb. 15,000 Feb. IS ;:;: Sichl Clothing Co Articles Nebr. City 15,000 Feb. 15 Sichl Clothing Co Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co. (formerly Sun - derland Roofing &amp; Supply Co.) Amend't Omaha Feb. 17 Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co. (formerly Sun - derland Roofing &amp; Supply Omaha Feb. 17 Starr-Kingman (The) Shoe Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Feb. 25 Starr-Kingman (The) Shoe Omaha 10,000 Feb. 2.'. Sovereign Camp of the Woodmen of the World i reign Camp of the Woodmen of the World Amend't Omaha Mar. 2 Amend't Omaha Mar o Suthern Coal and Supply Co. Articles Omaha 50,000 Mar. 10 Kern Coal and Supply Co.; h Independent Telephone! Articles Omaha 50,000 Mar. 10 Slugh Independent Telephone Co Articles Pierce l,25f Mar. 11 1.25C Mar 11 Sullivan-Mead Lumber Co Articles Ashland 25,001 Vlar. 17 25,001 Vlar. 17 Stockham Grain Co Articles Stockham 20,00&lt; . dar. 22 20.CKX , vlar Spalding Telephone Co Articles Spalding l0,00C Apr. 8 10,000 Apr. s Stidham Grain Co Articles Omaha 50.00C Apr. 8 5O,00C Apr. I Sterling Investment Co Superior Base Ball Assn Shafer (li. F.) &amp; Co... Smith (J. Sidney) Grain Co. Saronville Grain Co Sterling Investment Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Apr. 9 25,000 Apr. 9 Articles Superior 2,500 Apr. 12 Articles Omaha 25,000 Apr. 12 Articles Omaha 10,000 Apr. 16 Articles Saronville 20,000 Apr. IS State Bank of Poole St. Joseph Church Amend't Poole 10,000 Apr. 20 1910 Articles Platte Center Apr. 19 Rrity Investment &amp; Trust Articles Articles Articles Articles Amend't Articles Omaha 250,000 Apr. 20,000 May 10,000 May 25,000 May 50,000 May 2S I Eldwards Electric ( dard Produce Co.. tzel Stove Co St. Edward Omaha 3 .. 6 9 Omaha . Osmond Virginia Security State Bank Slater Drug Co 5,000 May u Sargent Grain &amp; Live Stock Articles Sargent 10,000 May- 18 Articles I Lincoln m.k.iMiv 26 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 76 MISCELLANEOUS (ORPORATIO&gt;S— (Continued) Kind of Kind of Author- Author- Place of ized ! When corporate name Instru- CORPORATE name Instru- Place of ized | When Business Capital Filed ment ment Business Capital Filed Stock Stock Smyrna (The) Co-Operative Co. Articles Smyrna (The) Co-Operative Co. Articles Smyrna - -.,000 May 30 lyio Hmvrna $ 5,000 May :to Sanitary Towel and Laundry Co Articles Sanitary Towel and Laundry Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 June 1 1910 Lincoln 10,000 June 1 i State Bank of Maywood Amend't State Bank of Maywood Amend't Maywood June 3 1910 Mavwood June Staplehurst Grain Co Articles Staplehurst Grain Co Articles Staplehurst .. 25,000 June 7 HMO Staplehurst Seward 25,000 June 25,000 June Seward Motor Car Co Articles Luis Land and Cattle Co. Amend't Seward Motor Car Co Articles Seward 25,000 June 7 1910 . Luis Land and Cattle Co. _ Amend't Omaha _ June 7 I'.no Omaha _ June 7 I'.no Shogo (The) Lithia Springs Shogo (The) Lithia Springs Co. Articles Tent and Awning Co Articles Co. Articles Lincoln Omaha Omaha Lincoln 50,000 June 8 1910 50,000 June 25,000 June 50,000 June ■ Tent and Awning Co Articles Omaha 25,000 June 8 l'.MO Security Realty Co Articles Security Realty Co Articles Omaha 50,000 June 14 1910 Sampson Tire Protector Sampson Tire Protect Manufacturing ('• Articles Grand Island 100,000 June 17 1910 Grand Island St. Libory 100,000 June MjMO June 20,000 June St. iThe) Lil&gt;ory State Bank Articles St. Libory 25,000 June 18 l'JIO Swartz (The) Printing Co Articles Swartz (The) Printing Co ..Articles Omaha 20,000 June 23 1910 Omaha Shippee (The) Elevator Co.. Articles Shippee (The) Elevator Co. ... Articles VVilsonville Neligh Wilsonville .... 5,000 June 29 1910 5,000 June 25,000 July 10,000 July Security (The) Bank Articles growers Telephone Co. Articles • tish Rite Cathedral -n Amend't Security (The) Bank Articles Neligh 25,000 July 8 1910 .growers Telephone Co. Articles Valentine 10,000 July 15 l'.MO Valentine ;sh Rite Cathedral Amend't Omaha July 29 1910 Omaha July 29 1910 Stamford Bank... Amend't Stamford Bank... Amend't Stamford 25,000 Aug. Stamford 25,000 Aug. 5 itlO 5 Servie (The) Co .... Articles Servie (The) Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Aug. 10 1910 Omaha 25,000 Aug. 10 1910 Security Real Estate Co Articles Security Real Estate Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Aug. 18 I*M Lincoln j 25,000 Aug. 18 1910 Slaughter-Thompson Co Articles Slaughter-Thompson Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Aug. 29 1910 Omaha 10,000 Aug. 29 1*10 St. Michaels Church Articles St. Michaels Church Articles Central City Sep. 13 1910 Central City.. 1 Sep. 13 1910 Standars Auto Tire Co Articles Standars Auto Tire Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Oct. 4 1010 Lincoln 10,000 Oct. 4 Hill) C H. Swallow &amp; Co Articles C H. Swallow &amp; Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Oct. 8 I'.Mii Lincoln J 10,000 Oct. Sichl Hotel Co Articles d of Nebraska of the Presbyterian Church of the I'nited States of America Articles Sichl Hotel Co Articles Xebr. City 25,000 Oct. 11 l'Mo N'ebr. City ; 25,000 Oct. 11 1910 I of Nebraska of the Presbvterian Church of the L'nited States of America Articles |Oct. 19 1910 Oct. 19 1910 Standard Land Co Articles Standard Land Co Articles Lincoln 10,000 Nov. 2 1910 Lincoln 10,000 Nov. 2 1910 o Sherian (The) Telephone Co. Artilces Sherian (The) Telephone Co.Artilces Atkinson 2,500 Nov. 5 l'.MO Atkinson 2,500 Nov. 5 1910 5 Shippers Grain Bureau Articles Shippers Grain Bureau Articles Omaha 10,000 Nov. 9 l'JIO Omaha 10,000 Nov. 9 1910 Smith (James G.) Hide Co ... Dissolu- Smith (James G.) Hide Co ... Dissolu- tion tion St. Jo'ph, Mo LtM St. Jo'ph, Mo Nov 12 South (The) Omaha - th (The) Omaha Stone Mfg. Co Articles South Omaha 10,000 Nov. 13 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">•i T I ; REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MISCELLANEOUS ( ORl'OKATIOJiS— (Iontlaae4) Kind of Instru - ment Author- )RPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock tr (The I of the Blessed •rament for Indians and Charter Articles Bucks Co., Pa Lincoln Nov. ■ z 100,000 Dec. II EJity Poultry Assn. (now ans-Mississippi Poultry rl Pet Stock Assn.) Omaha 2,000 Dec. 2 oo jw Til ton, H. M- Dec. Furniture Amend't Articles Articles Lincoln Benson Lincoln 10,000 Jan. 1 10,000 Jan. 1&gt;all (R. M.) Lumber Co. ner Lumber, Coal &amp; ardware Co Articles Articles Articles Articles Bethany Craig E Dixon Wakefield Cedar Rapid Eune Publishing Co. (for - •rly Westliche Presse Wishing Co, Omaha Mav Articles Articles Articles Articles Thedford Thurston Omaha . l,500june 10,000 fi.00" 25,000 4 i trston Mercantile ( n City Coal Co.... 1 0 Table Rock •J4 Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles 1 rans-Mississippi Land rumbull (R. M.) Lumber Cc rue (The) Voice Publishing Amend't Articles Articles Articles Omaha Sterling 18,000 Dec. 35,000 Feb. T 1 i People Tribune Publishing C&lt; Fry-City Poultry Assn and Fet Stock Assn.) Amend't Til ton ft Phelps Furniture 3! ,906 111900 M MM Times Publishing C Tirllmll (R. M.) Lur 15,000 Feb. 1 20,000, Feb. 2 50,000-Feb. 7 20,000 Feb. 15 t-ber (E. M.) Co Article ix (The) Land Co Article Theo. Carlson Co Article Timber Creek Independ- t Telephone Co Articlt une Publishing Co. (t l.OooMar. 10 K Wishing O Amend't ford (The) Telephone! Twin City Coal Co Table Rock Electric C&lt; - Nebraska Truck and Wakefield 10,000 Sep. 4 Omaha -ep. 4 Hildreth ~&lt;p. 7 Florence . 10.000 Sep. 14 Xorth Platte 10,000 Sep. 21 Fremont ity Printing C unty Telephor Hhrhardt Co... True (The) Voice P Ertelot-Barber Co lmseh Military Band ippert-Bentz Co Tecumseh Oshk </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 MISCELLA&gt;EOIS ('OKl'OKATKtt'S— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Articles Tekamal, .'.I.OOO Sep. 13 1910 Tekamah Tile Cc Articles Tekamah Turner Lumber, Coal and Hardware Co Articles Bethany 25,000 Sep. 27 1910 Articles Bethany 25,000 Sep. Stockman (The) and Farm - ers Bank Articles Harrison 50,000 Oct. 2f&gt; 1910 Articles Articles Harrison Nesbit 50,000 Oct. 3,000 Feb. o-. s Upper Loup Telephone Co Union Valley Telephone Co. Updike Milling Co Articles Nesbit 3,000 Feb. 3 1909 Kearney 5,000 Mar. 12 1909 a Kearney Omaha . 5,000 Mar. 100,000 Apr. 12 Amend't Omaha 100,000 Apr. 3 Amend't Unadilla Farmers Elevator Co. Articles Unadilla Apr. 8 1909 Articles Articles Amend't Articles Unadilla Omaha . Harvard Omaha . Apr. Apr. Apr. Apr. i United Grain Co.... Union State Bank Articles Omaha 100,000 Apr. 8 100,000 s Amend't Harvard Apr. 14 1909 u 17 Union Grain &amp; Elevator Co. Union Stock Yards Corn- Articles Omaha 50,000 Apr. 17 1909 50,000 pany of Grand Island Unity Real Estate Co.. -es (The) Land Co.. Amend't Grand Island 250,000 May 22 Amend't Articles Articles Grand Island Omaha Articles Omaha I 15,000 May 29 1909 Articles Ulysses 25,000 June 18 1909 Ulysses United States Equipment Co Articles New Jersey, N. J 2.-.0,000 Aug. 2f&gt; 1909 New Jersey, N. J Aug. 26 University (The) Publish ing i Amend't Lincoln .0,000 Sep. 20 1909 Lincoln Sep. :20 Union (The) Wall Paper &amp; Paint Co Articles Lincoln 50,000 Oct. 5 1909 Lincoln Oct. Ulysses Independent Tele - phone Co Amend't Ulysses Nov. 12 1909 Ulvsses Nov. 12 Illustrated Advertising and Distributing Co Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Articles Amend't Omaha Omaha Omaha Ulysses Omaha Omaha Ulysses Omaha 10,000 Dec. Feb. Feb. Feb. May Aug. Aug. Nov. 11 U. S. Live Stock C The Unigraph Co.. 200,000 10,000 ir&gt; Ulysses Hardware Co Union Realty Co 5,000 16 75,000 200,000 25,000 3 Updike Elevator Co Ulysses (The) Land Co Union Investment Co.. 10 10 25 Van Wickle Grain &amp; Lum ber Co Articles Articles Articles York 150,000 20,000 20,000 Dec. Jan. Mar. 4 s Venango State Bank.. Valentine Lumber Co Venango Valentine M 31 Valley Fruit Farm &amp; Gar 100,000 Apr. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 M1SCELL llfEOUS CORPORATlOSJi— (Continued) Kind of Instru - ment Author CORPORATE NAME Place of Business ized When Capital Filed Stock B-^tock Yards an ain Co Grain Co Amend't Valley &lt;i:&gt;0,000 May -"•i 1900 Amend' Dissolu tion Vallev Vote-Berger (The) Co Dissolu- tion La Crosse, W Aug. 16 1909 La Crosse, W Omaha Aug. I Victoria Cleanser C Articles Omaha 10,000 Sep. 21 1909 -ia Cleanser Co Amend't Omaha 50,000 Feb. 26 1910 Article Amend Article 10,000 Sep. 50,000 Feb. 100,000 Apr. ria Clean* t Omaha 5 Omaha Vacuum Cleaning Co Articles Omaha 100,000 Apr. 7 1910 7 Valley Stock Yards &amp; Grain Co Amend't Valley Apr. 23 1910 Vallev Stock Yards &amp; Grain Valley Apr. 23 t VanSickle Glass &amp; Paint Co. (formerly Maple-Van Sickle Glass &amp; Paint Co.) Amend't Lincoln .... June 16 1910 rge W., Co Articles Lincoln 50.000 July 5 1910 Tune Amend Article Article Article t Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln 16 I S0.000 July 6,000 Sep. 10,000 Nov. .i I Vienna Bakery Co Articles Lincoln 6,000 Sep. 6 1910 Valparaiso Electric Co Articles Valparaiso ... 10,000 Nov. 16 1910 Valparaiso Electri Valparaiso lfi Van N'nstrand Rotary Pl&lt; Articles Omaha 100,000 Nov. 23 1910 Article Article Article Omaha Omaha Omaha Western Theatre Co Articles Omaha 3,000 Dec. 6 1908 rn T 3.000 Dec. 6 1908 World (The) Investment Co. Articles Omaha 250,000 Dec. 12 1908 tern Publishing Co. (now Western Security Co.) Amend't Omaha Dec. 23 1908 Kid (The) Investment Co. tern Publishing Co. (now 250,000 Dec. 12 1906 Amend Article Amend Omaha Omaha Dec. 1 Wurn Optical Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Dec. 29 1908 10,000 Dec. 5,000 Dec. Western Land Co Amend't Hastings 5,000 Dec. 31 1908 tern Publishing ft En - graving Co Articles Lincoln 25,000 Jan. 6 1909 Hastings t Article Article Article Lincoln Omaha Lincoln i Western Buyers Assn Articles Omaha 2",000 Feb. 9 1909 l Brothers &amp; Boggs.... Articles Lincoln 3,000 Feb. 1" ■ming Conference Associ - ation of the Seventh-day Adventists Articles Crawford . Feb. 16 1909 Etern Buyers Assn ■&lt;ls Brothers &amp; Boggs... &gt;ming Conference Associ Feb. 10 I William Maier Co Articles Omaha 25,000 Mar. 4 1909 25,000 Mar. 25,000 Mar. 4 Webster County Bank Articles Red Cloud .'".000 Mar. 11 1909 It 13 If. White Salmon Lumber Co.... Amend't Lincoln Mar. 13 1909 Mar Western Advertising Co Amend't Lincoln 50,000 Mar. 16 1909 tern Motorist Publish - ing Co.. Articles Omaha 3,000 Apr. 3 1009 ■ds (The) Investment Co Articles Lincoln ",0.000 Apr. 5 1900 50,000 Mar, Articles Omaha 3,000 Apr. ing Co Is (The) Investment Lincoln Omaha .10,000 Apr. Wilson Steam Boiler Co_ Amend't Omaha Apr. 10 1909 Apr. Wilson Steam Boiler Western Motor &amp; Supply ( </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE MIS( ELLA&gt;EOIS ( OKPOR ATIONS— (Continued I Kind of Instru - ! ment Author- CORPORATE NAME Place of ized When Business Capital Filed Stock Wahc Earners Investment Articles Havelock $ 24,00(1 Apr. IS Western Nebraska Tele phone ' Articles Articles Harrisburg Lincoln 25,000 Apr. 25,000 May I* 14 Wells &amp; Frost Co Water (The) and Light Com - pany of Nebraska Cit Amend't Nebr. Citv 300,000 June 30 Western Trust and Security Amend't Fremont 10,000 June 30 Fremont Omaha . Kimball 10,000 June 25,000 July 75,000 July 10,000 July :m Welsh Brothf 'elsh Brothers Co Articles Omaha 25,000 July 5 West Nebraska Land Co Woodman Fraternal Co Western Rock Island Plow est Nebraska Land Co Articles Kimball 7.1,000 July 12 12 oodman Fraternal Co Articles Comstock 10,000 July 17 Com stock 17 'estern Rock Island Plow Co. Amend't Omaha 250,000 July 24 Omaha Co. I River Nursery Co Wolz Bakery Co ood River Nursery Co Amend't Wood River... 100,000 Aug. 25 Wood River Fremont .... olz Bakery &lt;"■■ Articles Fremont 25,000 Sep. 14 Western (The) O. I. C. Rec ording Co. •estern (The! O. I. C. Rec- ording (". Articles Hastings 10.000 Sep. 23 Hastings Omaha .. Articles Articles 10.000 Sep. 6,000 Oct. Weir Citv Coal Co eir City Coal Co Articles Omaha 6,000 Oct. 1 1 akefield (Thei Bottling Wakefield (The) Bottling Works Work- Articles Wakefield 10,000 Nov. 9 Articles Articles Wakefield Aurora ... 10,000 Nov 9 z Woman's (Thei Culture Club Wauneta (The) Oil and Oil Oman's (Thei Culture Club Articles Aurora Nov. 16 Nov Ifi auneta (The) Oil and Oil Burner Co Articles Wauneta 10,000 Nov. 24 Burner Co Articles Articles Wauneta Omaha .. 10,000 Nov 24 allace Automobile Co Articles Omaha 10,000 Dec. 23 Wallace Automobile Co 10,000 Dec. 23 1909 West Point Butter and Creamerv C&lt;&gt; est Point Butter and Creamery Co Amend't West Point Dec. 30 West Point Inman Dec. 30 \\ at son Hav Co D Hay C" Amend't Inman Jan. 7 Jan. Western Cigar Factory estern Cigar Factory Articles Hartington .. 10,000 Jan. 11 Hartington Aurora 10,000 Jan. 11 Woman's (The) Cluture Club World Publishing Co.... Oman's (The) Cluture Club Amend't Aurora Jan. 11 Jan. 11 orld Publishing Co Amend't Omaha . Feb!" 8 Omaha Feb. s Western Automobile Supply Co. estern Automobile Supply Co. Articles Omaha 30,000 Mar. S Omaha 30,000 Mar. Wymore Building and Loan ymore Building and Loan Assn Articles Assn Articles W ymore 100,000 Mar. 7 Wymore 100.000 Mar Women-Inavale Telephone omen-Inavale Telephone Assn Articles Womer, Kan. 2,000 Mar. 8 Womer, Kan 2,000 Mar. s Wesleyan (The) Nurses Training School and Ho» oital \mend't 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS— (Continued &gt; Kind of Author Author CORPORATK N\MK CORPORATE name Instru Place of ized Whet Place of ized When Business Capital Filed merit Business Capital Filec Stock n A Dana Articles Lincoln $ 20,000 Mar. 21 Article Amend Article Lincoln $20,000 Mar. 100,000 Mar. 200,000 Apr. 2! Waterloo Creamery Co Amend't Co. Bluffs, la. 100,000 Mar. 30 t H luffs, la Omaha . 30 Lawn Cemetery Articles Omaha 200,000 Apr. 1 1 Wiltamuth &amp; Feinberg Manufacturing O Articles Lincoln 10,000 Apr. 4 Article Amend Article Article Article Lincoln Omaha Omaha Ord 10,000 Apr. 4 Welsh Grain Co Amend't Omaha Apr. 4 Apr. I 4 Ward B. Falk Agency Articles Omaha 25,000 Apr. 8 25,000 Apr. 25,000 Apr. 100,000 Apr. - William ID. L.) Saddlery Co. Articles Ord 25,000 Apr. 11 U Whitmore Brothers Co Articles Valley l(M1.0O&lt;&gt; Apr. 26 Vallev Wage-Worker (The) Put&gt; - lishing Co . Articles Lincoln "H) May 5 5,000 May- Lincoln tern Bridge and Con- struction Co Amend't Omaha "".nooMay 6 Amend Article Omaha Waterlo t Waldron (The) Seed Co Articles Waterloo 7:&gt;,000 May 7 Klruff Bank N'ote Co. nerly Woodruff-Collins nting Co.i &lt;lruff Bank N'ote C ifrmerlv Woodruff-Collins Printing Co.) Amend't Lincoln.- May 13 Amend Article t Lincoln Lincoln imen Fire Insurance Co. Articles Lincoln 100,000 M .: tern Redpath Chautau- qua System Amend't Lincoln 20,000 June 11 Amend Article Article t Lincoln Cushing Butte 20,000 June 25,000 June 400,000 June 11 Western Land Roller Co Articles Cushing ... .".itOOjune 28 •J* Western Land Owners Co Articles Butte 400,000 Ju :m Wells Lumber A Coal Co. ■ rmerly Patrick Wells Lumber Co. i Amend't Omaha July 21 E; Lumber &amp; Coal Co. rmerly Patrick Wells ■nber Co.) t Omaha July 21 Walrath ft Sherwood Lum - ber Co Amend't Omaha : .' ..ihk&gt; July 29 Amend Amend Article t t Omaha .(25,000 July 200,000 Aug. rn Brick A Supply Co. Amend't Hastings .'on.ooo Aug. 2 Hastings Falls Citv Wright Lumber Co Articles Falls ('• • .000 Aug. 29 Western Automobile Supply tern Automobile Supply Co Amend't Omaha 40,000 Sep. 13 t Omaha 40,000 Sep. n ider (The) Grain Grad- er Co.. _ : Articles Lincoln p. 21 Article Article Article Lincoln Ekingmens (The) Club tern Investment Co tover, John (Incorpor Workingmens (The) Club Articles Grand Island 100 Sep. 29 Grand Island Lincoln Western Investment Co Articles Lincoln V),000 Oct. 7 50,000 Oct. tover, John (Incorpor- ated! Articles Lincoln TSjOMJOd 19 Lincoln 75,000 Oct. 19 Wortendyke (The) Lumber Co. ...Aritclet &lt;w Nov. 5 Ulvsses 20,000 N'ov Young i R. S.i Building Sup- 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">i REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE K&gt; MISCELLANEOUS CORPORATIONS -« ontinuedl Kind of Author- CORPORATE NAME Instru- Place of ized When ment Business Capital Filed Stock York Gas &amp; Electric Co Amend't York Young-Burke Co Articles Omal Articles Omaha Young &amp; Dill Investment Co. Articles Omaha 26,000 Dec. 15 York Gas &amp; Electri. i Amend't York Yetter (W. L.I I Amend't Omal Feb. 8 Amend't Omaha Aug. 23 York Implement Co * Feb. 4 1909 25,000 July 28 1909 10,000 Nov. 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 RAILWAY IMO1UM&gt;KATIO\S. Kind of COKPORATE NAME Instr Place of ment Business Chicago &amp; Great Wester Railroad Co Articles Lincoln (The) Omaha &amp; Denve Short Line Railroad Co.... i The) Omaha &amp; Denve Short Line Railroad Co.... July Author- ized When Capital Filed Stock Railroad Co Articles Chicago. I! »;Au«. 20 Lincoln Traction Co Articles Lincoln H,r&gt;00,000 Mar. 3 IMf i The) Missouri Pacific Rail- wav Co Articles St. Louis, Mo. 2W.00O Aug. (The I Omaha-Lincoln Inte urban Construction Co -&gt;00,)X)0 Mar Article! Denver. Colo.i U.wo.ooo Juh Short Line Railroad Co Amend't Denver, Col&lt; West Shore Railway Co Article! </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>