<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF KEITH NEVILLE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE THIRTY-FIFTH SESSION NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">c^VIESSAGE OF KEITH NEVILLE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE THIRTY-FIFTH SESSION NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Members of the Thirty-fifth session of the Legislature of Nebraska : GENTLEMEN: You have been delegated by the people of a great common - wealth to enact into law such measures as will in your judgment advance their interests and redound to their benefit. You should keep in mind at all times the limitations established by the State Constitution and consider carefully each enactment to the end that your labors will be fruitful. In the discharge of the consti - tutional obligation imposed upon me, I take pleasure in com - municating to you the following information and recommen - dations : The Prohibitory Amendment. The people, the highest authority in the state, through the Initiative and Referendum, have enacted an amendment to the State Constitution. It is effective May 1st, 1917, and prohibits the sale and manufacture of intoxicating liquors within the state, except for medicinal, mechanical, scientific and sacramental pur - poses. For some months prior to the election a comprehensive cam - paign was waged with reference to the amendment. The news - papers, with commendable fairness, sold space to the advocates of both sides to the controversy. A discussion both pro and con was permitted in their columns. Speakers for and against were given respectful and attentive hearings throughout the state. The dominant political parties realizing that sentiment within their ranks with reference to the question was divided and not desiring to violate the spirit of the Initiative and Referendum, through which the amendment was submitted to the people, wisely and properly took the following position with reference to it: That it was not political, that it had no place in party politics, that the people had every means of settling it, and that the majority should rule. Both parties pledged their can- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE didates to abide by the will of the people and to put their decree into effect. Notwithstanding the position taken by the parties, certain individuals sought to advance their personal interests and those of favored candidates by appealing to prejudices engendered by the controversy. The subterfuge failed. The number misled was insignificant and the results of the election were not effected. The action of the people was deliberate, the amendment car - ried by an emphatic majority of nearly 30,000 and the people, with equal deliberation, delegated to the Democratic Party the responsibility of putting their decree into effect. This action is the result of an intelligent retrospection of the past twenty years. The greater part of the moral and economic reforms enacted into law in that period have been fathered by democratic legislators, passed by democratic legis - latures and have been for the most part signed by democratic governors. With these facts before us, our course is obvious. We will keep faith with the people as the representatives of our party have at all times in the past. We must honestly, conscientiously and intelligently endeavor to prohibit the sale and manufacture of intoxicating liquor within the state after the amendment becomes effective. We are not in any sense exercising the functions of a physician towards a patient. The prohibitory amendment in no way assails the right of an individual to pur - chase intoxicating liquors for his personal use from sources outside the state and that right should not be abridged except to the extent necessary to carry out the provisions of the amendment prohibiting the illegal sale of liquor within the state. Any legislation necessary to carry out the letter and spirit of the prohibitory amendment should be enacted. In approaching this problem, we can safely assume that the peo - ple who voted for the amendment will approve the expenditure of such sums as may be necessary to put into effect and continue in effect their decree. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 5 In the words of the Constitution, "the supreme executive power of the state shall be vested in the Governor, who shall take care that the laws be faihfully executed." It is clearly intended that the chief executive shall have power to demand law enforcement by local authorities. The Sackett law is intended to give the Governor the power to remove officials for failure to enforce the laws of the state, but the delays incident to such removal render it practically valueless. It is doubtful whether the Sackett law could be amended so that it would be an effective instrument for law enforcement, but legislation can be enacted that will materially aid the Governor in enforcing the law. How to make prohibition a fact in Nebraska is indeed a problem and toward its solution the following legislation should be enacted: First: A Public Welfare Department should be created and the Governor be empowered to appoint a deputy and such assistant deputies as may be necessary. The salaries attached should be sufficiently large to attract honest, fearless and cap - able men, and such additional funds as are necessary for the operation of the department should be provided in order that it may perform the functions for which it is created. The principal duties of this department would be to gather information of law violations, help in prosecutions and assist generally in making the prohibitory amendment effective. It would also provide an excellent means of determining whether or not local officials were doing their full duty in the matter of law enforcement. Second: The Legal Department of the state should have authority at the direction of the Chief Executive to personally, or by representative, aid local authorities in conducting prosecu - tions; to bring and conduct such prosecutions in the name of the state if desirable and to maintain a special prosecutor where necessary. Third: The sale of intoxicating liquors by drug stores and other institutions should be strictly regulated and a state permit </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE issued to such institutions, permitting such sale for medicinal, mechanical, scientific and sacramental purposes only and pro - hibiting the sale of same for beverage purposes. In the absence of a state permit, the possession of a government permit to sell intoxicating liquors should be considered prima facie evi - dence of the unlawful sale of such liquors. Fourth: The shipment into the state of liquors for beverage purposes, containing wood alcohol or other harmful ingredients and being of such low grade and inferior quality as to place in jeopardy the health, mentality or sight of the consumer should be prohibited. The enforcement of such a law will fall upon the Pure Food Department, and judging by the experience of other prohibition states, additional chemists will be necessary to successfully cope with this phase of the problem. Fifth: If the spirit, as well as the letter of the prohibitory amendment is to be carried out, drinking clubs and similar institutions, wherein the members interest in the common liquor supply is represented by chips, cards, tickets and other methods of a like nature, or where the so-called locker system is used, must be prohibited. Sixth: The penalty for the sale of intoxicating liquors for beverage purposes from, or the manufacture of same in buildings within the state should fall upon the landlord as well as upon the tenant, as is done under the Alberts law in cases where buildings are rented for immoral purposes. Seventh: Police magistrates should be given full jurisdiction over cases arising out of violations of the liquor laws. Eighth: A fine, which would merely be a tax upon the profits of the industry, will not suffice to discourage bootlegging. Dras - tic penalties will be necessary. A fine or jail sentence should be provided as a penalty for the first offense. A graduated penalty of increasing severity, consisting of a jail sentence and fine, should be provided for each succeeding offense. Ninth: Contracting within the state for the delivery of in - toxicating liquors from sources without the state by represen- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 7 tatives of breweries, distilleries and similar institutions is clearly in violation of the letter of the amendment, and penalties should be fixed for such illegal sale. Tenth: Common carriers should file monthly with the County Clerk a record of all shipments delivered in each county, and no delivery should be made to any person other than the party to whom shipment is consigned. Eleventh: Legislation should be enacted enabling municipali - ties to take such steps by ordinance of otherwise as they may deem necessary to make effective the prohibitory amendment in their respective communities. Twelfth: Breweries and like institutions which may be con - verted into plants for the manufacture of non-intoxicating beverages should be strictly regulated, as should distilleries and iike institutions manufacturing alcohol for mechanical and scien - tific purposes. Thirteenth: It is of the utmost importance that a sufficient sum be appropriated to insure that the authorities be not hamp - ered by a lack of funds in making he prohibitory laws effective. Publicity Bureau. Nebraska is primarily an agricultural state. Our prosperity for the most part depends upon the success of those engaged in agricultural pursuits. We have about forty-two acres of ground for every man, woman and child in the state and over 200 acres for every head of a family. Nebraska has everything that would be attractive to a prospective home seeker. From statistics compiled by the Agricultural Society we learn that we stand third in the production of wheat, third in oats, fourth in corn, fifth in butter, second in alfalfa and third in hogs in comparison with all the states in the nation. In our cities we find a ready market for everything that can be raised upon the farm. These and other similar facts would be of interest to pro - spective home seekers and would cause them to conclude that </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE Nebraska is the ideal state in which to establish a home. The most feasible method of disseminating this information is through a Publicity Bureau maintained by the state. This department could also render invaluable service by assisting in the organiza - tion of farm loan associations after the Rural Credits system is in operation. Cost of Securing Farm Loans. One of the problems that should command the serious atten - tion of this Legislature is that of reducing the cost of securing farm loans, the bringing of the prospective borrower into cheaper and easier communication with capital. It is a delicate situation to remedy, for it would be folly to enact legislation that would discourage the investment in farm loans in any section of the state. The Rural Credits System, when it is in operation, will bring the desired relief, and in the meantime, considerable can be accomplished by reducing the commission rate on real estate loans. Such legislation would be a great benefit to many people, who, through lack of knowledge or indifference, will not avail themselves of the advantages to be gained by becoming patrons of the Rural Credits System. The present interest rate upon farm loans in Nebraska is variable. The rate of commission is from 1 per cent to 4 per cent. In eastern Nebraska the average interest rate is 5 per cent to 514 per cent and 1 per cent to iy 2 per cent commis - sion. In western Nebraska the best rate obtainable in many counties is 6 per cent interest and from 2 per cent to 3 per cent commission. In many instances the commission charged is determined by the necessity of the borrower. Avaricious money lenders represent their own money as foreign capital and charge a commission accordingly. A 2 per cent cash com - mission upon a $5,000.00 loan running 5 years would be $500.00. A renewal of the loan at the end of the period would involve the payment of the same commission under the present system. The actual expense of making a $5,000.00 or $10,000.00 loan is little more than that involved in the negotiation for a $1,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 9 loan. The cost of renewal is very considerably leas than that of making the original loan. Legislation should be enacted fixing a maximum commission rate of 2 per cent for all real estate loans up to and including $3,000.00 and a maximum commission rate of iy% per cent for all real estate loans above $3,000.00 and further providing that in all instances where the interest rate exceeds 6 per cent no commission shall be charged. Rural Credit Bonds. The Rural Credits System will shortly be in operation. Its success depends largely upon the demand for the bonds issued by the district banks. The federal act declares that such bonds shall be a proper investment for trust funds of every character. Legislation should be enacted permitting trust companies, banks and similar insti - tutions operating under the laws of the state to purchase this class of securities. Primary Elections Considerable dissatisfaction with the primary law has been engendered by reason of certain abuses that have grown up under it. There are perhaps some who feel that the primary system is wrong in theory, but they are so few in number that their views need not be considered. Each succeeding primary election attests the growing popularity of the principle. At the recent primary over 200,000 voters participated in the nomination of the candidates — over three-fourths of the vote cast at the general election in 1914. The dissatisfaction with the present law can be traced to three sources: First: The ease with which unqualified men may become candidates for the higher offices in the state and even in the nation. Second: That an elector receiving the votes of two or more </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE parties at the primary, though defeated for the nomination of the majority party, frequently is the nominee of a minority party by virtue of an insignificant number of votes. Third: That the primary election is not always final and that men without substantial support can be injected into the race by petition after candidates have been legitimately nomin - ated for the office. To correct these abuses, legislation should be enacted as follows : First: For all offices coated under the constitution of the state and nation any qualified voter may become a candidate by presenting to the Secretary of State a petition with signa - tures approximating 1 per cent of the total vote cast for all candidates for such office at the last general election, such signa - tures representing voters in at least two-thirds of the counties of the state or district. For legislative offices and that of county judge, the only county office established by the constitution as well as all other county offices the present system should be continued, for the reason that in the small units the voters have in a general way at least an idea of the qualifications of candidates for such offices. Second: In instances where a candidate seeks nomination on two tickets, if he loses the nomination of the majority party, he should not be permitted to accept the nomination of the minority party, unless the vote received by him from such minority party was in excess of that received by him from such majority party. The abuses sought to be corrected by this recommendation is minimized by the fact that two minority parties have ceased to exist as such by failure to fulfil the requirements as pro - vided by law. Members of those parties can present a ticket, however, in counties, legislative or congressional districts where their party candidates polled 1 per cent of the total vote cast at the recent election and where the requirements of the law have been met. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 11 Third: No candidate, whose name appeared on the primary ballot, should be permitted to file by petition and the number of signers required upon the petitions of persons desiring to become candidates after the primary should be greatly increased. Short Ballot. There is a very considerable demand on the part of the voters of the state for a shorter ballot, and at the same time a pronounced aversion to changing elective to appointive offices. A shorter ballot, would, without doubt, facilitate intelligent voting, and for that reason give general satisfaction. There are two ways that the election ballot can be shortened, without reducing the number of elective offices: First: Provide that at the general election in 1918 all county officers be elected for a term of four years. This change would cause the national and county elections to come in different years and would shorten the ballot in presidential years very considerably without increasing the length of it at other elec - tions. The great majority of county officers now serve more than one two-year term, and since they have to pass the scrutiny of the voters at both primary and election, there is little chance of incompetents being elected to county office in this state. Second: The constitution of the United States provides that the presidential electors shall be appointed in such manner as each state may direct. The legislature should direct that the names of the candidates for president and vice-president should appear upon the ballot at the election instead of the names of the electors and that the electors should be recommended by the state conventions of the respective parties to the Governor who should appoint those representing the party whose candidates for president and vice-president received a plurality of the votes cast for such offices. The moral obligation of the electors would be the same as under the present system and the ballot would be shortened. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE Public School System. If there is any one outstanding phase of our state existence that more than any other commands at the same time the notice and admiration of our sister states and the just pride of our people, it is our Public School System. Nebraska has always stood among the first states of the nation in the lack of illiterates. Our people have freely approved expenditures for educational purposes. We spend more money per capita upon our schools than any state in the Union and have a greater permanent school fund upon the same basis. Anything tending to increase the efficiency of our educational institutions will meet the hearty approval of our people. The names of all candidates for Regents of the State University and for all other state and county elective school officers should be submitted to the voters at both the primary and general elections upon the non-partisan judiciary ballot, thereby raising the schools of the state above political and party considerations. Appropriations should be made for the development, main - tenance and the support of all educational institutions, including rural high schools and consolidated schools, which have been authorized by previous legislation. Irrigation. The development of irrigation projects in western Nebraska is becoming more and more with each succeeding year an important factor in the state's prosperity. An ever increasing acreage in that most fertile territory is producing bountiful crops, adding to the sum total of the state's production, indif - ferent to climatic conditions, independent of rain or drouth. The upper North Platte valley is even now challenging all other sections of Nebraska in the matter of development and production. The fact that this very considerable territory has been enabled to play an important part in Nebraska's prosperity is due to the enterprise of its people. Secure in their faith in the future of irrigation, they have obligated their lands, borrowed money from the Federal Government </seg>
            <seg id="p013">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 13 through the Reclamation Service and have constructed great irrigation projects. They have asked little from the state and have received less. In years to come, following the con - tinued development of these and similar projects, the return waters from the irrigated lands will maintain a steady flow in the North Platte River from the Wyoming line to the Mis - souri. There should be the greatest possible co-operation between the State Board of Irrigation, Highways and Drainage and the United States Reclamation Service. At a conference of the Reclamation officials and a majority of the members of the State Board of Irrigation, Highways and Drainage, it was determined that the state could best co-operate by authorizing the State Engineer to employ two men to gauge and measure the North Platte River from the Wyoming line to Elm Creek, thereby assisting the Reclamation officials in determining the loss and gain from seepage and evaporation during the different periods throughout the irrigation season. A resolution, endorsing such co-operation, was passed at the annual meeting of the State Association of Irrigators held at Bridgeport, and such co-operation on the part of the state is a necessity. It is also of the greatest importance that a sufficient appropria - tion be made to enable the Legal Department of the state to fight to a successful conclusion the cases now pending in the Federal Courts, seeking to protect the just and prior rights of irrigators in Nebraska against encroachment on the part of water users in the states of Colorado and Wyoming. Capitol Building. The condition of the Capitol Building should also command your attention. It is entirely inadequate to properly house the various departments of the state government. The business of the commonwealth has grown to such proportions in recent years that many of the departments are handicapped in the handling of it, by reason of their cramped and crowded condi- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE tions. This is noticeably true of the Supreme Court, the State Health Department, the Pure Food Department, the Fire Com - missioner's Department and the Labor Department. To any one who has observed the quarters occupied by the Supreme Court, the disadvantages under which that body operates must be apparent. The State Library, valued at more than a half million dollars and containing thousands of volumes that could not be replaced, is absolutely without fire protection and many of the depart - ments are compelled to vacate their quarters at each session of the legislature, to make room for the officials of that body. There is another and even more serious situation to be con - sidered. The State Engineer reports that the south wall of the east wing has settled seven inches and a slight additional set - tling will cause that section of the building to collapse. It does not require technical knowledge to enable one to determine that that portion of the building is in immediate need of atten - tion. It would be folly for the legislature to adjourn without having taken remedial measures. There are three courses open: First: To repair the east wing of the building. This could be accomplished at no great cost, but such moneys as were expended would eventually be lost, for the congested condition of the departments would not be relieved, and within a few years at best, the ever increasing business of the state would make a new building an economic necessity. Second: To construct a new Capitol Building. This course would seem to be inexpedient at this time because of the abnor - mally high cost of building material, and for the further reason that to levy a sufficient tax to immediately cover the cost of an adequate state house would work a hardship upon the tax payers of the state. Third: To provide for a building commission to serve with - out pay. Decide upon a definite plan for a new Capitol, levy a tax extending over a number of years, to cover cost of sam&gt;* and erect a part of it, replacing the east wing of the present building. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 15 This plan would relieve the present congested conditions in the departments. The money spent would be permanently invested and there would be no burden upon the tax payers. The slightly increased cost of building piecemeal would be much more than offset by the reduced cost of building material when prices return to normal, and everything considered, the people's interests would best be conserved. National Guard. Six months ago the National Guard was called into the service of the country for the first time since 1898. The ranks of the companies were filled by willing recruits and the regi - ments left for the Mexican border, well officered and in excellent spirits, eager to be of service to their country and not knowing what hardships were to be endured, or what sacrifices might be demanded. In marked contrast to the excellent spirits of the men was their lack of proper and modern equipment. The crisis that caused the calling of the Guard to the border has passed. The Nebraska regiments will return shortly, after months of training under the most advantageous conditions, a splendid military organization, well officered and well equipped, and one in which the people of Nebraska can and should take a just pride. No one can foretell how soon these troops will be ordered to take the field for a more serious and important service. A month before the outbreak of the world war now devastating Europe, no one would admit of its possibility. The people of the nation are opposed to a large standing army. We must depend upon the National Guard as the nucleus of our fighting forces. There is an obligation resting upon the members of this leg - islature. You should give thoughtful consideration to the recommendations of the State's Military Department and enact such legislation as may be necessary to maintain the Guard in a reasonable state of efficiency, and to protect the property and equipment of that body, for which protection the state is responsible. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE Supreme Court Commission. In 1915 the Legislature created the Supreme Court Commis - sion. The work of the body began on September 20th of that year, at which time there were on the docket of the Su - preme Court of the state 978 cases undisposed of. On December 11th, 1916, there were 777 cases undisposed of, a gain of 201 cases in fifteen months. The cases disposed of in that time by the Commission number 299. Since justice delayed is often jus - tice denied, it is of the greatest importance that the Commission be continued. Hotel Commission. Under the laws of the State, it is the duty of the hotel inspectors, of which there are two, to visit each hotel for pur - poses of inspection at least once each year. Such a system cannot produce satisfactory results. It is also the duty of the pure food and drug department to make inspections in all hotels serving meals. The Hotel Commission should be consolidated with the Pure Food and Drug Department, thereby enabling the state to exercise effectual supervision over hotels and doing away with the duplication of effort by the inspectors of the two depart - ments under the present system. Permanent Roads The problem of permanent roads is one that should have your most earnest consideration. The fact that we have no natural material in Nebraska for hard surface roads would make the cost of such a system prohibitive. This knowledge on the part of the people of the state and the fear that local authorities would be deprived of a voice in determining where roads should be constructed and that money subscribed would not be spent for local benefit has aroused considerable antag - onism to any plan whatever. No success can be attained without the co-operation of a considerable majority of the people, and </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 17 any plan adopted should be inaugurated upon a conservative scale. The Federal Government has appropriated $75,000,000.00, to be distributed during the next five years among the several states of the Union for the betterment of roads over which the mails are carried. The principal obligations resting upon the states is that they shall provide a like amount, that through state supervision it will be intelligently spent without waste, that the roads be of a permanent nature and that provision for their maintenance be made. By permanent roads it is not meant that they must be of brick, concrete or of other hard surface character. Wonderful results have been obtained in Nebraska by a combination of clay and gravel — and even dirt and gravel — and these classes of roads meet the requirements of the Federal Act. It is not intended that the money should be spent upon one highway across the state. To accomplish the greatest good to the greatest number of people is the object and aim of the measure. There must be some responsible state body through which the Good Roads Fund would be distributed. This body should co-operate with the county authorities and act in an advisory capacity with reference to road making. It would also be a duty of this body to see to it that the Federal requirements were fulfilled and that a satisfactory return be received for the money expended. The cost of such road construction should be borne equally by the counties and by the Federal Government. In instances where the roads constructed connect county seats, thereby facilitating inter-county travel and being of general, as well as local benefit, state aid should be given, the cost being borne one-third by the county, one-third by the state and one-third by the Federal Government. Where feasible, convict labor should be utilized in the construction of roads. If a plan is worked out along the line of these suggestions and followed during the next five years an excellent start will </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE have been made towards a comprehensive system of permanent roads. Workmen's Compensation. In 1913 a "Workmen's Compensation Act was passed, based upon the principle that the injuring of an employe was as much a liability to the employer as the breaking of a valuable piece of machinery. The operation of this act has vindicated the judgment of the legislature, for during the past eleven months 5,411 cases have been successfully disposed of with benefit to the employed and to the employer. The measure is not a perfect one. There are two principal defects in it that should be corrected by this legislature. First: The compensation is in many instances inadequate. Second: The injured employe is not protected against the insolvency of his employer. Water Power. The natural resources of the state should be conserved and the development of water power from the streams of the state as authorized by law should be encouraged to the end that our people will be benefited. Appropriations. You should be economical in the expenditure of the public funds. All necessary appropriations should be made. No appro - priations for needless or impractical purposes should be con - sidered. I heartily endorse the recommendation made in 1915 by my illustrious predecessor to the effect that all appropriation bills should be considered early in the session at which time they would have the careful attention of the members of the Legislature. Senatorial Vacancies. In 1913 the XVII amendment to the Constitution of the United States was adopted, providing that United States Senators should </seg>
            <seg id="p019">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1917 19 be elected by direct vote of the people. The Legislature should direct in what manner vacancies in the United States Senate are to be filled. In conclusion, I express conviction that the relations between the Legislative and Executive departments during the session will be cordial and that the measures enacted will be of great benefit to the people of the state. KEITH NEVILLE. </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>