<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00039.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00039.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Seventh Annual Report of the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1915-12-28">1915-12-28</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">S Har Mis B.J Ott( Seventh Annual Report of the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner of the State of Nebraska RidfleU, - Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner F. Requartte, .... Assistant Assistant Mamie Muldoon. Secretary Inspector Murschel, Inspector McArdle. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">It I i i 1 1 1 • M \ III f 3 si:\ KNTll AXXl'AL KKI1&gt;KT. office of Stale File &lt; 'uiiiiiiissiinii r Stah i i|iitol. Lincoln. Neliraska. Hecemlter L'N. l!tl."». \lnnht ml. (Inn nun- nj tin &gt; iniiliaiicc witli lln' lMrc ( 'oiniiiissiini Law nf Ni I licicw ii li snltiuil t&lt;t von the St'Yt-ntli Aiiini.'il il tliis I tc|i;ll 1 Iliclll. Aid Ih ;iinl «rti. icn&lt;\ of this I &gt;c|p.i 11 niciil is sti-:itlily « tiuni vciif to vcar ami as the officials whose ihitv \\ ii-iipfiatc with us arc Itccttiniu^ aci|iiaintcil with lid its cmIim* til the Stale, its effect is Ikmujj seen. iicineii &lt;il' the slate whose liusitiess is I lie prevent ill xtiuffuiMbing "f Hr«" *w lieartilv inteicstiMl in uiviu assistance possiltle ami this IK*|wii*tiiieiit ami the nciallv has in iit-li to thank them for. Daring the ■ t vcar I lit' tire chiefs throughout the state have rc|toi-te&lt;l us |(ioin|iilv ami cuinjiletelv each tire occiiiini: in tliei: - alities. atxl w heiievef we have asked for particular ii: - ination concerning investigations they have most will Iv ci»n|ilieil with our i-e&lt;|Uest. We desire, through the il i ii in of this report, to extend one sincere thanks to ■iv tile chief ihroiiiihout tile stale for their assistance I interest in this iic|&gt;artnicnt and in the worthy cause tire |iri'vciiiiou. The tiieinan's duty does not begin en ilie call of tire is made; that is tin- ItegintiUiK "f 'I' 1 ' N I'.lil III Hill. -I (ill II II 'nli i, I \i hi ii xk n : </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 \ \ \ I end; his tlulv l.ruins in iirpvcutiun ml \ iii'c.llcss, iliinui'roiix hi-- lisizsml I'|KK.\ S ! In Kii /.i mil ( .11 in mil uiilv i'\i iti} uf liiiv TIm'H if i w hi ill ill. 1 iir.iti Whraxka I "it v« Ynrk. Ki-cnion w lirrr llii'V ii'iiiln !:&lt;■ i-iilli'il ii|inii in liiiln tin iiiiI uiilv |iru\f uf v;ilii iiinl rilin-iii ing |ii'.i|iii \' limn &lt; m-«ii ri nii. thin ii&lt; lii&gt; ln'in inu «iii/.«ii&gt; clciin ii|&lt; ili iititboritv in I" lui/.iinis Ihih lit lically c\ci\ I'iic &lt; illll lloi .\ V hi ( liluiii- 1 1 1 1 • I* iinvc ilv ;i&lt; well. We iiiiw iiiisMoiiii! with .mi li I'irt- I'oiiiliiiKsiull l.;\&gt; r"lh|M ll-.ll mil i &lt; &lt; • n i ii i ii it i i \ . 1 IniiMiiiiTM iiihI Ik hi' klluws liclliT I will) till- const Ilii Hani I v iii|in'sici| hihI ;i Hremen dniini; I in- |mk1 • hllilll.l. Sulllll nili;|||;|. LilU-olll. &lt;il. 111. I IK-V. CollllnltllK, I'll'.. III! II I'lulli &lt;■;!&lt; Ill- llrMUllJIIcil In inspect Ill-IM luil would In* of IM </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 COMMISSION I I &gt;ni ill in i i ii n Willl IIU additional expense for ipeal III till' II It'll MM M Ilinsl pin ill nut inli'i fere with anv of their ii divergence from their ordinaiv licnch'eial In themselves ;is Well ;is e volunteer tire dcparimcnis, the vil niplov ;i couple nt men t preferalilv Mil pay tlleln iilxilil X.'t.OU per &lt;|;l\ fur ■iieli Spiini; ;ilii| l-'iill t«i in^pecl tin - expense would lie of imilieil&gt;e Viihle ulil interest the citizens hum 1 I ally in lelnises iiixl freeing them friini tile liHintl in k«mm1, .1' Miine Iliulilll-. ml. I lie fiillnwccl ineilieil. s;lfe enll'lit inn nceil while thiisc foinnl in up until I he ihinuer I ii-s awl luwns thiit e;in .illuiil it. !&lt;• n chemical ;iin| hose \\a»oiis. (or wher. u lire \\ i I li&lt; n 1 1 (lie nsi- uf water |e|- 1 1 ; i iii.il;'' will lie climina tcil. nislier is ;i yreat factiir in I lie tin veiv liiisiiiess house ami store in nie nr more, acconliiii: In the size Ii. I I'Vrlv llnine shnlllil lie praiviileil die sin. ill e\i iii^nisli.T will put mil ami is niie ut ihe iinpnrtant appli- ki- Oiiialw, Suiiili Om;ili;i. Lincoln w « irk &lt;&gt;t' in-|icii inn sliniilii In 1 &lt;-;ii'- •ni lin- lighting ;i|&gt;|&gt;;ii;ii us should In* In- tii-riiirii iii ilu-ir work. Solilirr* wiili wliicli in Hglil ilicii- cnt'inics. I ilii' liiinilv i, ni-lii liu\\ in I'hsl. liii- |ii'i'\iiii inn Unix i-ini'iit . </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 EVEN II \\\ I'llIK ( UlIlM IV II lias iImij.- nun l-'iie &lt; o|- lllilVM|-&gt;. \\ Mi.li iiivcsii^;iiiiiii w I tssiii-y. Tlu- otlici ■!■ h iii cii its. villnscx. t«« smmI l'iic ( '.piiniiis occiii relict' of i tit' lire, i iirni il Wiil li-il sl;lleilielH ilf ;lll lire ;illil ranw ;iinl The prompt ii U-f .-is-sis:* lit Khali lie Ik'uuh within r his deputy sli; I Mn nij: tin- i "iniiiL: year wi HUVnrs ,llhi lire &lt;-]lic Is c&lt; &gt;1 1 1 1 • ;is follow K : "Si-,-. 6011. Chapter XVII. &lt;&gt;f NClir. litiiii. . Pirn*. ln\ Slate Pin* ('iniiiuisnioiM-i- him] i i it-n i ul cvciv rin nr nlliijji is ••siMltlislifil, siikI i In- mayor i i- low ii in « liicii ii" tii i- ileji liate ilic ci!U&gt;r. iiHuhi uihI &lt;m-»iii riii&gt;: in siic-h « • i i \ i»r xil county when i -riiiii'sicd by il :....... ... i .1. .. .: . .i. .. 1 1 ! ini*i i-&gt; ictl iliiiiMii Khali mve&gt; iirrlllli&gt;tilllri-s i.| cvi'l •&gt;■ lilr &lt;&gt; mil i li&lt;- limit* &gt;'( miy itrjzauiz which |iru|icii \ hao Itwn Hi- • -|&gt;i'ii:illy make itiveHtigatioii i In- reMnll uf carelessness nr </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 i ie luniks m-oviiU-il !i\ •siti'liT. Ill:- Mjilc Illr rOIIIIIHSMlOliel Ilitc ;| |vr«,|-.| uC ail Ii Its will. |i ni;iv In investigation* prorkk**] Iv this ju-i : ■II ill! lillli- l;c lipni III |ll&lt;- jllllllil KAS.wt'K. I Any otlicci- itI'i-i-i-im! |«i in I s I \nv iiftii-er referred in in i .who nculcr'x In ioiii|tl\ with illiv &lt;&gt;l uiiplv with jiiiv of I this ;nl sluiil lie |iiini--]|(. 1 | | IV ;i tile |ilini-hcil l&gt;\ ;i tin \&lt;hi.v-tivc hulhiis. ii. Ji- more r li:i ii Tw.i live l»u||;iis. 11 • if nnire [)|;||I T\\&lt; Pi;k\ km i&lt;&gt;\ So* iktiks. III i-^siniu* a Pirr 1'i-rvciiiiun s&lt;icict\ m i Fire I'leveiitinn SuciiM\ in l.lti 1 , ll;l\c the |i|-o|tc|-lv ii\viic|-s bntMIH' |n&lt;i|ti-i-lv HWiirrs Imh-uiiii «• iiiinii!iTti;ll cllili.v ;ilnl wciiili-nV rlu!i&gt; I wdiiicnV cln!i&gt; ■.'!i!i- ililfir~lc&lt;l. li;nf tin' niiivurs ,'iuil icri-tiil, hjivf the iiiiivurs nml silli' :| lIslV Ml ll'MSl twice ;l \«'ill- I CVCI-V ilay at h'.isi tw'wr ;i rmr i cvciv s .1 "I- l«*;l 11-11] •"* lla.T, « Ih'll i*Vt'l\- cili/.rll ii-ii|&gt; ilay, « hen ev« i ry ritu I iii rlciin up his premium ;in&lt;l mnkc i»fn, we WMilil |i;ivc ;iccuni|ilisli i| nil M|&gt; his premises him] mill' iVinild 1i:i\i- .H(HiM|&gt;lisli i| ■xtniimi linrs. ltnl&gt;l&gt;iv||. uilv r;iirs. &lt;-\- rtiv. &lt; Hd ilil;i|ii&lt;Li ifd lniil.1 in^s an* n ksIv h;lliillfi| uiisnliiic ami iiwl nil is ;i !!i&gt;iiiiiis .mil liicw (ii-ks rl;iiiu t li&lt; - i i- milt'il uiisiiliiM- an«l ttMiJ nil is i* . i ii*l lirew oi-ks i-lniui tin uniiiii livm i'vciv rear. \ ■li' Mil Mniclics rnliltl Iniik illlu the ■ (l;lll{*&lt;&gt;n« ;ilii| ililrli'st llicir luliiliilMlily We \\ i«i|| \\r ii &gt;| 1 1 &lt; I li,i\c tlirsc Z&lt; Hi Tilllv llirnilulH'lll illr &gt;t.llc. Stats I-'ii:k I &gt;av. Hid illlelest their • i iinlii lltli M We wish \\r inlllil ll.ixe 1 1 llv llll-uituliolll llle -l;ilc. FlUK I ni 1!»1 1 cll;icti'i| ;i l;l\\ clf;l!ill^ ;l Kile Tin' lirsi Krulav of NOvciiiln'i- is ;in- !'.•! 1 cll;ictei| ;i l;l\\ rntltill" ;l Kile I'iic l&gt;;i\ in tins ritatc. TIm- follttw-iu^ i i-sin-,1 h\ ( iii\iMiii&gt;i' .Mui-i-li&lt;-iiil ;i!-k i nii W lln- &lt;I;i\ ill .Mi ii|i|iiu|iri;ilc nuililici. III is ;||so | &gt; ji II 1 1'&lt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SEVENTH AXNIWI. RKIflR'l "FlKK I&gt;AY I'ltlMI.AMATION Sl;itl' of NVIinixki I'liiMI.AMA Til IX I V TIIK l.oVKKNu "One &lt;&gt;l &lt;mr iiinsi ritnl |ii-olili'iiis is tin- i|iicsiiuii ii| tin- \\;l.»lc. T\\i&gt; tlimls ul till' Sl'.IKMI.IIIMI MIIHIUll till' |n-&gt; : \ i • I &gt; I : I s k ; I is illlc tn r;l|-rli-ssnrss ;ilnl iliirinli;l risni, a IK I is .'III illisollitr \\;lslr .mil &lt;lr;lin 1 1 ) )• 1 1 1 dill lo.Hil res. I ;l|i|niillt rvt I \ pMid lili/.cll ill I hi' s( ;l 1 &lt; • ill Nrlir;lsk;| ;l roll I iniiicc iif our iii ;iiil in |»rrvefltiiig Irm by iiu-ciiiliiii ism ; :iM-i'il;iiliillu :is IH'jirly ;i&gt; |»issili|c when insiirnni r is Immiiu (;illi&lt;'i| I'm' a |OT«ter niuolilil lli;m llir v.-ililc of tin- |irn|i (;iiii&lt;'il I'm' a irreMt«*r aiiHiuni than tin- rahw of tin- i»roii (llv. I ll:l\r lilt (lull \\ lull .1 lirliliniiv \;ilnr i&gt; |il:iri-i| nil ritv. I Ii:i\i- lilt that when a !irliliuii&gt; ml lie it) | &gt; I :i &gt; t-&lt; t n |H n|iil I \ . I lit- li-lll|&gt;l;ll inll is Inn Itmil Iii Irvi.-l lin- ilcslllli- tion of iluii property. I lum- ;ihv;iys rmisiilciTil iluii this is the ilirrct riiusi- ul' h lifcjii iiiiMninl of the luss l,\ Mir in t ainiMint nl' tin' I i ilcsircs liiwcl' r; inn- si;iic. l^iirh ritiieu wliu ilcsircs lower raten of inwir- iiiur sliunlil kelp 1 1 1 * - i'iir ( '&lt;tiiiiiiis&gt;inii I &gt;i-|&gt;;ii-i im-in in i;rtlinp pill ul' i;lli'li'&gt;Mns&gt; .ilhl ilKilnli.l I i&gt;ln. "Tin- hank ittutninti la* bun ii-ilmcil t h«- ItMiik i;iilnir&gt; "Tlic hank "iiai'silltv law lia&gt; ii-ilnri-i| tin- dank fi |ii'it-i|iiilil\ in mil- shiic. itinl in u&lt; li nl it is In &lt; &gt; n Li 1 1 1 nImniI |ii'iri|ililil\ in our stair, it ml mm li nl it is ln«nij{ hv cadi hunk luiit til ntin^ tbfir &gt;h;n &lt;■ t&lt;&gt; tin- -u.i l;\ ciirli lunik i-uiii iii mini: tln'ir xhttre to lin- uu.n .iiitci fninl niiikin^ ilinn m &gt;-&lt; &gt;m an i 1 1 &lt;•&lt;■ in (jItp sih-Ii iiiforniMtimi I'iiiiiI makiuc tin-in a iiiiiiiiiitii-i' to i;i\ m i it «- Itaakiug Ihwnl .is will ahl in helping to k«*|i tin I .inks ln;lli;lj:('&lt;l ill M s;ilV ;lllil i i&gt;iimi\ ;il i\ r \\;l\. \\i I anks inanai:iil in a sale ami roiiwrvatire wax. \\ slmiilil ctinsiilcr t Ik- iiisin-i-i| in tin- *»m*e \\ . i \ mh «*«• iln ill. I ;ink l;iw. Largv Iusm-- inrrvaar iln- rate*, am iinlii cctly ilinsr wlm raiTr iiisiiiiinrc ; 1 1 • - sincUlmliliis ii imlii cit I y ilmsr wlin rarrx insiiram llic ciiiii|'jiiiirs TIh'.v rail niilv pz|iec1 rh««Jt iiisin;iiirc l&gt;\ I'i'diiciiij; tin 1 iierceiitsip* ul Inss. "Tlici-cfuif, in ;iilil;i inn tn \\li;ti tin- Itefmty Kir* &lt; 'tun i inissioncr luis tn siiy ill liis nn-ssii^c in the ] &gt;«■«») »l&lt; -. I w.iii tn s.-iv tliiii we slmiilil all niil in iluini; «mr |i;nt in li'nm'1 llic {.'Vent li»ss liy the rjiliscs nielli inlii'il |"tii\cn nnili-r my Innnl this Ilili ifaiv nl' &lt; »ciiili&lt;-r. I'.ilTi. •••liHIX II MiiKKIIKAK. " ( i'll'i I' HOI'. n i nni </seg>
            <seg id="p009">KIRK COMMISSION 9 \ Ii;ii "."&gt; per rent of I lit* enoruioiiH tire •\ is directly iln«' to carelessness and S We are living ;it a time in the history of oar when tilt- &lt;| nest ion of tin- preservation of resources. Plie preservation uf iiuy kind of propertj from any kind if waste slioiilil receive tile Utmost consideration from the general public. One of our most vital problems, and one ling for rapid solution is the problem of our innecessarv .11 id avoidable tin- waste; s"J.~&gt;n. MMt.MIKI of i •onsli-ilcteii property annually destroyed by tile n a direct rejii-oaeli npoB our civil irovcrn incuts ami upon people. Two-thirds of the f2.000,MM annual h"re lo&gt;&gt; Neliraska is due lo carelessness, ami is an absoluii- ancl iliain apoa our resources. It is deplet \\\&gt;i the of our slate. We are bimiinir &lt;lo\\n almost as fast are building up. No state or nation can long emlure lisolute \va&gt;le ami drain without feeling I he effects lost unfavoralile way. The Neliraska Legislature of 1911, having in miiul the n^t ivaiinn of tin- resources of our state, created a Fire l»;i\ Law aii&lt;l set aside ly law the First Friday if N'ovem each year to lie known and observed as State Fire Kverv citizen in the state should take an interest 1 iinportant matter of tire prevention and observe Fire May by a general cleaning up and removal of The Mayers of every city and village in the stale il proflamat ions asking their citizens to •o-opeiale in cleanini: up ■■d irinovinir all tire dangers. riic iit\ or village should furnish men and teams free &lt;&gt;f haul away all waste and rubbish. All Fire &lt;'hiefs should make a special inspection of their rritoi v and compel the chanire of any conditions which woiilil tend to eliininale tlie possibility of a Hie. Kverv &lt; 'onni'crcial Club in the state should have a Fire I'reveiitioii i 'ominillee. The commit tee should send out .1 call asking all citizens to cn-nperate in making I-"ire Da&gt;' a real Clean P|i l»ay. Woman's Clul s sliould lake an interest in the May and ■rali'il. is receiving ■ !jn'itt &lt;l&lt;";|] Of ;ll tcllt inn. isli ;in&lt;l \\;i-tc from their preniiw*. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SEVENTH ANXI'AL UKl'tilt'l i i A X ask every member to look into their Jiome eooditioufl wit ii view of abolitthing every poarible th-c danger. Heatiag apparataa, electric wiring and chimney* ttaou lie carefally Rose over and placed in a proper conditi&lt; for winter use. Public iiml private institutions, stores, factories, jjara&lt;:i and all business houses should lie inspected ;nn| ai changes made that will farther protect the premises fro tire. The public press can le ■ |»o\vefful factor iii the mov inetit of Fire Prevention. I»v instinctive ami timely pn liciitions they can interest the pabik* as no other fact* CJIJl. Teaching Fire I'uevention in oru S( Fire drills should be held on Fire Day in every pnl and private school in the state. The teaching of Fire I veiition in oar schools is a state law. and at this time heg to thank the teachers of the state for their real lerest in this important study. It will !«• the stri o|| Prevention impressed on their youim. alert niiml&gt; \\\ will after all l»e the ones who in ■ few years will reall hv\v&lt;x into the home and the Imsiness world a ranipaip of Fire Prevention that will materially decrease our (jm unnecessary tire loss. Teacher* will liinl iaterewting |&gt;i grains for l^ire I &gt;ay outlined in the Fire I'reveiition Te: Book* which the Fire ('ommissioii 1 &gt;epaitmeiit has fu nislie&lt;l them. We earnestly request every teacher to a ranjie and outline a program which will instnni and f tertain the papila. It would he well to arrange su&lt;l program as would interest the parents and let the pit] ask their parents to visit the school on the afternoon Friday, Novemlier 5th, ltla. i:es|tectfllll\ f'liirf Iti/niti/ Fin i'uiiuiiixsimit i children of today who ;ii-o bavii \V. S. RlIKiKIX. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 STATE KIKK COMMISSION i mi: snnv t»r fiijk 1'kkvkxtiox in sniooi.s With the end in \ icw, of rdaca Hag the public in this in 1 m &gt; i-r ;i 11 f subject, Nebraska lias taken tin- lead of all ither M;it&lt; -s ill tcacliiiiic lire prevention in Iht schools. A aw passed \-.\ the legislature of 1S)11 makes this a coni - mlsoi v branch of i-iliit-ation in this state. Nebraska lias the distinction of having in her schools I lie lh&gt;t complete and comprehensive text I k every pub - lished on this subject. The book was written and copy - righted by .Miss .Mamie Muldoou, Secretary of this I &gt;e |iartiuent. who s|»eiit over two years coinpiliiig it. As Miss Mnldoon has lieen Secretary of tliis department since it&gt; DTganiiUltioii and lias for several years Imhmi intereste«l in tire prevention work, she was most alily &lt;|iialiried to write .1 book &lt;•(' this kind The Iwiok is graded into lessons ranj;- 11 ir from the kindergarten throagh the Hijjh Brhoel. It oveis every pliasi- of i lie subject of tire prevention, &lt;-on - ains valnalile statistics and an elaborate treatise on tire ice. rale making, etc. Several other states in tli&lt; niiing the merits of the hook, are now makin cuts lo adopt it as they recognize its worth and •re iinxions to have a standard, uniform text hook on the siilijed to I.e nniversallv used, in schools. Fire l*roteetfcm," the leading tire prevention magazine of the I'nileil Stales, and the official paper of the Fire Marshals' Amnriatioii of North America, eoininentiii)! upon this liook recently, says: "Mis .Mamie .Mnldoon. Secretary of the Xehraska State I' ire ( 'onimission. has compiled and issued a school hook entitled. 'Lessons on Fire Prevention," for the instruction of children in tire prevention. It is an elaborate volume. and contains ;i series of lessons on tire prevention mid on tar effects of tire caielessness, for all the. grades, be&lt;:in aiag with simple stories and rhymes for the kindergarten and raaaiag through such statistical and anylytical pre - sentations of the subject as are appropriate for the lasr years of hijjli Hcbool. The lessons are not lonjr, hut they are comprehensive and admirably adapted to tlie uwmIs of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SKVKNTIl ANNTAI. ItKI'olM tlic respective pile*. If intelligently and carefully tangbi they should pnve ■■ effective agency ill »•&lt; 1 1 n-;i I i I iii tin children of the state to tlie need of tire prevent ion ami t&lt; inculcate in them habits of careful nesv "In effect, this lx&gt;ok marks the l&gt;ej;inniinj of ;i ire pre - vention literal nre. of which there may In* said to lie prac - tically none. And one is liadlv needed. The National Fire Protection Association emphasized that fad when ii issued its program for the observance of Fire Prevention Day, a couple of months ago. T(Hi much dependence should not be laid on edwatiaf children along this line. U'caiist- the real work lo lie done can he accomplished nnh liv appealing to the mature judgment and common sense of intelligent men and women, or by compelling them to In lire-carefnl where they will not of their own volition; but as an adjunct to this broader work it has a distinct lield of usefulness and should not lie neglected. The I i - ipicstion in. i\ he regarded as a tine start in the devc incut of a tire prevention literal nre. without which no prerialile decree of success could We hoped of educational work, and Neln-aska is to he that an employee of its Fire Commission ha: make so auspicious a beginning in this respi Teaching the vonth of the conntrx liabil caution regarding lire danger* mniit certainh result in nn limited good to the nation. Heretofore children of this country have not lieeii t aniili t the value of a match Hoi have they heen told of its destructive powers. In Kiiropeaii countries children are not allowed to play with matches and use them as "inexpensi ve toys."" The foreigner does noi throw matches carelessly about liecanse they are cheap. From childhood he has lieen taught habit* of economy. Not only will the teaching of lire preventMHi result in re - ilncinu that part of the tire waste of I he mail try due to children's carelessness and net: licence. 1 hi t &lt; in ■ child will • any home to his parents accounts id' the lessons he has lieen taught and the parents in this manner will haw called to their attention dangerous lialiils and conditions which they have never noticed hefore and which they will willingly correct. The child, when he leaven school, will </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE KIKE COMMISSION 13 tilled into his mind principle! ainl adrice, concern - &lt;l;tn^cis iiiul how to avoid them tliat must ulli- tell the value of this branch of education in re- itnral recKHircea, our forests, oar water ., and it certainly must appeal to every (Iliiient. alert, progressive individual that SOT run tictive resources should be preserved and a decided re- de in our nation's annual tire waste of s-j.iii. 11(10.(1(1(1.(1(1. Insurance is only a distributor of tliis loss collecting from uianv policy holders the amount sufficient unify the policy holders having a tire. We all con - oiir share to this ash heap of |25O,OOO,O0OJt. The iRnrance companies distribute our contributions; the ro|ierty and material destroyed l&gt;v lire is absolutely anil rahlv lost. i «mi- educnt ioual efforts will ressh in a decided n the lire losses of Nebraska, which aniout to nt !\\(i million dollars aunuall. The annual lire losses \«'l&gt;raska as reported to tliis otTice since its orjrani/.a- Almosi ten million dollars consumed by tire and rele d to ;ishcs in a short period of six years, jind the tail I losses would probably reach twelve million dollars, cause undoubtedly, a large number of tires are not re- ported to this department. This is surely an appalling situation and should make every citizen feel the necessity of curtailing this territic drain upon the wealth and pro- gress of our state. l&gt;i!iin&lt;r tlie rear 1913, 1.J14 tires in cities and towns were reported to us with a total loss of $1,758,231.00. Phis, however, with the loss on farm property amounting in $31,(139.00 makes, accordinu to our records, a total lo&gt;&gt; lit' stiitc. \\Y ti'iich ami piriirli con- follows : 1910 92,181,658.00 Hill l.Tss.ii':i.:{(i 1!UL' 2.251.774.33 1913 1,715,676.10 1!»14 l.ST^.OTl.lT. I91"i l.TSlt.L'f.'.t.oll iii ill.- st:it.' for 191 Ti of *1,7S9^»6».&lt;M&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SRVRNTI1 ANN! At. UKi'OUl The value of ciiv property actually on tire ami in &lt; I ; 1 1 1 «i« • I- of total destruction l.isl year was (12^58,712.4M). the amount actually destroyed was f 1,758^231 .00. This dierence of *10,N(HI,4S1.00 is a splendid trilmte to I In- Hi tii'iicv of our tiri' departments, hot li paid and rolnateer. Our fire departments, are indeed arsenals of safely and |»rotcction fur oar slate. Too much credit c;imiot U jjiven our lire fighters for tlieir v;iliant ti«*lil in the cause of the coiiservat ion of life ;ind property from dewtroctiou by tire. They are not soldiers in an inhuman war of de struction l.ut soldiers in a humane war of preservation. Every citizen of the state owes them irratitute and iti oiteratton. and this I &gt;epai tmeiit wishes tfl thank tliem most heartily for their assistaine and interest in tins work of tire prevent ion. caki:u:ss. ixm;« i:ssai:v kirkk Pron 70 per cent to 7.". per cent of the tiro which din ignorance, carelessness or neglect. This nun due to carelessness can lie eliminated by care. ( ai cleanliness. Defective chilnlievs or chilli liev* l if I lii^&lt; -&lt; t nuaor wood, caused 158 Area this rear. Twelve oruininated in doilies" rloMetfl l ( \ s|iarks in matches, lighted lani|»s and candles. It is ; i very dang ous thiny to take matches, or candles into dark dus.-i - s&lt;H' to pet clothing. No one should ever place a lamp it clothes closet and «o awav and leave it luirniii". Twenty-four tires caused by -Itovs smoking.' tramp* sinokiii}: in vacant houses or haitis. "and by I'ifCar IN cigarettes carelessly thrown away while iiiirnin^." is indeed a deplorable waste and destruction of property which could easily be avoided if men would always see that their cigars or cigarettes are not bamiaf when they throw i Ik- in awav. I lefective electric wiring caused 2fi tires. lOIectric wires should he carefully installed and examined fre&lt;|uently by nut onlv in Xcliiiiska imt in the I'liitcil Sl;il( </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE I IKK COMMISSION 15 • &gt;lll ) M't t-ll t electricians. Twent\ -seven tires c;iiiseil hv oil srnves exploding 01 arele»&gt;ness with &gt;;iine « onhl lie prevented liV using llll) iiiitiim. Twenty-live tires moan] by defective furnaces, over - leated furnace hi- having rubbish, wood, etc.. Inn near tile Miinne. n.iilil. with :i little rate and attention 1m' inateii lllv reduced. The (i'.t tires caused liv ignition of gasoline in various ways could he lessened in nuinlier, and tlie amount of mage ilone. if llie people of the state could he educated the fact that gasoline is a most dangerous explosive id must always be handled and stored with great care. The 1(» "lamp" tires could he reduced with a little care nd attention from the housewife. Matches are i&gt;or most prolific cause of tires. The danger children playing with matches is forcibly emphasized n the fact that ."if. tires originated by matches in the hands if children. We have repeatedly recommended the use of Safely .Matches only, and even these should lie kept safely iiwav from small children. Six tiie&gt; from "rubbish lying around or l&gt;eing carelessly irned" is gross carelessness. Fitift \ -nine tires caused from "overheatiMl stoves." oves with no •'protection underneath." loo close to wall wood," or baring "ruliliish lying around ahont the •ve." hot coals dropping from stove upon the Himii*." lothillg banging too near stove to dry." "stove-pip*' hole ■toplM-d with raj;s." "stove-|»ipe throuirh rriiing, raof or a nod partition," could be avoided. .Manx of the L'S tires cause*! liv s]iontaueous i omliiisl iuii ould be prevented with a little care. This list of careless tires should l&gt;iin» to the mind of every thoughtful man and woman the importance of re - ducing our great lire losses through these careless causes. Every citizen should lie impressed with a sense of duly and feel his individual responsibility in reducing this tire loss. The reduction of the tire Iomm of Nebraska should appeal to every man. woman and child as one of their most important duties. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SKVKXT1I AXXIAI. HKI'oItl 1 hi ring tin- past year 385 Brett ban; hrai report***! io u with the MMMK of t lit* lire »iven as ■* I " n k now 1 1." W hi 1 undoubtedly ihere are a ntuuber of lues wliosc nr.^i can not l&gt;c accounted lor, yet vearc sure if tiremen wouii invest iji;i t «' the cause of each ire thoroughly, it would no In- necessary to Mark so niiiny "unknown." Imviv eondi lion surrounding the ire should Ik- carelully invest i^aied 1 1n* parties owninu the Inn-nrd property KMoatd l»&lt;- critic ally &lt;|iicsiioiicd regardiug us origin, and every detail si thoroughly exuiuiuwl that, if a( all (MHwilile, the aiiua lausc id' the (ire will be asccitaiiu-d i.f Ire tlepartiueutM will give thi* aiotti ini|&gt;oitaiit matt* dm- rcui.-idcnii ion ai i'v&lt;-i\ lire they attend. IIAM»U\&lt;; (JAKOLIXK KAFEM Wv have iccoiimifiidi'd thai iii &lt;|iiainiiit&gt; exceeding live galloiiK, slim-Id ki-fi. &gt; Ktoied in itafe uwlergi-ouu«l tanks wlicn- the khmi diction as to how combiisti M bunk! lie sioicil. The law is as follow "Anv baikliug or btracture, which. sinli building or premises who shall cause, continue n maintain any such nuisance Khali lie gailty of a misdi meanor, and on coiiviciion thereof, -hall lie lined in an I N KNOWN FIREH \\ &lt;• iniist f;iilif.-l iv I'l-ijiii-sl thai lire cliiHs ;iihI be l-iiii in through a pip*' •• ■&gt;&lt; I pn nij hi I mi Heetiuo Five «&gt;l ilic lire L'ouuuisttioii Law repair, or by remtoa of age or tlilapi«hii any caoae, u&gt; t-npeeially liable to tire, au&lt;l which in &gt;&lt;&lt; iiaicd m t&lt;&gt; endanger &lt;&gt;t her ItailtlingH, i* pi «&gt;|ici i v ; and , ronilnistililt' or expkw»ve uatcrial, i»r iuflauiHisihle coi iii»ns, placed, kept, or exifttiuK in wr npon any buildiuj; |ii-«'iniscs wliicli is &lt;l;in^cruii&gt; li&gt; ilic s;ilVi\ of kmhI I &gt; ■ i i 1 * I i up jH'ciuiscs anil t lit' same is so xituuttNl as in cinlan other buildings or property, is hereby deeuiei] an&lt;i i tared to Ik- ■ Dniaaace; and any owner or imtiiiuiuI </seg>
            <seg id="p017">IT IKl DM MISSION exceeding the sum of 95OO.OU and the court shall id nuisance to Iw abated." ay thai practically every merchant retailing gasoline in Nebraska keeps Ins HUppiy stored at least three feet under ground in i. inks where the gasoline can Ik- run in through i pipe ami pumped out witli a pump. This has practically ■liininated the danger of tire from gasoline in l)iisine&gt;s liuildings that handle this explosive, hut ill the home where gasoline is used for cooking, cleaning clothes, wood- other articles the loss of life ami property lias A I as great as oilier years. The day before Thanksgiv - n Sou t ti Omaha a man and his wife were burned to from cleaning clothes with ganoline, and their three liiidren. ranging from two to six jcara of age were phaiif. A uniuber of men, women and children were h in ihis state faring the part year through lined t ii^erous explosive. This department is help \ t Mien ciiiu lialils of carelessness in the home but we iave tried by advice and instruction to inculcate in the inihls of the people i he danger always lurking in gasoline md have explained to them repeatedly why the utmost md caution should always In- used in handling it. r 10 other nin cause of tire that entails so much iijuiv and loss of life as does gasoline. Phis I department has issued the following rules and II insist upon every oil company doing business in the here to them in regard to the shipping and All oil houses which are built and inclosed with gal - vanised iron should be put up on props or posts to the height of 3 l /« or 1 ft.: said houses should have galvanized iron siding to run within 2 or 3 inches of the ground. These houses should Ite liuilt not less than 200 ft. from any oilier house, except liv special permission of all parties living in property nearer than this imiiiUer of feet. Bach house should he inclosed with a fence, either iron ur wire, with doable gates sufficient for a wagon to drive through and load from the house. For i In- juisi five wars ho vigorous has Imhmi our cain- 1 ii 1 1 regarding ili&lt;- &gt;i&lt;»iin^ of Kiwoline ''"" wt ' l ' au IIOW </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SEVKXTH AXXI'AI. KKl'oK'l Tilt" (Mltsitlc Jjate of this fence should lie lucked ;|I all times ;ind itlso the liouse, except at llie time lll;il the ajjeut owning tlie house is there jwrsoiial I y to look after gaaoline stored therein. All dry weeds, gnwa and rultiiisli should be kept cleaned rip within a radius of i'&lt;i ft. of said hnikling, and under no condition will the mat, or siny one in his employ, he al - lowed to smoke within the enclosure of ihis building &lt;&gt;r rard. All gasoline, except what is shipped in steel ram, win* lie naipped in iron, air-tiphi packages or di inns, and Bpoi arrival at stations shall he immediately emptied into th&lt; underground tank of the consignee, liiii in case the under ground tank is not siil'iicieut t«i empty the entire shipment the the remainder, not t&lt;&gt; exceed live barreJa, must hi placed on a vacant lot and in the open air. and not lea t linn 58 feet from anv other building. A full barrel of gasoline is nol dangeron* mil a severe tire around ii and is MlloViently hot to fn sure and lnirst t he barrel. A full barrel of gasoline will not exploit* itijLC it in the open air. 51 It. from a Imihl fectlv safe. around, nwini; to the laci that there is general cient amount of gasoline left in the barrel to fix luistion that will pplode A spark applied t&lt;&lt; an empty barrel tli contained uasoline is very liable to ram \iolent ex plosion. Kmjdoyees must not In- allowed to rarrj maiche&gt;. aromn the oil houses. There should he no trash, nily rag*, fM inliliish around the premises. If an\ nil is spilled on tin lloor and cleaned up with sawdust, the sawdust shotil&lt; Im* i-enioved from the premises at once, to avoid spontan eons combustion. There should lie no sinokinir of anv kind in or about the oil lioiiKM'. There should lie no weed* or graM allowed in BWf around the oil house. The weeds and urass should lie mt with a shovel verv close to the ground. It is v«'i-\ dangcron* i&lt;&gt; ;ill«&gt;w empn </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 STATE HKK COMMISSION lii case w lii-rc ii railroad ayeat receive* a iroaaifpMaeaj nil and finds barrel* are Icakini;, then naU ajjent should mediately notif\ the lu&lt;-;il aijent of the nil comp;Ul.\. mil In- shall iMiiiicliiiicIv put Raid barrels into an air-tij;lif Irani. It is ;ils«i i-i'i|iifsii'(| that as snon as a hairri containing jasnline is euptied, ir iniist at taken to the depot anil -lii|i|ieil hack immediately. Ml inei-ehaiits handling gafloline in an amount in ex s of ."&gt; gallons must have ilie same lnnieil not less ihan iniler ground &lt;!ascp|iiie is u ti-earheions, ilaiiiierons explosive, anil Ion inh rare ran not he used in handling and utorinc it. roXUKMXATlOX OF IM'IIJMXCS ii-euinstames wananteil anil when neeessarv. Olil inus that were part iciilailv siisreplilile In tire ami hat einlanyei-eil adjoiniDK proprHj were onlertMl con - temned it' ihev wen- lievonil repair. W'f timl araacrty 'wnei-s thi-oiiuhout i In- state most reasonable when •* how them that their property is a nuisam-e ami a men ice in iis dilapidated comlition ami they are most willing o complv with our onleis when they are conviiiceil that to their own as well as to their neighbor*' ailviinta«;c to have the old building* reniovtil. Many pieces of valu - able properly have for years lieen wasieil liecause owners left &gt;l;nnliiiu upon them old. dilapidated Iniildin^s unlil for ucciipaucy. the owners reieivinir lint nominal, if any. 'cut. After we condemned the litiiiilinirs as a nuisance in many instances [jood l(uililin»s have Im'cji ennteil thai netted the owners a most liherai income. We timl that it is not the poor ritiaea who owns most of the tire traps at the stale. In a majority of cases it la the men of wealth, &lt;&gt;r at least romforiaWlc means, who have plenty liesitlcs ami care not if tliev receive onlv a few dollars a month I Miring tlir year 1915, 14,500 bnildinjfM witc iaapeeteil :tl-l ilitlfirlil tnwns. "J'h'Slll lip" urdi-rs wi'l-c issued </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SEVENTH ANM'Al. UKI'oKI income from a dilapidated ltuil&lt;iiit.&lt;&gt; Kit anted &lt;m ,i vain* property. They would rather take tliis sniiill nwoatil rent i which do matter bow naiall. is often much mm than the Imililinu is wnrthi than improve their propei Mild their neit:hl&gt;orhood !;\ hnildinj; a wife a "tightly edifice. However. M slated aliove. We have i countered scarcely am unpleasantness in liaviim ilaiii: mis condition* reinoveil. Over Insikanck Resiiinsiih |)|-|»V( i|nire, and their pcatesi concern ■ Ht in everv of the orijjin of the tire with tire itself so ih;ii it is alums inipossihle for police officiate, detective* or slate officer to tind anythim: lint circnm«tantial evidence auains VHienre auains them. The only way that arson can he aliolislied is in nt&lt;»| Our experience in the invest ijjat ion uf liics li levond a ilmilii thiil over insurance is ih&lt;- predomiiu cause of arson. Fully !MI', iif the iiu endiary tires ait" for tlic pat-pot** i»f collecting the insurance money, h very easy for anyone to olt ;lill insurance on hotlrtPlli i^nods or stocks iif merchandise ill excess (it their |- Villlic. Wi' ll;l\e ll;|&lt;1 cilscs in this i|i'|i;llM Ilielll where i lionest persons li.ne obtained •^■_'..~)ii(i insiiriince mi koi ilclllilll.V V«rth Imt Sl.'itl.dll. &lt;&gt;i&gt;&lt;&gt; ,-,\n l-e;nlilv see the cetitive for ;irson in ■ caw ol this kimi. When ;in insnr;iiice n^ciit fir** ;i |M&gt;ii«-\ in ; i umn w the written .•issur.-iiice lliiit in c;ise nf lire he will p.iy s|iot ciish •*'_'.."&gt;()(• for nierch.-inilise that is not worth in&lt; than fl54, tlle|-e is evelV l-easol) to ln-|je\e thai tile &gt;h will he Imrneil up brfore the instn-ance po|i&lt;-v expires hix is the fire insurance Imsiness ami si» hhhv is ii to lain a policy for three, four, ytm i«'ii times what I instiled property is worth, that i»f crooks hi oruanized tlieinselves in wlial are calleil "iiimhi i ins and iH'arl.v every state has had its experience with tin '•arson trusts." They plan their work so well, tln-y h; all the time for deliberation and operation thai ihev </seg>
            <seg id="p021">KIKK I1IM MISSION 21 \ i i\ii- insurance; ilu-ii there will lit- im incentive fur it, as ew imw BIT committed ilnoiii;li spite or revenue. Insur - nice ('onpHuivM t Iti &lt; 1 1 1 *^ } i their 1* »«-:* 1 ajjents are tin- ilirvrt (liners throafth which rliis ileepicil:)** crime ran !&gt;&lt;■ Hiwin- i'il. If Insurance Companies would have ill) under ladiun with iln-if local agents wlirn they appoint them T li*- effect tliat the Company will not staml for the lag- ant writing of risks without imnpfttioa of tin- property to m- insured. an&lt;l that in case of tire ami upon investigation i.v tlic Company i lie loral agrat will lie held r«*s]M»nsili|» - or tin- over insurance anil loss to the Conipanv. then n wliicli to al:olis|i the crime of arson. S|xvial agents honlil Imp inot-e caieful in the appniattan of local i^i-nts. In fact it would lie reasonable to holt) the S|MM-ial \yei.is i'es|Mins!lile for the local agents. The state ami .pecial Agents of the various liiir Fire Insurance Com- mies receive larjje salaries ami their duties are not ilnons. Their business is- to appoint agents in ilitTerent itit-s anil towns to represent their Companies, ami it urelv should lie their ambition to appoint men who will Ktiesth deal with their Company. Cases have come to nit notice where a local ajjetit has over-insured a risk to he point of criniinalitv. ami vet the State Ayent diil .■ &gt;t up the agent's commission lint let him continue U&gt; -ein the Coni|ian.\. It wonlil lie time anil money well peni for the state ami special agents to visit their |iH-al U'eticies from time to time ami instead of |— If in ami IM-ndiiii; a inorninir or day tellin&gt;« stories and jollying: the local HJEPni for them to uo to the bonks and pick out five mi- six risks that seem to lie insured for a iroodly sum ami make a ]M-rsonal inspection of them and see for themselves what kind of risks their ajrent is placiti" upon the liooks of the Company. This &gt;eems to us to In- the only way to catch the careless or ignorant local ajrent. The state a^ent is on the ground then ami can uive him the advice or lalkinj; to that he deserves or requires. In the lio]M' of correct in» this lax wiitin^ of tire itisui - ince the Ictrislature of 1913 enacted a law and provided a w &lt; hi 1.1 nni lie su niiiiiv iiKciiiliiiiy Brew. It seems (&lt;&gt; us llnit sonic mrli micIIiimIs as this will In* the only \\n\ </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SKVKMII AXXTAI. KKI'uKT IM'iuilty for Im&gt;Ui tha local agent and the insured in rase of orer-insurance. Xo honest man wants a tire insurance policy for more than his property is worth for if he has no tire, and the probability always is that he will not have a tire, he is paying out an excess amount in premiums, that is, he is paying out a larger premium than he need pay for the honest and actual protection of his property which lie really needs and which is really a mvessity for his pro tection and credit. The following is the section of the law relating to ovn insurance : "Sec. ll(!». IWimilUim ■ — I Xl.AWKtl.. It shall Ik - unlawful for any insurance company or any agent to knowingly issue any tire insurance policy upon property within this sate for an amount which with any cxisin^ insurance exceeds the fair value of the properly or of tin - interest of the insured therein, or lor a loafer time than for hve years, except as provided in section 134. "Sec. 110. same — INSIUKM. It shall be unlawful foi any party having an insuralde interest in property locate in this state to knowingly procure any lire insurant! policy upon his interest in such property for an amount ii excess of the fair value of his interest in the property, or for an amount which with any exist ini»- insurance thereon, exceeds the fair value of his bite real in the property. "Sec. 111. ovKK-lxst UAXt K — t'K.x At.! Iks. Kverv insurer who makes insurance upon any building; or property &lt;&gt;l interest therein against loss or damage l»y fire, and every agent who issues a tire insurance policy covering an\ building or property or interests therein, and every in sured who procures a policy of tire insurance upon an\ Iniilding or property or interest therein owned liy him, is presumed to know tthe insurance value of such building «.i pi-oiHMty interest therein at the time such insurance is effected. Any insurer who knowingly makes insurance on any building or property or interest therein against loss or damage by fire in excess of the insuralde value thereof, shall 1m- tined in a sum not less than tiftv dolhtrsn or more </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE KIRK COMMISSION 23 than one hundred dollars. Any ajjent who knowingly ef - fects insurance on a liiiililin&lt;r or property or interest therein in excess of the insurahle value thereof, sliall lx - lined in ;i sum not less than fifteen nor more than twenty - five dollars." We intend ro raforre this law vigorously in every case where we tiiiil ptoptl'tj over-insured and the local afjent or insured are responsible. If we can bring the insurance agents of ijich town in the state to ;i realization of their i«-sjn msihility and duty in personally inspecting projM'rty hefore insuriiii: it. iiiceniliarisin will de«rease materially in this state. Fire insurance companies should lie held re - siMMisilile for the local ajjents which their special agents appoint and we would sni:&lt;:est that the insurance companies take this matter up with their wptn-ial and state agents for there are hundreds of local agents writing insurance throughout the state who have no t|ualitications and can nut ;ind do not write intelligently, ('aces have come to ■Ntr inn ice where the local aiient was even a party to Im i henetited in riMP of tire on some certain lisk he had written. • </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">A IK I IKK CUM MISSION INCENDIARY FIRES </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">STATK HKK COMMISSION 27 INTKX1UAKY F1RKS This department was called 1 1 1 &gt;&lt; &gt; 1 1 to investigate a tire ai Fullerton. Nebraska, which mami on November 125. 11114, haiMiag »us nwmil an&lt;l occupied by R. C. Knudson and was occupied as an implement store. Upon investiga - tion we round thai the building liad been fired from the outside under the Moor and a quantity of kerosene oil had lieen used. There was no evidence obtained in which a prosecution could be sustained. On l&gt;eccinher 29, 1!»H. a tire of incendiary origin oc - urred at Falls City, in a building owned by Ira Fredrick in which her huxbund Peter Frederick, Jr.. had operated a saloon a short time l»efore. Fire was started in three dif - fa real phi cm in the building at an early hour in the morning, and from the evidence obtained looked ver\ much like parties interested in the property might have had some connection with the transaction. However, we were unable to sectm- sufficient evidence upon which to !&gt;ase ■ prosecution. On l&gt;eceinln'i- 14. 1!»14. (luv K. and ('has. N'ickols of Hastings. Nebraska, rented a building in the suburltx of Hastings and on the above date secured insurance on six* head of horses, at xioo.oo each; also 9150.00 on hay. grain and vehicles. On the 17th, following they Itought live horses for fSS.it eacli. paying *."».(►(! cash and giving I mortgage on them for $T&gt;0.00. A few days later they Haded a rain coat to a Jew peddler for another horsv and put them all in the building which they had rented. On the morning of Ih-cemU-r li.'ith. &lt;iuv K. XickolH set tire to the kirn attempting to burn the horses which however, was not successful. He pleaded guilty of the crime of arson and was sent to the penitentiary from one to seven \ear&gt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 XRVENTH AXXtAI. UKI'tUM A Boarding House owned li\ Chas. I' Mrkeinia silu •tad iilnjiit I miles from O'Neill in 1 1 &lt; &gt; 1 1 county was burned to the ground on the l!)th nf February. l'.M.Y |i pi-olialily was over insured ami its only occupant was CtMirjic Stanford who made a pretense of o»rnp\ in^ the same. Tlie owner and occupant left the premises at nbual !&gt; :.".&lt;( I'. .M. and llie next morning the house was limned down. This however, was the second tire sustained by the owner under similar eirctimstaiires. A dwelling house owned by Mamie I'ostal in l»catric&lt; was partially destroyed by tire March M, 1JM.1. T\\\ - woman was of rather a )|iiestioual&gt;le character and ha&lt; liiid &lt;i number of matrimonial ventures, none of which lia. proved harmonious. Ami tlie cause of this tire is mipfMMei to have originated through jealousv hilling -l.iiniiir\ and Feltruarv of l'll.'i. there wei UiimlH'i- of small tires in I Sea trice which looked very n like the work of an incendiar.v. This depart incut tin sevuml evidence against a nine year old hoy who had I responsible for llie same. He was |da&lt;cd in charge • priiluitinii officer and fitiitllv left ilie stale for Kantm* On Keltruaiy L'Sih. the farm |&gt;ro|Mit\ of A. It. l*&lt; was destroytKl liv tire. Mr. Tarex had leased his land was alMiut to move 10 Holt county and had lieen irvin s«'ll tlie buildings. He claimed to have set this tir&lt; usiiifx a lighted match looking for &lt;loiln-s in a cluset. A property situated abnat two miles trom drawl Islaml HVMll l&gt;v Kiln Pasha, otherwise known as Venice WeU-i. was destroyed by tire on March .!rd. This place had formerly Ikhmi run as a resort and was closed up liv tIn - authoi-iti«'s of Hall county. I'roliaMv the contents weir insured for fl.~&gt;,500; practimlly a otai loss. So aw present at the time of the tire lint the owner and slu - claime&lt;l it originated around the furnace in tin- liasemeiit Thei-e was a very heavy snow on flic ground and the tire company from (irand Island was imnMe to do effective work. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">A IK I IKK COMMISSION 29 I About 1 A. M. on the morning of April 19, 1!&gt;1."&gt;. ;i Iwellinj; house owned and occupied liv Herman Wrtn-k i\;is discoveml on tire. The parties who first MBehli the ■MM of disaster foninl Mr. • Wrm-k laying on the H&lt;m»i- in he bed room suppose! to have lieen murdered and tried o remove his ImmIv tlii-oiijjh a window hut were unable t« lo so. The next &lt;lav the riMMwd remains of his wife MR akcn from tlie basement. We were unable to find evi - lence lending to establish aiiv ilut' as to the rnniiiiixxinn if ilii&gt; crime. \ hoarding lioiise in I 'aimer. Nebi-aska. owned and arc* d li\ Mm. .Marv Haf{pard WM set on tire May 14. IMSt .'. ::&gt;0 A. SI. We welt- nntible to find anv motive whai ver for the crinu A dwelling house in Hebron wms discovered on tire May 1. IMS, 8 !'• M. Mail been urvnpied by a family named Moui'iM-. This paily had inovetl part of their householil U r ood to another property which ihcy had reeently pur liased. The evidence was very stronji airainst the &lt;m-cii- &gt;ants of this property, esp»*cially ihe wife. Hut on ac omit of her advanced atre it would Ite almost imitossiMi iret a conviction &lt;"harles Wookey of Kairbury was eiiijuffeil in the restau - ant business for a year or two previous to May Vi, 1915; «»rt1&gt; Infore tliat date lie discontinued the restaurani insiiiess i»rincipally for tlie want of patronage and then iiovi-d his restauraui and tixnirex into a dwelling house md had an insurance policy $1 ..MMI transferred to the new local ion and as a natural coiisei|tience had a tire on the ibovc date. Cpon investigation found that the contents i. id Iki*ii 1 horoujrhly soaked with kerosem- but we were 1 1 1 1 : 1 1 1 1 1 • lo gH sufficient evidence to tile a complaint. ('onlents of residence occupied by Charles Hates ul lleatrice was partly destroyed by fire on .June."». 191.", same lii-iiifr insured for twice its value. Fire was started in two or three different rooms in tlie house. Wife and children were in Omaha and tlie husband had a complete ;ilil&gt;i. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 SEVENTH ANM'AI. KKI'oKT II I •&lt;l i n i i I i i v v x \ in mt A ranch house of W. \Y. Hill near Kalston was bar -hint' &lt;i. IMS. It warn oreapied by Frask l!;i!&lt;"s aad \\ Mr. Hates was a laborer on the t'ann ami his wile hoar the other hands employed there. His services were lained liv Mi-. Hill tliroujih a labor agency ami ii household goods consisted of a lial»y carriage, sew \\ niacliiin'. a bairH &lt;&gt;f canned fruit ami the content* i»f trunks. Mr. Bate* went into ■ hank ai Balatoa and plied for fCMMI ihi liouseliold gooda and ii wmm written him. The Ire M the a Love date was on Sunday w there was no one there except Mr. Bates; this lieimr MMMd atrempt. Mr. Kates had a tire altoiit a j previous to this one in a farm liotise near Qriswold, Io This Ire looked suspicions especially so on account of value of his household "umls and the insurance on sa ( 'ontents of shoe store ai Alma. Nebraska, belougii &lt; '. F. Mussellnian was totally destroyed by Ire on !'."», 1 A. M. This tire was started liv ignitiD); keiosei the floor ami was verv similar to other tire losses i w Mr. Miissellinan sustained in other years. There w ; i|iiestion I. ill that the dest ruct ion of this property with liialicioiis intent, l»u( there was not sutiicient erii upon which to I use pro&gt;ecution. The implement building of Carl S.limink a Nebraska, was set on tire .Inly 13, hut evidence! mission of the crime was very meaner. And n&lt; whatever. ]iointin«i to the owner. A Bouaiing House in llraad Island, operated h\ I'la Lewis was thoroughly saturated with kerosene oil and on tin* on August I'll, ahoni 1 1! ::ti &gt; A. M.. and was linjiuished by the tire company. It took lire again sho after the tire company had ROM awa.\. and was anain tinjruished without much loss. The circumstances rounding the same, point to the pnilt of the occtip l&gt;ut not sufficient evidence upon which to Imw a &lt;■ plaint. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATI IKK COMMISSION 31 ned by Kov Itannell at North Platt« \ ii her iif (irccks was totally dent roved ii .May !'!». al 111 :.:(» ;i. 111. V &lt;I. Smith lived in iii'i&lt;rhlMiihoo&lt;| chanjed with the crime and tried strii-r com! hi Lincoln county mb«1 discharged. inu i he week i&gt;f November 22, 1915, three incendiary ccurred iii Hastings. First one hpiajt a slaughter &gt;win'd by (i«i. and Williiini Harmon. Second a welling (H-cnpicd by Arthur llanlt. and Ike third, old house owned and occupied by Victor A. Palm. roperty had Ween a trading proposition for a nuin - vears and was occupied by 1'alin as ■■ art jjallen he had oltlained insurance on huildiiiL' nts. The ImildioK was thoroughly saturated \ kiiiuII lire originated in the liaseiueut of a store in i owned and operated hy M. ISalcom on l&gt;e d. 1M1.".. at •'. A. M. The owner, .Mr. Italcoin laud ottice in Sioux City, Iowa and Iradetil iu,k hist Fall. William Snow, an Indian. I to ni into the liasenieiit thronch it window 1 1&lt; I \\;i&lt; directed w here he would find a pile of ki mil in liould start the tire. Snow pleaded guilty Count v Jmlcr and was liound over t&lt;» tin ii &lt;'onrt. Snow savs "he was hired to commit me liv .1 white man named Kav Ogden." Thi In our last repori we gave a synopsis of the case of Ora i; and ha L Philips, charged witli an atteui|&gt;t mi arson of the I &gt;u i l&lt; I i nir in which they were conducting a :eneial inenliaiidise store. Ira Philips was convicted in he l&gt;isirict court of Itawes Poaaty and appealed his case to the Sii]ireme &lt;'(iin! w li'ch court in late decision granted him a new trial. 1'iilin luiil liis usual alilii. ilc|iiiitiiiciil is milking even effort to lonite this liiiin o^ilcn l&gt;ut it hnx liffii 11 n:&gt; I •]&lt;' in &lt;](• so ti | &gt; t&lt;&gt; tin- prcsciir </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 SEVKNTII ANMAI. KK11IRT \ Fire at Ames. Nelnaska. I *«*«-»'in Im*i- :», l!U."i. coiisistin&lt; • if household property hekMgfag to Kov Vsm&lt; ";uiip. Thi property was over-insured for ;i1miuI dmihle iis vahu-. .' thorough investigation was made \&gt;y this departiiient an&lt; l&gt;y Shi-riff Coadii of Itadge Ponnty. The matter was |&gt;n ii|» to 1 lie &lt;N&gt;untv Attorney with a i'c&lt;|tiest for a waiiani Me ilainu'il that there was not sufficient evidence to .nil viet. and we wei-e ioiii|&gt;«'lled to drop the case. Fire at I'ethanv. Nelnaska. NovemlM-i- 38, l§15. Tw l&gt;arns were set on tire liv two small Ih&gt;\s while playin with lliat&lt;lies. These Imivs confesse&lt;l lo settinj; rile tin aixl were turned over to the juvenile court at Uncoil Xehraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ATE KIRK COMMISSION Department Is Handicapped </seg>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035">ATE FIKK COMMISSION 35 \KIUTU.\1JV ACTION OF STATK TllKASriJKU HAM. HANDICAPS DEPAKTMKXT TO SOME EXTEXT licciiiisc tin- hist Legislator* did not make a specific ippropriatioa for this department State Treasurer Hall •topped payment on all salaries and warrants due the lepartmcut last .June as In' contended that he could not my any warrants unless the Legislature had appropriated 'limls for same. The Fire Commission Department is Maintained l&gt;y a direct tax upon the Fire Insurance Coin - uinics doiiux Imsiness in Nebraska and this tax is paid nto the State Treasury for the specific purpoac of paying he expenses incidental to this particular department and said fond* cannot be use&lt;l for any other purpose. When Mr Hall refused to pay our salaries for .Tune we went to ihe Attorney General of the tSate and laid the case be fore him and he gave Mr. Hall a written opinion to the t that ours was a special trust fund and did not re- i|uire an appropriation from the legislature and that Mr. Mall would not l&gt;e liable in any way to his Itoudsunen or ibt one else should he };o ahead and pay the expenses of he Fire Commission I &gt;epai tnient. It is an established rule that County Commissioners of .•very County go to the County Attorney for advice and opinions mi all cases in &lt;|iiestion and always act on the ad advice of the County Attorney as hat relieves the County Coniini&gt;sioners of any liability in case the County Attorney should lie legally wrong in his opinion. The rule applies the same as regard* the Attorney (leneral of the State in iri vinjr advice to the State Officials: in ease the Attorney &lt;ieneral is in error it is he and not the officials who accept Ins advice who are liable and responsible. However, the opinion of the Attorney General was not sufficient to satisfy Mr. &lt;Jeo. Hall and he insisted he must have the opinion of the Supreme Court of the State. He repeatedly </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 SKVKXTI1 ASM Al. KKl'OK'l tolil every umber of this department that lt«- wmmU I* satistii'd with whatever opinion the Hupreaie I'min rend end; in fad lie said In- heartily hoped they wmilil deciili that be would !»■ acting: within I Ik- law if ha paid us be cause he was most anxious to do so ami regretted dial In fell it liis duty to withhold the warrants until such linn as the Sii|irtMiic Court could reach the case. Aliout September tirst lie Found that even though im appropriation was made by the Legislature thai he law f ii 1 1 \ should pay us for the months of .Inne, Jnlv ami August and this Im- did last Meptember alter willfully anil unlawfully iff— inn '" !'"&gt; ns theae salaries For three inonlhs. llr has continued to refaae to pay us any moneys since August however, so that all told he stopped payment • &gt;u our funds in .lune. .Inly and August, then in Heptemliei - paid us for these three months which he willfully had withheld, and then since September 1st. has refused tn i&gt;sne us any further waitaiils. tetliBg us he would IMM pay any more imiil the Supremi' 4'oiirt would take up the matter and an opinion as in \\li:il he |e^all\ shmili! &gt;lo. Mr. Hall farther told our deputies ihat he would uo&lt; lijrht the case as he ineielv wauled an opinion from the court to sjinctiou his authority to pax our warranis ami that he would not employ any uttoraev to promi his case, contending; merely that we should have the A &lt;ieiieral present our side and uei an opinion Ii Supreme Court as he fell he was entitled to ili.i case was tiled in court by the Attorney Oeoeral I I )e]&gt;artiuent and Mr. liall employed four at torue\ : fend his arbitrary ,n\ not to |&gt;a\ uarraiits fur t • I. partment. We do not know whether Mi. Hall is payit these hijrh priced attorne.xs nut of his own innne\ • whetlier the State will have to pay it. At an\ hi&gt; attorneys appeared in court and had their bra ring anil after clue time (he Supreme Court of Nebraska hamlet! down the opinion that Mr. Hall said would satisfy him whether it Ik- to pay us aff noi in pa;, us. The opinion wa&gt; that he should pav us our salaries ami ntpenaex and all expenses incident to the tuaiuteiiance of the department, the court holding that tin- Kire &lt; 'oiiimissimi fund u;i&gt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 STATE KIBE COMMISSION s|H-cial fund paid iuto the State Treasury for a specific purpose, and did no require a specific appropriation by i lit* State Legislature. Mr. Hall, after the decision of the Supreme Court was handed down, evidently very much disappointed that they did not decide against us and for him, immediately tiled a motion for a rehearing of his rase which necessarily will cause a delay of at least another forty days ltefore anything further will be done in the matter. In the meantime all employees of the Depart - ment liave U-en without a cent of salary for over four months, or since last August through the wilful and un - lawful act of Mr. Hall in deliberately refusing to pay our warrants. This of course, has been a source of great in - convenience to them and has without doubt been a handi- cap to the workings of the Department. It has been the custom of the Department to issue monthly bulletins on Fire Prevention the same lteing printed in the different newspapers of the state warning citizens about prevalent tire dangers and cautioning and advising them how best to avoid careless and unnecessary fires. These bulletins have not been issued for the past five months owing to the fact that we had no money available with which to buy postage I wish tn thank all the employees of the department for iheii loyalty and faithfulness in performing all their duties and doing their work with the same willingix ■- when they were twing regularly paid for their services. Kespeetfully yours. \V. S. RlDOEl.L. Chiif Deputy h'ire Coinmixninm, . </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">A IK KIKK &lt; MM .MISSION DECISION OF SUPREME COURT State Fire Commissioner vs. State Treasurer </seg>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041">41 ATE FIRE COMMISSION ATE EX KKI.. UIIMiELL VS. Opinion Sled December S, 1S1&amp; 1913, ami set apart by lectioa 2511 &lt;»f that thap - special fui &lt;1 tin- the maintenance of the aflkc «»f niss'oner and the expense* incident thereto, nt by the state treasurer on \\;irrans prop - the auditor of state for the aavpaae without V hi lit. art. Ill of the Constitution, does not e use of that fund when the same has lieen s The ;i«t creating that fund was intended as a con u appropriation for the payment of rhe salaries and •cs nt' i lie state fire commissioner and the treasurer nired by mandamus to pay warrants properly tha fund when collected and in his hands. I. tion in mandamus to require the respond- state treasurer, to countersign and pay a war wn by the auditor of public accounts for *200 in i as chief deputy tire commissioner. known as the tire commissioner's fund. yment &lt;if tlic statutory salary and the iictual and ■ary expenses of the relator for the month of Sep- 1!»1."». in the due and ordinary conduct of his tt m Hi There is no disputed question of fact in tliin case. This made evident liv the following recital in the brief of the respondent : "The respondent by his answer lias endeav - ored to relieve the state of the proof of the essential facts in this case ami relies upon the want of statutory author - ity to countersign or pay the warrant involved in this No. 19407. Hull. c&lt;l ly the proririon of chapter 23, propriation hy the legislatnre. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 SEVENTH ANMAI. UKInlil i &lt;•ji.sc. The respondent lnis eadeavored to facilitate tli pMcratatioa of tliis matter to the coari in order that li might lie advised ;is to liis tlnties as state treasurer in re UYJM.I to the fund in controversy. In the construction ■ I lie law, as he finds It, he is nnalile to tind any author it lliat would justify him in connlersiiinini; or paying tli warrant involved and he, therefore, joins the relator i asking for a construction of the constitution and th statues involved in this case." The real i|iiestion for our determination is: whether ih respondent is required to pay tlie warrant in question i»u of the tire commissioner's fund in his hands, without , specific act of the legislature appropriating said him during each hieiinium to the payment of the salary am expenses of the officers administering the state lire d. partnient. chapter. It makes the governor the lii ami provides for the appointment of a chief detines his duties chief deputy slate tire commissioner shall n iiiil salary of two thousand dollars and deputy fire commissioner one thousand tive hum! I a is. payable monthly, and their actual and traveling expenses while en^a^ed ill the dll office. The tire commissioner shall employ clerks at sistans and incur such other expenses tu mav he m in the performance of 1 h&gt; - duties of his office, not to &lt;-\ cee&lt;], iftcloding salaries, such sum as mav he paid into lii state treasury in the manner hereinafter provided." Section 2510, Kev. St. 191:5, provide*: "For the pni pose of lnaintning the department of state tire coinmi&gt; sioner, and paying the expenses incident thereto, evei tire insurance company except Farmer*' Mutual*, whethei upon the stock or mutual plan, doinu liusinos in the Htati of Nehraska, shall pay to the state treasurer in the ntonti By section 2Tifl», Rev. Si. 1913, ii i&gt; prov Chapter 23, Hex. St. 1913, create* a tin- ron the affaire of which shall be conducted l&gt;\ a tin- tkmmt and smli snlitinlinatrs as arc provided foi </seg>
            <seg id="p043">ATE MICK COMMISSION 43 iiJnnary, annually, in additkM to t Ii«* taxes now re - nd l.v law to lie paid by such companies, three-eijihts per rent On the groat ire premium receipta, after nio on ill business done in Nebraska the year nevt pro - linjr, as shown by the annual statementsm, under oath, the state auditor, which sum shall be paid on or before st day of a-Tnuary of each year, and no certificate ie issued by the auditor to or aa behalf of any such oinpaiiv. authorizing it to do or continue business in this tate while any such pf rif tagf or tax remains due and npaid." Sitiion 2311, Bev. St. 1913, provides; "The state ■asurer shall hold the money so received into the trea&gt;- i special fund for the maintenance of the office of e commissioner, ami the exjM'nses incident theretto. ite tire commissioner shall keep on tile in his office ii itemized statement of all expens«»s incurred by his de - triment, anil shall approve all vouchers issued therefor. efore the same are submitted to the auditor of the state layineiit, which vouchers shall l*&gt; allowed ami paid in •a me manner as other claims auainst the state." It seems clear that the legislature, by the sections of ipter i 1 :: quoted atere, not only created a new depart lit of government knovMi as the state tire commission d&lt; partment. but also designated its officers, fixed the Mini of their salaries, and provided a social fund for lie liavment of such salaries and tt'ie lipuwi of ad - ninistei iii^ the depart inent. The fund thus collected max Ie ili situated as ;i trust fund, which, hv the terms of the act it^i-lf cannot lie ntsed for any oher purpose until ttutlii t legislative action. It is conceded that this fund is amply sufficient for the payment of the warrant in ipies tion. Indii'd. it is admitted that there is a larjje surplus of this fund in the hands of the respondent, who contends that lie has no authority to j»av the warrant in question hecanse ihe legislature, at is 1§15 session, made no specific appropriation of the fund for tin* payment of the relator's salary and the expenwn of administration. incellations and ieinsiiran&lt;»&gt;s. of sucli cum- </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 SEVENTH ANNUAL BEPOBT Iii Slmttiuk v. Kin&lt;;iiil. 31 Ore. ;!7:t. spanking &lt;i priations, the sonrt said: "And this geta us Lac! priatioas, tin- aoaii said: "And this original proporfiotiou thai an appropriation is i!h original propmiotion ihai an approj riatioa is the nettinj: aside or designation hv express direction or by iui] aside or designation liv express direction ur bj implication (if parti&lt;-ii.ar hinds for the discharge of definite ai of pai'tiru.ar hinds for the ili&gt;&lt; ltai p- of definite ami up tied (ililijiaiions or liabilities, which, however, hu tied obligations or liabilities, which, however, u «.-&lt; hi t t'li. i &gt;. ;i t i« hi . such m will arise in the future, conten.p.ation. such a&gt; will arise in the future, ami I appropriation n ay lie continuing in its nature, appropriation nay lie continuing in us nan legislative intent to have funds always ready and legislative intent i&lt;&gt; have funds always ready ami a able to their prompt dlacaargc at stated times w&lt; able to their prompt discharge at stated limes wori the appropriation, and nothing short of it can ha the appropriation, and nothing short &lt;&gt;f it can liavi an elite." &lt;'&lt;)ininon\vealtth v. Powell, 249 I'a. 144. was ■ I an effec." Connnonwealtth v. Powe wih the &lt;ni eat I ar. The niandamns to compel the wih the (in eat bar. The application was for a mandamus to compel the auditor general to d auditor general warrant on the state treasurer of the state of I vania in favor of the National Limestone Compa vania in favor of the National Limcsi fund received from the registration of license autoiiKil iles. which was sppropriated by the tern act iniiiosiiiir the fees, for the maintenance and r&lt; net imposing the fees, for the uaintei the stale highway*. The opinion of the supreme i the stale highways. The opinion of i Pennsylvania, in thai case i&gt; instinctive and pn Pennsylvania, in thai &lt; nisi iik determines the quest ions involved in (leteiinines t lie (|iiest ions involved in llit- case at i; Constituion of Pennsylvania (&lt;'oiim. ait. 111. Coustitnion of Pennsylvania (Cot provides: "No Mil, except general uppropriatii provides: "No bill, except general appro] shall be passed containing more than one subject shall be passed containing more than one -n shall lie clearly expressed in its title.* 1 Section shall be clearly expressed in its title." S III, of the Constitution of ilia state provides: -'I i eral appropriation hill shall enibnu priaions for the ordinary expenses of the eiecnl x legislative and judicial departments of the (Nnniuoi wealth, interest on ilie jmlilic debl ami for the pu schools; all other appropriationM shall lie made l&gt;\ separate liills. each embracing bat one unbjert. Seitioi 1(J of the same Constitntion provides: "No money shal lie paid out of the treasury, except upon apprupriatioi made liy law. ami no warrant drawn l&gt;\ the proper nfllcei in pursuance thereof." In flisciissini; the question arixii in that rase, the court said: "Clearly the disposition </seg>
            <seg id="p045">vn I IKK COMMISSION i&gt; ;iii incident to the svstem of regulation. i&lt; isi-1 \ allied thereto, and naturally to he it* l«-iii &gt; la i in-** in connection with the main act. The Ktatnte would liave been inconi v disposition of them. . .o argument should he 0 ■how thai jirovisii ' s for attaining various which relate to the gt-ucrul subject of the bill, \ ted that the act offends against see- f I lie Constitution whicli provides that all other &gt;t is thai the act of 1913 «as a separate bill when it ! Ik- legislature and it cuiitains only otn - invaniiiii of the organic law as we hav ut in this opinion; the second is that lie &lt; 'onstitution was only intended to !ii&lt; nnial appropriations made l&gt;y the leginla the m»neral revenues nf the Commonwealth. inn tu a fund created for a special pur - d Iiv the ad trader which such fund is »li&lt; a particular use. The appropriation of continues as long as the act wliiili (iciilar use remains in force." wit respondent's contention that no n from the treasury except in pur \ n|H-\ ml provides: -The slate treasurer shall hold the money » received into the treasury as a uperial fund for the laintetiance of the office of slate tire commissioner, and he expanses incident thereto. " Kev. St. 1!U:{. sec. 2511. Stat&lt; r. i'nruiU. (ill Nel&gt;. 27*, cited l»v respondent in upport off his contention can easily be distinguished from he case at liar Tin" &gt;■ the appropriation was made from I tin* payment of l'trs without provid- alt with 'i.v its tcni; . without laying it open to ■ of containing more ilian one sulijcct. • • » ■hall lie made !v m»parate hills, eaek em- suhjft i." Tlicruuri further ttaid: "There usurps to i his coniriitioii, each equally per- 1 hot li c«,i!. Insivc of I he i|in'si : &lt;ni involvcil. The appropriation* Made by law. I 1 iln i itself makes the sju'cific appropriation </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 SEVENTH AXXCAI. UKI'lUM loll ..•.I I I til* ii I ,\ tile flllld.- of I lit- still*- treasury raised liv general taxat ami was a part of the general wmw of tin- slate. In the rase , -it liar t lie appropriat inn is the s|ieci;il fund ra tar the sjKvial purpose nient iotieil in chapter -'■'&gt;. atnl ha not hint; to iln, w hatsoever. with the general revenue longing to the state. By the art in &lt;|ucstion the legislature dearly intei that the money paid to the treasurer under the art sin Im' applied hy the deputy commissioner to the payiuen his salary anil the e\pen&gt;es of inanauin^ his ortire perforaiiBK tlie duties thereof. The right of the h-^isi Mm* to establish such an nrtire and provide the fund the ne&lt;-cssar.\' expenses as this art does is not &lt;|iiesti&lt; The taxpayers, or parties upon whom the liurden i ire not complaining. The fund has lieen provided an ervices rendered. If the statute is tinconstitiitinna if the taxpayers roaM demand a return of tlie mom are not doing so. They made no objection I &lt; • tlie ait tlie money was called for from them. They have act is unconstitutional i voluntarily provided tin It is the general rule that patties not affected mi heard to challenge the constitutionalitx stances it is the duty of the custodian of the fund vent the application of it to the pnrpoM* for w hi provided in accordance with tin 1 evident int&lt; legislature. We are of tin the res | m &gt;nd en t to counter • luestion. opinion i liat it i&gt; the d ijrn and pay the warn The writ as prayed for awarded Judgment ArfortHni/fi/. .Morrissey. &lt; '. .1. I'.arnes, Hamer. l.eiioii and S«*&lt;t{" I. .T.. sitting. Fawcett and Kose. .1. .1.. not sittin;; legislature We dn m&gt;t think tlut innlei </seg>
            <seg id="p047">A IK I'lltK COM MISSION 17 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES 1915 </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">STATK KIRK COMMISSION 49 RKrKIPTS AMI EXPENDITURES. 1915. lvECKIPTS. Vinount paid iuto the State Treasury during year 1915 *12,3:!7.46 Balance on hand, .lanuarv 5th, 1915 1,684.33 ♦14.01 1.7» KXPEXIHTI KKS. Salaries $ 7,515.7;5 Transportation 944 61 Hotel expenses 1,472.95 Liverv and bus hire 132.45 Street car Care 1.40 Telephone and telegraph 188.74 Portage 187.59 Kxpress 2.83 Office supplies and printin&lt;r 537.67 I'lirniture and fixtures 1.25 Stenographer fees 62.45 Attorney's fees 50.00 Witness fees 23.10 Sheriff fees 4.95 Fire Thief's f.-es 480.20 Miscellaneous 29.37 Total ex|M-nses fl 1.635.29 Mnlaixeon hand ■Taniiarv ."»tli 1915 2,376.50 ♦14,01 1.79 *1 4.011.7!i </seg>
            <seg id="p050"/>
            <seg id="p051">ATK KIRK COMMISSION .'.I COLLECTIONS FROM INSURANCE COMPANIES </seg>
            <seg id="p052">• </seg>
            <seg id="p053">STATIC FIKK roM MISSION 53 uLl.K' TIOXS I'KO.M INSURANCE COMPANIES. I'm ili«- parptNH* "I maintaining the Fire Conuuimiou li •|i;iii imiii fv«'i-,v tire j— mil i eompnny doing busine)*** Nebraska (except the Fwtin Mutual) must pay to State Treasurer annually three-eight* of one per rent i the grot* fire |&gt;reiiiiiiiiiH wriitt'ii in Nehranka, after It-ting eaneellations and reinsuranct In t-oiiiplianee with this law tlie following companies liavi- |wid the amount set opposite their names: Aii^ln Aint'iicaii Kt'-Iiisu ranee &lt;'n | .7."&gt; Aarlit-n &amp; Mnni.li Fit* Ins. Co I'L'.^:: Anna l'itv ln&gt;. i &lt;&gt; 440.20 ina 1'iif In.v In 440.2(i AjcTM-nltarv Hi* In*. Co 7"&gt;.l(t Aim -i i&lt; an Fire Ins. Co l(i!).C»!( AiMi-iiriin Ccnti-al Fire Ins. Ou "((.&lt;&gt;."» \iin-riran Central Fire Ins. Ou 7O.C»r» Aiiii'iiciin l»riiyy;isi l-'ire Ins. On Ml Aihis Fire Ins. &lt;"o J2.5T i:.i&gt;iun Fire Ins. &lt;'o 32.il! ii Fire Ins. Co X2.iV2 I'.ritisli Ainciiran I"ii»' Ins. Co .!1.24 ii Ainciiran Fin 1 Ins. Co :»1.1'4 ITiiITiiIii fliiMM Tin- Ins. Co :il.00 ilo (icrinan Fire Ins. &lt; 'o :il.00 Caledonia Fii&lt;- ln&gt;. c. 4"J.7ti onia Fin" Ins. &lt;'.. 42.7I'. • ';!iii&lt;lcn I'iic ln&gt;. ( 'o • V2.-W eii Fit* In&gt;. &lt; '« • \'2.'.W I 'iii/ciis- Fin* Ins. l'« L'l.Kt; y.nis- Fire Ins. C» 21M i &lt; ii v i»f New York 8.02 N.-w York 8.01' i 'mrincrcial I'nion Kir* Ins. Co., N«»w York . . . HA- i ial I'nion Fii-«- Ins. Co., New York . . . HA- CoHiiiHTrial 1'nion Fin* ln&gt;. Co.. Loadoa J35.73 I 'oinnioiiwralf Ii Fire Ins. Co :V2.V.t C«Hiimon«'ealtfa Fin 1 Ins. Co :V2.V.i I 'niK'onlia l-'iit- Ins. Co .'SI. 97 &lt; 'on! inriiial Fin* I us. ( "i&gt; :!7&lt;&gt;. .'!.'» &lt; uniMMiiciii Fiw Ins. Co 2M.43 Dwelling Mmi.v Mutual Ins. Co 1 »»&gt;."» I »iiliii«|iic Fire Jk Marine Ins Co l'7.(i(i K«initalile Fin* Ins. Co HMil ilerateil Men hants .Mutual Ins. Co., Omaha.. 11).L'."i ■ aiinei-s 1 us. i '«»., of ( Vil«r Ka]ii&lt;ls. la :!!».! 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 SEVENTH ANNUAL KKI'OUI Fidelity I'henix Ins. Co Federal Ins. Co., New York. . . . Fin- Association of Philadelphia Firemans Ins. Co., of Newark. . Fireman's Fund Ins. Co Franklin Fire Ins. ' '&lt; General Firv Ins. Co Cierinan Alliance Fire Ins. Co • JIoIk' &amp; limbers Fire Ins. Co.. New Fork * Jiain Healers Ins. Co.. Indianapolis.... (lerman American Fin 1 Ins. Co If, L'l.ct; :!0!u;:. HlMU &lt; iermania Fire Ins ( 'o Qirard Fire ft Marine Ins. Co Oka Falls Fire Ins. Co Hainhiujr-Itreineii Fire Ins. C :•&gt; ( is-j o Hanover File Ins. ( Hartford Fire Ins. &lt; Home Fire Ins Co. KlL'.V.i &lt;s Insurance Company of North Ainei '.I Insurance Company of State nf Pennuylvj Imperial Fire Ins. f*« !i 1 Liverpool, London k 'llobe of New Y London Assurance Co London I Lanschire Ins. &lt; '&lt;&lt;. Mechanics ft Traders Ins. Co Mechanics Fire Ins. Co Michigan Commercial Fire Ins Co. MilWs Mutual Fire Ins. Co Miller's National Fire Ins. Co.... Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Ins d&gt;. Minnea|H&gt;lis Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co :W.«s Hi.nr. i i 1 T.'.ts •j::.&lt;; .-,i.n:: 1 •_'!.:: l 11MM, Mutual Protective Fire Ass'n.. Reward, Nclu National Fire Ins. Co National Hen Franklin Fire Ins. Co National I'nioii Fire of Pittsburgh Nebraska LuihenMn'i Ins. Co.. Netherlands Fire Ins. Co iiii.:n 20.44 11.01 Nebraska Hardware Mutual Ins. Co 19.2S Law, I'liion Jk I'iM-k Ins. (■&lt;» Liverpool, Lnadoa &amp; Hiolw i&gt;f Km :i ( &lt;; {7."&gt;.r»t; •'i'. os </seg>
            <seg id="p055">ATh I I UK I'l iM: MISSION 55 New Hampshire Fire Ins. Co !*7.7!&gt; Newark Fire Ins. &lt; '&lt;&gt; 1!(.."&gt;'.» Niagara File Ins. Co I'.i.ii'.t Niagara Fire Ins. Co r.i.r,:i North River Fire Ins. Co L'T.TS North Uiver File Ins. &lt; 'o L'T.TS North Mriiisli ft .Mci.antilr Fire Ins. Co SU.48 North Mriiisli ft Mercantile Fire Ins. Co 31.48 Xortlu-rii Assurance Co Vt..~&gt;i&gt; Noitliwfsiciii Fire ft Marine Ins. di 22.K Sorth wester n Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co 22.S5 N'liriliwt'siciii N;uiun.il Pire Ii:&gt;. &lt;'o M3LM Northwestern National Fire Inf. Co L63.9U Norwich Uuion Pire Ins. Co B&amp;S2 Norwich Union Fire Ins. Co 58.32 N'onl I ttMltsclic Insiil;lli( r Co lS.'ts N'onl ! tetitsclie Insurance Co ls.'ts New I 'rnnswick Fire Ins ('&lt;» LAB New I trniisw i( k Fire Ins Co LAB Old C. ini.lv Fire Ins. Co t£jgj Old O.nolv Fire Ins. Co ll'.JST Orient Fire Ins. Co 41.44 Orient Fire Ins. Co 41.44 Palantine Fii-c Ins. &lt; 'o rt'.t.i'it intine File Ins. &lt; '■» rt'.t.i'it I'fim.-.x Ivia Fiiv Ins. Co lltt.)i."» l'enns\ Ivia Fire Ins. Co 1 1O.(5."» People's Xalimial Fir* Ins. Co 1 1. .*&gt;.". I'cople's National Fire Ins. Co 1 !..*»."» I'lincnix Pire Ins. Co., Hartford m 2'2U.D- I'linenix Fire Ins. Co., Hnrtfonl 229.9J Phoenix Ins. &lt; '&lt;&gt;.. London I5JM I'lioenix Ins. ( 'ii., Lonilon 4."&gt;.r»»; i'latic .Mutiin! Fire Ins. Co US i'latie .Mut iiiil Fire Ins. Co L'.O'J Providence Washington Pire Inn, Co 4i!.H» Washington Fire Ins. Co 42.lt I'insMaii National Fire Ins. Co tr&gt;.4»&gt; Queens ins. Co 1M.67 Ueliaine Fire Ins. Co Tl.s:'. Retail Merchant*) Ins. Co :!.r&gt;o Ulioile Island Fire Ins. Co 15.HU Uovai Fire Ins. Co liT:'&gt;.7»i Rxrhance Assurance Co --. ."&gt;7 ... Scottish Union &amp; National Fire Ins. Co 32.92 Secuiiiv Fire Ins. Co 155.6- Spriniitield Fire ft .Marine Ins. Co ."iC.it. L's Standard Fire Ins. Co 11.12 St. I'aul Fire ft Marine ."'.54. :.'."&gt; Sun Fire Ins. Co ":'.. 70 Svea Fire Ins. Co 3t.4C Western Assurance c«... Toronto 41.24 \\ estchester Fire Ins. Co t»4.S(i Williainsliui'i City Fire Ins. &lt; \i 1SL22 Inion Fire Ins. Co.. tax for I'M:', and UM4 200.0II Total #1l».::-J7.4« </seg>
            <seg id="p056"/>
            <seg id="p057">V1K KIKK COMMISSION ... INSPECTIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059">IN! M \i 1 ln\ VI \S!T.&lt;TloNS »1."» ::14 towns wen- visited uih! 1 4.."»ui I »t i.MNi; THI Vkak 1!)1."&gt; Tl»WXH IXSI'KITKII Kllui ( (niiilia ().\f(»l(| &lt;&gt;iik&lt;lal&lt;- O'Neill O:iklaii&lt;l Oioiitn &lt; Mlcans Old KMwimhI KM is \ i:iin On4 Klifiii Pairbarv I'aiiiiiuni KairiMd Fill Is Citx I'lilli-rtnn I' I'lviiioiuli Till r \ II \ II l'lattc rciiti'i- Kn&lt;li&lt;-&lt;&gt;! i Rdzar ( &gt;lii&lt;)\\ii &lt; &gt;MllllI|(l Orchard Ohm Oimi l".ll\Vll &lt; iiillldll I'Nltlsiiinlilli I'tilmyni I'apilliun I'.iwin'c &lt; 'it&gt; l'laiiivicw IN'i-n &lt; ioIIk'HIiII &lt; i Irtllil &lt; iflill" &lt; : i.i r • ! Cecil w i ii ii &lt; illilll- Ii'iii • 1 mui r.-n.lcr Pmmun ri.kit'i &lt; il |'&lt;-||'\ IVt«M-slnir«: </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 SKVKXTH ASM Al. ItWoltl n &lt; 11 \ I'.luii' &lt;i«'lH'V;l I'h'lvi I'.lil.l.Ml Gordon I'onto H\w Spring* I teenier &lt;M'iioa liivt'ito i Grant! Island Ituslivil Rattle Creek RrowarilW Itamroft Herman Hetuuiinirfortl Karen n IIiiiiiIimMi Kosali*' Howe Rohrw Homer Kepnbii Ililiiiin Kut-kvil llradshau Hendenum Uiiskin Itlooininuioii Brarfc Hcnd]&lt;\ Ramlol) lluimr Koscli Harhine Se*lan ll.ii -lin^i.i ii Sinn*' IVfCMro 4ohnwti s J'ollcjjr View -lafkscni laikson Sin; &lt; 'larks -liinsun •lansoii Stelli Cnili Orrktrd Lincoln MjiiiIu ciciii-wiiti'i' LyoBH Sim In &lt;'r;ii^ Louisvil Lonisvilh- Si I* Oinial city Oafcara Oinial « "it v ('oniKtock Lexbam Sl|l|i!ls ronistotk Lningi LraingttHi Silver &lt; 'ir Lpxinfton Silver ( &lt;'li«'st&lt;'i- Liidifn- &lt; "Im's(&lt;m- Cortlan.l Cliapinaii &lt; 'ott'S field &lt; 'liadi-on (VmIv Utehfielil Stteinnnei &lt;'nrtl;m,l l..llill;ini Laiihain Sioi; Cliiipmaii L— p &lt;' I.oilp City Speiici &lt; 'otcstit'ltl Lunniis Looinis Shicklf \ rhjidron LHmwii L«'I&gt;;iiioii Sheltuii &lt;'&lt;&gt;&lt;1.V I..V!!«I| Lynch Suinne riavfonia &lt;'l;ivtiinia L«»rt&lt;ni Lortoa St;i]il&lt;-t i&gt;n LoftoB Sta|ileli u I£&lt; -• I &lt; "Inm! Harvard ■ i! ul&lt;&gt; Unite heal lice Itocllls KurwHI llrilin Flk-k man Kavnt&lt; BoTcr &lt; 'itv Bertram! I'.iavion lla/.anl Si. R&lt; Kmvhard HiMicili Stcili I Suit II iiiii|&gt;linv Swi-«|i Itlooufk'kl Hiiopi-r S\\;iiii r.innsw irk Hu\vi'II&gt; Sclniv lity Ontrr Inavali- rtuper (Vrlcn Iimiaii Salem «'i«'t«' hh|M'iial Siiiini </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 KIBE ct&gt;M Ml.ssioN LiU-it.v Lmuun Bpankling Snvdt'i- Mrtibaer S|iciM-«'r St. LiImm-v Talniiijif Tnbian Law ivinr Liiui-t'l Taiiiui-ii T»'cnins«-li Til.l.'ii &lt; arkHou •••iillitoii i &gt;,\Vi \|;ir(|ll&lt;-ll. - .Mci'nok Weeping \\';ili|- Walton »;i\ 1(1 111 •nlillcsle .Mi'i i iinaii Mill.T West I'oiiii Wisiu'i- MollKM- Miiilcii M..H-.-II W'vnioi-r WjlVllc Wa'llliill lilt W'iiiiM'liai;"" Walla..- I Mill \«.i-r.»ik \.'lii;li Nciiialiji Nclsnli Wilsonvilh' Winiift/Min W.'lltl.M-t Ouliois I Mxun Wailtarh Wcstcin Wav.-ilv I " I in \\ I Illsir Klvriii &lt; "«&gt;Z;nl &lt; 'in-tis &lt; 'lisllilii; took Liiiilsn.v Lynch Lolly i'iiii' Lcwistuii Leiftk Miiilisuii &lt; "am &lt;"nal&lt; &lt; .illhn t Vi];ii- K;i|iitl &lt; 'oleridci 1 M«MHi &lt;"ii\ TVk;mi;ili MiinliM-k fih Barl Meadow &lt;imve I'nion MilVWoml Vt'ldoll Miilii-ny Vcst;i Miii-sliiiMl Vwdlgre Mcii.ii WilU'i- NYwiiiiin ISnnri N'rlliiwkil IfclMirl Kxt'tci K.I.Ivvilk KlIH'IS.IM i:ik Cnrk KMttlf Nuiili |.&lt;ni|i Western \il|MHI('&lt;- WjlVi'Hv Viobram WTiwwlrivrr Ninth IMilllr WUHHI N«\v.;isil&lt;- I WaMMI Nurili IU-ii.1 Winnide ()&lt;l&lt;-ll Wv.int \V;lt&lt; -rllon &lt; &gt;v&lt;&gt;ii«&gt;ii </seg>
            <seg id="p062"/>
            <seg id="p063">TATK KIRK COMMISSION «; FARM LOSSES IN NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p064"/>
            <seg id="p065">\IK KIKE COMMISSION 65 w 1 i W r. i hat III lift n.| w hit I It V In •elii N KAKM I.OSSKS IN NKISUASKA ■ the l-'iic ( i»:ii mission Law provides iluil lire chiefs pnri .ill tires i m» u iii nii in their district in thi- tin- I lepartmcnl has no way of BKWiag f; 1 1- 1 • &lt; mill iii older to make oin- records more authentic ii 1 1 1 l«-t •-. ill uin ;i mill;) I ie|M)il hist year we askinl nsurancc companies i|oin&lt;; Imsiness in Nebraska to I t&lt;&gt; us ea&lt;-li tire lli;i! llieir companv sustained, (tar w ;l&gt; as follow is otitre lias no way of &lt; &gt;lit ;t i ii i nt&gt; statistics on farm Mm ami we must reipiesi tire insurance companies farm risks to report to us each fire which they &lt;l upon to adjust. In this manner we can make records more complete and lie aMe to furnish statis which will mote correct Iv show the actual fire losses state. We will furnish tlit' various coinpanics writ - inn risks with all necessarv lilanks for rt'|MH-tinj: es and trusi ihat thev will nive us their co-o|M'i-a ihis matter for l'.iKJ." e followed this ap|ieal with a ppflMMl letter to everv insurance &lt;-ompiinv ihiini: Imsiness in Nelnaska, and ticall.v everv eompanv writinji farm risks wrote us the\ would l&gt;e to coinply with our re&lt;|iiest. We out some three llioiisatid rite report lilanks to the rein companies, lint regret to sav hat only ihree lanies. sent us in reports of losses in farm property h I hex were called upon to adjust. We wish mperi - to thank the I'nion Fire Insurance Company of Lin , Nelnaska. for their interest in this matter, and we ve that they have reported, without exception, every thev have sustained on their form risks. are \ei\ &gt;ori\ indeed tliaf we .ire not aMe to show </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 SEVENTH AXXFAI. UKI'ultl MH CMTMtlj the f;inn losses in Nebraska, bill unless t lie insurance companies take an interest in this matter ami are willing to fjo to the little trouble of sending us a re - |K)rt upon the lilanks which we furnish — we cannot com pile these statistics correctly. We Hffain earnestly re&lt;|iiest the insurance companies hi (■ken interest in this matter and to co-o]&gt;erate with i his Department so thai the statistics we •rather from tire losses in the state may lie compiled in a comprehensive and authentic manner. All the companies were supplied with blanks for this purpose last year. Imt if they haw mislaid or thrown them away, we will send another supplv upon re&lt;|iiesl. The reports which have conic to us show the following losses on farm pro|K-ri v : 1914 Value of liiiihlinys Value of contents Insurance on lint tilings | :t i,n:;. 711 jti,'.i:;ii on . . . . «»♦;,( iss. on Insurance on contents Ia&gt;k&amp; to liuiMinjjs Loss to content* Total loss L'ti,!t:t!t.tMI .".■_'.4^::.mi 23,747.tTi 7K,17O.7."i lit 1.1 Value of buildingM Value of contents Insurance on luiikliug Insurance am contents Loss on buildings L5J812.WI . . . . 49,020.041 .... ZlfiM.tm 21,174.1'ii Loss on contents Total loss !t.S(;4.lL' :t1.(»:{s.4l </seg>
            <seg id="p067">• 17 \TK 1'lltK COMMISSION COUNTRY FIRES </seg>
            <seg id="p068"/>
            <seg id="p069">KIttK COMMISSION 69 i ( ( mi;v Kibkk &gt;\vs the mini Ix'i- ;iml locution ol \ lire* in Nflti-Hxkti reported to us from .l:imi:trv 1, h.Ti-llll.cl- .'ll. I'll.') ''ouniies NiiiiiIm'I- nf Files Iiuli j Arthur ] . Ill-own 1 Holt \ .&lt; Irani i . &lt; msi.m- i York 1 t*itr\n 1 . I'lllllJIS 1 i . Knox 1 IMielps 1 . Xiilice •» . . Lincoln ] &lt; 'rawing Hevard 1 Boek l . .&lt; 'lister .Keith i I'l.llle I hiwson | Moll Knox • lister 1 .&lt; i.irtieM i .Ii;ill . &lt; lievenne 1 I l&gt;;l\\es 1 i Orchard Jolmson 1 I hmninK RImIw* 1 I &gt;i\on I Hxon j . I &gt;;i « son l Ihuinebrnc Howard • Kl|rin \ntelope ] </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 SEVENTH AX.MAI. KEIMMC1 Klba Howar.l l-usiis Frontii Karnaiii I &gt;a\vs&lt;&gt;ii PHlfV ( i;l"i- • Jriint Perkins &lt; Sotbenl»nru . i htw'MW • Sm*l«'V &lt; iicclcx &lt;M'lloa SaiH-l- Ilt'lnoii Thaw Harrington i "««dar Hazaicl Slit-iiiiaii !&lt;«•;( II l»-\ l.;iln ;l&gt;|f| LJn«*o||l I ),iu vnn Lexington Morrill Morrill Clu-riv .MnHcii I'illnu.i Millican Mariitum Norfolk \nt«'lo|»&lt; N'i'liirli \'a!l«-v Xoi-tli Lo«|i | »&lt; h 1 ii&lt; North I'.cih! Lincoln North Plan.' Keva Pahs NohIch «;iii&lt;i&lt;'n &lt; islikush &lt; iurtlen On] \ ; illr\ l»agp Holt I'fti'l slimi; I'.imiiii I'al r Merrk-k IMatle Sami.li r- F'flllr.l I&gt;ixuli Paxton Keith H«m1 rioud WCI.si.i Kisinj: City Rntler St. Edward Rtton«- SinlicrlaiKl Liiiculn Stiir Holt Spal&lt;lin&lt;r Oreelej Shorinan Fornax Swanton .Saline St. Paul Howard </seg>
            <seg id="p071">IRK CiiMMIssliiN ■ Inlmsnii Si \v;ml Hall .. \IIO\ Pot i. I </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 SKVRNTII A VMM UK I 'DIM Smoking I'oIitiiIi- out of iiolt S|K&gt;nt;i!icous conilii stion . . . t Mill Thresh in ji m;ichiin\ i;iiiil;Iii fVon ThftWtaf Wit wnter |,i|,es I'nkiiow n Weeds Imriiili" Caisks or F.Mt.M Kite IltK Itcil \\ : I r 1 1 1&lt;- 1- »t-l till- Iii Im-iI &lt; 'liinuicv, sp;irk fro &lt; 'hiiimc.v in- Him-, ili-li live Oiciisc tiikini: lire &lt;m siu\i &lt; IsisoliiM' ll;it iruii i^niti'il Illrliililtur Lantern « * x | &gt;l « »&lt; 1 1-&lt; l L;inlriii. cow or Iioim- kiikiiiu nver s;iu Match, »pMrkn tiuin in clothed rlfiKH . . Matt'hen ami rhikln'ii Miili-li. spiiiks living iiiini Oil st..\r &lt; Ml. rkwmng haracH n'itli saim- ... Stovi-. nvcllir;itt'il Stove. 4-jnijrh t from |in|M*r. n'omt or rnblii Wow, «lef«ti ve Slnoklllii. I:OVS or llll'M </seg>
            <seg id="p073">&gt; ATK KIRK COMMISSION »'■&gt; I'ikks ix en Iks ami Towns I Aslic&gt;. hot, thrown .i^iiinsi tNiildiiigH !&gt; A-hcs. liui. in wiMiilcn harrd &lt;&gt;v liox .'I Ashes, hot . hilling mi tluors or ciiivlcsslv thrown 1 i lloois or ciirclcsslx • ilii-own 1 AlltO, klrlvtil-illJJ •"» &gt; Auto. i;ikin&lt;r lire 3 Illr 5 Auto, viilriiniziujj. lire 1 1 • t" t Iwrniag 1 ilijiniziii-j. lire left ItnrnitiK 1 Ami. Ifiik 1 1 I'.i'X. hoi (in Imirlii); |nilii'v 1 rliii! iiiiiii'\ 1 Ituiilircs 7 i I toiler, iiuiuiii Iioiii - lUu-k tiring - •&gt; ( 'liiiniii'.v sparks Irn H K9 • ';ilimli&lt;- ;|ci«l. llli'll ill^; Silllli- &lt;U| stuVf 1 lie oil stiiVf 1 « 'IlilHIK'V llcl'citivc 71 71 fliiiuiHM l»nrniii|&gt; mil •• I 'liiniiicv | »1 niiii* •• I willi \vo&lt;m1 1 ||||1!I!I«hI W il ll Wood 1 &lt; 'luisl iii;is &lt;;i in 1 1 cs mi 1 1 ( * 'hiiniH'.v slop Iffi &lt;nii •'» &lt; 'ii;;ii- up &lt; "ij;;ii&lt;'tl( s c;ircli'ssl v tliruwn Ki &lt; 'hiiiiiu'V ovi'i-lii';iii'il 1 n playing witli irr 8 ( i "|r;il Her. vnljllilf explosion 1 li-ii- wiling ili'fcriive 4"J Icl'i st.nitliiii; on cloth 4 Klrclric wires nil u:i^ jt'l &gt;.; </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 sKVKNTII ANMAI. UKI'oltl" Kx plosion, car I ii hi Fi reworks I Furnace pipe, cauirht trom Furance. defective . . . ... . . Pomace, kotc ur owrhe«ted Furnace, hot or overheated. Furnace, caught from tthig tire to kindling diisli loo near to. . . . w in ti Ftirnace. lirooui set over rt Lll ter. Furnace, lied lakinj; lire from regintei Fuinij;atini; I • iasoliue stove &lt; iasoline e.\]ilosiou or ignition &lt;Iasoline stove leaking I'll &lt;iasoline used in cleaning clothing. plnmeH, eic. (■asoline cottee urn lau^lil lire while tilling sain &lt; iasoliue Hat iron ignited &lt;iasoline lani]i or lighting plant &lt; iasoline engine &lt;irease lakinjr tire on slove lioilinj; &lt;&gt;\i Hanoi iue, ntartins lire with same .. aiiii- &lt;irass luirnin^ around luiildin Inciihator. caught from Inceiiiliarv :.u Lamp exploded V Lain]) or open light, curtain, ranghi Iron Lamp, i-a ugh 1 from Lamp dropped on lioor Lantern 1 Lightning I: Locomotive, sparks from Match, sparks from in clothes closet Matches in clotlics VI I .Matches carelessness with 17 Fuiiiiirt'. explosion &lt;&gt;! &lt;;&lt;is healer upset &lt; Jiis stove, I'uujchl from &lt; iasi stove tun cldsc to woodwork &lt; iilS lcilkill^ (ias jet, caughi from </seg>
            <seg id="p075">K1KK I I &gt;M MISSION STATl 75 Matches ami children •"»'•&gt; Matches iiin! niitf !•"» M.-Mclies iiMiiti-d by suns rsivs 1 Match, spark t1\ ini: from mum l\ Match, spark t1\ ini: from MUM •&amp; Motor short cin-iiiir&lt;l 4 Motor short rirrnittfl 4 Motcr. sparks in nil room Motor, spai-ks in nil room &lt; til utovf leakiag &lt; Ml lank l.urst iny Nd on pressure tank 1 &lt; Ml so;ikci] waste ranglM ttom 1 &lt; Ml so;ikci] Wiisic fjiny;lit (loin 1 &lt; »i i stove, cniiiilil I'roni -T &lt; »i i sto\ c, i-anehi 1'rom -" nil healing stove " nil healing stove ' I'lmiilif rs lilow poi •' I'lllllllicl-s hlow |tol *t l';l|Ml- ltillloon on loot' 1 Ml- ltilllooll OH lOdf 1 Ki ;isui . coffee takini: tire iii it 1 ee takint: tin- in it 1 Uiililii&gt;li. baniian Haute cai-elesslv &lt;» liiirniiij: same carelessly i\ Smoking. 11(1 ;in&lt;l liovs 8 .» Slo\e, ovei-llt'ilti'il -4 ve, overlieateil -4 nve. caniili lioni |Miper, wood or niMiish too close.. 1 Sllnve. r.nilill tioni |Miper, wood or lllMiisli too close. . 1 Stove loo dose to \\;lll ol- woodwork 9 in wall or woodwork 9 Stove ciiiijjit from 4 e caniiln from 4 Stove tinner's 1 1 Move I HUH Stove, sparks from - • &gt; Stove, clothing banjtinff too near 1 tliiiiii hMngtns too near 1 Stovepipe, ciiiiuht from H* iiie. canullt flom !•' Stovepipe, throii^li ceiliiiii. roof or wood partition... '2i iliioiiiili .-fi I i nii. roof or « 1 partition... 24 Smoking in h*d lS Smoking in IhmI Suspicions -0 211 MIM &gt; &gt;piMoon. \\ li'ii - Spnntiineoiis coinlin&gt;lion 4S Forvh overlieated Torcli o\crlie;lted r rr;unps, set liv " liiknown :&gt; &gt;^"» Water pipe* and t;ink&gt; tli;i\\ inir out -I 121 r» </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 SEVENTH AXNTAI. BEIMIK1 : i S}U3iUO3 br lf ! / uo ssoq /. / -. i uo sscrj /. ■/. Sinp|ing uo V- y. X 33UHJnSUJ /. S}U3jUOn I- — X jo an|BA /. r;u.p|ina isszsSssilH-s i - jo anjCA •/. S / — Sinpimg ~; -3 = i~ ?■ " 3DUBjnSUI * — .- -i - "I -i — - r: sajijjo-oN &lt;H3 I = i jo auiej^ -r .E </seg>
            <seg id="p077">BK COMMISSION i • ■/ »~ i i- i_ i- — y. — — i I X — -I i i- ti ■ x I »" £ )* tt C 1 i :i rt Ji X ti / i i i f. i i i )- — &gt;~ ~*. 1.-71 J. i- i- i- c i- i~ - S i- / /' l- &gt; &gt;~ S t I I j i* Ci i I /. « « I- I i / i i &gt; i* it • x r. x. '* 1 71 i i i- ri n ri — i i ti &gt;t — i / J l\\ I y / / N u f &gt; : l </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 SEVENTH A.VXIAI. KKl'nKI s)uajuo 3 v.s^'SSb 1 -?,-""?."--!'-^/^ i rt ~. — / uo ssoq riumnnu = ~ § - ■ : &gt;' 7 - ; r :i -" E c : - c i" i »* .n. a / :: c. - • x X — — &gt;~ i~ — ~ — i- i~ i- y_ r i UO SSOq ti y. i- — — _ — - £t ?, (U3JUO3 uo : 5 § i* § § § § :§ §§= : i = = : SJU3JUO3 UO a3uejnsu{ ~ / ~ / / »3uejnsu[ '-'^ — — -;— ' rirf— — ' Mlipifilj-J uo uipimg uo §||5 = i| = i = § aDUEinsuj ' " -j '-"; '~- -' 7l - Z' 'j. -' ' 2 - jjuBinsuj ' ~ -j '-"; '~- -' 7r - Z' !-: -■ ' 7i '-' -• ~ / i s,u3;uo D =§i = §|| = i = g2 sjua;uo3 c g g c * g : jo an|B A "l!'?^^^I:" r: ""~77~^^^: guipnng JO 3I1|HA Huipung =§§§ :§ = §!:= = = = = §i:§ = £ X r ; i- y. = :: — — s i - i- i- it :- c ,: / — aniE\ ?-; — «r-t tl -«« - -' r f -t x r; i- "/. • 5 5* S — J i: i* S it ■ i-r ,:'/ saai^ }o on aai^ jo -on r: ,: - - ,- , - , :,:,■.-- -.1. = r — ~ - -£.*/ — •: = M!3 — 3 * J = -= -5 jt r^t&gt;I^i 7 = JO 3UIEN ;" = _= z 1 ~. 5 = = J "t I- f- 2 1 i= r. 7! </seg>
            <seg id="p079">:■• i — It I* '" ■J. Ml i /. i i i / i ; /. j. at / /. / STATE F1KK COMMISSION .— r: — &gt;; s — ~ is 15 c 1- • &gt;t s • — 1: :i c / :i /. c - r it - :i; . — iSSXtS ti rt --i • = —■-- ~. -\ -\ i- i~ — /. »Si"i&gt;H 3j s i- i~ — -» — ti — ' ss i- rf — ' it -r rt* — " :r " - i: i- r: r: ■ rf — • ti • i- • i- • • —. — ". '" *&gt;. —.'-""* ' *". • — . •" ' — — rf — PS i- — '■ ''' ' CI ' —•" ' -f* ~ — — ir. ~ i- :\ — &gt;-. &gt;-. — i- ~ — &gt;• . to a • : '" re ci / i- •"' — c ' : — — T 1 tl — — ' «■:" ::' ?i —* — .-' — — ' /. t~ • z\ ■ 3 — </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 seventh .\\.\i \i. f:ki'&lt;&gt;i:i i -\ / / |§ uo ssoq »«!Pi«na §p?.l ■■iA^^c^;~^iA uo ssoq M ~ ~ - dDueansuj | - -' - - :: / n'uipnny uo § g g = § | | | | ; = = § : $ -s - - - it i-i: i- 5 :: - i — i — &lt; — • i'- ■ S aauBjnsuj -;____• _• • .-• -■ Jiuipimy uo aauBjnsuj -; _■ S}uajuo3 = = •*== iiisxT'isl!!? 1 ' SJU3JUO3 ~ ~ &gt;' ,o an , BA E 5 X 5f! 3;r"^I Hu'Plina 5 f VI § I 1 1 * S I 1 § Vf .^ ~ § 5 fc'uipimg JO 3niP : \ ,r_t;^r: ? ! ,^ / S3iljp-OM _ -i n 7I - --. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">SI (OM MISSION i / i- • ;i ii i fi / &gt;t it X i c it I- Tl x — i- •■ — - i l~ l~ tl I- I / / I I I I , w • ~ I / t i~ it • /. i: -i I I I — X I i / t it 1 Tl i ■ i;t / I tl tl t i I it C i ~ v. • » / I I it ti i i / i it ti i i i i /. /. / 7 t. « / x. it x. x. x x. x. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 SKVKNTII \NM Al. UKI'dUl sjuajuo^ ] ~. - '' ?_ ''■ : 5 ,? p ~~\ I / i - 1 i UO SSO"] Suipimg Ti ' uo ssoi i - ' i X V S}U3}UO3 Ul 33UPiIli&gt;UJ jo auiejsj </seg>
            <seg id="p083">I MISSION - I y / / t i / / i i i 1 1 1 I i I 71 /. I 1 i / f 1 '. I I /- : : 2 /. 7. - * i i l. a' x /. /. /. x /. x /. -i. £ /- x v x x i x /. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 SEVENTH AXNTAL UKI'olM i- / 3u!PI!ng Si f ?,!: II Z p. fi jszSf.s ?J uo ssot "■ Tl i y /. i sjuajuo^uo a:&gt;ue.insuj "' '• /. Jimpiing uo / aDucansuj ■/. siuaiiKr) /. '/. ;" /. jo an|B\ ■/ Suipiing ~l Tl 7 l" / jo anjE.\ ri S3.UJ JO ON :: " _ i- s - /. -L / — s ~ *»!0 % joauiEfyi SIU3JU03 5 § 5 g ; U § £ ?i uo ssoq — </seg>
            <seg id="p085">K &lt; u.MMlSsliiN COMPARATIVE TABLES </seg>
            <seg id="p086"/>
            <seg id="p087">ATK 1 IKK COMMISSION 87 1'OSITAKATIVK TAIILKH I IkII.iw i nji l.ililo show the villllf of hnilililljjs iillii d him! the iinioinii nf tlnmn^c t-iius&lt;&gt;&lt;l l&gt;y tire for flu* i l'.Hlt. I'.ill. 1!»1_'. l!li:t, 1!»14 ;iml 191."i Itlf Value ..I l»iiililiiij;s * T.(&gt;til,17."».tMi \ iiiilihii Valw of &lt; onients .'&gt;,71S,l.V.t.(M» Vnlnr of (•intents , r Insurance &lt;&gt;n liiiiMinins 4,753,628.00 liiMiriiiu -c on t-outi'iiis :'.,X47,C&gt;90.00 IliMUMIli r on rolitcnts :!, Los&gt; to l.niMinjjs 1,0!&gt;7.40:',.00 lililini: Loss to contents 1,083.855.08 o itinit'iiis l,us::.»i."M.(M» IM1 Value i»f lniililiu&lt;&gt;s x S,(&gt;S7.414.(M&gt; V«lQf ot rolilt'llls N.IMm.SU.OO \iiliic i»f contents N.IMiT.SlT.OO I n&gt;in-;ini-i- on luiililin^s r»,7i&gt;."&gt;,!M(l.."&gt;U InMii;in&lt;c on .onicnis ."),i'S!&gt;,S!M».7."» llMll;in&lt;e on . i. nil-Ills o.L'SiJ.SJMt.T."* jmm hi l.nil.liiiiis 1 .01 7,^1 l.fi.% LfMw n. liiiil.lin.iis 1,(11 7,21 l.fi." Loss to rolltellls 7li().!U 1 .&lt;»."» Loss to rontcnis 7l!().!Ul.&lt;tr» lit 11' V.-iliic ol lniililinj;s s. \\,:\7:i.-2S4..\s Valve of contents (;,l»;s.:i!»7.r»4 \iilue of contt'iils (;,l»;s.:!!»7.."4 Insurance on hvildiajpi 4,!HS,:U0.(M» Insurance on hnililinjpj 4,!)1S,:U(I.(M» InsniiiiKe on conlents :{,809,970.0&lt;l liisiii;in&lt;e on contt-nts :t,S09,970.(MI Loss i&lt;» lniililiiij:s S(»!»,(KiS.4O Ltmm to (onteiits I.::i4.."&gt;(!.!&gt;:{ IM3 191.1 \iiltie of luiildini:* I 5,432,421^8 Yiihit of luiililin-s r&gt;,432,421.:til s Value of contents ljtB1 F BHBP Value of contents 4,051^43.58 Insni-aiice on Imiltlin^s 3^84,453.011 Insni-iiMi-e on bniklinuM :'.,: :!.'»S4,4.").(M» Insuiiiiice on contents LMUD.itlil.lMI Ilisiiiaiice on cotili'iils | Loss to liuililin^s 7!&gt;'?,(&gt;7S.7&lt;&gt; Loss to « onteiits !&gt;•_•!. SS7.."U </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 SEVKVTII A.NXI Al. UKI'iiltl III IIH n i I'.H 1 Elllc of iNHMillfpi 111*' of colnilts. * ."..'.I l!l. si II I i.('»T&gt;4.0S(i liiMHiiiicc on buihlinp* Insurance on ( oiiiiin&gt; . i.::::..l'ns IJSS.L'IT ti Ik Itiiililin-js s to content h. 7:&lt;7.-J'.tj:ut l.l l.'i.T^J '.' 1 !»!."• \;illlr »f iMliltlilljp*. \';ililc of idiiicnts. . llisii|-;lllcc oil lillililin Ilisiii-iiiicc on content Lmm to Imihliiiffx . . . F 7. i».tr».r, i:i. mi 1(1 •VJi'T.ir.i.iMi 1.007 1.&lt;M Loss to content SIX Vi Sv|| Ih r&lt;it;|l Willie «if |i|ip|;im| V mi |j T&lt;&gt;t;ll loss nf |n-n|M'il\ i,\ lire ihi six \ i-;ii-s Tnl.ll : 1 1 1 1 &lt; • 1 1 1 1 1 ill' j &gt;i&lt; &gt;| &gt;• si iliclion \&gt;\ till'. iTlli- lilcnicli of llic stale ;||-c i-nli is cii&lt;iiiiiuh&gt; Miiiuinit of iiiu|mmi\ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>