<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00013">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00013</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>SIXTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Asylum for the Chronic Insane AT HASTINGS, NEBRASKA, TO THE GOVERNOR.  FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900</title>
		             <date value="1901">1901</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-24</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>

			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">SIXTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

Asylum for the Chronic Insane 

i\ 

G-OYER1TOB. 

OR THK BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1900 

, NEI 
PAXV 

\T HASTINGS, NEBRASKA </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
KOAKD OF CONTROL 

Joseph T. Steele, M. 1» . 
Daniel S. Woodard, M. I) 
Halle L. Ewins;, M. l&gt;. .. 

Fiisl Assistant 

Si-cond Assistant I'll 

•James B. Barnes. 
Miss Xettie Honn 

Stew 
Mai 

Ja&lt;ol&gt; V. Wolfe. . . .Commissioner of Public Lands ami Buildii 
William F. Porter Secretary of St; 
John P.. Meserve Treasure, of st, 
• •unstant ine .1. Smyth \ttornev &lt; iene 

RKSIDKXT OFFKKKS </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
i 

REPOKI 

His Excellency. William A. Poynter. Governor of the State of 
Nebraska : 

1 have the honor herewith to submit the following report, for 
e sixth biennial period of the Asylum for Chronic Insane, 

nding November :50. 11MMI. 

There has been an entire change in the resident officers during 

his biennial period, with the exception of matron. I assumed 
ontrol of the institution May l. r &gt;. 1S!«); Dr. Kohert Uamerell. my 

redecessor. having tendered his resignation, to take effect at 
hat date, and l&gt;r. 1&gt;. S. Woodard. appointed to micceed me as 

sistant physician, assumed his duties at the same time. 

lames I». Barues succeeded^Mr. Scott as steward, who resigned 
• ii tlie 15th of May. An act having passed the legislature pro- 

for a female physician. Dr. Halle Kwiug was appointed 
nd assistant physician, and began her duties July 1. MMM). 

There remained in the institution at the close of file fifth 

Hiinial period six hundred twenty-six |(!"_M&gt;| patients; three 
indred forty six i:!4(ii males, and two hundred • eighty C2S0) 

There were received by admission two hundred twenty 
lieiits; one liuiidi i-d fifty (l")(h males, and seventy |7(I) 

males; by re-coiinnit ttnent one ill male; by return from fur 
ugh seven; three |3| males, four i4l females. 

l'liele Wei 

Males. Females. Total 

harged as cured "_' 11 IS 

7(J 4:'. U!» 

Now in hospital 

. .41fi 21)7 71.-* 

40S 

::.')4 

S52 

liscliiirjrcd improved 
:-• -iipfd </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
210 

I.ANll I'OMMISSIOXEK 

UKI'OKT. 

Leaving at the end of this biennial period. Nov. :»(&gt;. 1000. 718. 
The greatest number present daring the period was October 5, 
1900, 42.{ males aud 3041 females; and the least number present at 
anv one time during the biennium was Feb. 14. lSlt'.t. 338 males. 
27*J females; total. 610. The daily average number present during 
the biennium ending Nov. 30, 1900, was (&gt;57. 

There has been an average of eight sick jwitients dailv. and 
ll!t deaths, whirh is about S per cent. Tsikinjr into consideration 
the fact that most of the patients admitted to this institution 
are aged, and many infirm, the rate of mortality is certainly verv 

low. 

With one exception all deaths above reported were due hi iiht 

ual causes, no suicides or homicides having occurred during th&lt; 

period. No epidemics have visited the hospital, and 

health and physical cHndition of patients has been exception 
good. The dietary has been liberal and abundant, and &lt;&gt;u I 

days and special occasions the patients have been siij 

w 

fruit and oilier delicacies suitable to the sea 

As many male patients as 

ible have been en 

farm and in the garden, beside I hose who ai 

Mam of the female patients are employed in sewing roo 

hens, laundry, and dining rooms. In 
e is now largely composed of inmate: 

Officers' department 

I 

iliout tlir stables and van! </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
CHBDNIC IXSAXK ASYU'M, HASTINGS. 

211 

Males. Females. Total 

s 

wins; 

. 

i 

liter shop 3 

Mil jobs 22 22 

Total 156 

15fi 

Upsides being &lt;»f direct benefit to those employed, it is a gre 

Uesides being &lt;»f direct benefit to those employed, it is a great 

aving to i he state in labor. It will be noticed that our pav-n 

lie state in labor. It will be noticed that our pay-roll 

s very light for the number of inmates we have under treatinei 

wry light for the number of inmates we have under treatment, 

nil i lie per capita cost of maintenance at this institution is on 

ic per capita cost of maintenance at this institution is only 

i boil l one-half what it is in other institutions. This is largely 

ibout one-half what it is in other institutions. This is large 

lue to the saving in labor, and to the large amount of vegetables 

lue to the saving in labor, and to the large amount of vegetabl 

mil produce raised on the place. With a view of making tl 

id produce raised on the place. With a view of making tht 

nstitiition lo some slight degree self-sustaining 1 have undt 

islitution in some slight degree self-sustaining I have under 

al;cn i lie organization of an industrial department, and with tl 

inization of an industrial department, and with tht 

• [-operation of the Hoard much can be accomplished in this wn 

peration of the Hoard much can be accomplished in this way. 

We are ;it present conducting a sewing room, in which from 

Ye are at present conducting a sewing room, in which fro 

even td feii people are constantly employed, and where we ina 

people are constantly employed, and where we man- 

ifacture all the garments, bedding, towels, etc., for the fenia 

he garments, bedding, towels, etc., for the femalt 

vards. beside the bedding and a great amount of general sewil 

side the bedding and a 

reat amount of general sewing 

in the entire institution. 
We also manufacture all our own mattresses, at a saving 

list itution 

\\ 

iwii mattresses, at a saving of 

in- 

boiil one-half in cost. Thirty people are engaged in the laundi 

il one-half in cost. Thirty people are engaged in the laundry. 

di.-re L'M.oitll pieces arc washed each week. requiring the use 

rvh.-re 2'UMMI pieces arc washed each week, mini ring the use of 

¦w&gt; pounds of soap, which is manufactured at comparative 

nap. which is manufactured at comparatively 

iuli- expense, and much waste material being made use of th 

f. and much waste material being made use of that 

I'liiM otherwise be lost. Fpom two to three people are at woi 

se be lost. Fi-om two to three people are at work 

it The carpenter shop: besides keeping up genera! repairs, mal 
greal inany articles of furniture. 
F:mn:ng and stock raising have been carried on extensive! 

&gt;p: besides keeping up general repairs, make 

»f furnitui 

sing have been carried on extensively. 

We keen constantly mi hand fron 

Ve keen • ¦uiistant I v on hand from (id to KMI head of beef cattl 

• to 1(11) he:id of beef cattle 

.hid! aie l'"&lt;i ami slaughtered here, providing the very choice 

oviding the very choicest 

,\ 

f meal. Reside raising all the hogs necessary for use we ha 

iry for use we have 

urned into the credit of the institution from sales during tl 

(lit of the ill 

ion from sales during the 

ear about $1..~&gt;IH&gt;. and now have on hand 25(1 head We al 

n hand 250 head. We also 

.")(( COWS 

vhich supplies an abundance </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
212 

LAND COMM1 

IOXKK 

liKI'nilT. 

of fresh milk ;ind cream for kitchens, dining rooms, and in 

Urinary. 

The farm and garden have yielded abundantly, and have full \ 

met the demands of the institution for vegetables of all kind 

in their season. The following figures will give some idea of 

the amounts raised and consumed: 

&lt; 'ucuinbers, dozen 200 

&lt; 'abbage. dozen heads 19,000 

( tarrots, bushels 444 

&lt; 'oru (green), dozen 2.1&amp;S 

Egg plant, dozen 48 

Lettuce, dozen bunches &lt;W2 

Melons, water, dozen 321 

Melons, musk, dozen 304 

Onions, bushels 441 

Onions (green), dozen bunches 3,000 

Potatoes, bushels 5.8(M 

J'ie plain, pounds 

Radishes, dozen buuches 

2,80n 

Tomatoes, bushels 4&lt;;4 

Tnrnijm. bushels 7."»&lt;i 
The matter of proper amusement and entertainment is out- 

The matter of proper amusement and entertaiiimeii 

which greatly concerns the management of all institutions of 

which greaflv concerns the management of all institu 

ions 

This kind, and with the very limited means at our command has 

this kind, and with the very limited means at our command has 

required very close attention in order that anything like satis 

required very close attention in order that anything like satis 

factory results might be obtained. Our amusement hall was 

factory results might be obtained. Our amusement hall was 

built for the use of the institution when it contained not more 

built for the use of the institution when it contained n 

m&gt; 

than 200 people, and is, for present demands, practically useless. 

than 200 people, and is. for present demands, practically useles 

I have asked that an appropriation of #14.000 be made for th&lt; 

purpose of rebuilding and enlarging the cottage with an aiims 

nient hall on second floor. 

Through the kindness of the editors of a large number of news 

papers and periodicals we have been able to provide gratuitously 

considerable reading matter: and ministers of different denom 

nations have occasionally contributed to the social ami spirit </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
213 

HROXI 

IXSAXE ASYI.IV, HASTINGS. 


i 

I 

I 

.vellbeing of our people, for which rhe management desire to 

xtend their cordial thanks. 
The regular Thursday evening 

dances have been in progress 
season, and are enjoyed by the 
oiniiiodate. During the winter 
and other entertainments are 
applied with all sorts of games 

xcepting during the very warm 
united number we are able to act 

m a number of fancy balls 
ded. The wards are amply &gt; 

urs who are inclined to participate in snch amusements 

EI'AIKS AND l.\ 

I'KllVKMEX'I 

Vi no period during the history 
¦n done iii this line as during 1 

of the institution has as much 
he past two years. The inside 

f the building has been thoroughly overhauled; wards, dormi- 

nd side rooms have been painted, decorated, and in 

new floors have been laid. Much has been added 

patients in this way, beside 
ondition. 

Main 

his institution are from their 

•e hopeless, and a large part of the population will be coni- 

¦d to spend their remaining years here; no pains should 
pared to add to their comfort and pleasure. I have en- 

vored. as far as possible, to remove every idea or suggestion 

if the prison or asylum, and to make their surroundings as 

homelike as possible. With this aim in view, the 

ivalls have been tastefully decorated with drapes and pictures 

he windows furnished with lace curtains; rugs and carpets have 

&gt;een supplied and so arranged as To make the apartments atractive. 


A greater amount and variety of Mowers have been used and 
iring the winter months the wards have been abundantly sup- 

plied. From friends and relatives of patients, who were able 
md cared to do so. 1 have solicited rocking chairs and other 

nfort and conveniences not supplied by the state; 

nd in this way about :i(H&gt; attractive pieces of furniture have 
een secured, which add materially to rhe comfort of patients 

*s well as the attractiveness of the wards. 

•it and pleasure of tl 
nproving t lie sanitary 
he cases admitted to </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
214 

LA NT 

COMMISSIONER 

BBPORT. 

During the summer mouths the patients are kept a greal portion 
of the time in the open air; usually taking a walk it, 
the country doting the morning hours, while the afternoon and 
evening is spent under the shade of the trees on the lawn and 
about the building. To provide for the increasing demand iu 
this particular, as well as to add to the beauty and attractive- 

tion up to the present time with the most gratifyh 

everything in connection with the same being the latest imj 

and strictly first-class, with capacity sufficient to manufacture 

five tons of ice every 24 hours and maintain proper temperat 

in our cooling rooms 

The boilers, engines, and dvnamo have been removed fron 

their former location to the new building and all placed 
substantial foundations, with new fronts for boilers and 

new boiler added, now giving us a batterv of five la 

sufficient to meet the n 

stantial and commodious tunnel has b 
from the boiler room underneath the old 

¦ad in 

house and engill 

room to the junction box of the old tun 

200 ft., though which all steal 

and cables for electric lighting pli 

their connection with the main plant and wing bv usi 

already in place, making a complete system 

ness of the grounds, the lawn has been enlarged and many new 

H- 

I SIN 

trees have been set out. 

The entire front of the building has been repaired and painted 

a new porch and cupola lias been built; an incandescent an 

light placed over the main entrance; all greatly improving tin 

appearance of the .institution. 

The sum of flo.OOO was appropriated bv the last legislatun 

for the purpose of erecting a building to be used for boilei 

house, engine room, and cold storage; and providing and puttinj 

in place the necessary machinery, also new wells and air lif 

pump. The building has been constructed in a very substantia 

and satisfactory manner; the ice machine and refrigerating plan 

was ready for operation June 1. and lias been in constant opera </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
215 

HliOXlt 

IXSAXK ASYLUM. HASTINGS 

During the summer the heating system has been reorganized 

ii a cost of #7.i'4T. and so arranged that we have three distinct 

heating plants, one for the center building and one for each 

wing, with proper return pipes, so that either may be operated 

ndependent of the othe 

There lias also been placed in each steam main a pressure 
;ulatiug valve with steam gauge, by which we may know ex 

and regulate at all times, the necessary amount of steam 
p all parts of the building at proper temperature. 

lie courtesy of the management of the B. &amp; M. Railde 
track has been built from their main line to our 

li i&lt;-li enables us to unload coal without re-handling; 

iiid when it is remembered that in extreme weather we use 
iIioiii one car load of coal per day. it will be readily seen this 

t great saving of time and labor. 

Heretofore the buildings have been very poorly supplied with 
ire protection; in fact, this matter seems to have been almost 
¦ntirely overlooked. I have placed Babcock tire extinguishers in 
onvenient places and have put in a number of new water mains, 

with sufficient hose to reach any part of center building. A room 

lias been set apart exclusively for lire apparatus with two hose 
carts and about l.(MN) ft. extra heavy fire hose, with nozzles 
and other appliances for immediate and successful operation, 

and it is my purpose, should it meet the approval of the Board 

iiid Supplies, lo put in place a good sized tire alarm 

lize a tire department, and to equip and maintain 

ie highest point of efficiency 

Numerous smaller improvements have been carried forward 
ring the past bie.nnium, shch as grading of roadways, paving 

ters with rock and tiling same so as to carry off all surface 

nd outbiiildi 

T 

ntial fences, besides the re-model 

n for carpenter shop and store- 

ibout the building ;m&lt;l 

ill order and repair, and we are ready to 

further needs of the institution </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
216 

LAM) COMMISSIOXKH's REPORT. 

I 

? 

i 

NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION 

Ir will be noticed from the figures given above that only 
small number of female patients were admitted to the institute 
daring the ]»asr t\\(» years, compared with those on the oth&lt; 
side of the house. This is owing to the very crowded conditu 
of the female wings, which were originally intended to ac.oni 

date ±J0 patients and have at present l &gt;( .)7. The appropriati 
recomiiK nded by the superintendent, and passed bv the last l&lt; 

can be carried in warm from the patients" kitchen to the table 
The second floor, which would be 40 ft. wide, by 120 ft. in lengtl 
is to be used for an amusement hall; and the upper floor to lj 
occupied by employees as sleeping rooms. Also $5,000 has bee 
asked for a barn, and f 1.400 for two new wells and pumpin 
machinery. With these additions and improvements this inst 
tution would provide for 1.000 patients with necessary ofticet 
and employees. 

In making my estimates for the regular appropriations fci 
the coming hienniiim I have based my figures upon a daily ave: 
age per capita of 35 cents, and have asked that the followin 
amounts be appropriated: 

's 

lslatnre. of |30.000 for an annex for female patients, was entirt 

inadequate. I would, therefore, recommend that the sum of $4 

QflO'be appropriated for a fireproof building sufficient to ami 

modate 2&lt;MI patients, similar in architet tare and construction 

the one recently built and now in use on The male side. 

The other asylums. 1 understand, are now crowded to Ilu 

utmost capacity, and with the exception of possibly l'O m;i 

patients, no more can be received at this institution until fi 

ther accommodations have been provided. 

1 have also asked for rt 4.000 for enlarging and improving pr, 

ent kitchen and amusement hall. We are now compelled 

carry the fond from the kitchen out of doors for a long distan 

to the dining room. The appropriation asked for contemplat 

the addition to the north and south ends of the present cotta 

building in rear court of 411 ft., with basement and tunnel en 

necting the same with the general dining rooms, so that the fo« 

le f </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
C 1XSAXE ASYl.IWI, HASTIN 

17 

Maim 

uler many obligations, and hero desirt 

en- miiiring energy and loyal support ha\ 

ssisted me in the discharge of the duties of nn orti 

so glad to have an opportunity to here ucknow ledge the 

I by the Board of Public Lands and 

ing upon a superintendent 

essened by the confidence and support of tin 

dly given, and I desire to as 

ition 

is my pleasure and duty to acknowl 
your Excellency for the wise counsel 

fesv, and 

:' generous support you have given. 
ibniitted. 

Superintendent 

*144.&lt;iOO IM&gt; 

fliecra and employ* 

•I. T. SlKKI.E, M. I) </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
218 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

I 

TEWARDS KEPOH'l 

Balance of appropriation of HH&gt;7 on h 

Kami 

Employees' wages 
Fuel and lights . . . 
Board and clothing 

¦1 

Music and amasements. . 
Repairs and improvements 
Fnrnitnre and bedding . . . 

451 

u 

1- 

Incidental expenses 

m; 

Drugs, books, and instrument* 
Paints and oils 

li. 

¦I 

Stationery and postage . 
Telephone and telegraph 
Freight and express. . 

44(i 85 
19:5 16 

Burial expense. 

Transferring patienU 
Superintendent's salary 
Assistant physician's salary 

Total 

'J appropriation oj i«:&lt;7 on Hand .\ ovember .10, ls:&gt;* 
same to March SI, ISO'', and balance reverting to stm 

BaUnce of ' Expended Balance 
1897 appro- to March Tertiug 
priation 31, l^S'i treasur 

¦mxi (X) -iim (hi -in in 
158 !.""&gt; 17 4!l 14(1 !« 
1IHNI (HI 1IMHI IKl 

$46-r&gt;t&lt; 22 $:mo:s «i $11 </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
CHROXIO 

IXSAXE ASYLUM. HASTINGS. 

219 

x5 

? 

m ¦ ¦ .joe e 

* : 5 ::::::: : : : - IS 

r- 

£ n fr. 

5"S^3E 

ast- • x o&lt; -w = 

&lt;- 

i 

¦^ 

* 

i 

— — i- i- ??w(N^ S 551 e 

¦/ 

«fr 

«» 

¦2R s 9 !P x te i- r- o &gt;-i s is o o o o s cj 

*SxSi*.SS£SxSSS^5SS §. 

rjESs-j'-tssvijii;? I « 

x ?i ic l*: if* — 

fc-5! I 9C 

V. 

* - s 

-*- 

/ 


-&lt;¦ 

-I 

V, 

3 


t.' X — 


2 m-Sx 

» i 

i 

3 O- (T S 
t- — r. t, 

K-&lt;5 


r? = — — i- d s a 51 n i 

= tr 

— ¦ 

»_ X r~ 35 L~ 30 «D 1~ t~ O u? CO i.~ = U3 
i s|gs- i ca«8s5 i -gg 

— -s. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
220 

LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT. 

Appropriations for the bienniil peril 

d, April 1, 1899 to March 

A PP™P" a - £3£K Ba.anc&lt; 

Fund 

tion 

1900 

Superintendent's salary. . . 
Assistant physician's salary 
Female physician's salary. . 
Employees' wages 

$4000 00 $3000 00 $1000 01 
3000 00 2250 00 750 0( 

2400 00 1500 00 900 Oi 
47800 00 38655 51 9144 4! 

Board, olothinu. etc 

12O000 00 71021 

Telephone and telegraph 

400 IK) 216 51 18: 

Total. 

$177600 00 $11064: 

ASH IT XI 

•td 

fc-ceipls Dtoburse- Balance 

inent 

Nov. 30, 1K98, Balance on hand 

Dec. 31, 1898, Transactions durinp month $124 44 v.'37 .'&gt;.". 

Jan. :{1. 1*99, Transaction* during month 7li 73 4:! f &gt;T 

Feb. -28, 1899, Transactions during mouth 19-2 02 162 16 

Feb. 28, 18951, Transactions during moulr 

Mar. 31, 1899, Transactions during month] 113 S9 ' --•T4 411 

Mar. 31, 1699, Transactions during montl 

Apr. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 06 20 6li 41 

Apr. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 

May 31, 1899, Transactions during month 247 22 223 85 

May 31, 1899, Transactions during month 

June 30, 1-^99, Transactions daring month 273 84 78 f&gt;0 

Jnne 30, 1^99, Transactions during month 

-i 

July 31, 1899, Transactions during month 74 (17 79 6* 

July 31, 1899, Transactions during month 74 (17 

Aug. 31, 1899, Transactions during month 148 89 55 18 

Aug. 31, 1899, Transactions during month 148 

Sept. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 

Sept. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 68 42 24 10 

42 ,'4 10 444 

Oct. 31, 1899, Transactions during month 22 60 174 78 

Oct. 31, 1899, Transactions during month 22 60 174 7 

Nov. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 136 11 168 69 

Nov. 30, 1899, Transactions during month 136 11 

Dec. 31, 1899. Transactions during month 2315 38 87 1* 

Dec. 31, 1899. Transactions during month 

Jan. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 203 89 120 41 

Jan. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 205 89 120 41 491 

Feb. 28, 1900, Transactions daring mouth 126 72 57 07 

Feb. 28, 1900, Transactions during mouth 126 72 57 07 561 

Mar. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 12 11 105 09 

Mar. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 12 11 105 09 468 O! 

Apr. 30, 1900, Transactions during month 273 10 919.") 

Apr. 30, 1900, Transactions during month 273 1" 9195 649 

May 31, 1900, Transactions during month 106 82 174 10 

May 31, 1900, Transactions during month 106 *2 174 10 581 

June 30, 1900,' Transactions dnring month 947 59 399 

Jane 30, 1900, Transactions dnring mom 1: 947 59 399 77 

1129 

July 31, 1900, Transactions during month 757 75 255 22 

July 31, 1900, Transactions during month 757 75 255 22- 1632 31 

Aug. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 10 40 47 05 

Aug. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 10 40 47 05 1595 St 

Sept. 30, 1900, Transactions during month 55 55 227 02 

Sept. 30, 1900, Transactions during month 55 55 227 02 1424 14 

Oct. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 33 45 97 97 1359 

Oct. 31, 1900, Transactions during month 33 45 97 97 

Nov. 30, 1900, Transactions during month 213 12 424 26 

1 I- 

Total receipts during biennium 84520 31 S3676 07 

Total receipts during biennium 

Cash on hand at beginning of biennium . . 304 29 

Cash on hand at hetMiinineof biennium 

S4824 60 

Total expenditures during biennium. . . . 3676 07 

Balance on hand at close of biennium . . $1148 53 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
HItoNIt 

INSANE ASYLUM, HASTINGS 

221 

&lt;r.Y 

kdp:\ ri 

PORT. 

&gt;M NOVEMBER 'Mi. INKS. TO NOVEMBKR HO, If 

10, lfHMI 

\sparagus, dozen bunches SS 

Reets, hiisht 

:$0S 

Reel greens, bushels 11;$ 

Beans, string, bushels K;4 

Reims, lima, bushels 

28 

&lt; 'abbajre. doaen heads l.fMH» 

&lt; 'arrots. bushels 444 

' 'orn (green), dozen o 048 

• 'ucuinbers. dozen 

1'IM) 

plant, dozen 4^ 

• ireens. bushels 

140 

lice, dozen 

'.t'.tL' 

Melons, water, dozen ;}--&gt;^ 

.Melons, niusk, dozen 

:W4 

&lt; »nions. jjreen. dozen bunches 3 

S.O0O 

' inions. bushels 

:!())) 

1'ie plant, pounds 

285 

reen, bushe 

19:^ 

'otatoes. sweet, bushel 

114 

1'oiafoes. bushels 

5.809 

Peaches, bushel 

Plums, bushels 

•&gt; 

Radishes, dozen bunches 

2,800 

Spinach, bushels 

188 

Salsify, bushels 

la 

Squash, dozen 

IT 

Purnips, bushels 

756 

buslu 

2ti5 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
222 

i.axij commissioner's kkpokt. 

FARM PRODUCTS PRODUCED SINCE NOVEMBER :i», lsits. 

Millet hav, tons 
Cane, tons . . . 

:i 

l :« 

Forage, tons 

Corn fodder, acres 
Corn, bushels . . . 

mi 

INK 

Oats, bushels 

1 linn 

Beef cattle, head 
Milch cows, head . 
Bull, head 

!« 

:Ms 

- 

MATRONS REPORT 

30. 1S!)S. TO NOVEMBER 30. l!t(tO 
Aprons, bleached 

Aprons, unbleached 
Aprons, bib 

4 

Bandages, roll 

Bands for curtain 
Bags of mending 

Comfort 

'.i 

Chemises, unbleached 
Chemises, bleached . . 
Curtains, cheese cloth 

STOCK ON HAM) NoVEMHKK nil. tjmn 

Hojrs and ]&gt;i;js. In 
Horses, head . . . . 

GARMENTS MAIIK AMI KKI'AI KKH IN THE SEWINU RIHIM N( 

Aprons, jjingham 
Aprons, tickinn 
Api-mis. barber . 
Red licks 
Bibs </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
HHOXIC rXSA.NK ASYI.IM. HA8TIN&lt; 

223 

1 

II 

111 

nun 

4 
1 

i 

urtains. ha 

t 

iirfains. India limni 

• 

( 

urrains. sas 

i 

iiriains. inns 

ti 

( 

iiriains. radial 

1 

Curlailis. -rice 

I 

( 

tains, transom 

U 

&lt; 

111! &lt;-lol lls 

¦¦&gt; 

• 'uiiiiiiodf scarfs i.) 

i 

91 

( 

irpets 

It 

* aniisoli- 

::s 

l&gt; 

f»4i; 

1 &gt;r&lt;'sst's. denim 

r,n 

I Messrs. witul 

l&gt; 

1 

II 

26 

Drawers, blcaclicd B o 

Drawers, iinhleaclied 

10«&gt; 

I) 

« 

1f»f&gt; 

1 

26 

lfiS 

K 

18 

20 

M 
M 

36 

6 

Mittens. Canton Hiiniu 

i 

264 

I 

]ln» 

38 

Him ias 

ached 

:i68 

Mow cases, llllhleached 

1.189 

I 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
224 

LA XL 

MM I 

IO.NEt 

DEl'ORT 

Bass 

(5 

Sheets, unbleached 
Sheets, bleached . 
Shrouds 

Suspender* 

Skirts. Canton flannel 
Skirts, bleached 

Skirts, unbleached 
Splashers 

Shades 

Shirts, night 
Stretcher . . 

Sunbonnets . 
Towels, bath 
Towels, roller 
Towels, tea . 
Table cloths 
Table covers . 

i strainers, muslin 

Waists. Canton flannel 
Wash cloths 

Miscellaneous 

IVach butter, quarts . . 
Plum butter, quarts . . 
Tomatoes, quarts 
ftrape butter, quarts. . 
Blackberry jam. quarts 
«Tiape jelly, quarts. . . . 
Gooseberry jelly, quart 
Apple jelly, quarts. . . . 

Strawberry jelly, quart 

Ties 
Titfjx, duck </seg>

            <seg id="p019">lEKEKVKS. JKI.l.IKS AM) I'N'KI.KS 


HKON'ft 

XSAXE 

ASVI.fM. 

HASTINi; 

225 

IVach pickles, quarts .• g^ 

W aienneloii jelly, quarts j^q 

Cucumber jelly, quarts qq 

&lt; 'hili sauce, quarts jy. 

Total, quart 

748 

MONTHLY ADMISSION OF PATIENTS S1N&lt; 

E N'OVKMIiKK 

::u 

1NHN. 

Males. 

Females 

Total. 

l&gt;ecember, 1S9N 
•Januarv, 1M!»;&gt; . 

•&gt; 

•&gt; 

1 1 

•&gt; 

February, 189JI 
.March. 1S!»!I . 

• &gt; 

•&gt; 

in 

...) 

\pril, 1899 

•&gt; 

•&gt; 

¦I illy. 1S9!I 2g 

•_".t 

\iiK»«t. lS9!t 

t 8 15 

i 

October, 1SJW 

¦&gt; 

Xinellllier. 1S!»!I 

1 K» 11 

Deieuiber. 1S!*!I g 1O 

laiiuaiy. l'MMi 1(J 

21 

• &gt; 

March. l'.MMI 

24 « 30 

lime, llinii 

L'n 

o 1'5 

I ¦- 

1 .. 1 

October. UHNI .&gt;! ,., 

Total 

MO 

Tii 

220 

lined from furlough 3 &lt; 

fe&lt;l 

1 

1 

154 

74 

_':&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
226 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REI'ORT. 

• 

KESIDENCF. 

OF PATIENTS BY COUNTIES ADMITTED 

SINCE NOVEMBER 

10, 1898. 

County. Males. Females. Total. 

Adams 4 2 6 

•&gt; 

Antelope 5 0 5 

Boone -2 0 

•&gt; 

Buffalo 3 1 4 

Burt 3 0 

Box Butte 1 l 

&lt; 'ass 0 i i 

Cedar 1 0 

("lav 

Colfax 

1 

Chevenne 

Caster 
Cuniing 

Davves 

1 

Dawson 
Dodge . 

Douglas 
1 teuel . . 

II 

Duixh 

i 

Fillmore 
Frontier 
Franklin 

n 

Fu rn as 

(xage 5 4 

!? 

Greeley 2 1 

Gospf r 0 1 

Hall 6 1 

Harlan 1 fl \ 

Hamilton 

it 

Hitchcock :', 1 4 

Howard 1 0 1 

Holt 1 0 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
HI 

I 

ftONK 

INSANE ASYLUM, HASTINGS. 

227 

Count v. 

Males. Females. Total 

Jefferson 5 1 g 

Johnson 1 q 

Kearnev 

1 ' 0 1 

Kit - fh 1 0 1 

Kuux 2 0 2 

o 

Lancaster 

9 9 18 

Lincoln 

4 0 4 

.Madison 

3 0 3 

Men-irk 0 3 

Xaii« 

illl&lt;( ' 1 0 1 

NVinaha 1 1 2 

Nil. 

3 1 4 

(M.. 

4 0 4 

I'awut 

1 0 1 

1'llfll.s 

1 

I'lat 

(I 

IVi-kins 

1 0 1 

i 0 1 

1 1 

I.'.mI Willow 

• 1 

Kichaidson 

•&gt; 

Sal in 

0 1 1 

1 

1 

Siiimil 

.3 1 4 

Sarpy 

1 n 1 

Scotts Bluff 1 0 1 

Kewai 

1 1 

Sh. 

0 2 

s 

I 0 1 

Tli 11 

1 0 I 

Tim 

1 

• &gt; 

Vail. 

1 0 1 

Washington 

ii 

• 1 

XX'aviii 

11 

¦ &gt; 

W.-l.st 

M fllSNT 

J j .-, 

Y " lk ?, 1 I 

I'nknowi! o u o 

Totals 150 70 220 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
228 

LAND 

OMMISSIOXER 

REl'ORT 

NATIVITY OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINCE NOVEMBEI 

30. 1898. 

Nativity. Males. Females. Total 

Arkansas n i i 

Connecticut ~2 0 

Illinois 14 f, -JO 

I wa .' 

13 2 15 

Indiana 5 6 U 

. . 5 C. 11 

Indian Territory 1 0 1 
Minnesota 1 o i 

Indian Territory 1 0 1 

Minnesota 1 o i 

Michigan 2 0 2 

Michigan 

it 

M issouri 3 i ± 

Missouri 

. :i 1 4 

.Mississippi i o 1 

1 0 l 

Nebraska Id 3 j:5 

New Jersey 1 II 1 

New Jersey 

1 0 1 

New York 7 ;; j|&gt; 

New Yorl 

Ht 

OWo 7 5 12 

Ohio 

li' 

Pennsylvania 8 1 !? 

Pennsylvania 8 1 !? 

lT fah ! „ t 

I 'tali 

ii 

Vermont 0 1 1 

Vermont 

0 1 

Wesi Virginia 1 0 ] 

West Vinrini 

* 1 n 

Wisconsin •&gt; -j 

Wisconsin 

1 

Unknown ,s 5 2 -5 
Foreign : 

I " II kllow || 

H 

13 

Foreign 

Austria j j o 

Austria 

1 

Bohemia 7 

Bohemia 

t 11 

i 

&lt; 'anada 

&lt; "ana&lt;l;i o q .&gt; 

o 

Oramark , ; 0 G 

Denmark 

li 0 6 

England ;! t 4 

1 4 

Germany 20 11 31 

Germany 

Holland 1 0 

Ireland 

f» (I 0 

\oi\va\ 

ii 

Russia 

0 

Scotland 

1 0 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
229 

I'Hlio.NK' INSANE A8Tt.rM, HASTIX&lt; 

Males. Females. Total. 

Sweden 

11 6 17 

Switzerland 0 1 1 

0 9 9 

I'nkuowi 

Totals 

150 70 2:20 

EDUCATION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINCE NOVEM 

BER 30. 1898. 

Education. Males. Females. Total. 

Academic .-..., 9 0 9 

( 'ollegiate 2 0 2 

&lt; 'omuion school 39 39 78 

Read and write 27 16 43 

•&gt;- 

Read onlv 22 1 23 

•&gt;•&gt; 

Not stated 35 9 44 

None 16 5 "1 

Total 150 79 220 

C1VII, CONDITION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINCE 

NOVEMBER 30, 1898. 

Males. Females. Total. 

Divorced 1 2 

•&gt; 

•&gt; 

Married 47 35 82 

Single 90 20 110 

Widower and widow 5 11 16 

Unknown 7 2 9 

Total 150 70 220 </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
¦2:5(1 

LAND 

OMMISSIONER 

KKl'ORT. 

¦OCCUPATION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINCE NOVE 

M 

BER 30, 1898. 

Occupation. Males. Females. Tot 

t 

Blacksmith 2 0 2 

Bartender 1 0 1 

Brick mason 2 0 2 

Bill poster 1 0 1 

Butcher 1 0 1 

Carpenter 3 « 3 

Clerk 1 § l 

Coojter 1 9 1 

Drug clerk 1 # i 

Editor 1 § i 

Fanner 76 • 7« 

Harnessmaker 1 • l 

Hostler 1 f , i 

Insurance agent 1 « 

Laborer 32 • it 

Machinist 2 • t 

Merchant 1 ft 1 

Mill hand 1 n 1 

Painter 1 n 

Physician 1 ft \ 

Printer 1 o 1 

Stock dealer 1 o 1 

Stone cutter 1 o 1 

Tinner 1 o 1 

Unknown 8 1 9 

None 7 3 10 

Domestic 0 14 14 

Bookkeeper 0 1 1 

Housewife 0 49 49 

Teacher 0 1 1 

Nurse 

se 0 1 l 

Total ,...150 70 220 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
231 

HKiiNir INSANE ASYLUM, HASTINGS. 

HKHKDITAKY TENDENCIES OF PATIENTS ADM1TTE 

1&gt; 

SINCE NOVEMBER 

30, 1898. 

Males 

Females. 

Tots 

id 

Aunt insaiii 

!• 

•&gt; 

11 

Brother insane 9 1 10 

Brother and sister insane 0 1 1 

Brothers, two. insane 

1 

1 

I) 

Cousin insane 2 0 

• &gt; 

¦&gt; 

Father insane 5 

•• 

» 

Father and untie insane 2 0 

• &gt; 

Grandfather insane 0 1 1 

Grandmother insane 1 1 2 

Grandmother and aunt insane 2 0 i 

•&gt; 

A 

Mother and two aunts ft 1 1 

Mother and one aunt 0 1 1 

Mother insane, brother a suicide Oil 

Mother insane 

5 0 

Mother and one sister insane 1 • 1 

Mister insani 

i 2 1 

Sisters, two. insane 0 1 1 

Uncle insane 3 0 

Uncle and aunt insane 1 0 1 

1 1 real uncle insane 0 1 1 

Grandfather, mother, one cousin 

one 

uncle insane 0 1 1 

Father and mother intemperate 0 

•&gt; 

• i 

Great grandfather a suicide and father in 

temperate 
Unknown . 

ii 

0 

1 

42 45 87 

03 5 ¦OS 

150 

in 

220 

XcHlt </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
232 

UMI COMMISSIONEK 

KKFOHT. 

RELIGION OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINCE NOVEMBI 

I 

:W, 1898. 

Religion. 

Males. Females. To 

i 

Catholic 

• &gt;- 

:;i 

_i 

Hebrew 

u 

1 

1 

Protestant 

42 120 

78 

None 

12 

6 

18 

Unkuown 

. . 33 12 45 

Total 

150 

TO 22&lt;» 

ALLEGED CAU8E OF INSANITY OF PATIENTS A 
MITTED SINCE NOVEMBER 30. 1898. 

n 

Cause. Males. Females. Toti 

t 

Alcoholism 5 1 &lt;; 

Finaiu-ial reverses :{ l 4 

Epilepsy 15 2 17 

Grief 2 4 (', 

Head injuries 9 1 im 

Hereditary 33 18 51 

111 health 0 1 l 

Injury to sjiiue 1 0 1 

La grippe 2 1 

Masturbation 10 o io 

Melancholia 1 o 1 

Menopause &gt;. 0 i i 

Menstrual 0 i i 

Puerperal 0 1 1 

Poverty 1 o i 

Paralysis 1 &lt;) i 

Religious excitement 10 1 11 

Sunstroke 6 0 fi 

Syphilis 2 0 

Uterine 0 i i 

Not stated 49 :{&lt;j 

Total 150 70 220 </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
233 

Ki&gt;Xl&lt; 

INSANE ASYl.r.M. HASTINGS. 

AGE WHKX FIKST 
AK.MITTKD 
A^v. 

A I &gt;.l IIX iEI) INSANE OF PATIENTS 
SINCE NOVEMBER 30, 1S9N. 
Males. Females. Total. 

Vu 

Males 

Females 

Total. 

Four 0 1 I 

Four 
Five 

0 1 I 

Five i) i i 

it I 1 

Thirteen 2 0 2 

Thirteen 2 n 2 

Fourteen D l i 

Fourteen D l i 

Sixteen 7 o *J 

Sixteen 7 o l&gt; 

o 

¦ 

Seventeen 1 2 3 

Seventeen 1 

Eighteen 0 2 2 

Eighteen 0 2 

•&gt; 

Nineteen 12 1 13 

Nineteen 12 1 13 

Twenty 10 3 1:i 

Twenty 

10 3 IS 

Twenty-two 3 2 5 

Twentv-two 

¦&gt; 

i Z o 

Twenty-three -, 4 9 

Twenty tint 

.) 

4 » 

Twenty-four II) 0 10 

Twenty four II) o 10 

Twenty-live 0 3 3 • 

Twentv-flve 

0 3 

¦A 

•'. 

Twenty-sixth 2 1 3 

Twenty-sixth 2 1 3 

•'? 

Twenty-seven 
Twenty-eight 
Twenty-nine . 
Thirty 

Twenty-seven l:{ 3 ig 

13 3 16 

Twenty-eight ir 3 3 

o- 3 3 

Twenty-nine 0 1 1 

0 1 1 

T1 'i''fy 10 4 14 

10 4 14 

Thirty-one 0 5 5 

Thirty-one 

0 5 5 

Thirty-two 4 0 4 

Thirty-two 4 q ± 
Thirty-three 1 2 3 

Thirty-three 1 2 3 

Thirty-four g j j 

Thirty-four 6 i j 

Thirty-live 0 2 2 

Thirty-six 2 1 3 

Thirty-seven 7 q 7 

Thirty-eight o q o 

Thirty-nine 3 1 4 

Thirty-nine 3 4 

Foi 'ty , 5 2 7 

Fortv 

o 2 7 

Forty-one 0 9 o 

Forty-two 

4 2 6 

Forty-five 

8 2 10 

Fort v-se veil 

10 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
234 

LAND COMMISSIO.NKK 

KEI'OKT. 

A W- 

Males. Females. ToTa 

Forty-eight 1 i ;&amp;gt; 

Forty-eight 1 i 

Forty-nine 7 \ g 

Forty-nine 7 ] 

Fifty 0 ! 1 

Fifty 0 1 1 

Fifty-one {) ]_ I 

Fifty-one 

Fifty-two :; ; ; (i 

Fifty-two 

Fifty-trix 3 0 3 

Fifty-six 3 y 

Fifty-seven 0 1 1 

Fifty-seven 0 1 1 

Sixty •_&gt; 0 ¦« 

Sixty 

0 

Sixty-one 0 1 \ 

Sixty-one 0 \ 

Sixtv-five •&gt; a •. 

Seventy g « 3 

Seventy-six 1 • \ 

SJeventy -eight 1 « \ 

SJeventy -eight 1 « 

1 

Eighty-six 1 • 1 

•ongenital :\ 1 4 

4 

Ynknown 

Total 

!»• 

7* ?« 

•AUSE OF DEATH OF PATIENTS SINOE XOVKMHM 

;0, 1898. 

Cause. Males. Females. Tola 
Acute dysentery tj \ 7 

H 

Accident, killed by the cars 1 
Chronic dysentery (j 

1 

Anemia, chronic :j i 4 
Asthma 1 0 1 

Catarrhal janndii 

1 

]&gt;iabetes 

Diabetic gangrene 
Enteritis 

i 

Epilepsy 

9 

Erysipelas, phlegmonous 
General paralysis 

20 

11 

SI </seg>


            <seg id="p029">235 

HKOXK 

INSANE ASYLUM, HASTIM 

Males. Females. Total. 

lit mi! failure 0 1 1 

Hypostatii pneumonia 1 0 1 

Inanition 1 0 1 

Intestinal obstruction 2 0 2 

Nervous prostration 5 0 5 

Nephritis 1 0 1 

Old at 

•T 

Paralysis 4 G 4 

Paralytic dementia 0 1 1 

Pneumonia a 6 11 

Peritonitis 2 • 2 

¦&gt; 

Tuberculosis 9 lft i§ 

Septicaemia #. 1 1 

Loc&lt;, motor ataxia • 1 1 

&lt; 'ancer of uterus • 2 2 

Valvular heart disease 1 9 1 

oial 7« 43 lit 

FORMS OF DISEASES OF PATIENTS ADMITTED SINOB 

NOVEMBER 30, 1898. 

Form of Diseas 

Males. Females. Total. 

Delusional insanity 

46 5 51 

Dellieli 

* 

II 

- 

Dementia, senile 5 0 5 

Dementia, paralytic S 0 8 

Emotional insanity 14 2 16 

Epilepl i»- insanity lo 2 17 

Idiocv 

3 14 

Mania, cliron 

42 38 SO 

Mania, syphilitic 1 0 1 

Melancholia 

16 14 30 

Total 150 TO 220 
</seg>

            <seg id="p030">2tt&gt; 

A.ND CIIMMISSKINKK'S 

KKI'UKT. 

KECA PIT L LA T1ON. 

Males. Females. Total 

Died 7C 4:t 1 1» 

Discharged cured 2 11 13 

Discharged improved 
Escaped 

it 

ii 

Furloughed 

Total 

M 

57 1 4 1 

Patients present on this date. . . . 
Patients on furl ouch on this date 

Total mi books this &lt;la\ 

US .ion 71K 

41&lt;; 2!»7 71: </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>